<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1282a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1282a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1282a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1282a"><akn:num>1282a</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency supply of agricultural products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1282a. Emergency supply of agricultural products(a) Establishment of prices to insure orderly, adequate and steady supply of productsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture shall assist farmers, processors, and distributors in obtaining such prices for agricultural products that an orderly, adequate and steady supply of such products will exist for the consumers of this nation.


(b) Adjustments in maximum price of products subject to any price control or freeze order or regulation to increase supplyThe President shall make appropriate adjustments in the maximum price which may be charged under the provisions of Executive Order 11723 (dated June 13, 1973) or any subsequent Executive Order for any agricultural products (at any point in the distribution chain) as to which the Secretary of Agriculture certifies to the President that the supply of the product will be reduced to unacceptably low levels as a result of any price control or freeze order or regulation and that alternative means for increasing the supply are not available.


(c) “Agricultural products” definedUnder this section, the term “agricultural products” shall include meat, poultry, vegetables, fruits and all other agricultural commodities in raw or processed form, except forestry products or fish or fishery products.


(d) Implementation of policies to encourage full production in periods of short supply at fair and reasonable pricesThe Secretary of Agriculture is directed to implement policies under this Act which are designed to encourage American farmers to produce to their full capabilities during periods of short supply to assure American consumers with an adequate supply of food and fiber at fair and reasonable prices.


(Pub. L. 91–524, title VIII, § 815, as added Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(27)(B), Aug. 10, 1973, 87 Stat. 240.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextExecutive Order 11723 (dated June 13, 1973), referred to in subsec. (b), was revoked by Ex. Ord. No. 11788</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of prices to insure orderly, adequate and steady supply of products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of prices to insure orderly, adequate and steady supply of products Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture shall assist farmers, processors, and distributors in obtaining such prices for agricultural products that an orderly, adequate and steady supply of such products will exist for the consumers of this nation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments in maximum price of products subject to any price control or freeze order or regulation to increase supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustments in maximum price of products subject to any price control or freeze order or regulation to increase supply The President shall make appropriate adjustments in the maximum price which may be charged under the provisions of Executive Order 11723 (dated June 13, 1973) or any subsequent Executive Order for any agricultural products (at any point in the distribution chain) as to which the Secretary of Agriculture certifies to the President that the supply of the product will be reduced to unacceptably low levels as a result of any price control or freeze order or regulation and that alternative means for increasing the supply are not available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Agricultural products” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Agricultural products” defined Under this section, the term “agricultural products” shall include meat, poultry, vegetables, fruits and all other agricultural commodities in raw or processed form, except forestry products or fish or fishery products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1282a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of policies to encourage full production in periods of short supply at fair and reasonable prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation of policies to encourage full production in periods of short supply at fair and reasonable prices The Secretary of Agriculture is directed to implement policies under this Act which are designed to encourage American farmers to produce to their full capabilities during periods of short supply to assure American consumers with an adequate supply of food and fiber at fair and reasonable prices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>