<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/12c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/12c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/12c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12c"><akn:num>12c</akn:num><akn:heading>Disciplinary actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12c. Disciplinary actions(a) Action taken; written notice of reasons for action(1) Any exchange or the Commission if the exchange fails to act, may suspend, expel, or otherwise discipline any person who is a member of that exchange, or deny any person access to the exchange. Any such action shall be taken solely in accordance with the rules of that exchange.

(2) Any suspension, expulsion, disciplinary, or access denial procedure established by an exchange rule shall provide for written notice to the Commission and to the person who is suspended, expelled, or disciplined, or denied access, within thirty days, which includes the reasons for the exchange action in the form and manner the Commission prescribes. An exchange shall make public its findings and the reasons for the exchange action in any such proceeding, including the action taken or the penalty imposed, but shall not disclose the evidence therefor, except to the person who is suspended, expelled, or disciplined, or denied access, and to the Commission.


(b) Review by CommissionThe Commission may, in its discretion and in accordance with such standards and procedures as it deems appropriate, review any decision by an exchange whereby a person is suspended, expelled, otherwise disciplined, or denied access to the exchange. In addition, the Commission may, in its discretion and upon application of any person who is adversely affected by any other exchange action, review such action.


(c) Affirmance, modification, set aside, or remand of actionThe Commission may affirm, modify, set aside, or remand any exchange decision it reviews pursuant to subsection (b), after a determination on the record whether the action of the exchange was in accordance with the policies of this chapter. Subject to judicial review, any order of the Commission entered pursuant to subsection (b) shall govern the exchange in its further treatment of the matter.


(d) Stay of actionThe Commission, in its discretion, may order a stay o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action taken; written notice of reasons for action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Action taken; written notice of reasons for action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review by Commission The Commission may, in its discretion and in accordance with such standards and procedures as it deems appropriate, review any decision by an exchange whereby a person is suspended, expelled, otherwise disciplined, or denied access to the exchange. In addition, the Commission may, in its discretion and upon application of any person who is adversely affected by any other exchange action, review such action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affirmance, modification, set aside, or remand of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Affirmance, modification, set aside, or remand of action The Commission may affirm, modify, set aside, or remand any exchange decision it reviews pursuant to subsection (b), after a determination on the record whether the action of the exchange was in accordance with the policies of this chapter. Subject to judicial review, any order of the Commission entered pursuant to subsection (b) shall govern the exchange in its further treatment of the matter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Stay of action The Commission, in its discretion, may order a stay of any action taken pursuant to subsection (a) pending review thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major disciplinary rule violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Major disciplinary rule violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>