<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1305"><akn:num>1305</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of acreage allotments or feed grain bases on public lands upon request of State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1305. Transfer of acreage allotments or feed grain bases on public lands upon request of State agencies
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, upon the request of any agency of any State charged with the administration of the public lands of the State, may permit the transfer of acreage allotments or feed grain bases together with relevant production histories which have been determined pursuant to the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, as amended [7 U.S.C. 1281 et seq.], or section 590p of title 16, from any farm composed of public lands to any other farm or farms in the same county composed of public lands: Provided, That as a condition for the transfer of any allotment or base an acreage equal to or greater than the allotment or base transferred prior to adjustment, if any, shall be devoted to and maintained in permanent vegetative cover on the farm from which the transfer is made. The Secretary shall prescribe regulations which he deems necessary for the administration of this section, which may provide for adjusting downward the size of the allotment or base transferred if the farm to which the allotment or base is transferred normally has a higher yield per acre for the commodity for which the allotment or base is determined, for reasonable limitations on the size of the resulting allotments and bases on farms to which transfers are made, taking into account the size of the allotments and bases on farms of similar size in the community, and for retransferring allotments or bases and relevant histories if the conditions of the transfers are not fulfilled.
(Pub. L. 89–321, title VII, § 706, Nov. 3, 1965, 79 Stat. 1210; Pub. L. 91–524, title IV, § 405(a), formerly § 405, title VI, § 606, Nov. 30, 1970, 84 Stat. 1366, 1378, renumbered § 405(a) and amended Pub. L. 93–86, § 1(12)(a), Aug. 10, 1973, 87 Stat. 229.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938, referred to in text, is act Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, 52 </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>