<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1308–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1308–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1308–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1308_3"><akn:num>1308–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign persons made ineligible for program benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1308–3. Foreign persons made ineligible for program benefits
Notwithstanding any other provision of law:(a) In generalAny person who is not a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted into the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.) shall be ineligible to receive any type of loans or payments made available under title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [7 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.], title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [7 U.S.C. 9001 et seq.], the Agricultural Market Transition Act [7 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.], the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (15 U.S.C. 714 et seq.), or subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3831 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or under any contract entered into under title XII [16 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.], with respect to any commodity produced, or land set aside from production, on a farm that is owned or operated by such person, unless such person is an individual who is providing land, capital, and a substantial amount of personal labor in the production of crops on such farm.


(b) Corporations or other entitiesFor purposes of subsection (a), a corporation or other entity shall be considered a person that is ineligible for production adjustment payments, price support program loans, payments, or benefits if more than 10 percent of the beneficial ownership of the entity is held by persons who are not citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted into the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.], unless such persons provide a substantial amount of personal labor in the production of crops on such farm. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subsection, with respect to an entity that is determined to be ineligible to receive such payments, loans, or other benefits, the Secretary may make payments, loans, and other benefi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any person who is not a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted into the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.) shall be ineligible to receive any type of loans or payments made available under title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 [7 U.S.C. 8701 et seq.], title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [7 U.S.C. 9001 et seq.], the Agricultural Market Transition Act [7 U.S.C. 7201 et seq.], the Commodity Credit Corporation Charter Act (15 U.S.C. 714 et seq.), or subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3831 et seq.),11 See References in Text note below. or under any contract entered into under title XII [16 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.], with respect to any commodity produced, or land set aside from production, on a farm that is owned or operated by such person, unless such person is an individual who is providing land, capital, and a substantial amount of pe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporations or other entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Corporations or other entities For purposes of subsection (a), a corporation or other entity shall be considered a person that is ineligible for production adjustment payments, price support program loans, payments, or benefits if more than 10 percent of the beneficial ownership of the entity is held by persons who are not citizens of the United States or aliens lawfully admitted into the United States for permanent residence under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.], unless such persons provide a substantial amount of personal labor in the production of crops on such farm. Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this subsection, with respect to an entity that is determined to be ineligible to receive such payments, loans, or other benefits, the Secretary may make payments, loans, and other benefits in an amount determined by the Secretary to be representative of the percentage interests of the entity that is owned by citizens of the United States and al</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1308_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prospective application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prospective application No person shall become ineligible under this section for production adjustment payments, price support program loans, payments or benefits as the result of the production of a crop of an agricultural commodity planted, or commodity program or conservation reserve contract entered into, before December 22, 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>