<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1343"><akn:num>1343</akn:num><akn:heading>Referendum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1343. Referendum
Not later than December 15 following the issuance of the marketing quota proclamation provided for in section 1342 of this title, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum, by secret ballot, of farmers engaged in the production of cotton in the calendar year in which the referendum is held, to determine whether such farmers are in favor of or opposed to the quota so proclaimed. If more than one-third of the farmers voting in the referendum oppose the national marketing quota, such quota shall become ineffective upon proclamation of the results of the referendum. The Secretary shall proclaim the results of any referendum held hereunder within thirty days after the date of such referendum. Notwithstanding any other provision hereof, the referendum with respect to the national marketing quota for cotton for the marketing year beginning August 1, 1986, may be conducted not later than thirty-one days after adjournment sine die of the first session of the Ninety-ninth Congress.
(Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 343, 52 Stat. 56; Apr. 7, 1938, ch. 107, § 8, 52 Stat. 203; July 26, 1939, ch. 376, 53 Stat. 1125; July 3, 1948, ch. 827, title II, § 207(c), 62 Stat. 1257; Aug. 29, 1949, ch. 518, § 1, 63 Stat. 670; Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, title IV, § 415(e), 63 Stat. 1058; Pub. L. 97–77, § 2(c), Nov. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 1069; Pub. L. 99–157, § 4, Nov. 15, 1985, 99 Stat. 818.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Provision that if marketing quotas were proclaimed for the 1950 crop, farmers eligible to vote in the referendum with respect to such crop were to be those farmers who had produced cotton in the 1948 calendar year was omitted from the Code.

Amendments1985—Pub. L. 99–157 amended last sentence generally, substituting “August 1, 1986, may be conducted not later than thirty-one days after adjournment sine die of the first session of the Ninety-ninth Congress” for “August 1, 1982, may be conducted not later than the earlier of the following: (1) thirty days after</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>