<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1344b"><akn:num>1344b</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale, lease, or transfer of cotton acreage allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1344b. Sale, lease, or transfer of cotton acreage allotments(a) Authority for calendar years 1966 through 1970; transfer periodsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, if he determines that it will not impair the effective operation of the program involved, (1) may permit the owner and operator of any farm for which a cotton acreage allotment is established to sell or lease all or any part or the right to all or any part of such allotment (excluding that part of the allotment which the Secretary determines was apportioned to the farm from the national acreage reserve) to any other owner or operator of a farm for transfer to such farm; (2) may permit the owner of a farm to transfer all or any part of such allotment to any other farm owned or controlled by him; Provided, That the authority granted under this section may be exercised for the calendar years 1966 through 1970, but all transfers hereunder shall be for such period of years as the parties thereto may agree.


(b) Requisite conditions for transfer of acreage allotmentsTransfers under this section shall be subject to the following conditions: (i) no allotment shall be transferred to a farm in another State or to a person for use in another State; (ii) no farm allotment may be sold or leased for transfer to a farm in another county unless the producers of cotton in the county from which transfer is being made have voted in a referendum within three years of the date of such transfer, by a two-thirds majority of the producers participating in such referendum, to permit the transfer of allotments to farms outside the county, which referendum, insofar as practicable, shall be held in conjunction with the marketing quota referendum for the commodity; (iii) no transfer of an allotment from a farm subject to a mortgage or other lien shall be permitted unless the transfer is agreed to by the lienholder; (iv) no sale of a farm allotment shall be permitted if any sale of cotton allotment to the sam</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for calendar years 1966 through 1970; transfer periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority for calendar years 1966 through 1970; transfer periods Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary, if he determines that it will not impair the effective operation of the program involved, (1) may permit the owner and operator of any farm for which a cotton acreage allotment is established to sell or lease all or any part or the right to all or any part of such allotment (excluding that part of the allotment which the Secretary determines was apportioned to the farm from the national acreage reserve) to any other owner or operator of a farm for transfer to such farm; (2) may permit the owner of a farm to transfer all or any part of such allotment to any other farm owned or controlled by him; Provided, That the authority granted under this section may be exercised for the calendar years 1966 through 1970, but all transfers hereunder shall be for such period of years as the parties thereto may agree.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisite conditions for transfer of acreage allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requisite conditions for transfer of acreage allotments Transfers under this section shall be subject to the following conditions: (i) no allotment shall be transferred to a farm in another State or to a person for use in another State; (ii) no farm allotment may be sold or leased for transfer to a farm in another county unless the producers of cotton in the county from which transfer is being made have voted in a referendum within three years of the date of such transfer, by a two-thirds majority of the producers participating in such referendum, to permit the transfer of allotments to farms outside the county, which referendum, insofar as practicable, shall be held in conjunction with the marketing quota referendum for the commodity; (iii) no transfer of an allotment from a farm subject to a mortgage or other lien shall be permitted unless the transfer is agreed to by the lienholder; (iv) no sale of a farm allotment shall be permitted if any sale of cotton allotment to the same f</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extent of estate transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extent of estate transferred The transfer of an allotment shall have the effect of transferring also the acreage history, farm base, and marketing quota attributable to such allotment and if the transfer is made prior to the determination of the allotment for any year the transfer shall include the right of the owner or operator to have an allotment determined for the farm for such year: Provided, That in the case of a transfer by lease, the amount of the allotment shall be considered for purposes of determining allotments after the expiration of the lease to have been planted on the farm from which such allotment is transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of ineligibility of land for new allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of ineligibility of land for new allotment The land in the farm from which the entire cotton allotment and acreage history have been transferred shall not be eligible for a new farm cotton allotment during the five years following the year in which such transfer is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of allotments established under minimum allotment provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer of allotments established under minimum allotment provisions The transfer of a portion of a farm allotment which was established under minimum farm allotment provisions for cotton or which operates to bring the farm within the minimum farm allotment provision for cotton shall cause the minimum farm allotment or base to be reduced to an amount equal to the allotment remaining on the farm after such transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules and regulations The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section, which shall include provisions for adjusting the size of the allotment transferred if the farm to which the allotment is transferred has a substantially higher yield per acre and such other terms and conditions as he deems necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment upon transfer of land covered by conservation reserve contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjustment upon transfer of land covered by conservation reserve contract If the sale or lease occurs during a period in which the farm is covered by a conservation reserve contract, cropland conversion agreement, cropland adjustment agreement, or other similar land utilization agreement, the rates of payment provided for in the contract or agreement of the farm from which the transfer is made shall be subject to an appropriate adjustment, but no adjustment shall be made in the contract or agreement of the farm to which the allotment is transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of cotton acreage allotments for rice acreage allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exchange of cotton acreage allotments for rice acreage allotments The Secretary shall by regulations authorize the exchange between farms in the same county, or between farms in adjoining counties within a State, of cotton acreage allotment for rice acreage allotment. Any such exchange shall be made on the basis of application filed with the county committee by the owners and operators of the farms, and the transfer of allotment between the farms shall include transfer of the related acreage history for the commodity. The exchange shall be acre for acre or on such other basis as the Secretary determines is fair and reasonable, taking into consideration the comparative productivity of the soil for the farms involved and other relevant factors. No farm from which the entire cotton or rice allotment has been transferred shall be eligible for an allotment of cotton or rice as a new farm within a period of five crop years after the date of such exchange.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to cotton restricted to upland cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability to cotton restricted to upland cotton The provisions of this section relating to cotton shall apply only to upland cotton.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>