<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1344"><akn:num>1344</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment of national acreage allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1344. Apportionment of national acreage allotments(a) BasisWhenever a national marketing quota is proclaimed under section 1342 of this title, the Secretary shall determine and proclaim a national acreage allotment for the crop of cotton to be produced in the next calendar year. The national acreage allotment for cotton shall be that acreage, based upon the national average yield per acre of cotton for the four years immediately preceding the calendar year in which the national marketing quota is proclaimed, required to make available from such crop an amount of cotton equal to the national marketing quota.


(b) Apportionment among States for year 1953 and subsequent years; adjustment; national acreage reserveThe national acreage allotment for cotton for 1953 and subsequent years shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of the acreage planted to cotton (including the acreage regarded as having been planted to cotton under the provisions of Public Law 12, Seventy-ninth Congress) during the five calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which the national marketing quota is proclaimed, with adjustments for abnormal weather conditions during such period: Provided, That there is established a national acreage reserve consisting of three hundred and ten thousand acres which shall be in addition to the national acreage allotment; and such reserve shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of their needs for additional acreage for establishing minimum farm allotments under subsection (f)(1), as determined by the Secretary without regard to State and county acreage reserves (except that the amount apportioned to Nevada shall be one thousand acres). For the 1960 and succeeding crops of cotton, the needs of States (other than Nevada) for such additional acreage for such purpose may be estimated by the Secretary, after taking into consideration such needs as determined or estimated for the preceding crop of cotton and the size of the national acr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basis Whenever a national marketing quota is proclaimed under section 1342 of this title, the Secretary shall determine and proclaim a national acreage allotment for the crop of cotton to be produced in the next calendar year. The national acreage allotment for cotton shall be that acreage, based upon the national average yield per acre of cotton for the four years immediately preceding the calendar year in which the national marketing quota is proclaimed, required to make available from such crop an amount of cotton equal to the national marketing quota.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment among States for year 1953 and subsequent years; adjustment; national acreage reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Apportionment among States for year 1953 and subsequent years; adjustment; national acreage reserve The national acreage allotment for cotton for 1953 and subsequent years shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of the acreage planted to cotton (including the acreage regarded as having been planted to cotton under the provisions of Public Law 12, Seventy-ninth Congress) during the five calendar years immediately preceding the calendar year in which the national marketing quota is proclaimed, with adjustments for abnormal weather conditions during such period: Provided, That there is established a national acreage reserve consisting of three hundred and ten thousand acres which shall be in addition to the national acreage allotment; and such reserve shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of their needs for additional acreage for establishing minimum farm allotments under subsection (f)(1), as determined by the Secretary without regard to State and county acreage res</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment among States for years 1950 and 1951; computation and adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Apportionment among States for years 1950 and 1951; computation and adjustment The national acreage allotments for cotton for the years 1950 and 1951 shall be apportioned to the States on the basis of a national acreage allotment base of twenty-two million five hundred thousand acres, computed and adjusted as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment for year 1952; adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Apportionment for year 1952; adjustment The national acreage allotment for cotton for 1952 shall be apportioned to States on the basis of the acreage planted to cotton (including the acreage regarded as having been planted to cotton under the provisions of Public Law 12, Seventy-ninth Congress) during the years 1946, 1947, 1948, and 1950, with adjustments for abnormal weather conditions during such period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment among counties; reservation of acreage; additional acreage for establishing minimum farm allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Apportionment among counties; reservation of acreage; additional acreage for establishing minimum farm allotments The State acreage allotment for cotton shall be apportioned to counties on the same basis as to years and conditions as is applicable to the State under subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section: Provided, That the State committee may reserve not to exceed 10 per centum of its State acreage allotment (15 per centum if the State’s 1948 planted acreage was in excess of one million acres and less than half its 1943 allotment) which shall be used to make adjustments in county allotments for trends in acreage, for counties adversely affected by abnormal conditions affecting plantings, or for small or new farms, or to correct inequities in farm allotments and to prevent hardship: Provided further, That if the additional acreage allocated to a State under the proviso in subsection (b) is less than the requirements as determined or estimated by the Secretary for establishin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment among farms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Apportionment among farms The county acreage allotment, less not to exceed the percentage provided for in paragraph 3 of this subsection, shall be apportioned to farms on which cotton has been planted (or regarded as having been planted under the provisions of Public Law 12, Seventy-ninth Congress) in any one of the three years immediately preceding the year for which such allotment is determined on the following basis:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law and conditions governing establishment of acreage allotments and yields</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Law and conditions governing establishment of acreage allotments and yields Notwithstanding the foregoing provisions of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 378(d), as added Aug. 28, 1958, Pub. L. 85–835, title V, § 501, 72 Stat. 996</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess planting; old and new farm allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Excess planting; old and new farm allotment Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, any acreage planted to cotton in excess of the farm acreage allotment shall not be taken into account in establishing State, county, and farm acreage allotments. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, beginning with the 1960 crop the planting of cotton on a farm in any of the immediately preceding three years that allotments were in effect but no allotment was established for such farm for any year of such three-year period shall not make the farm eligible for an allotment as an old farm under subsection (f) of this section: Provided, however, That by reason of such planting the farm need not be considered as ineligible for a new farm allotment under subsection (f)(3) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1344_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of records for inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Availability of records for inspection Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, State and county committees shall make available for inspection by owners or operators of farms receiving cotton acreage allotments all records pertaining to cotton acreage allotments and marketing quotas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>