<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1345" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1345/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1345/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1345"><akn:num>1345</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm marketing quotas; farm marketing excess</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1345. Farm marketing quotas; farm marketing excess
The farm marketing quota for any crop of cotton shall be the actual production of the acreage planted to cotton on the farm less the farm marketing excess. The farm marketing excess shall be the normal production of that acreage planted to cotton on the farm which is in excess of the farm acreage allotment: Provided, That such farm marketing excess shall not be larger than the amount by which the actual production of cotton on the farm exceeds the normal production of the farm acreage allotment, if the producer establishes such actual production to the satisfaction of the Secretary.
(Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 345, 52 Stat. 58; July 3, 1948, ch. 827, title II, § 205, 62 Stat. 1256; Aug. 29, 1949, ch. 518, § 1, 63 Stat. 674; Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, title IV, § 415(e), 63 Stat. 1058.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1949—Act Oct. 31, 1949, repealed amendatory provisions of act July 3, 1948.
Act Aug. 29, 1949, stated what the farm marketing quota shall be and what the farm marketing excess shall be.
1948—Act July 3, 1948, changed conditions which must be determined by Secretary to exist before marketing quotas can be imposed.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1948 AmendmentAmendment by act July 3, 1948, effective Jan. 1, 1950, see section 303 of act July 3, 1948, set out as a note under section 1301 of this title.

Inapplicability of SectionSection inapplicable to 1984 and subsequent crops of extra long staple cotton, see section 3 of Pub. L. 98–88, set out as a note under section 1342 of this title.
Section inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning Feb. 7, 2014, through Dec. 31, 2018, see section 9092(a)(1) of this title.
Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning June 18, 2008, through Dec. 31, 2012, se</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>