<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359ii" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359ii/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359ii/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1359ii"><akn:num>1359ii</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1359ii. Appeals(a) In generalAn appeal may be taken to the Secretary from any decision under section 1359dd of this title establishing allocations of marketing allotments, or under section 1359ff or 1359gg(d) of this title, by any person adversely affected by reason of any such decision.


(b) Procedure(1) Notice of appealAny such appeal shall be taken by filing with the Secretary, within 20 days after the decision complained of is effective, notice in writing of the appeal and a statement of the reasons therefor. Unless a later date is specified by the Secretary as part of the Secretary’s decision, the decision complained of shall be considered to be effective as of the date on which announcement of the decision is made. The Secretary shall deliver a copy of any notice of appeal to each person shown by the records of the Secretary to be adversely affected by reason of the decision appealed, and shall at all times thereafter permit any such person to inspect and make copies of appellant’s reasons for the appeal and shall on application permit the person to intervene in the appeal.


(2) HearingThe Secretary shall provide each appellant an opportunity for a hearing before an administrative law judge in accordance with sections 554 and 556 of title 5. The expenses for conducting the hearing shall be reimbursed by the Commodity Credit Corporation.



(Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 359i, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1403, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 202; amended Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1403(h), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 988; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title I, § 1403(h), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1716.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1359ii, act Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 359i, as added Pub. L. 101–624, title IX, § 902, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3487; am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359ii_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An appeal may be taken to the Secretary from any decision under section 1359dd of this title establishing allocations of marketing allotments, or under section 1359ff or 1359gg(d) of this title, by any person adversely affected by reason of any such decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359ii_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>