<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359kk" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359kk/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359kk/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1359kk"><akn:num>1359kk</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of tariff rate quotas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1359kk. Administration of tariff rate quotas(a) Establishment(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, at the beginning of the quota year, the Secretary shall establish the tariff-rate quotas for raw cane sugar and refined sugars at the minimum level necessary to comply with obligations under international trade agreements that have been approved by Congress.


(2) ExceptionParagraph (1) shall not apply to specialty sugar.



(b) Adjustment(1) Before April 1Before April 1 of each fiscal year, for the sole purpose of responding directly to an emergency shortage of sugar in the United States market that is caused by a war, flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster, or other similar event as determined by the Secretary—(A) the Secretary shall take action to increase the supply of sugar in accordance with sections 1359cc(b)(2) and 1359ee(b) of this title, including an increase in the tariff-rate quota for raw cane sugar to accommodate the reassignment to imports; and

(B) if there is still a shortage of sugar in the United States market, and marketing of domestic sugar has been maximized, and domestic raw cane sugar refining capacity has been maximized, the Secretary may increase the tariff-rate quota for refined sugars sufficient to accommodate the supply increase, if the further increase will not threaten to result in the forfeiture of sugar pledged as collateral for a loan under section 7272 of this title.


(2) On or after April 1On or after April 1 of each fiscal year—(A) the Secretary may take action to increase the supply of sugar in accordance with sections 1359cc(b)(2) and 1359ee(b) of this title, including an increase in the tariff-rate quota for raw cane sugar to accommodate the reassignment to imports; and

(B) if there is still a shortage of sugar in the United States market, and marketing of domestic sugar has been maximized, the Secretary may increase the tariff-rate quota for raw cane sugar if t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359kk_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359kk_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359kk_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reallocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359kk_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refined sugar</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Refined sugar</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>