<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359cc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359cc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359cc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1359cc"><akn:num>1359cc</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of flexible marketing allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1359cc. Establishment of flexible marketing allotments(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish flexible marketing allotments for sugar for any crop year in which the allotments are required under section 1359bb(b) of this title in accordance with this section.


(b) Overall allotment quantity(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish the overall quantity of sugar to be allotted for the crop year (referred to in this subpart as the “overall allotment quantity”) at a level that is—(A) sufficient to maintain raw and refined sugar prices above forfeiture levels to avoid forfeiture of sugar to the Commodity Credit Corporation; but

(B) not less than a quantity equal to 85 percent of the estimated quantity of sugar for domestic human consumption for the crop year.


(2) AdjustmentSubject to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall adjust the overall allotment quantity to maintain—(A) raw and refined sugar prices above forfeiture levels to avoid the forfeiture of sugar to the Commodity Credit Corporation; and

(B) adequate supplies of raw and refined sugar in the domestic market.



(c) Marketing allotment for sugar derived from sugar beets and sugar derived from sugarcaneThe overall allotment quantity for the crop year shall be allotted between—(1) sugar derived from sugar beets by establishing a marketing allotment for a crop year at a quantity equal to the product of multiplying the overall allotment quantity for the crop year by 54.35 percent; and

(2) sugar derived from sugarcane by establishing a marketing allotment for a crop year at a quantity equal to the product of multiplying the overall allotment quantity for the crop year by 45.65 percent.


(d) Filling cane sugar and beet sugar allotments(1) Cane sugarEach marketing allotment for cane sugar established under this section may only be filled with sugar processed from domestically grown sugarcane.


(2) Beet sugarEach marketing allotment for beet sugar established under this section may only be filled with sugar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish flexible marketing allotments for sugar for any crop year in which the allotments are required under section 1359bb(b) of this title in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overall allotment quantity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Overall allotment quantity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing allotment for sugar derived from sugar beets and sugar derived from sugarcane</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Marketing allotment for sugar derived from sugar beets and sugar derived from sugarcane The overall allotment quantity for the crop year shall be allotted between—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filling cane sugar and beet sugar allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filling cane sugar and beet sugar allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State cane sugar allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State cane sugar allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filling cane sugar allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Filling cane sugar allotments Except as provided in section 1359ee of this title, a State cane sugar allotment established under subsection (e) for a crop year may be filled only with sugar processed from sugarcane grown in the State covered by the allotment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359cc_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of marketing allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjustment of marketing allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>