<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359aa" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359aa/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1359aa/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1359aa"><akn:num>1359aa</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1359aa. Definitions
In this subpart:(1) Human consumptionThe term “human consumption”, when used in the context of a reference to sugar (whether in the form of sugar, in-process sugar, syrup, molasses, or in some other form) for human consumption, includes sugar for use in human food, beverages, or similar products.


(2) Mainland StateThe term “mainland State” means a State other than an offshore State.


(3) Market(A) In generalThe term “market” means to sell or otherwise dispose of in commerce in the United States.


(B) InclusionsThe term “market” includes—(i) the forfeiture of sugar under the loan program for sugar established under section 7272 of this title;

(ii) with respect to any integrated processor and refiner, the movement of raw cane sugar into the refining process; and

(iii) the sale of sugar for the production of ethanol or other bioenergy product, if the disposition of the sugar is administered by the Secretary under section 8110 of this title.


(C) Marketing yearForfeited sugar described in subparagraph (B)(i) shall be considered to have been marketed during the crop year for which a loan is made under the loan program described in that subparagraph.



(4) Offshore StateThe term “offshore State” means a sugarcane producing State located outside of the continental United States.


(5) StateNotwithstanding section 1301 of this title, the term “State” means—(A) a State;

(B) the District of Columbia; and

(C) the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.


(6) United StatesThe term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.


(Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title III, § 359a, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1403, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 187; amended Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1403(a), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 981; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title I, § 1403(a), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1709.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Human consumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Human consumption The term “human consumption”, when used in the context of a reference to sugar (whether in the form of sugar, in-process sugar, syrup, molasses, or in some other form) for human consumption, includes sugar for use in human food, beverages, or similar products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mainland State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Mainland State The term “mainland State” means a State other than an offshore State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Market</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Market</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offshore State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Offshore State The term “offshore State” means a sugarcane producing State located outside of the continental United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) State Notwithstanding section 1301 of this title, the term “State” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1359aa_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) United States The term “United States”, when used in a geographical sense, means all of the States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>