<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136"><akn:num>136</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter—(a) Active ingredientThe term “active ingredient” means—(1) in the case of a pesticide other than a plant regulator, defoliant, desiccant, or nitrogen stabilizer, an ingredient which will prevent, destroy, repel, or mitigate any pest;

(2) in the case of a plant regulator, an ingredient which, through physiological action, will accelerate or retard the rate of growth or rate of maturation or otherwise alter the behavior of ornamental or crop plants or the product thereof;

(3) in the case of a defoliant, an ingredient which will cause the leaves or foliage to drop from a plant;

(4) in the case of a desiccant, an ingredient which will artificially accelerate the drying of plant tissue; and

(5) in the case of a nitrogen stabilizer, an ingredient which will prevent or hinder the process of nitrification, denitrification, ammonia volatilization, or urease production through action affecting soil bacteria.


(b) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(c) AdulteratedThe term “adulterated” applies to any pesticide if—(1) its strength or purity falls below the professed standard of quality as expressed on its labeling under which it is sold;

(2) any substance has been substituted wholly or in part for the pesticide; or

(3) any valuable constituent of the pesticide has been wholly or in part abstracted.


(d) AnimalThe term “animal” means all vertebrate and invertebrate species, including but not limited to man and other mammals, birds, fish, and shellfish.


(e) Certified applicator, etc.(1) Certified applicatorThe term “certified applicator” means any individual who is certified under section 136i of this title as authorized to use or supervise the use of any pesticide which is classified for restricted use. Any applicator who holds or applies registered pesticides, or uses dilutions of registered pesticides consistent with subsection (ee), only to provid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Active ingredient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Active ingredient The term “active ingredient” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adulterated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adulterated The term “adulterated” applies to any pesticide if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Animal The term “animal” means all vertebrate and invertebrate species, including but not limited to man and other mammals, birds, fish, and shellfish.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified applicator, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certified applicator, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defoliant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Defoliant The term “defoliant” means any substance or mixture of substances intended for causing the leaves or foliage to drop from a plant, with or without causing abscission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Desiccant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Desiccant The term “desiccant” means any substance or mixture of substances intended for artificially accelerating the drying of plant tissue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Device</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Device The term “device” means any instrument or contrivance (other than a firearm) which is intended for trapping, destroying, repelling, or mitigating any pest or any other form of plant or animal life (other than man and other than bacteria, virus, or other microorganism on or in living man or other living animals); but not including equipment used for the application of pesticides when sold separately therefrom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>District court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) District court The term “district court” means a United States district court, the District Court of Guam, the District Court of the Virgin Islands, and the highest court of American Samoa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Environment The term “environment” includes water, air, land, and all plants and man and other animals living therein, and the interrelationships which exist among these.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>