<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136a"><akn:num>136a</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration of pesticides</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136a. Registration of pesticides(a) Requirement of registrationExcept as provided by this subchapter, no person in any State may distribute or sell to any person any pesticide that is not registered under this subchapter. To the extent necessary to prevent unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, the Administrator may by regulation limit the distribution, sale, or use in any State of any pesticide that is not registered under this subchapter and that is not the subject of an experimental use permit under section 136c of this title or an emergency exemption under section 136p of this title.


(b) ExemptionsA pesticide which is not registered with the Administrator may be transferred if—(1) the transfer is from one registered establishment to another registered establishment operated by the same producer solely for packaging at the second establishment or for use as a constituent part of another pesticide produced at the second establishment; or

(2) the transfer is pursuant to and in accordance with the requirements of an experimental use permit.


(c) Procedure for registration(1) Statement requiredEach applicant for registration of a pesticide shall file with the Administrator a statement which includes—(A) the name and address of the applicant and of any other person whose name will appear on the labeling;

(B) the name of the pesticide;

(C) a complete copy of the labeling of the pesticide, a statement of all claims to be made for it, and any directions for its use;

(D) the complete formula of the pesticide;

(E) a request that the pesticide be classified for general use or for restricted use, or for both; and

(F) except as otherwise provided in paragraph (2)(D), if requested by the Administrator, a full description of the tests made and the results thereof upon which the claims are based, or alternatively a citation to data that appear in the public literature or that previously had been submitted to the Administrator and that the Administrator may c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of registration Except as provided by this subchapter, no person in any State may distribute or sell to any person any pesticide that is not registered under this subchapter. To the extent necessary to prevent unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, the Administrator may by regulation limit the distribution, sale, or use in any State of any pesticide that is not registered under this subchapter and that is not the subject of an experimental use permit under section 136c of this title or an emergency exemption under section 136p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions A pesticide which is not registered with the Administrator may be transferred if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedure for registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of pesticides</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Classification of pesticides</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products with same formulation and claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Products with same formulation and claims Products which have the same formulation, are manufactured by the same person, the labeling of which contains the same claims, and the labels of which bear a designation identifying the product as the same pesticide may be registered as a single pesticide; and additional names and labels shall be added to the registration by supplemental statements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Miscellaneous</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Registration review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration requirements for antimicrobial pesticides</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Registration requirements for antimicrobial pesticides</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>