<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136a–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136a_1"><akn:num>136a–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Reregistration of registered pesticides</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136a–1. Reregistration of registered pesticides(a) General ruleThe Administrator shall reregister, in accordance with this section, each registered pesticide containing any active ingredient contained in any pesticide first registered before November 1, 1984, except for any pesticide as to which the Administrator has determined, after November 1, 1984, and before the effective date of this section, that—(1) there are no outstanding data requirements; and

(2) the requirements of section 136a(c)(5) of this title have been satisfied.


(b) Reregistration phasesReregistrations of pesticides under this section shall be carried out in the following phases:(1) The first phase shall include the listing under subsection (c) of the active ingredients of the pesticides that will be reregistered.

(2) The second phase shall include the submission to the Administrator under subsection (d) of notices by registrants respecting their intention to seek reregistration, identification by registrants of missing and inadequate data for such pesticides, and commitments by registrants to replace such missing or inadequate data within the applicable time period.

(3) The third phase shall include submission to the Administrator by registrants of the information required under subsection (e).

(4) The fourth phase shall include an independent, initial review by the Administrator under subsection (f) of submissions under phases two and three, identification of outstanding data requirements, and the issuance, as necessary, of requests for additional data.

(5) The fifth phase shall include the review by the Administrator under subsection (g) of data submitted for reregistration and appropriate regulatory action by the Administrator.


(c) Phase one(1) Priority for reregistrationFor purposes of the reregistration of the pesticides described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall list the active ingredients of pesticides and shall give priority to, among others, active ingredients (other</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule The Administrator shall reregister, in accordance with this section, each registered pesticide containing any active ingredient contained in any pesticide first registered before November 1, 1984, except for any pesticide as to which the Administrator has determined, after November 1, 1984, and before the effective date of this section, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reregistration phases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reregistration phases Reregistrations of pesticides under this section shall be carried out in the following phases:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase one</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Phase one</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase two</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Phase two</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase three</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Phase three</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase four</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Phase four</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase five</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Phase five</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of data submitter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compensation of data submitter If data that are submitted by a registrant under subsection (d), (e), (f), or (g) are used to support the application of another person under section 136a of this title, the registrant who submitted such data shall be entitled to compensation for the use of such data as prescribed by section 136a(c)(1)(D) 1 of this title. In determining the amount of such compensation, the fees paid by the registrant under this section shall be taken into account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136a_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of certain registrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption of certain registrants The requirements of subsections (d), (e), (f), and (i) (other than subsection (i)(1)) regarding data concerning an active ingredient and fees for review of such data shall not apply to any person who is the registrant of a pesticide to the extent that, under section 136a(c)(2)(D) of this title, the person would not be required to submit or cite such data to obtain an initial registration of such pesticide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>