<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136d"><akn:num>136d</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative review; suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136d. Administrative review; suspension(a) Existing stocks and information(1) Existing stocksThe Administrator may permit the continued sale and use of existing stocks of a pesticide whose registration is suspended or canceled under this section, or section 136a or 136a–1 of this title, to such extent, under such conditions, and for such uses as the Administrator determines that such sale or use is not inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter.


(2) InformationIf at any time after the registration of a pesticide the registrant has additional factual information regarding unreasonable adverse effects on the environment of the pesticide, the registrant shall submit such information to the Administrator.



(b) Cancellation and change in classificationIf it appears to the Administrator that a pesticide or its labeling or other material required to be submitted does not comply with the provisions of this subchapter or, when used in accordance with widespread and commonly recognized practice, generally causes unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, the Administrator may issue a notice of the Administrator’s intent either—(1) to cancel its registration or to change its classification together with the reasons (including the factual basis) for the Administrator’s action, or

(2) to hold a hearing to determine whether or not its registration should be canceled or its classification changed.


Such notice shall be sent to the registrant and made public. In determining whether to issue any such notice, the Administrator shall include among those factors to be taken into account the impact of the action proposed in such notice on production and prices of agricultural commodities, retail food prices, and otherwise on the agricultural economy. At least 60 days prior to sending such notice to the registrant or making public such notice, whichever occurs first, the Administrator shall provide the Secretary of Agriculture with a copy of such notice and an analys</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing stocks and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing stocks and information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation and change in classification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cancellation and change in classification If it appears to the Administrator that a pesticide or its labeling or other material required to be submitted does not comply with the provisions of this subchapter or, when used in accordance with widespread and commonly recognized practice, generally causes unreasonable adverse effects on the environment, the Administrator may issue a notice of the Administrator’s intent either— Such notice shall be sent to the registrant and made public. In determining whether to issue any such notice, the Administrator shall include among those factors to be taken into account the impact of the action proposed in such notice on production and prices of agricultural commodities, retail food prices, and otherwise on the agricultural economy. At least 60 days prior to sending such notice to the registrant or making public such notice, whichever occurs first, the Administrator shall provide the Secretary of Agriculture with a copy of such notice and an ana</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearings and scientific review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public hearings and scientific review In the event a hearing is requested pursuant to subsection (b) or determined upon by the Administrator pursuant to subsection (b), such hearing shall be held after due notice for the purpose of receiving evidence relevant and material to the issues raised by the objections filed by the applicant or other interested parties, or to the issues stated by the Administrator, if the hearing is called by the Administrator rather than by the filing of objections. Upon a showing of relevance and reasonable scope of evidence sought by any party to a public hearing, the Hearing Examiner shall issue a subpena to compel testimony or production of documents from any person. The Hearing Examiner shall be guided by the principles of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure in making any order for the protection of the witness or the content of documents produced and shall order the payment of reasonable fees and expenses as a condition to requiring testimony of the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Conditional registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) General provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice for stored pesticides with canceled or suspended registrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice for stored pesticides with canceled or suspended registrations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Judicial review Final orders of the Administrator under this section shall be subject to judicial review pursuant to section 136n of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>