<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136h"><akn:num>136h</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of trade secrets and other information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136h. Protection of trade secrets and other information(a) In generalIn submitting data required by this subchapter, the applicant may (1) clearly mark any portions thereof which in the applicant’s opinion are trade secrets or commercial or financial information and (2) submit such market material separately from other material required to be submitted under this subchapter.


(b) DisclosureNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter and subject to the limitations in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the Administrator shall not make public information which in the Administrator’s judgment contains or relates to trade secrets or commercial or financial information obtained from a person and privileged or confidential, except that, when necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, information relating to formulas of products acquired by authorization of this subchapter may be revealed to any Federal agency consulted and may be revealed at a public hearing or in findings of fact issued by the Administrator.


(c) DisputesIf the Administrator proposes to release for inspection information which the applicant or registrant believes to be protected from disclosure under subsection (b), the Administrator shall notify the applicant or registrant, in writing, by certified mail. The Administrator shall not thereafter make available for inspection such data until thirty days after receipt of the notice by the applicant or registrant. During this period, the applicant or registrant may institute an action in an appropriate district court for a declaratory judgment as to whether such information is subject to protection under subsection (b).


(d) Limitations(1) All information concerning the objectives, methodology, results, or significance of any test or experiment performed on or with a registered or previously registered pesticide or its separate ingredients, impurities, or degradation products, and any information concerning the effects of s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In submitting data required by this subchapter, the applicant may (1) clearly mark any portions thereof which in the applicant’s opinion are trade secrets or commercial or financial information and (2) submit such market material separately from other material required to be submitted under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter and subject to the limitations in subsections (d) and (e) of this section, the Administrator shall not make public information which in the Administrator’s judgment contains or relates to trade secrets or commercial or financial information obtained from a person and privileged or confidential, except that, when necessary to carry out the provisions of this subchapter, information relating to formulas of products acquired by authorization of this subchapter may be revealed to any Federal agency consulted and may be revealed at a public hearing or in findings of fact issued by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disputes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disputes If the Administrator proposes to release for inspection information which the applicant or registrant believes to be protected from disclosure under subsection (b), the Administrator shall notify the applicant or registrant, in writing, by certified mail. The Administrator shall not thereafter make available for inspection such data until thirty days after receipt of the notice by the applicant or registrant. During this period, the applicant or registrant may institute an action in an appropriate district court for a declaratory judgment as to whether such information is subject to protection under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure to contractors Information otherwise protected from disclosure to the public under subsection (b) of this section may be disclosed to contractors with the United States and employees of such contractors if, in the opinion of the Administrator, such disclosure is necessary for the satisfactory performance by the contractor of a contract with the United States for the performance of work in connection with this subchapter and under such conditions as the Administrator may specify. The Administrator shall require as a condition to the disclosure of information under this subsection that the person receiving it take such security precautions respecting the information as the Administrator shall by regulation prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for disclosure by Federal employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Penalty for disclosure by Federal employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to foreign and multinational pesticide producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disclosure to foreign and multinational pesticide producers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>