<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136o"><akn:num>136o</akn:num><akn:heading>Imports and exports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136o. Imports and exports(a) Pesticides and devices intended for exportNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, no pesticide or device or active ingredient used in producing a pesticide intended solely for export to any foreign country shall be deemed in violation of this subchapter—(1) when prepared or packed according to the specifications or directions of the foreign purchaser, except that producers of such pesticides and devices and active ingredients used in producing pesticides shall be subject to sections 136(p), 136(q)(1)(A), (C), (D), (E), (G), and (H), 136(q)(2)(A), (B), (C)(i) and (iii), and (D), 136e, and 136f of this title; and

(2) in the case of any pesticide other than a pesticide registered under section 136a or sold under section 136d(a)(1) of this title, if, prior to export, the foreign purchaser has signed a statement acknowledging that the purchaser understands that such pesticide is not registered for use in the United States and cannot be sold in the United States under this subchapter.


A copy of that statement shall be transmitted to an appropriate official of the government of the importing country.

(b) Cancellation notices furnished to foreign governmentsWhenever a registration, or a cancellation or suspension of the registration of a pesticide becomes effective, or ceases to be effective, the Administrator shall transmit through the State Department notification thereof to the governments of other countries and to appropriate international agencies. Such notification shall, upon request, include all information related to the cancellation or suspension of the registration of the pesticide and information concerning other pesticides that are registered under section 136a of this title and that could be used in lieu of such pesticide.


(c) Importation of pesticides and devices(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall notify the Administrator of the arrival of pesticides and devices and shall deliver to the Admini</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pesticides and devices intended for export</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pesticides and devices intended for export Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, no pesticide or device or active ingredient used in producing a pesticide intended solely for export to any foreign country shall be deemed in violation of this subchapter— A copy of that statement shall be transmitted to an appropriate official of the government of the importing country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation notices furnished to foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cancellation notices furnished to foreign governments Whenever a registration, or a cancellation or suspension of the registration of a pesticide becomes effective, or ceases to be effective, the Administrator shall transmit through the State Department notification thereof to the governments of other countries and to appropriate international agencies. Such notification shall, upon request, include all information related to the cancellation or suspension of the registration of the pesticide and information concerning other pesticides that are registered under section 136a of this title and that could be used in lieu of such pesticide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation of pesticides and devices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Importation of pesticides and devices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation in international efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperation in international efforts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Administrator, shall prescribe regulations for the enforcement of subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>