<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/136r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_136r"><akn:num>136r</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 136r. Research and monitoring(a) ResearchThe Administrator shall undertake research including research by grant or contract with other Federal agencies, universities, or others as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, and the Administrator shall conduct research into integrated pest management in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture. The Administrator shall also take care to ensure that such research does not duplicate research being undertaken by any other Federal agency.


(b) National monitoring planThe Administrator shall formulate and periodically revise, in cooperation with other Federal, State, or local agencies, a national plan for monitoring pesticides.


(c) MonitoringThe Administrator shall undertake such monitoring activities, including, but not limited to monitoring in air, soil, water, man, plants, and animals, as may be necessary for the implementation of this subchapter and of the national pesticide monitoring plan. The Administrator shall establish procedures for the monitoring of man and animals and their environment for incidential 11 So in original. Probably should be “incidental”. pesticide exposure, including, but not limited to, the quantification of incidental human and environmental pesticide pollution and the secular trends thereof, and identification of the sources of contamination and their relationship to human and environmental effects. Such activities shall be carried out in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies.


(June 25, 1947, ch. 125, § 20, as added Pub. L. 92–516, § 2, Oct. 21, 1972, 86 Stat. 996; amended Pub. L. 95–396, § 20, Sept. 30, 1978, 92 Stat. 834; Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1006(a)(10), (b)(1), Dec. 13, 1991, 105 Stat. 1895.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1991—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–237 substituted “ensure” for “insure” and “the Administrator” for “he” before “shall conduct”.
1978—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 95–396, § 20(1), substituted in first sentence “shall conduct re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research The Administrator shall undertake research including research by grant or contract with other Federal agencies, universities, or others as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this subchapter, and the Administrator shall conduct research into integrated pest management in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture. The Administrator shall also take care to ensure that such research does not duplicate research being undertaken by any other Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National monitoring plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National monitoring plan The Administrator shall formulate and periodically revise, in cooperation with other Federal, State, or local agencies, a national plan for monitoring pesticides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_136r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Monitoring The Administrator shall undertake such monitoring activities, including, but not limited to monitoring in air, soil, water, man, plants, and animals, as may be necessary for the implementation of this subchapter and of the national pesticide monitoring plan. The Administrator shall establish procedures for the monitoring of man and animals and their environment for incidential 11 So in original. Probably should be “incidental”. pesticide exposure, including, but not limited to, the quantification of incidental human and environmental pesticide pollution and the secular trends thereof, and identification of the sources of contamination and their relationship to human and environmental effects. Such activities shall be carried out in cooperation with other Federal, State, and local agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>