<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1372" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1372/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1372/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1372"><akn:num>1372</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment, collection, and refund of penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1372. Payment, collection, and refund of penalties(a) The penalty with respect to the marketing, by sale, of wheat, cotton, or rice, if the sale is to any person within the United States, shall be collected by the buyer.

(b) All penalties provided for in part B of this subchapter shall be collected and paid in such manner, at such times, and under such conditions as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. Such penalties shall be remitted to the Secretary by the person liable for the penalty, except that if any other person is liable for the collection of the penalty, such other person shall remit the penalty. Except as provided in section 1314h 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the amount of such penalties shall be covered into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.

(c) Whenever, pursuant to a claim filed with the Secretary within two years after payment to him of any penalty collected from any person pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary finds that such penalty was erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully collected and the claimant bore the burden of the payment of such penalty, the Secretary shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to the claimant, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury, such amount as the Secretary finds the claimant is entitled to receive as a refund of such penalty.Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to prescribe by regulations for the identification of farms and it shall be sufficient to schedule receipts into special deposit accounts or to schedule such receipts for transfer therefrom, or directly, into the separate fund provided for in subsection (b) by means of such identification without reference to the names of the producers on such farms.
The Secretary is authorized to prescribe regulations governing the filing of such claims and the determination of such refunds.


(d) No penalty shall be collected under t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1372_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The penalty with respect to the marketing, by sale, of wheat, cotton, or rice, if the sale is to any person within the United States, shall be collected by the buyer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1372_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) All penalties provided for in part B of this subchapter shall be collected and paid in such manner, at such times, and under such conditions as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. Such penalties shall be remitted to the Secretary by the person liable for the penalty, except that if any other person is liable for the collection of the penalty, such other person shall remit the penalty. Except as provided in section 1314h 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the amount of such penalties shall be covered into the general fund of the Treasury of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1372_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever, pursuant to a claim filed with the Secretary within two years after payment to him of any penalty collected from any person pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary finds that such penalty was erroneously, illegally, or wrongfully collected and the claimant bore the burden of the payment of such penalty, the Secretary shall certify to the Secretary of the Treasury for payment to the claimant, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury, such amount as the Secretary finds the claimant is entitled to receive as a refund of such penalty.Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary is authorized to prescribe by regulations for the identification of farms and it shall be sufficient to schedule receipts into special deposit accounts or to schedule such receipts for transfer therefrom, or directly, into the separate fund provided for in subsection (b) by means of such identification without reference to the names of the producers on suc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1372_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No penalty shall be collected under this chapter with respect to the marketing of any agricultural commodity grown for experimental purposes only by any publicly owned agricultural experiment station. Effective with the 1978 crops, no penalty shall be collected under this chapter with respect to the marketing of any agricultural commodity grown on State prison farms for consumption within such State prison system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>