<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1378" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1378/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1378/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1378"><akn:num>1378</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of acreage allotments ensuing from agency acquisition of farmlands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1378. Transfer of acreage allotments ensuing from agency acquisition of farmlands(a) Allotment poolNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the allotment determined for any commodity for any land from which the owner is displaced because of acquisition of the land for any purpose, other than for the continued production of allotted crops, by any Federal, State, or other agency having the right of eminent domain shall be placed in an allotment pool and shall be available only for use in providing allotments for other farms owned by the owner so displaced. Upon application to the county committee, within three years after the date of such displacement, any owner so displaced shall be entitled to have allotments established for other farms owned by him, taking into consideration the land, labor, and equipment available on such other farms for the production of the commodity, crop-rotation practices, and the soil and other physical factors affecting the production of the commodity: Provided, That the acreage used to establish or increase the allotments for such farms shall be transferred from the pool and shall not exceed the allotment most recently established for the farm acquired from the applicant and placed in the pool. During the period of eligibility for the making of allotments under this section for a displaced owner, acreage allotments for the farm from which the owner was so displaced shall be established in accordance with the procedure applicable to other farms, and such allotments shall be considered to have been fully planted. After such allotment is made under this section, the proportionate part, or all, as the case may be, of the past acreage used in establishing the allotment most recently placed in the pool for the farm from which the owner was so displaced shall be transferred to and considered for the purposes of future State, county, and farm acreage allotments to have been planted on the farm to which allotment is made under this se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1378_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment pool</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allotment pool Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the allotment determined for any commodity for any land from which the owner is displaced because of acquisition of the land for any purpose, other than for the continued production of allotted crops, by any Federal, State, or other agency having the right of eminent domain shall be placed in an allotment pool and shall be available only for use in providing allotments for other farms owned by the owner so displaced. Upon application to the county committee, within three years after the date of such displacement, any owner so displaced shall be entitled to have allotments established for other farms owned by him, taking into consideration the land, labor, and equipment available on such other farms for the production of the commodity, crop-rotation practices, and the soil and other physical factors affecting the production of the commodity: Provided, That the acreage used to establish or increase the allotments for</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1378_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circumstances precluding application of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Circumstances precluding application of provisions The provisions of this section shall not be applicable if (1) there is any marketing quota penalty due with respect to the marketing of the commodity from the farm acquired by the Federal, State, or other agency or by the owner of the farm; (2) any of the commodity produced on such farm has not been accounted for as required by the Secretary; or (3) the allotment next established for the farm acquired by the Federal, State, or other agency would have been reduced because of false or improper identification of the commodity produced on or marketed from such farm or due to a false acreage report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1378_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of displacement determining application of provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time of displacement determining application of provisions This section shall not be applicable, in the case of and 22 So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear. cotton, to any farm from which the owner was displaced prior to 1950, in the case of wheat and corn, to any farm from which the owner was displaced prior to 1954, and in the case of rice, to any farm from which the owner was displaced prior to 1955. In any case where the cropland acquired for nonfarming purposes from an owner by an agency having the right of eminent domain represents less than 15 per centum of the total cropland on the farm, the allotment attributable to that portion of the farm so acquired shall be transferred to that portion of the farm not so acquired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>