<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_138b"><akn:num>138b</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 138b. Accreditation(a) In generalThe Secretary shall issue certificates of accreditation to laboratories that meet the requirements of this chapter, as determined by the Secretary.


(b) Requirements for accreditationTo receive accreditation under this chapter, a laboratory shall prepare and submit an application for accreditation to the Secretary and shall complete such required tests, and meet such standards as established under section 138a of this title.


(c) Failure to meet accreditation standardsThe Secretary shall deny an application for accreditation or shall revoke any existing accreditation with respect to any laboratory that fails to meet the requirements for accreditation under this chapter.


(d) Limited accreditationThe Secretary may issue certificates of accreditation to laboratories that are limited to specific fields of testing.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII, § 1323, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3563.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall issue certificates of accreditation to laboratories that meet the requirements of this chapter, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for accreditation To receive accreditation under this chapter, a laboratory shall prepare and submit an application for accreditation to the Secretary and shall complete such required tests, and meet such standards as established under section 138a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet accreditation standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to meet accreditation standards The Secretary shall deny an application for accreditation or shall revoke any existing accreditation with respect to any laboratory that fails to meet the requirements for accreditation under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limited accreditation The Secretary may issue certificates of accreditation to laboratories that are limited to specific fields of testing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>