<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/138f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_138f"><akn:num>138f</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 138f. Fees(a) In generalAt the time that an application for accreditation is received by the Secretary and annually thereafter, a laboratory seeking accreditation by the Secretary under the authority of this chapter, the Federal Meat Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), or the Poultry Products Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 451 et seq.) shall pay to the Secretary a nonrefundable accreditation fee. All fees collected by the Secretary shall be credited to the account from which the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program are paid and, subject to subsection (e), shall be available immediately and remain available until expended to pay the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program.


(b) Amount of feeThe fee required under this section shall be established by the Secretary in an amount that will offset the cost of the laboratory accreditation programs administered by the Secretary under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).


(c) Reimbursement of expensesEach laboratory that is accredited under a statutory authority set forth in subsection (a) or that has applied for accreditation under such authority shall reimburse the Secretary for reasonable travel and other expenses necessary to perform onsite inspections of the laboratory.


(d) Adjustment of feesThe Secretary may, on an annual basis, adjust the fees imposed under this section as necessary to support the full costs of the laboratory accreditation programs carried out under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).


(e) Appropriations prerequisiteNo fees collected under this section may be used to offset the cost of laboratory accreditation without appropriations made under subsection (f).


(f) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary for laboratory accreditation services under this section.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XIII, § 1327, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3565; Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 101</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general At the time that an application for accreditation is received by the Secretary and annually thereafter, a laboratory seeking accreditation by the Secretary under the authority of this chapter, the Federal Meat Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), or the Poultry Products Inspection Act (21 U.S.C. 451 et seq.) shall pay to the Secretary a nonrefundable accreditation fee. All fees collected by the Secretary shall be credited to the account from which the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program are paid and, subject to subsection (e), shall be available immediately and remain available until expended to pay the expenses of the laboratory accreditation program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of fee The fee required under this section shall be established by the Secretary in an amount that will offset the cost of the laboratory accreditation programs administered by the Secretary under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reimbursement of expenses Each laboratory that is accredited under a statutory authority set forth in subsection (a) or that has applied for accreditation under such authority shall reimburse the Secretary for reasonable travel and other expenses necessary to perform onsite inspections of the laboratory.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustment of fees The Secretary may, on an annual basis, adjust the fees imposed under this section as necessary to support the full costs of the laboratory accreditation programs carried out under the statutory authorities set forth in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations prerequisite</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appropriations prerequisite No fees collected under this section may be used to offset the cost of laboratory accreditation without appropriations made under subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_138f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary for laboratory accreditation services under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>