<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1421"><akn:num>1421</akn:num><akn:heading>Price support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1421. Price support(a) SourceThe Secretary shall provide the price support authorized or required herein through the Commodity Credit Corporation and other means available to him.


(b) Authority of Secretary; factors consideredExcept as otherwise provided in this Act, the amounts, terms, and conditions of price support operations and the extent to which such operations are carried out, shall be determined or approved by the Secretary. The following factors shall be taken into consideration in determining, in the case of any commodity for which price support is discretionary, whether a price-support operation shall be undertaken and the level of such support and, in the case of any commodity for which price support is mandatory, the level of support in excess of the minimum level prescribed for such commodity: (1) the supply of the commodity in relation to the demand therefor, (2) the price levels at which other commodities are being supported and, in the case of feed grains, the feed values of such grains in relation to corn, (3) the availability of funds, (4) the perishability of the commodity, (5) the importance of the commodity to agriculture and the national economy, (6) the ability to dispose of stocks acquired through a price-support operation, (7) the need for offsetting temporary losses of export markets, (8) the ability and willingness of producers to keep supplies in line with demand and (9), in the case of upland cotton, changes in the cost of producing such cotton.


(c) Compliance by producer; program for diverted acresCompliance by the producer with acreage allotments, production goals and marketing practices (including marketing quotas when authorized by law), prescribed by the Secretary, may be required as a condition of eligibility for price support. In administering any program for diverted acres the Secretary may make his regulations applicable on an appropriate geographical basis. Such regulations shall be administered (1) in semiarid or other</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Source The Secretary shall provide the price support authorized or required herein through the Commodity Credit Corporation and other means available to him.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; factors considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Secretary; factors considered Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the amounts, terms, and conditions of price support operations and the extent to which such operations are carried out, shall be determined or approved by the Secretary. The following factors shall be taken into consideration in determining, in the case of any commodity for which price support is discretionary, whether a price-support operation shall be undertaken and the level of such support and, in the case of any commodity for which price support is mandatory, the level of support in excess of the minimum level prescribed for such commodity: (1) the supply of the commodity in relation to the demand therefor, (2) the price levels at which other commodities are being supported and, in the case of feed grains, the feed values of such grains in relation to corn, (3) the availability of funds, (4) the perishability of the commodity, (5) the importance of the commodity to agriculture and the national</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance by producer; program for diverted acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance by producer; program for diverted acres Compliance by the producer with acreage allotments, production goals and marketing practices (including marketing quotas when authorized by law), prescribed by the Secretary, may be required as a condition of eligibility for price support. In administering any program for diverted acres the Secretary may make his regulations applicable on an appropriate geographical basis. Such regulations shall be administered (1) in semiarid or other areas where good husbandry requires maintenance of a prudent feed reserve in such manner as to permit, to the extent so required by good husbandry, the production of forage crops for storage and subsequent use either on the farm or in feeding operations of the farm operator, and (2) in areas declared to be disaster areas by the President under the Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.], in such manner as will most quickly restore the normal pattern of their agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of determining levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time of determining levels The level of price support for any commodity shall be determined upon the basis of its parity price as of the beginning of the marketing year or season in the case of any commodity marketed on a marketing year or season basis and as of January 1 in the case of any other commodity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Processors’ assurances; payment if assurances inadequate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Processors’ assurances; payment if assurances inadequate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>