<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1421d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1421d"><akn:num>1421d</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1421d. Commodity reports(a) Crop reportsThe Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall gather data from producers to be used to develop crop reports to be distributed by the Secretary during the growing season. The report shall contain statements of the conditions of those crops by State, with such explanations, comparisons, and information as may be useful for illustrating such reports.


(b) Special reports(1) In generalIn addition to the reports compiled pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall annually survey producers for information for reports regarding supply, acreage, production, disposition, and prices for the following commodities as determined by the Secretary:(A) 25 fresh market vegetables;

(B) 3 processing vegetables;

(C) 6 fruits and nuts;

(D) 17 forage and turf seeds;

(E) 50 vegetable seeds; and

(F) maple syrup.


(2) AdministrativeThe Secretary shall annually prepare a report containing results of the surveys described in paragraph (1) in such States as determined by the Secretary. Such reports shall be submitted to and officially approved by the Secretary of Agriculture before being issued or published.



(c) Tree inventoriesThe Secretary shall survey producers for information for reports regarding fruit and nut tree inventories. Such surveys and reports shall be conducted, printed, and distributed on a regular basis every 3 to 5 years as determined by the Secretary. Reports shall be submitted to and officially approved by the Secretary before being issued or published.


(d) Omitted

(e) AuthorizationThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XXV, § 2514, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4074.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, and not as part of the Agricultural Act of 1949 which is classified principally to this chapter. For com</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crop reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Crop reports The Secretary of Agriculture (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall gather data from producers to be used to develop crop reports to be distributed by the Secretary during the growing season. The report shall contain statements of the conditions of those crops by State, with such explanations, comparisons, and information as may be useful for illustrating such reports.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tree inventories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tree inventories The Secretary shall survey producers for information for reports regarding fruit and nut tree inventories. Such surveys and reports shall be conducted, printed, and distributed on a regular basis every 3 to 5 years as determined by the Secretary. Reports shall be submitted to and officially approved by the Secretary before being issued or published.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1421d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>