<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1427" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1427/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1427/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1427"><akn:num>1427</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity Credit Corporation sales price restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1427. Commodity Credit Corporation sales price restrictions(a) In generalThe Commodity Credit Corporation may sell any farm commodity owned or controlled by the Corporation at any price not prohibited by this section.


(b) InventoriesIn determining sales policies for basic agricultural commodities or storable nonbasic commodities, the Corporation should consider the establishment of such policies with respect to prices, terms, and conditions as the Corporation determines will not discourage or deter manufacturers, processors, and dealers from acquiring and carrying normal inventories of the commodity of the current crop.


(c) Sales price restrictions(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, the Corporation shall not sell any basic agricultural commodity or storable nonbasic commodity at less than 115 percent of the lower of—(A) the current national average price support loan rate for the commodity adjusted for the current market differentials reflecting grade, quality, location, reasonable carrying charges, and other factors determined appropriate by the Corporation; or

(B) the loan repayment level.


(2) Extra long staple cottonThe Corporation may sell extra long staple cotton for unrestricted use at such price as the Corporation determines is appropriate to maintain and expand export and domestic markets.


(3) OilseedsThe Corporation shall not sell oilseeds at less than the lower of—(A) 105 percent of the current national average price support loan rate for the oilseed, adjusted for the current market differentials reflecting grade, quality, location, reasonable carrying charges, and other factors determined appropriate by the Corporation; or

(B) 115 percent of the loan repayment level.


(4) Wheat and feed grainsWhenever the producer reserve program for wheat and feed grains established under section 1445e of this title is in effect, the Corporation may not sell any of its stocks of wheat or feed grains at a level that is less than 150 pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Commodity Credit Corporation may sell any farm commodity owned or controlled by the Corporation at any price not prohibited by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inventories In determining sales policies for basic agricultural commodities or storable nonbasic commodities, the Corporation should consider the establishment of such policies with respect to prices, terms, and conditions as the Corporation determines will not discourage or deter manufacturers, processors, and dealers from acquiring and carrying normal inventories of the commodity of the current crop.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales price restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sales price restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplication of sales price restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nonapplication of sales price restrictions The foregoing restrictions of this section shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distress, disaster, and livestock emergency areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distress, disaster, and livestock emergency areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Efficient operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Efficient operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1427_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales for export</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sales for export For the purposes of this section, sales for export shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>