<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1428" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1428/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1428/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1428"><akn:num>1428</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1428. Definitions
For the purposes of this Act—(a) A commodity shall be considered storable upon determination by the Secretary that, in normal trade practice, it is stored for substantial periods of time and that it can be stored under the price-support program without excessive loss through deterioration or spoilage or without excessive cost for storage for such periods as will permit its disposition without substantial impairment of the effectiveness of the price-support program.

(b) A “cooperator” with respect to any basic agricultural commodity shall be a producer on whose farm the acreage planted to the commodity does not exceed the farm acreage allotment for the commodity under subchapter II of chapter 35 of this title, or in the case of price support for corn or wheat to a producer outside the commercial corn-producing or wheat-producing area, a producer who complies with conditions of eligibility prescribed by the Secretary: Provided, That for upland cotton a cooperator shall be a producer on whose farm the acreage planted to such cotton does not exceed the cooperator percentage, which shall be in the case of the 1966 crop, 87.5 per centum of such farm acreage allotment and, in the case of each of the 1967 through 1970 crops, such percentage, not less than 87.5 or more than 100 per centum, of such farm acreage allotment as the Secretary may specify for such crop, except that in the case of small farms (i.e. farms on which the acreage allotment is 10 acres or less, or on which the projected farm yield times the acreage allotment is 3,600 pounds or less, and the acreage allotment has not been reduced under section 1344(m) of this title) the acreage of cotton on the farm shall not be required to be reduced below the farm acreage allotment: And provided, That for the 1971 through 1977 crops of upland cotton a cooperator shall be a producer on a farm on which a farm base acreage allotment has been established who has set aside the acreage required under secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A commodity shall be considered storable upon determination by the Secretary that, in normal trade practice, it is stored for substantial periods of time and that it can be stored under the price-support program without excessive loss through deterioration or spoilage or without excessive cost for storage for such periods as will permit its disposition without substantial impairment of the effectiveness of the price-support program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A “cooperator” with respect to any basic agricultural commodity shall be a producer on whose farm the acreage planted to the commodity does not exceed the farm acreage allotment for the commodity under subchapter II of chapter 35 of this title, or in the case of price support for corn or wheat to a producer outside the commercial corn-producing or wheat-producing area, a producer who complies with conditions of eligibility prescribed by the Secretary: Provided, That for upland cotton a cooperator shall be a producer on whose farm the acreage planted to such cotton does not exceed the cooperator percentage, which shall be in the case of the 1966 crop, 87.5 per centum of such farm acreage allotment and, in the case of each of the 1967 through 1970 crops, such percentage, not less than 87.5 or more than 100 per centum, of such farm acreage allotment as the Secretary may specify for such crop, except that in the case of small farms (i.e. farms on which the acreage allotment is 10 acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A “basic agricultural commodity” shall mean corn, cotton, rice, and wheat, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A “nonbasic agricultural commodity” shall mean any agricultural commodity other than a basic agricultural commodity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The “supply percentage” as to any commodity shall be the percentage which the estimated total supply is of the normal supply as determined by the Secretary from the latest available statistics of the Department of Agriculture as of the beginning of the marketing year for the commodity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Total supply” of any nonbasic agricultural commodity for any marketing year shall be the carry-over at the beginning of such marketing year, plus the estimated production of the commodity in the United States during the calendar year in which such marketing year begins and the estimated imports of the commodity into the United States during such marketing year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Carry-over” of any nonbasic agricultural commodity for any marketing year shall be the quantity of the commodity on hand in the United States at the beginning of such marketing year, not including any part of the crop or production of such commodity which was produced in the United States during the calendar year then current. The carryover of any such commodity may also include the quantity of such commodity in processed form on hand in the United States at the beginning of such marketing year, if the Secretary determines that the inclusion of such processed quantity of the commodity is necessary to effectuate the purposes of this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Normal supply” of any nonbasic agricultural commodity for any marketing year shall be (1) the estimated domestic consumption of the commodity for the marketing year for which such normal supply is being determined, plus (2) the estimated exports of the commodity for such marketing year, plus (3) an allowance for carry-over. The allowance for carry-over shall be the average carry-over of the commodity for the five marketing years immediately preceding the marketing year in which such normal supply is determined, adjusted for surpluses or deficiencies caused by abnormal conditions, changes in marketing conditions, or the operation of any agricultural program. In determining normal supply, the Secretary shall make such adjustments for current trends in consumption and for unusual conditions as he may deem necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) “Marketing year” for any nonbasic agricultural commodity means any period determined by the Secretary during which substantially all of a crop or production of such commodity is normally marketed by the producers thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1428_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Any term defined in the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 [7 U.S.C. 1281 et seq.], shall have the same meaning when used in this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>