<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1444" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1444/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1444/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1444"><akn:num>1444</akn:num><akn:heading>Cotton price support levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1444. Cotton price support levels(a) Basic support levels for 1961 and subsequent yearsNotwithstanding the provisions of section 1441 of this title, price support to cooperators for each crop of upland cotton, beginning with the 1961 crop, for which producers have not disapproved marketing quotas shall be at such level not more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor nor less than the minimum level prescribed below as the Secretary determines appropriate after consideration of the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title. For the 1961 crop the minimum level shall be 70 per centum of the parity price therefor, and for each subsequent crop the minimum level shall be 65 per centum of the parity price therefor: Provided, That the price support for the 1965 crop shall be a national average support price which reflects 30 cents per pound for Middling one-inch cotton. Price support in the case of noncooperators and in case marketing quotas are disapproved shall be as provided in section 1441(d)(3) and (5) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(b) Additional support levels for 1964 and 1965If producers have not disapproved marketing quotas, the Secretary shall provide additional price support on the 1964 and 1965 crops of upland cotton to cooperators on whose farms the acreage planted to upland cotton for harvest does not exceed the farm domestic allotment established under section 1350 of this title. Such additional support shall be at a level up to 15 per centum in excess of the basic level of support established under subsection (a) and shall be provided on the normal yield of the acreage planted for harvest within the farm domestic allotment. For purposes of this subsection, an acreage on the farm which the Secretary finds was not planted to cotton in 1965 because of flood, drought, or other natural disaster shall be deemed by the Secretary to be an actual acreage of cotton planted on the farm for harvest, provided such acreage is no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic support levels for 1961 and subsequent years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basic support levels for 1961 and subsequent years Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1441 of this title, price support to cooperators for each crop of upland cotton, beginning with the 1961 crop, for which producers have not disapproved marketing quotas shall be at such level not more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor nor less than the minimum level prescribed below as the Secretary determines appropriate after consideration of the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title. For the 1961 crop the minimum level shall be 70 per centum of the parity price therefor, and for each subsequent crop the minimum level shall be 65 per centum of the parity price therefor: Provided, That the price support for the 1965 crop shall be a national average support price which reflects 30 cents per pound for Middling one-inch cotton. Price support in the case of noncooperators and in case marketing quotas are disapproved shall be as provided in section 1441(d)(3) and (5) </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional support levels for 1964 and 1965</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional support levels for 1964 and 1965 If producers have not disapproved marketing quotas, the Secretary shall provide additional price support on the 1964 and 1965 crops of upland cotton to cooperators on whose farms the acreage planted to upland cotton for harvest does not exceed the farm domestic allotment established under section 1350 of this title. Such additional support shall be at a level up to 15 per centum in excess of the basic level of support established under subsection (a) and shall be provided on the normal yield of the acreage planted for harvest within the farm domestic allotment. For purposes of this subsection, an acreage on the farm which the Secretary finds was not planted to cotton in 1965 because of flood, drought, or other natural disaster shall be deemed by the Secretary to be an actual acreage of cotton planted on the farm for harvest, provided such acreage is not subsequently devoted to any price supported crop for 1965.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative operations for carrying out additional price support; payment-in-kind certificates: value, marketing assistance, redemption, and deductions after thirty day period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative operations for carrying out additional price support; payment-in-kind certificates: value, marketing assistance, redemption, and deductions after thirty day period In order to keep upland cotton to the maximum extent practicable in the normal channels of trade, any additional price support under subsection (b) of this section may be carried out through the simultaneous purchase of cotton at the support price therefor under subsection (b) and the sale of such cotton at the support price therefor under subsection (a) or similar operations, including loans under which the cotton would be redeemable by payment of the amount for which the cotton would be redeemable if the loan thereon had been made at the support price for such cotton under subsection (a), or payments-in-kind through the issuance of certificates which the Commodity Credit Corporation shall redeem for cotton under regulations issued by the Secretary. If such additional support is provided through the issuance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Price support and diversion payments for 1966 through 1970 crops</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Price support and diversion payments for 1966 through 1970 crops</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Price support, diversion, and cropland set-aside program for crops beginning with 1971 crop</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Price support, diversion, and cropland set-aside program for crops beginning with 1971 crop</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (g) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) , (g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1444_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for extra long staple cotton beginning with 1984 crop</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Program for extra long staple cotton beginning with 1984 crop</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>