<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445a"><akn:num>1445a</akn:num><akn:heading>Wheat price support levels; “cooperator” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445a. Wheat price support levels; “cooperator” defined
Notwithstanding the provisions of section 1441 of this title, beginning with the 1964 crop—(1) Price support for wheat accompanied by domestic certificates shall be at such level not less than 65 per centum or more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title.

(2) Price support for wheat accompanied by export certificates shall be at such level not more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title.

(3) Price support for wheat not accompanied by marketing certificates shall be at such level, not in excess of 90 per centum of the parity price therefor, as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration competitive world prices of wheat, the feeding value of wheat in relation to feed grains, and the level at which price support is made available for feed grains.

(4) Price support shall be made available only to cooperators: and, if a commercial wheat-producing area is established for such crop, price support shall be made available only in the commercial wheat-producing area.

(5) Effective with respect to crops planted for harvest in the calendar year 1966 and any subsequent year, the level of price support for any crop of wheat for which a national marketing quota is not proclaimed or for which marketing quotas have been disapproved by producers shall be as provided in section 1441 of this title.

(6) A “cooperator” with respect to any crop of wheat produced on a farm shall be a producer who (i) does not knowingly exceed (A) the farm acreage allotment for wheat on the farm or (B) except as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe, the farm acreage allotment for wheat on any other farm on which the producer shares in the production of wheat, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Price support for wheat accompanied by domestic certificates shall be at such level not less than 65 per centum or more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Price support for wheat accompanied by export certificates shall be at such level not more than 90 per centum of the parity price therefor as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration the factors specified in section 1421(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Price support for wheat not accompanied by marketing certificates shall be at such level, not in excess of 90 per centum of the parity price therefor, as the Secretary determines appropriate, taking into consideration competitive world prices of wheat, the feeding value of wheat in relation to feed grains, and the level at which price support is made available for feed grains.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Price support shall be made available only to cooperators: and, if a commercial wheat-producing area is established for such crop, price support shall be made available only in the commercial wheat-producing area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Effective with respect to crops planted for harvest in the calendar year 1966 and any subsequent year, the level of price support for any crop of wheat for which a national marketing quota is not proclaimed or for which marketing quotas have been disapproved by producers shall be as provided in section 1441 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) A “cooperator” with respect to any crop of wheat produced on a farm shall be a producer who (i) does not knowingly exceed (A) the farm acreage allotment for wheat on the farm or (B) except as the Secretary may by regulation prescribe, the farm acreage allotment for wheat on any other farm on which the producer shares in the production of wheat, and (ii) complies with the land-use requirements of section 1339 of this title, to the extent prescribed by the Secretary. Effective with respect to crops planted for harvest in the calendar year 1966 and any subsequent year, if marketing quotas are not in effect for the crop of wheat, a “cooperator” with respect to any crop of wheat produced on a farm shall be a producer who does not knowingly exceed the farm acreage allotment for wheat. No producer shall be deemed to have exceeded a farm acreage allotment for wheat if the entire amount of the farm marketing excess is delivered to the Secretary or stored in accordance with applicable regula</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>