<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445_3"><akn:num>1445–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of inventory stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445–3. Purchase of inventory stock
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in order to reduce or eliminate the excessive inventories of Flue-cured and Burley tobacco held by associations from the 1976 through 1984 crops, and in order to provide for the orderly disposition of such excessive inventories of tobacco in a manner that will not disrupt the orderly marketing of new tobacco crops and will minimize any losses to the Federal Government:(a) Sale of inventory stock(1) The producer-owned cooperative marketing association that has entered into a loan agreement with the Commodity Credit Corporation to make price support available to producers of Flue-cured tobacco shall offer to sell the stocks of Flue-cured tobacco of the association from the 1976 through 1984 crops as provided in this section.

(2) Each producer-owned cooperative marketing association that has entered into a loan agreement with the Commodity Credit Corporation to make price support available to producers of Burley tobacco shall offer to sell its stocks of Burley tobacco from the 1982 and 1984 crops as provided in this section.

(3)(A)(i) Not later than 30 days after April 7, 1986, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall acquire title to the Burley tobacco from the 1983 crop that is pledged as security for loans on such tobacco by calling the loans on such tobacco.

(ii) The Corporation shall, then, offer such tobacco for sale at such times, in such quantities, and subject to such conditions as the Corporation considers appropriate.


(B) If the Commodity Credit Corporation has not sold all of the stocks of the 1983 crop of Burley tobacco within 2 years from the date the Corporation calls the loans on such tobacco, the Corporation may offer to sell to domestic manufacturers of cigarettes the remaining stocks of such tobacco as provided in this section.



(b) Sale prices(1)(A) The stocks of Flue-cured tobacco from the 1976 through 1984 crops shall be offered for sale at the base prices, incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of inventory stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sale of inventory stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sale prices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Approval of agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure The limitations on disclosure set forth in subsections (c) and (d) of section 1314g 1 of this title shall apply to information submitted by domestic manufacturers of cigarettes under this section with respect to net cigarettes manufactured for use, including information provided on ATF Form 3068. Any officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture who violates such limitations on disclosure shall be subject to the penalties set forth in section 1314g(c)(4) 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>