<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445g"><akn:num>1445g</akn:num><akn:heading>Production of commodities for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons; terms and conditions; incenti</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445g. Production of commodities for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons; terms and conditions; incentive payments; regulations; appropriations; effective date
Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act—(a) The Secretary may permit, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, all or any part of the acreage set aside or diverted from the production of a commodity for any crop year under this subchapter to be devoted to the production of any commodity (other than the commodities for which acreage is being set aside or diverted) for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons and blending with gasoline or other fossil fuels for use as motor or industrial fuel, if the Secretary determines that such production is desirable in order to provide an adequate supply of commodities for such purpose, is not likely to increase the cost of the price support programs, and will not adversely affect farm income.

(b)(1) During any year in which there is no set-aside or diversion of acreage under this subchapter, the Secretary may formulate and administer a program for the production, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, of commodities for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons and blending with gasoline or other fossil fuels for use as motor or industrial fuel, if the Secretary determines that such production is desirable in order to provide an adequate supply of commodities for such purpose, is not likely to increase the cost of the price support programs, and will not adversely affect farm income. Under the program, producers of wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, and rice shall be paid incentive payments to devote a portion of their acreage to the production of commodities for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons and blending with gasoline or other fossil fuels for use as motor or industrial fuel.

(2) The payments under this subsection shall be at such rate or rates as the Secretary determines to be fair and reas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may permit, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe, all or any part of the acreage set aside or diverted from the production of a commodity for any crop year under this subchapter to be devoted to the production of any commodity (other than the commodities for which acreage is being set aside or diverted) for conversion into industrial hydrocarbons and blending with gasoline or other fossil fuels for use as motor or industrial fuel, if the Secretary determines that such production is desirable in order to provide an adequate supply of commodities for such purpose, is not likely to increase the cost of the price support programs, and will not adversely affect farm income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>