<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1445j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1445j"><akn:num>1445j</akn:num><akn:heading>Deficiency and land diversion payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1445j. Deficiency and land diversion payments(a) Deficiency payments(1) In generalIf the Secretary establishes an acreage limitation program for any of the 1991 through 1997 crops of wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, or rice under this Act and determines that deficiency payments will likely be made for the commodity for the crop, the Secretary shall make advance deficiency payments available to producers for each of the crops.


(2) Terms and conditionsAdvance deficiency payments under paragraph (1) shall be made to the producer under the following terms and conditions:(A) FormSuch payments may be made available in the form of—(i) cash;

(ii) commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation and certificates redeemable in a commodity owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation, except that not more than 50 percent of the payments may be made in commodities or the certificates in the case of any producer; or

(iii) any combination of clauses (i) and (ii).


(B) Commodities and certificatesIf payments are made available to producers as provided for under subparagraph (A)(ii), such producers may elect to receive such payments either in the form of—(i) such commodities; or

(ii) such certificates.


(C) MaturitySuch a certificate shall be redeemable for a period not to exceed 3 years from the date the certificate is issued.


(D) StorageThe Commodity Credit Corporation shall pay the cost of storing a commodity that may be received under such a certificate until such time as the certificate is redeemed.


(E) TimingThe payments shall be made available as soon as practicable after the producer enters into a contract with the Secretary to participate in such program.


(F) AmountsThe payments shall be made available in such amounts as the Secretary determines appropriate to encourage adequate participation in the program, except that the amount may not exceed an amount determined by multiplying—(i) the estimated payment acreage for the crop; by

(ii) the farm program </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deficiency payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deficiency payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1445j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (c) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 171(b)(2)(G), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 938</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) , (c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>