<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1446a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1446a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1446a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1446a"><akn:num>1446a</akn:num><akn:heading>Dairy products; availability through Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1446a. Dairy products; availability through Commodity Credit Corporation
As a means of increasing the utilization of dairy products (including for purposes of this section, milk) upon the certification by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs or by the Secretary of the Army, acting for the military departments under the Department of Defense’s Single Service Purchase Assignment for Subsistence, or their duly authorized representatives that the usual quantities of dairy products have been purchased in the normal channels of trade—(a) Secretary of Veterans Affairs; needs; report to CongressThe Commodity Credit Corporation until December 31, 1995, shall make available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs at warehouses where dairy products are stored, such dairy products acquired under price-support programs as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs certifies that he requires in order to provide butter and cheese and other dairy products as a part of the ration in hospitals under his jurisdiction. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall report every six months to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of Agriculture the amount of dairy products used under this subsection.


(b) Secretary of the Army; needs; report to CongressThe Commodity Credit Corporation until December 31, 1995, shall make available to the Secretary of the Army, at warehouses where dairy products are stored, such dairy products acquired under price-support programs as the Secretary of the Army or his duly authorized representative certifies can be utilized in order to provide additional butter and cheese and other dairy products as a part of the ration (1) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Coast Guard, (2) in hospitals under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, and (3) of cadets and midshipmen at, and other personnel assigned to, the United States Merchant Marine Academy. The Secretary of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1446a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Veterans Affairs; needs; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Secretary of Veterans Affairs; needs; report to Congress The Commodity Credit Corporation until December 31, 1995, shall make available to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs at warehouses where dairy products are stored, such dairy products acquired under price-support programs as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs certifies that he requires in order to provide butter and cheese and other dairy products as a part of the ration in hospitals under his jurisdiction. The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall report every six months to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of Agriculture the amount of dairy products used under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1446a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of the Army; needs; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretary of the Army; needs; report to Congress The Commodity Credit Corporation until December 31, 1995, shall make available to the Secretary of the Army, at warehouses where dairy products are stored, such dairy products acquired under price-support programs as the Secretary of the Army or his duly authorized representative certifies can be utilized in order to provide additional butter and cheese and other dairy products as a part of the ration (1) of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Coast Guard, (2) in hospitals under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, and (3) of cadets and midshipmen at, and other personnel assigned to, the United States Merchant Marine Academy. The Secretary of the Army shall report every six months to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of Agriculture the amount of dairy products used under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1446a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Costs Dairy products made available under this section shall be made available without charge, except that the Secretary of the Army or the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall pay the Commodity Credit Corporation the costs of packaging incurred in making such products so available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1446a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dairy products available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dairy products available The obligation of the Commodity Credit Corporation to make dairy products available pursuant to the above shall be limited to dairy products acquired by the Corporation through price-support operations and not disposed of under provisions (1) and (2) of section 1431 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>