<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1447" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1447/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1447/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1447"><akn:num>1447</akn:num><akn:heading>Price support levels for other nonbasic agricultural commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1447. Price support levels for other nonbasic agricultural commodities
The Secretary is authorized to make available through loans, purchases, or other operations price support to producers for any nonbasic agricultural commodity not designated in sections 1446, 1446a, and 1446d 11 See References in Text note below. of this title at a level not in excess of 90 per centum of the parity price for the commodity.
(Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, title III, § 301, 63 Stat. 1053; Pub. L. 95–113, title X, § 1003(a), Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 950.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1446d of this title, referred to in text, was omitted from the Code.

Amendments1977—Pub. L. 95–113 temporarily inserted provisions authorizing Secretary to make price support available for the 1978 through 1981 crops of flaxseed, dry edible beans, gum naval stores, and, in the case of the 1979 through 1981 crops, sugar beets and sugar cane, and for other nonbasic undesignated commodities. See Effective and Termination Dates of 1977 Amendment note below.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective and Termination Dates of 1977 AmendmentPub. L. 95–113, title X, § 1003(a), Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 950, provided that the amendment made by section 1003(a) is effective only with respect to the 1978 through 1981 crops.

Inapplicability of SectionSection inapplicable to 2014 through 2018 crops of covered commodities, cotton, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning Feb. 7, 2014, through Dec. 31, 2018, see section 9092(b)(9) of this title.
Section inapplicable to 2008 through 2012 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning June 18, 2008, through Dec. 31, 2012, see section 8782(b)(9) of this title.
Section inapplicable to 2002 through 2007 crops of covered commodities, peanuts, and sugar and inapplicable to milk during period beginning May 13, 2002, through Dec. 31, 2007, see section 7992(b)(9) of this title.
Section inapp</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>