<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1471e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1471e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1471e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1471e"><akn:num>1471e</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1471e. Additional assistance(a) Determination by SecretaryIn addition to the assistance provided under section 1471d of this title, if the Secretary determines that the livestock emergency also requires the implementation of one or more of the assistance programs described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall implement such programs.


(b) Programs authorizedSpecial assistance under this section includes—(1) the donation of feed owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation for use in feeding livestock stranded and unidentified as to its owner, including the cost of transporting feed to the affected area, during such period as the Secretary, by regulation, may prescribe;

(2) reimbursement of not to exceed 50 percent of the cost of—(A) installing pipelines (if that is the least expensive method) or other facilities, including tanks or troughs, for livestock water;

(B) construction or deepening of wells or ponds for livestock water; or

(C) developing springs or seeps for livestock water,


as appropriate in drought areas to facilitate more efficient and better-distributed grazing on land normally used for grazing. Such cost-share assistance may not be made available to provide water for wildlife or recreational livestock, dry lot feeding, or barns or corrals, or to acquire pumping equipment;

(3) reimbursement of not to exceed 50 percent of the cost of burning prickly pear cactus to make it suitable for animal feed; and

(4) making commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation available to livestock producers through the use of a catalog that specifies lots of a size that are economically feasible for a small producer to obtain by means of certificate exchanges.


(c) Water development projects for 1988 and 1989 emergenciesThe Secretary may make available at least $25,000,000 to provide special assistance under subsection (b)(2) for livestock emergencies in 1988 and 1989.


(Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, title VI, § 607, as added Pub. L. 100–387, title I, § 101(a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1471e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination by Secretary In addition to the assistance provided under section 1471d of this title, if the Secretary determines that the livestock emergency also requires the implementation of one or more of the assistance programs described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall implement such programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1471e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Programs authorized Special assistance under this section includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1471e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water development projects for 1988 and 1989 emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Water development projects for 1988 and 1989 emergencies The Secretary may make available at least $25,000,000 to provide special assistance under subsection (b)(2) for livestock emergencies in 1988 and 1989.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>