<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1506"><akn:num>1506</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1506. General powers(a) SuccessionThe Corporation shall have succession in its corporate name.


(b) Corporate sealThe Corporation may adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed.


(c) PropertyThe Corporation may purchase or lease and hold such real and personal property as it deems necessary or convenient in the transaction of its business, and may dispose of such property held by it upon such terms as it deems appropriate.


(d) SuitSubject to section 1508(j)(2)(A) of this title, the Corporation, subject to the provisions of section 1508(j) of this title,11 So in original. may sue and be sued in its corporate name, but no attachment, injunction, garnishment, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the Corporation or its property. The district courts of the United States, including the district courts of the District of Columbia and of any territory or possession, shall have exclusive original jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy, of all suits brought by or against the Corporation. The Corporation may intervene in any court in any suit, action, or proceeding in which it has an interest. Any suit against the Corporation shall be brought in the District of Columbia, or in the district wherein the plaintiff resides or is engaged in business.


(e) Bylaws and regulationsThe Corporation may adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the manner in which its business may be conducted and the powers granted to it by law may be exercised and enjoyed.


(f) MailsThe Corporation shall be entitled to the use of the United States mails in the same manner as the other executive agencies of the Government.


(g) AssistanceThe Corporation, with the consent of any board, commission, independent establishment, or executive department of the Government, including any field service thereof, may avail itself of the use of information, services, facilities, officials, and employees the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Succession</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Succession The Corporation shall have succession in its corporate name.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporate seal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Corporate seal The Corporation may adopt, alter, and use a corporate seal, which shall be judicially noticed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Property The Corporation may purchase or lease and hold such real and personal property as it deems necessary or convenient in the transaction of its business, and may dispose of such property held by it upon such terms as it deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Suit Subject to section 1508(j)(2)(A) of this title, the Corporation, subject to the provisions of section 1508(j) of this title,11 So in original. may sue and be sued in its corporate name, but no attachment, injunction, garnishment, or other similar process, mesne or final, shall be issued against the Corporation or its property. The district courts of the United States, including the district courts of the District of Columbia and of any territory or possession, shall have exclusive original jurisdiction, without regard to the amount in controversy, of all suits brought by or against the Corporation. The Corporation may intervene in any court in any suit, action, or proceeding in which it has an interest. Any suit against the Corporation shall be brought in the District of Columbia, or in the district wherein the plaintiff resides or is engaged in business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bylaws and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Bylaws and regulations The Corporation may adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, and regulations governing the manner in which its business may be conducted and the powers granted to it by law may be exercised and enjoyed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mails The Corporation shall be entitled to the use of the United States mails in the same manner as the other executive agencies of the Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance The Corporation, with the consent of any board, commission, independent establishment, or executive department of the Government, including any field service thereof, may avail itself of the use of information, services, facilities, officials, and employees thereof in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and sharing of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Collection and sharing of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Expenditures The Corporation shall determine the character and necessity for its expenditures under this subchapter and the manner in which they shall be incurred, allowed, and paid, without regard to the provisions of any other laws governing the expenditure of public funds and such determinations shall be final and conclusive upon all other officers of the Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1506_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settling claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Settling claims The Corporation shall have the authority to make final and conclusive settlement and adjustment of any claim by or against the Corporation or a fiscal officer of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>