<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1508a"><akn:num>1508a</akn:num><akn:heading>Double insurance and prevented planting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1508a. Double insurance and prevented planting(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) First cropThe term “first crop” means the first crop of the first agricultural commodity planted for harvest, or prevented from being planted, on specific acreage during a crop year and insured under this subchapter.


(2) Second cropThe term “second crop” means a second crop of the same agricultural commodity as the first crop, or a crop of a different agricultural commodity following the first crop, planted on the same acreage as the first crop for harvest in the same crop year, except the term does not include a replanted crop.


(3) Replanted cropThe term “replanted crop” means any agricultural commodity replanted on the same acreage as the first crop for harvest in the same crop year if the replanting is required by the terms of the policy of insurance covering the first crop.



(b) Double insurance(1) Options on loss to first cropExcept as provided in subsections (d) and (e), if a first crop insured under this subchapter in a crop year has a total or partial insurable loss, the producer of the first crop may elect one of the following options:(A) No second crop plantedThe producer may—(i) elect to not plant a second crop on the same acreage for harvest in the same crop year; and

(ii) collect an indemnity payment that is equal to 100 percent of the insurable loss for the first crop.


(B) Second crop plantedThe producer may—(i) plant a second crop on the same acreage for harvest in the same crop year; and

(ii) collect an indemnity payment established by the Corporation for the first crop, but not to exceed 35 percent of the insurable loss for the first crop.



(2) Effect of no loss to second cropIf a producer makes an election under paragraph (1)(B) and the producer does not suffer an insurable loss to the second crop, the producer may collect an indemnity payment for the first crop that is equal to—(A) 100 percent of the insurable loss for the first crop; less

(B) the amoun</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Double insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Double insurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevented planting coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prevented planting coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for established double cropping practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception for established double cropping practices A producer may receive full indemnity payments on two or more crops planted for harvest in the same crop year and insured under this subchapter if each of the following conditions are met:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent crops</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsequent crops Except in the case of double cropping described in subsection (d), if a producer elects to plant a crop (other than a replanted crop) subsequent to a second crop on the same acreage as the first crop and second crop for harvest in the same crop year, the producer shall not be eligible for insurance under this subchapter, or noninsured crop assistance under section 7333 of this title, for the subsequent crop.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>