<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1508c"><akn:num>1508c</akn:num><akn:heading>Peanut revenue crop insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1508c. Peanut revenue crop insurance(a) In generalEffective beginning with the 2015 crop year, the Risk Management Agency and the Corporation shall make available to producers of peanuts a revenue crop insurance program for peanuts.


(b) Effective priceSubject to subsection (c), for purposes of the revenue crop insurance program and the multiperil crop insurance program under this subchapter, the effective price for peanuts shall be equal to the Rotterdam price index for peanuts or other appropriate price as determined by the Secretary, as adjusted to reflect the farmer stock price of peanuts in the United States.


(c) Adjustments(1) In generalThe effective price for peanuts established under subsection (b) may be adjusted by the Risk Management Agency and the Corporation to correct distortions.


(2) AdministrationIf an adjustment is made under paragraph (1), the Risk Management Agency and the Corporation shall—(A) make the adjustment in an open and transparent manner; and

(B) submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that describes the reasons for the adjustment.



(Feb. 16, 1938, ch. 30, title V, § 508C, as added Pub. L. 113–79, title XI, § 11018, Feb. 7, 2014, 128 Stat. 966.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Effective beginning with the 2015 crop year, the Risk Management Agency and the Corporation shall make available to producers of peanuts a revenue crop insurance program for peanuts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective price Subject to subsection (c), for purposes of the revenue crop insurance program and the multiperil crop insurance program under this subchapter, the effective price for peanuts shall be equal to the Rotterdam price index for peanuts or other appropriate price as determined by the Secretary, as adjusted to reflect the farmer stock price of peanuts in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>