<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1508b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1508b"><akn:num>1508b</akn:num><akn:heading>Stacked Income Protection Plan for producers of upland cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1508b. Stacked Income Protection Plan for producers of upland cotton(a) AvailabilityBeginning not later than the 2015 crop of upland cotton, the Corporation shall make available to producers of upland cotton an additional policy (to be known as the “Stacked Income Protection Plan”), which shall provide coverage consistent with the Group Risk Income Protection Plan (and the associated Harvest Revenue Option Endorsement) offered by the Corporation for the 2011 crop year.


(b) Required termsThe Corporation may modify the Stacked Income Protection Plan on a program-wide basis, except that the Stacked Income Protection Plan shall comply with the following requirements:(1) Provide coverage for revenue loss of not less than 10 percent and not more than 30 percent of expected county revenue, specified in increments of 5 percent. The deductible shall be the minimum percent of revenue loss at which indemnities are triggered under the plan, not to be less than 10 percent of the expected county revenue.

(2) Be offered to producers of upland cotton in all counties with upland cotton production—(A) at a county-wide level to the fullest extent practicable; or

(B) in counties that lack sufficient data, on the basis of such larger geographical area as the Corporation determines to provide sufficient data for purposes of providing the coverage.


(3) Be purchased in addition to any other individual or area coverage in effect on the producer’s acreage or as a stand-alone policy, except that if a producer has an individual or area coverage for the same acreage, the maximum coverage available under the Stacked Income Protection Plan shall not exceed the deductible for the individual or area coverage.

(4) Establish coverage based on—(A) the expected price established under existing Group Risk Income Protection or area wide policy offered by the Corporation for the applicable county (or area) and crop year; and

(B) an expected county yield that is the higher of—(i) the expected cou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability Beginning not later than the 2015 crop of upland cotton, the Corporation shall make available to producers of upland cotton an additional policy (to be known as the “Stacked Income Protection Plan”), which shall provide coverage consistent with the Group Risk Income Protection Plan (and the associated Harvest Revenue Option Endorsement) offered by the Corporation for the 2011 crop year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required terms The Corporation may modify the Stacked Income Protection Plan on a program-wide basis, except that the Stacked Income Protection Plan shall comply with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Premium Notwithstanding section 1508(d) of this title, the premium for the Stacked Income Protection Plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of portion of premium by corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of portion of premium by corporation Subject to section 1508(e)(4) of this title, the amount of premium paid by the Corporation for all qualifying coverage levels of the Stacked Income Protection Plan shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other coverages</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relation to other coverages The Stacked Income Protection Plan is in addition to all other coverages available to producers of upland cotton.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1508b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation Effective beginning with the 2019 crop year, a farm shall not be eligible for the Stacked Income Protection Plan for upland cotton for a crop year for which the farm is enrolled in coverage for seed cotton under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>