<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1515"><akn:num>1515</akn:num><akn:heading>Program compliance and integrity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1515. Program compliance and integrity(a) Purpose(1) In generalThe purpose of this section is to improve compliance with, and the integrity of, the Federal crop insurance program.


(2) Role of insurance providersThe Corporation shall work actively with approved insurance providers to address program compliance and integrity issues as such issues develop.



(b) Notification of compliance problems(1) Notification of errors, omissions, and failuresThe Corporation shall notify in writing an approved insurance provider of any error, omission, or failure to follow Corporation regulations or procedures for which the approved insurance provider may be responsible and which may result in a debt owed the Corporation.


(2) Time for notificationNotice under paragraph (1) shall be given within 3 years after the end of the insurance period during which the error, omission, or failure is alleged to have occurred, except that this time limitation shall not apply with respect to an error, omission, or procedural violation that is willful or intentional.


(3) Effect of failure to timely notifyExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the failure to timely provide the notice required under this subsection shall relieve the approved insurance provider from the debt owed the Corporation.



(c) Reconciling producer information(1) In generalThe Secretary shall develop and implement a coordinated plan for the Corporation and the Farm Service Agency to reconcile all relevant information received by the Corporation or the Farm Service Agency from a producer who obtains crop insurance coverage under this subchapter.


(2) FrequencyBeginning with the 2001 crop year, the Secretary shall require that the Corporation and the Farm Service Agency reconcile such producer-derived information on at least an annual basis in order to identify and address any discrepancies.


(3) Corrections(A) In generalIn addition to the corrections permitted by the Corporation as of the day before February 7, 2014, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of compliance problems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of compliance problems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reconciling producer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reconciling producer information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and elimination of fraud, waste, and abuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identification and elimination of fraud, waste, and abuse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with State FSA committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with State FSA committees The Secretary shall establish procedures under which the Corporation shall consult with the State committee of the Farm Service Agency for a State with respect to policies, plans of insurance, and material related to such policies or plans of insurance (including applicable sales closing dates, assigned yields, and transitional yields) offered in that State under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detection of disparate performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Detection of disparate performance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of information to Corporation to support compliance efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Submission of information to Corporation to support compliance efforts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions for program noncompliance and fraud</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sanctions for program noncompliance and fraud</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on program compliance and integrity efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual report on program compliance and integrity efforts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1515_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Information management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>