<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1622"><akn:num>1622</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary relating to agricultural products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1622. Duties of Secretary relating to agricultural products
The Secretary of Agriculture is directed and authorized:(a) Determination of methods of processing, packaging, marketing, etc.; publication of resultsTo conduct, assist, and foster research, investigation, and experimentation to determine the best methods of processing, preparation for market, packaging, handling, transporting, storing, distributing, and marketing agricultural products: Provided, That the results of such research shall be made available to the public for the purpose of expanding the use of American agricultural products in such manner as the Secretary of Agriculture may determine.


(b) Determination of costsTo determine costs of marketing agricultural products in their various forms and through the various channels and to foster and assist in the development and establishment of more efficient marketing methods (including analyses of methods and proposed methods), practices, and facilities, for the purpose of bringing about more efficient and orderly marketing, and reducing the price spread between the producer and the consumer.


(c) Improvement of standards of quality, condition, etc.; standard of quality for ice creamTo develop and improve standards of quality, condition, quantity, grade, and packaging, and recommend and demonstrate such standards in order to encourage uniformity and consistency in commercial practices. Within thirty days after September 29, 1977, the Secretary shall by regulation adopt a standard of quality for ice cream which shall provide that ice cream shall contain at least 1.6 pounds of total solids to the gallon, weigh not less than 4.5 pounds to the gallon and contain not less than 20 percent total milk solids, constituted of not less than 10 percent milkfat. In no case shall the content of milk solids not fat be less than 6 percent. Whey shall not, by weight, be more than 25 percent of the milk solids not fat. Only those products which meet the standard issue</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of methods of processing, packaging, marketing, etc.; publication of results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of methods of processing, packaging, marketing, etc.; publication of results To conduct, assist, and foster research, investigation, and experimentation to determine the best methods of processing, preparation for market, packaging, handling, transporting, storing, distributing, and marketing agricultural products: Provided, That the results of such research shall be made available to the public for the purpose of expanding the use of American agricultural products in such manner as the Secretary of Agriculture may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of costs To determine costs of marketing agricultural products in their various forms and through the various channels and to foster and assist in the development and establishment of more efficient marketing methods (including analyses of methods and proposed methods), practices, and facilities, for the purpose of bringing about more efficient and orderly marketing, and reducing the price spread between the producer and the consumer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of standards of quality, condition, etc.; standard of quality for ice cream</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Improvement of standards of quality, condition, etc.; standard of quality for ice cream To develop and improve standards of quality, condition, quantity, grade, and packaging, and recommend and demonstrate such standards in order to encourage uniformity and consistency in commercial practices. Within thirty days after September 29, 1977, the Secretary shall by regulation adopt a standard of quality for ice cream which shall provide that ice cream shall contain at least 1.6 pounds of total solids to the gallon, weigh not less than 4.5 pounds to the gallon and contain not less than 20 percent total milk solids, constituted of not less than 10 percent milkfat. In no case shall the content of milk solids not fat be less than 6 percent. Whey shall not, by weight, be more than 25 percent of the milk solids not fat. Only those products which meet the standard issued by the Secretary may bear a symbol thereon indicating that they meet the Department of Agriculture standard for “ice cream”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elimination of artificial barriers to free movement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Elimination of artificial barriers to free movement To conduct, assist, foster, and direct studies and informational programs designed to eliminate artificial barriers to the free movement of agricultural products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of new markets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Development of new markets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increasing consumer education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Increasing consumer education To conduct and cooperate in consumer education for the more effective utilization and greater consumption of agricultural products: Provided, That no money appropriated under the authority of this Act shall be used to pay for newspaper or periodical advertising space or radio time in carrying out the purposes of this section and subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and dissemination of marketing information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Collection and dissemination of marketing information To collect and disseminate marketing information, including adequate outlook information on a market-area basis, for the purpose of anticipating and meeting consumer requirements, aiding in the maintenance of farm income, and bringing about a balance between production and utilization of agricultural products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection and certification of products in interstate commerce; credit and future availability of funds; investment; certificates as evidence; penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Inspection and certification of products in interstate commerce; credit and future availability of funds; investment; certificates as evidence; penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of facilities for assembling, processing, transporting, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Development of facilities for assembling, processing, transporting, etc. To determine the needs and develop or assist in the development of plans for efficient facilities and methods of operating such facilities for the proper assembly, processing, transportation, storage, distribution, and handling of agricultural products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1622_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of transportation facilities and rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Improvement of transportation facilities and rates To assist in improving transportation services and facilities and in obtaining equitable and reasonable transportation rates and services and adequate transportation facilities for agricultural products and farm supplies by making complaint or petition to the Surface Transportation Board, the Federal Maritime Commission, or other Federal or State transportation regulatory body, or the Secretary of Transportation, with respect to rates, charges, tariffs, practices, and services, or by working directly with individual carriers or groups of carriers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>