<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1631"><akn:num>1631</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection for purchasers of farm products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1631. Protection for purchasers of farm products(a) Congressional findingsCongress finds that—(1) certain State laws permit a secured lender to enforce liens against a purchaser of farm products even if the purchaser does not know that the sale of the products violates the lender’s security interest in the products, lacks any practical method for discovering the existence of the security interest, and has no reasonable means to ensure that the seller uses the sales proceeds to repay the lender;

(2) these laws subject the purchaser of farm products to double payment for the products, once at the time of purchase, and again when the seller fails to repay the lender;

(3) the exposure of purchasers of farm products to double payment inhibits free competition in the market for farm products; and

(4) this exposure constitutes a burden on and an obstruction to interstate commerce in farm products.


(b) Declaration of purposeThe purpose of this section is to remove such burden on and obstruction to interstate commerce in farm products.


(c) DefinitionsFor the purposes of this section—(1) The term “buyer in the ordinary course of business” means a person who, in the ordinary course of business, buys farm products from a person engaged in farming operations who is in the business of selling farm products.

(2) The term “central filing system” means a system for filing effective financing statements or notice of such financing statements on a statewide basis and which has been certified by the Secretary of the United States Department of Agriculture; the Secretary shall certify such system if the system complies with the requirements of this section; specifically under such system—(A) effective financing statements or notice of such financing statements are filed with the office of the Secretary of State of a State;

(B) the Secretary of State records the date and hour of the filing of such statements;

(C) the Secretary of State compiles all such statements into a mast</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Declaration of purpose The purpose of this section is to remove such burden on and obstruction to interstate commerce in farm products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases free of security interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Purchases free of security interest Except as provided in subsection (e) and notwithstanding any other provision of Federal, State, or local law, a buyer who in the ordinary course of business buys a farm product from a seller engaged in farming operations shall take free of a security interest created by the seller, even though the security interest is perfected; and the buyer knows of the existence of such interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases subject to security interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Purchases subject to security interest A buyer of farm products takes subject to a security interest created by the seller if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law governing “receipt”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Law governing “receipt” What constitutes receipt, as used in this section, shall be determined by the law of the State in which the buyer resides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission merchants or selling agents: sales free of or subject to security interest; law governing “receipt”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Commission merchants or selling agents: sales free of or subject to security interest; law governing “receipt”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security agreements; identity lists; notice of identity or accounting for proceeds; violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Security agreements; identity lists; notice of identity or accounting for proceeds; violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary of Agriculture shall prescribe regulations not later than 90 days after December 23, 1985, to aid States in the implementation and management of a central filing system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1631_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Effective date This section shall become effective 12 months after December 23, 1985.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>