<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1635m"><akn:num>1635m</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory reporting for lambs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1635m. Mandatory reporting for lambs(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary may establish a program of mandatory lamb price information reporting that will—(1) provide timely, accurate, and reliable market information;

(2) facilitate more informed marketing decisions; and

(3) promote competition in the lamb slaughtering industry.


(b) Notice and commentIf the Secretary establishes a mandatory price reporting program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for comment on proposed regulations to establish the program during the 30-day period beginning on the date of the publication of the proposed regulations.


(Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 966, title II, § 241, as added Pub. L. 106–78, title IX, § 911(2), Oct. 22, 1999, 113 Stat. 1200.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Lamb ReportingPub. L. 114–54, title I, § 103, Sept. 30, 2015, 129 Stat. 514, provided that: 
“Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act [Sept. 30, 2015], the Secretary of Agriculture shall revise section 59.300 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, so that—
“(1) the definition of the term ‘importer’—“(A) includes only those importers that imported an average of 1,000 metric tons of lamb meat products per year during the immediately preceding 4 calendar years; and

“(B) may include any person that does not meet the requirement referred to in subparagraph (A), if the Secretary determines that the person should be considered an importer based on their volume of lamb imports; and


“(2) the definition of the term ‘packer’—“(A) applies to any entity with 50 percent or more ownership in a facility;

“(B) includes a federally inspected lamb processing plant which slaughtered or processed the equivalent of an average of 35,000 head of lambs per year during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years; and

“(C) may include any other lamb processing plant that does not meet the requirement referred to in subparagraph (B), if the Secretary determines that the processin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary may establish a program of mandatory lamb price information reporting that will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice and comment If the Secretary establishes a mandatory price reporting program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for comment on proposed regulations to establish the program during the 30-day period beginning on the date of the publication of the proposed regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>