<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1635d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1635d"><akn:num>1635d</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1635d. Definitions
In this part:(1) Cattle committedThe term “cattle committed” means cattle that are scheduled to be delivered to a packer within the 7-day period beginning on the date of an agreement to sell the cattle.


(2) Cattle typeThe term “cattle type” means the following types of cattle purchased for slaughter:(A) Fed steers.

(B) Fed heifers.

(C) Fed Holsteins and other fed dairy steers and heifers.

(D) Cows.

(E) Bulls.


(3) Formula marketing arrangementThe term “formula marketing arrangement” means the advance commitment of cattle for slaughter by any means other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward contract, using a method for calculating price in which the price is determined at a future date.


(4) Forward contractThe term “forward contract” means—(A) an agreement for the purchase of cattle, executed in advance of slaughter, under which the base price is established by reference to—(i) prices quoted on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange; or

(ii) other comparable publicly available prices; or


(B) such other forward contract as the Secretary determines to be applicable.


(5) PackerThe term “packer” means any person engaged in the business of buying cattle in commerce for purposes of slaughter, of manufacturing or preparing meats or meat food products from cattle for sale or shipment in commerce, or of marketing meats or meat food products from cattle in an unmanufactured form acting as a wholesale broker, dealer, or distributor in commerce, except that—(A) the term includes only a cattle processing plant that is federally inspected;

(B) for any calendar year, the term includes only a cattle processing plant that slaughtered an average of at least 125,000 head of cattle per year during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years; and

(C) in the case of a cattle processing plant that did not slaughter cattle during the immediately preceding 5 calendar years, the Secretary shall consider the plant capacity of the processing plant in dete</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cattle committed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Cattle committed The term “cattle committed” means cattle that are scheduled to be delivered to a packer within the 7-day period beginning on the date of an agreement to sell the cattle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cattle type</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cattle type The term “cattle type” means the following types of cattle purchased for slaughter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula marketing arrangement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Formula marketing arrangement The term “formula marketing arrangement” means the advance commitment of cattle for slaughter by any means other than through a negotiated purchase or a forward contract, using a method for calculating price in which the price is determined at a future date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forward contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Forward contract The term “forward contract” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Packer The term “packer” means any person engaged in the business of buying cattle in commerce for purposes of slaughter, of manufacturing or preparing meats or meat food products from cattle for sale or shipment in commerce, or of marketing meats or meat food products from cattle in an unmanufactured form acting as a wholesale broker, dealer, or distributor in commerce, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Packer-owned cattle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Packer-owned cattle The term “packer-owned cattle” means cattle that a packer owns for at least 14 days immediately before slaughter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Terms of trade The term “terms of trade” includes, with respect to the purchase of cattle for slaughter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1635d_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type of purchase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Type of purchase The term “type of purchase”, with respect to cattle, means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>