<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1637b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1637b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1637b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1637b"><akn:num>1637b</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory reporting for dairy products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1637b. Mandatory reporting for dairy products(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program of mandatory dairy product information reporting that will—(1) provide timely, accurate, and reliable market information;

(2) facilitate more informed marketing decisions; and

(3) promote competition in the dairy product manufacturing industry.


(b) Requirements(1) In generalIn establishing the program, the Secretary shall only—(A)(i) subject to the conditions described in paragraph (2), require each manufacturer to report to the Secretary information concerning the price, quantity, and moisture content of dairy products sold by the manufacturer; and

(ii) modify the format used to provide the information on the day before November 22, 2000, to ensure that the information can be readily understood by market participants; and


(B) require each manufacturer and other person storing dairy products to report to the Secretary, at a periodic interval determined by the Secretary, information on the quantity of dairy products stored.


(2) ConditionsThe conditions referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i) are that—(A) the information referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i) is required only with respect to those package sizes actually used to establish minimum prices for Class III or Class IV milk under a Federal milk marketing order;

(B) the information referred to in paragraph (1)(A)(i) is required only to the extent that the information is actually used to establish minimum prices for Class III or Class IV milk under a Federal milk marketing order;

(C) the frequency of the required reporting under paragraph (1)(A)(i) does not exceed the frequency used to establish minimum prices for Class III or Class IV milk under a Federal milk marketing order; and

(D) the Secretary may exempt from all reporting requirements any manufacturer that processes and markets less than 1,000,000 pounds of dairy products per year.



(c) Administration(1) In generalThe Secretary shall promulgate su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program of mandatory dairy product information reporting that will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Electronic reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1637b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>