<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1638" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1638/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1638/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1638"><akn:num>1638</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1638. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Covered commodity(A) In generalThe term “covered commodity” means—(i) muscle cuts of lamb and venison;

(ii) ground lamb and ground venison;

(iii) farm-raised fish;

(iv) wild fish;

(v) a perishable agricultural commodity;

(vi) peanuts; and 11 So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear.

(vii) meat produced from goats;

(viii) chicken, in whole and in part;

(ix) ginseng;

(x) pecans; and

(xi) macadamia nuts.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “covered commodity” does not include an item described in subparagraph (A) if the item is an ingredient in a processed food item.



(2) Farm-raised fishThe term “farm-raised fish” includes—(A) farm-raised shellfish; and

(B) fillets, steaks, nuggets, and any other flesh from a farm-raised fish or shellfish.


(3) Food service establishmentThe term “food service establishment” means a restaurant, cafeteria, lunch room, food stand, saloon, tavern, bar, lounge, or other similar facility operated as an enterprise engaged in the business of selling food to the public.


(4) LambThe term “lamb” means meat, other than mutton, produced from sheep.


(5) Perishable agricultural commodity; retailerThe terms “perishable agricultural commodity” and “retailer” have the meanings given the terms in section 499a(b) of this title.


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Agricultural Marketing Service.


(7) Wild fish(A) In generalThe term “wild fish” means naturally-born or hatchery-raised fish and shellfish harvested in the wild.


(B) InclusionsThe term “wild fish” includes a fillet, steak, nugget, and any other flesh from wild fish or shellfish.


(C) ExclusionsThe term “wild fish” excludes net-pen aquacultural or other farm-raised fish.



(Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 966, title II, § 281, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10816, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 533; amended Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11002(1), May 22, 2008, 112 Stat. 1351; Pub. L. 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Covered commodity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm-raised fish</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Farm-raised fish The term “farm-raised fish” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Food service establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Food service establishment The term “food service establishment” means a restaurant, cafeteria, lunch room, food stand, saloon, tavern, bar, lounge, or other similar facility operated as an enterprise engaged in the business of selling food to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lamb</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Lamb The term “lamb” means meat, other than mutton, produced from sheep.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Perishable agricultural commodity; retailer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Perishable agricultural commodity; retailer The terms “perishable agricultural commodity” and “retailer” have the meanings given the terms in section 499a(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Agricultural Marketing Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1638_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wild fish</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Wild fish</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>