<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1639o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1639o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1639o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1639o"><akn:num>1639o</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1639o. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) HempThe term “hemp” means the plant Cannabis sativa L. and any part of that plant, including the seeds thereof and all derivatives, extracts, cannabinoids, isomers, acids, salts, and salts of isomers, whether growing or not, with a delta-9 tetrahydrocannabinol concentration of not more than 0.3 percent on a dry weight basis.


(2) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(4) StateThe term “State” means—(A) a State;

(B) the District of Columbia;

(C) the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico; and

(D) any other territory or possession of the United States.


(5) State department of agricultureThe term “State department of agriculture” means the agency, commission, or department of a State government responsible for agriculture in the State.


(6) Tribal governmentThe term “Tribal government” means the governing body of an Indian tribe.


(Aug. 14, 1946, ch. 966, title II, § 297A, as added Pub. L. 115–334, title X, § 10113, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4908; amended Pub. L. 119–37, div. B, title VII, § 781(1), (2), Nov. 12, 2025, 139 Stat. 558.)

Amendment of SectionPub. L. 119–37, div. B, title VII, § 781(1), (2), Nov. 12, 2025, 139 Stat. 558, provided that, effective 365 days after the enactment of Pub. L. 119–37 (approved Nov. 12, 2025), this section is amended by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (6) as (4) through (8), respectively and by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:
(1) Hemp
(A) In general
The term “hemp” means the plant Cannabis sativa L. and any part of that plant, including the seeds thereof and all derivatives, extracts, cannabinoids, isomers, acids, salts, and salts of isomers, whether growing or not, with a total tetrahydrocannabinols concentration (including tetrahydrocannabinolic acid) of not more than 0.3 percent on a dry weight basis.
(B) Inclusion
Such term includes in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hemp</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Hemp The term “hemp” means the plant Cannabis sativa L. and any part of that plant, including the seeds thereof and all derivatives, extracts, cannabinoids, isomers, acids, salts, and salts of isomers, whether growing or not, with a delta-9 tetrahydrocannabinol concentration of not more than 0.3 percent on a dry weight basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) State The term “State” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>State department of agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) State department of agriculture The term “State department of agriculture” means the agency, commission, or department of a State government responsible for agriculture in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1639o_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Tribal government The term “Tribal government” means the governing body of an Indian tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>