<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1702"><akn:num>1702</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements regarding eligible countries and private entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1702. Agreements regarding eligible countries and private entities(a) PriorityIn selecting agreements to be entered into under this subchapter, the Secretary shall give priority to agreements providing for the export of agricultural commodities to developing countries that—(1) are undertaking measures for economic development purposes to improve food security and agricultural development, alleviate poverty, and promote broad-based equitable and sustainable development; and

(2) demonstrate the greatest need for food.


(b) Private entitiesAn agreement entered into under this subchapter with a private entity shall require such security, or such other provisions as the Secretary determines necessary, to provide reasonable and adequate assurance of repayment of the financing extended to the private entity.


(July 10, 1954, ch. 469, title I, § 102, 68 Stat. 455; Apr. 25, 1955, ch. 27, 69 Stat. 44; Pub. L. 88–638, § 1(3), Oct. 8, 1964, 78 Stat. 1035; Pub. L. 89–808, § 2(B), Nov. 11, 1966, 80 Stat. 1526; Pub. L. 90–436, § 9, July 29, 1968, 82 Stat. 451; Pub. L. 95–88, title II, § 201(a), Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 545; Pub. L. 95–113, title XII, § 1201, Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 955; Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1512, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3634; Pub. L. 104–127, title II, § 203, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 951; Pub. L. 110–246, title III, § 3005, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1822.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2008—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 110–246, § 3005(1), redesignated pars. (2) and (3) as (1) and (2), respectively, and struck out former par. (1) which read as follows: “have the demonstrated potential to become commercial markets for competitively priced United States agricultural commodities;”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 110–246, § 3005(2), struck out subsec. (c) which related to agricultural market development plan pursuant to which a developing country could demonstrate potential to become a commercial market for competitively priced United States agricultural commodities for the purp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Priority In selecting agreements to be entered into under this subchapter, the Secretary shall give priority to agreements providing for the export of agricultural commodities to developing countries that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Private entities An agreement entered into under this subchapter with a private entity shall require such security, or such other provisions as the Secretary determines necessary, to provide reasonable and adequate assurance of repayment of the financing extended to the private entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>