<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1703"><akn:num>1703</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1703. Terms and conditions of sales(a) Payment(1) DollarsExcept as provided in paragraph (2), agreements under this subchapter shall require that payment for agricultural commodities be made in dollars.


(2) Local currencies(A) In generalThe Secretary may permit payment under an agreement under this subchapter in the local currency of the appropriate country in order to use the proceeds from such payments to carry out activities under section 1704 of this title.


(B) Rates of exchangePayments in local currency shall be at rates of exchange that are no less favorable than the highest exchange rate legally obtainable in the country and that are no less favorable than the highest exchange rate obtainable by any other country.




(b) InterestSuch agreements shall provide that interest accrue on the payment deferred under such agreement at a concessional rate as determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(c) DurationPayments required under such agreements may be made in reasonable annual amounts over the period (not more than 30 years from the date of the last delivery of commodities in each year under such agreement) specified in the agreement.


(d) Deferral of paymentsThe Secretary may defer the date on which the developing country or private entity is required to begin making payment, under such agreements, for a period of not in excess of 5 years after the date of the last delivery of commodities in each year under the agreement, and interest shall be computed from the date of such last delivery.


(e) Delivery of commoditiesDelivery of the commodities shall be made in accordance with the terms of the agreement.


(July 10, 1954, ch. 469, title I, § 103, 68 Stat. 456; Aug. 12, 1955, ch. 873, § 1, 69 Stat. 721; May 28, 1956, ch. 327, title II, § 208(a), 70 Stat. 201; Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 933, § 1, 70 Stat. 988; Pub. L. 85–128, § 1(2), Aug. 13, 1957, 71 Stat. 345; Pub. L. 85–931, § 2, Sept. 6, 1958, 72 Stat. 1790; Pub. L. 86–341, title I, § 2, Sept. 21, 1959, 73 Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interest Such agreements shall provide that interest accrue on the payment deferred under such agreement at a concessional rate as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duration Payments required under such agreements may be made in reasonable annual amounts over the period (not more than 30 years from the date of the last delivery of commodities in each year under such agreement) specified in the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deferral of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Deferral of payments The Secretary may defer the date on which the developing country or private entity is required to begin making payment, under such agreements, for a period of not in excess of 5 years after the date of the last delivery of commodities in each year under the agreement, and interest shall be computed from the date of such last delivery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Delivery of commodities Delivery of the commodities shall be made in accordance with the terms of the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>