<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704"><akn:num>1704</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of local currency payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704. Use of local currency payment(a) In generalAgreements under this subchapter may provide that the Secretary shall use payments made in local currencies by the developing country or private entity in accordance with this section.


(b) Special accountForeign currencies received by the Secretary under this subchapter shall be deposited in a separate account, that may be interest-bearing, to the credit of the United States and such currencies and interest thereon shall be used as provided for in this section.


(c) ActivitiesThe proceeds from the payments referred to in subsection (a) may be used in the appropriate developing country, through agreements with recipient governments, private voluntary organizations, and cooperatives, for the following:(1) Agricultural developmentTo support—(A) increased agricultural production, including availability of agricultural inputs, with emphasis on small farms, processing of agricultural commodities, forestry management, and land and water management;

(B) credit policies for private-sector agriculture development;

(C) establishment and expansion of institutions for basic and applied agricultural research and the use of such research through development of extension services;

(D) programs to control rodents, insects, weeds, and other animal or plant pests; and

(E) the improvement of the trade capacity of the recipient country.


(2) Agricultural business development loansTo make loans to United States business entities (including cooperatives) and branches, subsidiaries, or affiliates of such entities for development of agricultural businesses and agricultural trade capacity in such appropriate developing countries.


(3) Agricultural facilities loansTo make loans to domestic or foreign entities (including cooperatives) for the establishment of facilities for aiding in the utilization or distribution of agricultural products.


(4) Trade promotionTo promote agricultural trade development, under procedures established by</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Agreements under this subchapter may provide that the Secretary shall use payments made in local currencies by the developing country or private entity in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special account Foreign currencies received by the Secretary under this subchapter shall be deposited in a separate account, that may be interest-bearing, to the credit of the United States and such currencies and interest thereon shall be used as provided for in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities The proceeds from the payments referred to in subsection (a) may be used in the appropriate developing country, through agreements with recipient governments, private voluntary organizations, and cooperatives, for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal requirements regarding use of local currencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fiscal requirements regarding use of local currencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>