<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1722" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1722/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1722/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1722"><akn:num>1722</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of agricultural commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1722. Provision of agricultural commodities(a) Emergency assistanceNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may provide agricultural commodities to meet emergency food needs under this subchapter through governments and public or private agencies, including intergovernmental organizations such as the World Food Program and other multilateral organizations, in such manner and on such terms and conditions as the Administrator determines appropriate to respond to the emergency.


(b) Nonemergency assistance(1) In generalThe Administrator may provide agricultural commodities for nonemergency assistance under this subchapter through eligible organizations (as described in subsection (d)) that have entered into an agreement with the Administrator to use the commodities in accordance with this subchapter.


(2) LimitationThe Administrator may not use as a sole rationale for denying a request for funds submitted under this subsection because the program for which the funds are requested—(A) would be carried out by the eligible organization in a foreign country in which the Agency for International Development does not have a mission, office, or other presence; or

(B) is not part of a development plan for the country prepared by the Agency.


(3) Program diversityThe Administrator shall—(A) encourage eligible organizations to propose and implement program plans to address 1 or more aspects of the program under section 1721 of this title; and

(B) consider proposals that incorporate a variety of program objectives and strategic plans based on the identification by eligible organizations of appropriate activities, consistent with section 1721 of this title, to assist development of foreign countries.



(c) Uses of assistanceAgricultural commodities provided under this subchapter may be made available for direct distribution, sale, barter, or other appropriate disposition.


(d) Eligible organizationsTo be eligible to receive assistance under subsection</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Emergency assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may provide agricultural commodities to meet emergency food needs under this subchapter through governments and public or private agencies, including intergovernmental organizations such as the World Food Program and other multilateral organizations, in such manner and on such terms and conditions as the Administrator determines appropriate to respond to the emergency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonemergency assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nonemergency assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uses of assistance Agricultural commodities provided under this subchapter may be made available for direct distribution, sale, barter, or other appropriate disposition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible organizations To be eligible to receive assistance under subsection (b) an organization shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for eligible organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Support for eligible organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective use of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective use of commodities To ensure that agricultural commodities made available under this subchapter are used effectively and in the areas of greatest need, organizations or cooperatives through which such commodities are distributed shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Labeling of assistance Agricultural commodities and other assistance provided under this subchapter shall, to the extent practicable, be clearly identified with appropriate markings on the package or container of such agricultural commodities or food procured outside of the United States, or on printed material that accompanies other assistance, in the language of the locality in which such commodities and other assistance are distributed, as being furnished by the people of the United States of America.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1722_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Food aid quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Food aid quality</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>