<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1724" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1724/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1724/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1724"><akn:num>1724</akn:num><akn:heading>Levels of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1724. Levels of assistance(a) Minimum levels(1) Minimum assistanceExcept as provided in paragraph (3), the Administrator shall make agricultural commodities available for food distribution under this subchapter in an amount that for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023 is not less than 2,500,000 metric tons.


(2) Minimum non-emergency assistanceOf the amounts specified in paragraph (1), and except as provided in paragraph (3), the Administrator shall make agricultural commodities available for non-emergency food distribution through eligible organizations under section 1722 of this title in an amount that for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023 is not less than 1,875,000 metric tons.


(3) ExceptionThe Administrator may waive the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) for any fiscal year if the Administrator determines that such quantities of commodities cannot be used effectively to carry out this subchapter or in order to meet an emergency. In making a waiver under this paragraph, the Administrator shall prepare and submit to the Committees on International Relations, Agriculture and Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committees on Appropriations and Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report containing the reasons for the waiver. No waiver shall be made before the beginning of the applicable fiscal year.



(b) Use of value-added commodities(1) Minimum levelsExcept as provided in paragraph (2), in making agricultural commodities available under this subchapter, the Administrator shall ensure that not less than 75 percent of the quantity of such commodities required to be distributed during each fiscal year under subsection (a)(2) be in the form of processed, fortified, or bagged commodities and that not less than 50 percent of the quantity of the bagged commodities that are whole grain commodities be bagged in the United States.


(2) Waiver of minimumThe Administrator may waive the requirement of paragraph (1) for an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Minimum levels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of value-added commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of value-added commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>