<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1726a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1726a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1726a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1726a"><akn:num>1726a</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1726a. Administration(a) Proposals(1) Recipient countriesA proposal to enter into a nonemergency food assistance agreement under this subchapter shall identify the recipient country or countries that are the subject of the agreement.


(2) TimingNot later than 120 days after the date of receipt by the Administrator of a proposal submitted by an eligible organization under this subchapter, the Administrator shall determine whether to accept the proposal.


(3) DenialIf a proposal under paragraph (1) is denied, the response shall specify the reasons for denial.



(b) Notice and commentNot later than 30 days prior to the issuance of a final guideline or annual policy guidance to carry out this subchapter, the Administrator shall—(1) provide notice of the existence of a proposed guideline or annual policy guidance, and that such guideline or annual policy guidance is available for review and comment, to eligible organizations that participate in programs under this subchapter, and to other interested persons;

(2) make the proposed guideline or annual policy guidance available, on request, to the eligible organizations and other persons referred to in paragraph (1); and

(3) take any comments received into consideration prior to the issuance of the final guideline or annual policy guidance.


(c) Regulations and guidance(1) In generalThe Administrator shall promptly issue all necessary regulations and make revisions to agency guidelines with respect to changes in the operation or implementation of the program established under this subchapter. Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018, the Administrator shall issue all regulations and revisions to agency guidance necessary to implement the amendments made to this subchapter by such Act.


(2) RequirementsThe Administrator shall develop regulations and guidance with the intent of—(A) simplifying procedures for participation in the programs established under this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice and comment Not later than 30 days prior to the issuance of a final guideline or annual policy guidance to carry out this subchapter, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations and guidance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely provision of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timely provision of commodities The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall develop procedures that ensure expedited processing of commodity call forwards in order to provide commodities overseas in a timely manner and to the extent feasible, according to planned delivery schedules.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Timely approval The Administrator is encouraged to finalize program agreements and resource requests for programs under this section before the beginning of each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program oversight, monitoring, and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Program oversight, monitoring, and evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1726a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Project reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>