<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1727" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1727/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1727/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1727"><akn:num>1727</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1727. Bilateral grant program(a) In generalThe President shall establish a program under which agricultural commodities are donated in accordance with this subchapter to least developed countries. The revenue generated by the sale of such commodities in the recipient country may be utilized for economic development activities. Such program shall be implemented by the Administrator.


(b) General authorityTo carry out the policies and accomplish the objectives described in section 1691 of this title, the Administrator may negotiate and execute agreements with least developed countries to provide commodities to such countries on a grant basis.


(July 10, 1954, ch. 469, title III, § 301, as added Pub. L. 95–88, title II, § 211(a)(2), Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 548; amended Pub. L. 96–53, title II, § 204(a), Aug. 14, 1979, 93 Stat. 369; Pub. L. 99–198, title XI, § 1112(a)(3), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1478; Pub. L. 100–576, § 4(a)(1), Oct. 31, 1988, 102 Stat. 2898; Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1512, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3641.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 301 of act July 10, 1954, ch. 469, title III, 68 Stat. 458, which amended section 1427 of this title, was renumbered section 308 by Pub. L. 95–88, title II, § 211(a)(1), Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 548.

Amendments1990—Pub. L. 101–624 amended section generally, substituting present provisions for provisions outlining Congressional purpose with regard to Food for Development Program, establishment of program, goal of assistance under program, range of assistance and emphasized activities, and use of funds for disaster assistance.
1988—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 100–576 added subsec. (c).
1985—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 99–198 inserted “(including immunization of children)” after “health services”.
1979—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 96–53 inserted “, or the dollar sales value of the commodities themselves,” after “the local sale of such commodities”, and substituted “in the participating country of funds from the sale of such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1727_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President shall establish a program under which agricultural commodities are donated in accordance with this subchapter to least developed countries. The revenue generated by the sale of such commodities in the recipient country may be utilized for economic development activities. Such program shall be implemented by the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1727_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority To carry out the policies and accomplish the objectives described in section 1691 of this title, the Administrator may negotiate and execute agreements with least developed countries to provide commodities to such countries on a grant basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>