<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1733" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1733/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1733/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1733"><akn:num>1733</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1733. General provisions(a) ProhibitionNo agricultural commodity, food procured outside of the United States, food voucher, or cash transfer for food shall be made available under this chapter unless it is determined that—(1) in the case of the provision of an agricultural commodity, adequate storage facilities will be available in the recipient country at the time of the arrival of the commodity to prevent the spoilage or waste of the commodity; and

(2) the distribution of the agricultural commodity or use of the food procured outside of the United States, food voucher, or cash transfer for food in the recipient country will not result in a substantial disincentive to or interference with domestic production or marketing in that country.


(b) Impact on local farmers and economyThe Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall ensure that the importation of United States agricultural commodities, the use of food procured outside of the United States, food vouchers, and cash transfers for food, and the use of local currencies for development purposes will not have a disruptive impact on the farmers or the local economy of the recipient country. The Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall seek information, as part of the regular proposal and submission process, from implementing agencies on the potential costs and benefits to the local economy within the recipient country.


(c) TransshipmentThe Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall, under such terms and conditions as are determined to be appropriate, require commitments designed to prevent or restrict the resale or transshipment to other countries, or use for other than domestic purposes, of agricultural commodities donated or purchased under this chapter.


(d) Private trade channels and small businessPrivate trade channels shall be used under this chapter to the maximum extent practicable in the United States and in the recipient countries with respect to—(1) sales from pri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition No agricultural commodity, food procured outside of the United States, food voucher, or cash transfer for food shall be made available under this chapter unless it is determined that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact on local farmers and economy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Impact on local farmers and economy The Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall ensure that the importation of United States agricultural commodities, the use of food procured outside of the United States, food vouchers, and cash transfers for food, and the use of local currencies for development purposes will not have a disruptive impact on the farmers or the local economy of the recipient country. The Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall seek information, as part of the regular proposal and submission process, from implementing agencies on the potential costs and benefits to the local economy within the recipient country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transshipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transshipment The Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall, under such terms and conditions as are determined to be appropriate, require commitments designed to prevent or restrict the resale or transshipment to other countries, or use for other than domestic purposes, of agricultural commodities donated or purchased under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private trade channels and small business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Private trade channels and small business Private trade channels shall be used under this chapter to the maximum extent practicable in the United States and in the recipient countries with respect to— Small businesses shall be provided adequate and fair opportunity to participate in such sales.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>World prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) World prices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publicity Commitments shall be obtained from countries or private entities, as appropriate, receiving commodities under this chapter that such countries or private entities will widely publicize, to the extent practicable, through the use of the public media and through other means, that such commodities are being provided through the friendship of the American people as food for peace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of private sector</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Participation of private sector The Secretary or the Administrator, as appropriate, shall encourage the private sector of the United States and private importers in developing countries to participate in the programs established under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguard usual marketings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Safeguard usual marketings In carrying out this chapter, reasonable precautions shall be taken to safeguard the usual marketings of the United States and to avoid displacing any sales of the United States agricultural commodities that the Secretary or Administrator determines would otherwise be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military distribution of food aid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Military distribution of food aid</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1733_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations of human rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Violations of human rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>