<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1736_1"><akn:num>1736–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Assistant for Agricultural Trade and Food Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1736–1. Special Assistant for Agricultural Trade and Food Assistance(a) Appointment by PresidentThe President shall appoint a Special Assistant to the President for Agricultural Trade and Food Assistance (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Special Assistant”). The President shall appoint the initial Special Assistant not later than May 1, 1986.


(b) Service in Executive Office of PresidentThe Special Assistant shall serve in the Executive Office of the President.


(c) Required functionsThe Special Assistant shall—(1) assist and advise the President in order to improve and enhance food assistance programs carried out in the United States and foreign countries;

(2) be available to receive suggestions and complaints concerning the implementation of United States food aid and agricultural export programs anywhere in the United States Government and provide prompt responses thereto, including expediting the program implementation in any instances in which there is unreasonable delay;

(3) make recommendations to the President on means to coordinate and streamline the manner in which food assistance programs are carried out by the Department of Agriculture and the Agency for International Development, in order to improve their overall effectiveness;

(4) make recommendations to the President on measures to be taken to increase use of United States agricultural commodities and the products thereof through food assistance programs;

(5) advise the President on agricultural trade;

(6) advise the President on the Food for Progress Program and expedite its implementation;

(7) serve as a member of the Development Coordination Committee and the Food Aid Subcommittee of such Committee;

(8) advise departments and agencies of the Federal Government on their policy guidelines on basic issues of food assistance policy to the extent necessary to assure the coordination of food assistance programs, consistent with law, and with the advice of such Subcommittee; and
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment by President The President shall appoint a Special Assistant to the President for Agricultural Trade and Food Assistance (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Special Assistant”). The President shall appoint the initial Special Assistant not later than May 1, 1986.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service in Executive Office of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Service in Executive Office of President The Special Assistant shall serve in the Executive Office of the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Required functions The Special Assistant shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation Compensation for the Special Assistant shall be fixed by the President at an annual rate of basic pay of not less than the rate applicable to positions in level III of the Executive Schedule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>