<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736f–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736f–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736f–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1736f_1"><akn:num>1736f–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of commodity trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1736f–1. Establishment of commodity trust(a) In generalTo provide for a trust solely to meet emergency humanitarian food needs in developing countries, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish and maintain a trust of wheat, rice, corn, or sorghum, any combination of the commodities, or funds for use as described in subsection (c).


(b) Commodities or funds in trust(1) In generalThe trust established under this section shall consist of—(A) wheat in the reserve established under the Food Security Wheat Reserve Act of 1980 as of April 4, 1996;

(B) wheat, rice, corn, and sorghum (referred to in this section as “eligible commodities”) acquired in accordance with paragraph (2) to replenish eligible commodities released from the trust, including wheat to replenish wheat released from the reserve established under the Food Security Wheat Reserve Act of 1980 but not replenished as of April 4, 1996;

(C) such rice, corn, and sorghum as the Secretary may, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary determines appropriate, acquire as a result of exchanging an equivalent value of wheat in the trust established under this section; and

(D) funds made available—(i) under paragraph (2)(B);

(ii) as a result of an exchange of any commodity held in the trust for an equivalent amount of funds from the market, if the Secretary determines that such a sale of the commodity on the market will not unduly disrupt domestic markets; or

(iii) to maximize the value of the trust, in accordance with subsection (d)(3).



(2) Replenishment of trust(A) In generalSubject to subsection (h), commodities of equivalent value to eligible commodities in the trust established under this section may be acquired—(i) through purchases—(I) from producers; or

(II) in the market, if the Secretary determines that the purchases will not unduly disrupt the market; or


(ii) by designation by the Secretary of stocks of eligible commodities of the Commod</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To provide for a trust solely to meet emergency humanitarian food needs in developing countries, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish and maintain a trust of wheat, rice, corn, or sorghum, any combination of the commodities, or funds for use as described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodities or funds in trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commodities or funds in trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of eligible commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Release of eligible commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of trust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management of trust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of trust under other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of trust under other law Eligible commodities in the trust established under this section shall not be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Finality of determination Any determination by the Secretary under this section shall be final.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736f_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination of authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>