<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1736o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1736o"><akn:num>1736o</akn:num><akn:heading>Food for progress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1736o. Food for progress(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Food for Progress Act of 1985”.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) CooperativeThe term “cooperative” has the meaning given the term in section 402 of the Food for Peace Act (7 U.S.C. 1732).


(2) CorporationThe term “Corporation” means the Commodity Credit Corporation.


(3) Developing countryThe term “developing country” has the meaning given the term in section 402 of the Food for Peace Act (7 U.S.C. 1732).


(4) Eligible commodityThe term “eligible commodity” means an agricultural commodity, or a product of an agricultural commodity, in inventories of the Corporation or acquired by the Secretary or the Corporation for disposition through commercial purchases under a program authorized under this section.


(5) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(A) the government of an emerging agricultural country;

(B) an intergovernmental organization;

(C) a private voluntary organization;

(D) a nonprofit agricultural organization or cooperative;

(E) a nongovernmental organization;

(F) a college or university (as such terms are defined in section 3103(4) of this title); and

(G) any other private entity.


(6) Food securityThe term “food security” means access by all people at all times to sufficient food and nutrition for a healthy and productive life.


(7) Nongovernmental organizationThe term “nongovernmental organization” has the meaning given the term in section 402 of the Food for Peace Act (7 U.S.C. 1732).


(8) Private voluntary organizationThe term “private voluntary organization” has the meaning given the term in section 402 of the Food for Peace Act (7 U.S.C. 1732).


(9) ProgramThe term “program” means a food assistance or development initiative proposed by an eligible entity and approved by the Secretary under this section.


(10) Rate of returnFor purposes of applying subsection (j)(3), the rate of return for an eligible commodity shall be equal to the proportion that—(A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Food for Progress Act of 1985”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program In order to use the food resources of the United States more effectively in support of developing countries, and countries that are emerging democracies that have made commitments to introduce or expand free enterprise elements in their agricultural economies through changes in commodity pricing, marketing, input availability, distribution, and private sector involvement, the Secretary shall enter into agreements with eligible entities to furnish to the countries eligible commodities made available under subsections (e) and (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration for agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consideration for agreements In determining whether to enter into an agreement under this section, the Secretary shall consider whether a potential recipient country is committed to carry out, or is carrying out, policies that promote economic freedom, private, domestic production of eligible commodities for domestic consumption, and the creation and expansion of efficient domestic markets for the purchase and sale of such eligible commodities. Such policies may provide for, among other things—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding of eligible commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding of eligible commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of eligible commodities to developing countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Provision of eligible commodities to developing countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum tonnage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Minimum tonnage Subject to subsection (f)(3), not less than 400,000 metric tons of eligible commodities shall be provided under this section for the program for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on resale or transshipment of eligible commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibition on resale or transshipment of eligible commodities An agreement entered into under this section shall prohibit the resale or transshipment of the eligible commodities provided under the agreement to other countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Displacement of United States commercial sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Displacement of United States commercial sales In entering into agreements under this section, the Secretary shall take reasonable steps to avoid displacement of any sales of United States commodities that would otherwise be made to such countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1736o_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multicountry or multiyear basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Multicountry or multiyear basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>