<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1738m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1738m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1738m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1738m"><akn:num>1738m</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1738m. Annual report to Congress(a) In generalNot later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the President shall prepare and submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate an annual report concerning the operation of the Facility for the prior fiscal year. This report shall include—(1) a description of the activities undertaken by the Facility during the previous fiscal year;

(2) a description of any Enviromental 11 So in original. Probably should be “Environmental”. Framework Agreement entered into under this subchapter;

(3) a report on what Environmental Funds have been established under this subchapter and on the operations of such Funds; and

(4) a description of any grants that have been extended by administering bodies pursuant to an Enviromental 1 Framework Agreement under this subchapter.


(b) Supplemental views in annual reportNo later than December 15 of each fiscal year, each member of the Board shall be entitled to receive a copy of the report required under subsection (a). Each member of the Board may prepare and submit supplemental views to the President on the implementation of this subchapter by December 31 for inclusion in the annual report when it is transmitted to Congress pursuant to this section.


(July 10, 1954, ch. 469, title VI, § 614, as added Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1512, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3662; as amended Pub. L. 102–237, title III, § 330, Dec. 13, 1991, 105 Stat. 1858; Pub. L. 102–532, § 3, Oct. 27, 1992, 106 Stat. 3512.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–532 inserted at end “This report shall include—” and pars. (1) to (4).
1991—Pub. L. 102–237 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Termination of Reporting RequirementsFor termination, effective May 15, 2000, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1738m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than December 31 of each fiscal year, the President shall prepare and submit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President Pro Tempore of the Senate an annual report concerning the operation of the Facility for the prior fiscal year. This report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1738m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental views in annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supplemental views in annual report No later than December 15 of each fiscal year, each member of the Board shall be entitled to receive a copy of the report required under subsection (a). Each member of the Board may prepare and submit supplemental views to the President on the implementation of this subchapter by December 31 for inclusion in the annual report when it is transmitted to Congress pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>