<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/178i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/178i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/178i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_178i"><akn:num>178i</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of activities with Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 178i. Coordination of activities with Federal agencies
In carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretaries and the Joint Commission shall cooperate with each other in the conduct of their activities under this subchapter, and shall ensure that their activities under this subchapter are closely coordinated with the activities of other Federal agencies such as the Department of the Interior, National Science Foundation, Bureau of Indian Affairs, Department of Energy, Department of State, Department of Defense, Treasury Department, Federal Emergency Management Agency, and others, in order to prevent duplication of effort, ensure compatibility with ongoing programs and policies, and to fully exploit the opportunities inherent in the culture and manufacture of native latex.
(Pub. L. 95–592, § 11, Nov. 4, 1978, 92 Stat. 2533; Pub. L. 98–284, § 11, May 16, 1984, 98 Stat. 184; Pub. L. 102–237, title X, § 1005(2), Dec. 13, 1991, 105 Stat. 1894.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1991—Pub. L. 102–237 substituted “ensure” for “insure” in two places.
1984—Pub. L. 98–284 substituted “shall cooperate with each other in the conduct of their activities under this subchapter, and shall insure that their activities under this subchapter are closely coordinated with the activities of other Federal agencies” for “shall insure that their activities are closely coordinated with the activities of other Federal agencies” and “Federal Emergency Management Agency, and others,” for “Federal Preparedness Agency, and others”, and inserted “Department of State,”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the functions of the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management relating thereto, to the Federal Emergency Management Agency, see section 315(a)(1) of Title 6, Domestic Security.
For transfer of fun</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>