<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1926a"><akn:num>1926a</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency and imminent community water assistance grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1926a. Emergency and imminent community water assistance grant program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall provide grants in accordance with this section to assist the residents of rural areas and small communities to secure adequate quantities of safe water—(1) after a significant decline in the quantity or quality of water available from the water supplies of such rural areas and small communities, or when such a decline is imminent; or

(2) when repairs, partial replacement, or significant maintenance efforts on established water systems would remedy—(A) an acute, or imminent, shortage of quality water; or

(B) a significant decline, or imminent decline, in the quantity or quality of water that is available.



(b) PriorityIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—(1) give priority to projects described in subsection (a)(1), particularly to projects to address contamination that—(A) poses a threat to human health or the environment; and

(B) was caused by circumstances beyond the control of the applicant for a grant, including circumstances that occurred over a period of time; and


(2) provide at least 70 percent of all such grants to such projects.


(c) EligibilityTo be eligible to obtain a grant under this section, an applicant shall—(1) be a public or private nonprofit entity; and

(2) in the case of a grant made under subsection (a)(1), demonstrate to the Secretary that the decline referred to in such subsection occurred, or will occur, within 2 years of the date the application was filed for such grant.


(d) Uses(1) In generalGrants made under this section may be used—(A) for waterline extensions from existing systems, laying of new waterlines, repairs, significant maintenance, digging of new wells, equipment replacement, and hook and tap fees;

(B) for any other appropriate purpose associated with developing sources of, treating, storing, or distributing water;

(C) to assist communities in complying with the requirements of the Federal Water Po</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall provide grants in accordance with this section to assist the residents of rural areas and small communities to secure adequate quantities of safe water—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility To be eligible to obtain a grant under this section, an applicant shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Maximum grants Grants made under this section may not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Full funding Subject to subsection (e), grants under this section shall be made in an amount equal to 100 percent of the costs of the projects conducted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>