<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1926d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1926d"><akn:num>1926d</akn:num><akn:heading>Water systems for rural and Native villages in Alaska</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1926d. Water systems for rural and Native villages in Alaska(a) In generalThe Secretary may make grants to the State of Alaska, a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 (Public Law 105–83; 111 Stat. 1597), and Native villages (as defined in section 1602 of title 43) for the benefit of rural or Native villages in Alaska to provide for the development and construction of water and wastewater systems to improve the health and sanitation conditions in those villages.


(b) Matching fundsTo be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), the State of Alaska shall provide 25 percent in matching funds from non-Federal sources for any grant awarded under subsection (a).


(c) Consultation with State of AlaskaThe Secretary shall consult with the State of Alaska on a method of prioritizing the allocation of grants under subsection (a) according to the needs of, and relative health and sanitation conditions in, each village.


(d) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.


(2) Training and technical assistanceNot more than 2 percent of the amount made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year may be used by the State of Alaska, and not more than 2 percent of the amount made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year may be used by a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 (Public Law 105–83; 111 Stat. 1597), for training and technical assistance programs relating to the operation and management of water and waste disposal services in rural and Native villages.


(3) AvailabilityFunds appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations in paragraph (1) shall be available until expended.



(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 306D, as added Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 75</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make grants to the State of Alaska, a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1998 (Public Law 105–83; 111 Stat. 1597), and Native villages (as defined in section 1602 of title 43) for the benefit of rural or Native villages in Alaska to provide for the development and construction of water and wastewater systems to improve the health and sanitation conditions in those villages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matching funds To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), the State of Alaska shall provide 25 percent in matching funds from non-Federal sources for any grant awarded under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with State of Alaska</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation with State of Alaska The Secretary shall consult with the State of Alaska on a method of prioritizing the allocation of grants under subsection (a) according to the needs of, and relative health and sanitation conditions in, each village.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1926d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>