<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1927" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1927/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1927/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1927"><akn:num>1927</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1927. Repayment requirements(a) Period of repayment; interest rates(1) The period for repayment of loans under this subchapter shall not exceed forty years.

(2) Except as otherwise provided in paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of this subsection, the interest rates on loans under this subchapter shall be as determined by the Secretary, but not in excess of the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, plus not to exceed 1 per centum, as determined by the Secretary, and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum.

(3)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of the constitution or laws of any State limiting the rate or amount of interest that may be charged, taken, received, or reserved, except as provided in paragraph (6), the interest rates on loans (other than guaranteed loans), to public bodies or nonprofit associations (including Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations and other federally recognized Indian tribal groups) for water and waste disposal facilities and essential community facilities shall be set by the Secretary at rates not to exceed the current market yield for outstanding municipal obligations with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturity for such loans, and adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum; and not in excess of 5 per centum per annum for any such loans which are for the upgrading of existing facilities or construction of new facilities as required to meet applicable health or sanitary standards in areas where the median household income of the persons to be served by such facility is below the higher of 80 per centum of the statewide nonmetropolitan median household income or the poverty line established by the Office of Management and Budget, as revised under section 9902(2) of title 42 and in other areas as the Secretary may designate where a significant percen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of repayment; interest rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Period of repayment; interest rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of charges; prepayment of taxes and insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of charges; prepayment of taxes and insurance The borrower shall pay such fees and other charges as the Secretary may require, and borrowers under this chapter shall prepay to the Secretary such taxes and insurance as the Secretary may require, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mortgages, liens, and other security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mortgages, liens, and other security The Secretary shall take as security for the obligations entered into in connection with loans, mortgages on farms with respect to which such loans are made or such other security as the Secretary may require, and for obligations in connection with loans to associations under section 1926 of this title, shall take liens on the facility or such other security as he may determine to be necessary. Such security instruments may constitute liens running to the United States notwithstanding the fact that the notes may be held by lenders other than the United States. A borrower may use the same collateral to secure two or more loans made, insured, or guaranteed under this subchapter, except that the outstanding amount of such loans may not exceed the total value of the collateral so used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1927_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional collateral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional collateral The Secretary may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>