<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1935" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1935/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1935/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1935"><akn:num>1935</akn:num><akn:heading>Down payment loan program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1935. Down payment loan program(a) In general(1) EstablishmentNotwithstanding any other section of this subchapter, the Secretary shall establish, within the farm ownership loan program established under this subchapter, a program under which loans shall be made under this section to eligible farmers or ranchers for down payments on farm ownership loans.


(2) AdministrationThe Secretary shall be the primary coordinator of credit supervision for the down payment loan program established under this section, in consultation with the commercial or cooperative lender and, if applicable, the contracting credit counseling service selected under section 2006b(c) of this title.



(b) Loan terms(1) PrincipalEach loan made under this section shall be in an amount that does not exceed 45 percent of the least of—(A) the purchase price of the farm or ranch to be acquired;

(B) the appraised value of the farm or ranch to be acquired; or

(C) $667,000.


(2) Interest rateThe interest rate on any loan made by the Secretary under this section shall be a rate equal to the greater of—(A) the difference obtained by subtracting 4 percent from the interest rate for farm ownership loans under this subchapter; or

(B) 1.5 percent.


(3) DurationEach loan under this section shall be made for a period of 20 years or less, at the option of the borrower.


(4) RepaymentEach borrower of a loan under this section shall repay the loan to the Secretary in equal annual installments.


(5) Nature of retained security interestThe Secretary shall retain an interest in each farm or ranch acquired with a loan made under this section that shall—(A) be secured by the farm or ranch;

(B) be junior only to such interests in the farm or ranch as may be conveyed at the time of acquisition to the person (including a lender) from whom the borrower obtained a loan used to acquire the farm or ranch; and

(C) require the borrower to obtain the permission of the Secretary before the borrower may grant an additio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1935_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1935_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Loan terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1935_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1935_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1935_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible farmer or rancher</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definition of eligible farmer or rancher In this section, the term “eligible farmer or rancher” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>