<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1936c"><akn:num>1936c</akn:num><akn:heading>Relending program to resolve ownership and succession on farmland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1936c. Relending program to resolve ownership and succession on farmland(a) In generalThe Secretary may make loans to eligible entities described in subsection (b) so that the eligible entities may relend the funds to individuals and entities for the purposes described in subsection (c).


(b) Eligible entitiesEntities eligible for loans described in subsection (a) are cooperatives, credit unions, and nonprofit organizations with—(1) certification under section 1805.201 of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), to operate as a lender;

(2) experience assisting socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers (as defined in subsection (a) of section 2279 of this title) or limited resource or new and beginning farmers and ranchers, rural businesses, cooperatives, or credit unions, including experience in making and servicing agricultural and commercial loans; and

(3) the ability to provide adequate assurance of the repayment of a loan.


(c) Eligible purposesThe proceeds from loans made by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) shall be re-lent by eligible entities for projects that assist heirs with undivided ownership interests to resolve ownership and succession on farmland that has multiple owners.


(d) PreferenceIn making loans under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities—(1) with not less than 10 years of experience serving socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers; and

(2) in States that have adopted a statute consisting of an enactment or adoption of the Uniform Partition of Heirs Property Act, as approved and recommended for enactment in all States by the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws in 2010, that relend to owners of heirs property (as defined in that Act).


(e) Loan terms and conditionsThe following terms and conditions shall apply to loans made under this section:(1) The interest rate at which intermediaries may borrow funds under this section shall be determined</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make loans to eligible entities described in subsection (b) so that the eligible entities may relend the funds to individuals and entities for the purposes described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities Entities eligible for loans described in subsection (a) are cooperatives, credit unions, and nonprofit organizations with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible purposes The proceeds from loans made by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (a) shall be re-lent by eligible entities for projects that assist heirs with undivided ownership interests to resolve ownership and succession on farmland that has multiple owners.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preference In making loans under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Loan terms and conditions The following terms and conditions shall apply to loans made under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 1 year after December 20, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the operation and outcomes of the program under this section, with recommendations on how to strengthen the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>