<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1936/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1936"><akn:num>1936</akn:num><akn:heading>Beginning farmer or rancher and socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher contract land sales program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1936. Beginning farmer or rancher and socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher contract land sales program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, guarantee a loan made by a private seller of a farm or ranch to a qualified beginning farmer or rancher or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher (as defined in section 2003(e)(2) of this title) on a contract land sales basis.


(b) EligibilityIn order to be eligible for a loan guarantee under subsection (a)—(1) the qualified beginning farmer or rancher or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher shall—(A) on the date the contract land sale that is subject of the loan is complete, own and operate the farm or ranch that is the subject of the contract land sale;

(B) have a credit history that—(i) includes a record of satisfactory debt repayment, as determined by the Secretary; and

(ii) is acceptable to the Secretary; and


(C) demonstrate to the Secretary that the farmer or rancher, as the case may be, is unable to obtain sufficient credit without a guarantee to finance any actual need of the farmer or rancher, as the case may be, at a reasonable rate or term; and


(2) the loan shall meet applicable underwriting criteria, as determined by the Secretary.


(c) Limitations(1) Down paymentThe Secretary shall not provide a loan guarantee under subsection (a) if the contribution of the qualified beginning farmer or rancher or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher to the down payment for the farm or ranch that is the subject of the contract land sale would be less than 5 percent of the purchase price of the farm or ranch.


(2) Maximum purchase priceThe Secretary shall not provide a loan guarantee under subsection (a) if the purchase price or the appraisal value of the farm or ranch that is the subject of the contract land sale is greater than $500,000.



(d) Period of guaranteeThe period during which a loan guarantee under this section is in effect shall be the 10-year period beginning with </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall, in accordance with this section, guarantee a loan made by a private seller of a farm or ranch to a qualified beginning farmer or rancher or socially disadvantaged farmer or rancher (as defined in section 2003(e)(2) of this title) on a contract land sales basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility In order to be eligible for a loan guarantee under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of guarantee The period during which a loan guarantee under this section is in effect shall be the 10-year period beginning with the date the guarantee is provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantee plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Guarantee plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1936_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition from pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transition from pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>