<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/197c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/197c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/197c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_197c"><akn:num>197c</akn:num><akn:heading>Arbitration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 197c. Arbitration(a) In generalAny livestock or poultry contract that contains a provision requiring the use of arbitration to resolve any controversy that may arise under the contract shall contain a provision that allows a producer or grower, prior to entering the contract 11 So in original. A comma probably should appear. to decline to be bound by the arbitration provision.


(b) DisclosureAny livestock or poultry contract that contains a provision requiring the use of arbitration shall contain terms that conspicuously disclose the right of the contract producer or grower, prior to entering the contract, to decline the requirement to use arbitration to resolve any controversy that may arise under the livestock or poultry contract.


(c) Dispute resolutionAny contract producer or grower that declines a requirement of arbitration pursuant to subsection (b) has the right,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. to nonetheless seek to resolve any controversy that may arise under the livestock or poultry contract, if, after the controversy arises, both parties consent in writing to use arbitration to settle the controversy.


(d) ApplicationSubsections (a) 1 (b) and (c) shall apply to any contract entered into, amended, altered, modified, renewed, or extended after the date of the enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008.


(e) Unlawful practiceAny action by or on behalf of a packer, swine contractor, or live poultry dealer that violates this section (including any action that has the intent or effect of limiting the ability of a producer or grower to freely make a choice described in subsection (b)) is an unlawful practice under this chapter.


(f) RegulationsThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations to—(1) carry out this section; and

(2) establish criteria that the Secretary will consider in determining whether the arbitration process provided in a contract provides a meaningful opportunity for the grower or producer to partici</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any livestock or poultry contract that contains a provision requiring the use of arbitration to resolve any controversy that may arise under the contract shall contain a provision that allows a producer or grower, prior to entering the contract 11 So in original. A comma probably should appear. to decline to be bound by the arbitration provision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure Any livestock or poultry contract that contains a provision requiring the use of arbitration shall contain terms that conspicuously disclose the right of the contract producer or grower, prior to entering the contract, to decline the requirement to use arbitration to resolve any controversy that may arise under the livestock or poultry contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dispute resolution Any contract producer or grower that declines a requirement of arbitration pursuant to subsection (b) has the right,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. to nonetheless seek to resolve any controversy that may arise under the livestock or poultry contract, if, after the controversy arises, both parties consent in writing to use arbitration to settle the controversy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application Subsections (a) 1 (b) and (c) shall apply to any contract entered into, amended, altered, modified, renewed, or extended after the date of the enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unlawful practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Unlawful practice Any action by or on behalf of a packer, swine contractor, or live poultry dealer that violates this section (including any action that has the intent or effect of limiting the ability of a producer or grower to freely make a choice described in subsection (b)) is an unlawful practice under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_197c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>