<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1981f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1981f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1981f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1981f"><akn:num>1981f</akn:num><akn:heading>Underwriting forms and standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1981f. Underwriting forms and standards
In the administration of this chapter, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, use underwriting forms, standards, practices, and terminology similar to the forms, standards, practices, and terminology used by lenders in the private sector.
(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 331F, as added Pub. L. 101–624, title XVIII, § 1808(a), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3820.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of Pub. L. 87–128, Aug. 8, 1961, 75 Stat. 307, known as the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1921 of this title and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
RegulationsPub. L. 101–624, title XVIII, § 1808(b), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3820, provided that: “The Secretary of Agriculture shall not issue final regulations providing for the use of ratios and standards for determining the degree of potential loan risk under section 331F of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act [7 U.S.C. 1981f] (as added by subsection (a) of this section), prior to the submission of the study and report on the effects of the regulations required by section 621 of the Agricultural Credit Act of 1987 (7 U.S.C. 1989 note).”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>