<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1983b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1983b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1983b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1983b"><akn:num>1983b</akn:num><akn:heading>Beginning farmer and rancher individual development accounts pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1983b. Beginning farmer and rancher individual development accounts pilot program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Demonstration programThe term “demonstration program” means a demonstration program carried out by a qualified entity under the pilot program established in subsection (b)(1).


(2) Eligible participantThe term “eligible participant” means a qualified beginning farmer or rancher that—(A) lacks significant financial resources or assets; and

(B) has an income that is less than—(i) 80 percent of the median income of the State in which the farmer or rancher resides; or

(ii) 200 percent of the most recent annual Federal Poverty Income Guidelines published by the Department of Health and Human Services for the State.



(3) Individual development accountThe term “individual development account” means a savings account described in subsection (b)(4)(A).


(4) Qualified entity(A) In generalThe term “qualified entity” means—(i) 1 or more organizations—(I) described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26; and

(II) exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such title; or


(ii) a State, local, or tribal government submitting an application jointly with an organization described in clause (i).


(B) No prohibition on collaborationAn organization described in subparagraph (A)(i) may collaborate with a financial institution or for-profit community development corporation to carry out the purposes of this section.




(b) Pilot program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a pilot program to be known as the “New Farmer Individual Development Accounts Pilot Program” under which the Secretary shall work through qualified entities to establish demonstration programs—(A) of at least 5 years in duration; and

(B) in at least 15 States.


(2) CoordinationThe Secretary shall operate the pilot program through, and in coordination with the farm loan programs of, the Farm Service Agency.


(3) Reserve funds(A) In generalA qualified entity carrying out a demonstration pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual review The Secretary may conduct an annual review of the financial records of a qualified entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations In carrying out this section, the Secretary may promulgate regulations to ensure that the program includes provisions for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1983b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>