<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1986" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1986/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/1986/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1986"><akn:num>1986</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicts of interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1986. Conflicts of interests(a) Acceptance of fees, commissions, gifts, or other considerations prohibitedNo officer, attorney, or other employee of the Secretary shall, directly or indirectly, be the beneficiary of or receive any fee, commission, gift, or other consideration for or in connection with any transaction or business under this chapter other than such salary, fee, or other compensation as he may receive as such officer, attorney, or employee.


(b) Acquisition of interest in land by certain officers or employees of Department of Agriculture prohibited; 3-year periodExcept as otherwise provided in this subsection, no officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture who acts on or reviews an application made by any person under this chapter for a loan to purchase land may acquire, directly or indirectly, any interest in such land for a period of three years after the date on which such action is taken or such review is made. This prohibition shall not apply to a former member of a county committee upon a determination by the Secretary, prior to the acquisition of such interest, that such former member acted in good faith when acting on or reviewing such application.


(c) Certifications on loans to family members prohibitedNo member of a county committee shall knowingly make or join in making any certification with respect to a loan to purchase any land in which he or any person related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity has or may acquire any interest or with respect to any applicant related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity.


(d) PenaltiesAny persons violating any provision of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by a fine of not more than $2,000 or imprisonment for not more than two years, or both.


(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 336, Aug. 8, 1961, 75 Stat. 316; Pub. L. 98–258, title VI, § 606, Apr. 10, 1984, 98 Stat. 140; Pub. L. 107–171, title V, § 5501(b), May 13, 2002, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of fees, commissions, gifts, or other considerations prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acceptance of fees, commissions, gifts, or other considerations prohibited No officer, attorney, or other employee of the Secretary shall, directly or indirectly, be the beneficiary of or receive any fee, commission, gift, or other consideration for or in connection with any transaction or business under this chapter other than such salary, fee, or other compensation as he may receive as such officer, attorney, or employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of interest in land by certain officers or employees of Department of Agriculture prohibited; 3-year period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisition of interest in land by certain officers or employees of Department of Agriculture prohibited; 3-year period Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, no officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture who acts on or reviews an application made by any person under this chapter for a loan to purchase land may acquire, directly or indirectly, any interest in such land for a period of three years after the date on which such action is taken or such review is made. This prohibition shall not apply to a former member of a county committee upon a determination by the Secretary, prior to the acquisition of such interest, that such former member acted in good faith when acting on or reviewing such application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications on loans to family members prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certifications on loans to family members prohibited No member of a county committee shall knowingly make or join in making any certification with respect to a loan to purchase any land in which he or any person related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity has or may acquire any interest or with respect to any applicant related to him within the second degree of consanguinity or affinity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1986_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalties Any persons violating any provision of this section shall, upon conviction thereof, be punished by a fine of not more than $2,000 or imprisonment for not more than two years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>