<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2"><akn:num>2</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Commission; liability of principal for act of agent; Commodity Futures Trading Commi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2. Jurisdiction of Commission; liability of principal for act of agent; Commodity Futures Trading Commission; transaction in interstate commerce(a) Jurisdiction of Commission; Commodity Futures Trading Commission(1) Jurisdiction of Commission(A) In generalThe Commission shall have exclusive jurisdiction, except to the extent otherwise provided in the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010 (including an amendment made by that Act) and subparagraphs (C), (D), and (I) of this paragraph and subsections (c) and (f), with respect to accounts, agreements (including any transaction which is of the character of, or is commonly known to the trade as, an “option”, “privilege”, “indemnity”, “bid”, “offer”, “put”, “call”, “advance guaranty”, or “decline guaranty”), and transactions involving swaps or contracts of sale of a commodity for future delivery (including significant price discovery contracts), traded or executed on a contract market designated pursuant to section 7 of this title or a swap execution facility pursuant to section 7b–3 of this title or any other board of trade, exchange, or market, and transactions subject to regulation by the Commission pursuant to section 23 of this title. Except as hereinabove provided, nothing contained in this section shall (I) supersede or limit the jurisdiction at any time conferred on the Securities and Exchange Commission or other regulatory authorities under the laws of the United States or of any State, or (II) restrict the Securities and Exchange Commission and such other authorities from carrying out their duties and responsibilities in accordance with such laws. Nothing in this section shall supersede or limit the jurisdiction conferred on courts of the United States or any State.


(B) Liability of principal for act of agentThe act, omission, or failure of any official, agent, or other person acting for any individual, association, partnership, corporation, or trust within the scope of his employment or off</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Commission; Commodity Futures Trading Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Jurisdiction of Commission; Commodity Futures Trading Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transaction in interstate commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transaction in interstate commerce For the purposes of this chapter (but not in any wise limiting the foregoing definition of interstate commerce) a transaction in respect to any article shall be considered to be in interstate commerce if such article is part of that current of commerce usual in the commodity trade whereby commodities and commodity products and by-products thereof are sent from one State, with the expectation that they will end their transit, after purchase, in another, including in addition to cases within the above general description, all cases where purchase or sale is either for shipment to another State, or for manufacture within the State and the shipment outside the State of the products resulting from such manufacture. Articles normally in such current of commerce shall not be considered out of such commerce through resort being had to any means or device intended to remove transactions in respect thereto from the provisions of this chapter. For the purpos</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements, contracts, and transactions in foreign currency, government securities, and certain other commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements, contracts, and transactions in foreign currency, government securities, and certain other commodities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Swaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Swaps Nothing in this chapter (other than subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (D), (G), and (H) of subsection (a)(1), subsections (f) and (g), sections 1a, 2(a)(13), 2(c)(2)(A)(ii), 2(e), 2(h), 6(c), 6a, 6b, and 6b–1 of this title, subsections (a), (b), and (g) of section 6c of this title, sections 6d, 6e, 6f, 6g, 6h, 6i, 6j, 6k, 6l, 6m, 6n, 6o, 6p, 6r, 6s, 6t, 7, 7a–1, 7a–2, 7b, and 7b–3 of this title, sections 9 and 13b of this title, sections 13a–1, 13a–2, 12, 12a, and 13 of this title, subsections (e)(2), (f), and (h) of section 16 of this title, subsections (a) and (b) of section 13c of this title, sections 21, 24, 24a, and 25(a)(4) of this title, and any other provision of this chapter that is applicable to registered entities or Commission registrants) governs or applies to a swap.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on participation It shall be unlawful for any person, other than an eligible contract participant, to enter into a swap unless the swap is entered into on, or subject to the rules of, a board of trade designated as a contract market under section 7 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for qualifying hybrid instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusion for qualifying hybrid instruments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of commodity futures laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of commodity futures laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clearing requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Clearing requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Applicability The provisions of this chapter relating to swaps that were enacted by the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010 (including any rule prescribed or regulation promulgated under that Act), shall not apply to activities outside the United States unless those activities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee approval by Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Committee approval by Board Exemptions from the requirements of subsection (h)(1) to clear a swap and subsection (h)(8) to execute a swap through a board of trade or swap execution facility shall be available to a counterparty that is an issuer of securities that are registered under section 12 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78l) or that is required to file reports pursuant to section 15(d) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (15 U.S.C. 78o[d]) only if an appropriate committee of the issuer’s board or governing body has reviewed and approved its decision to enter into swaps that are subject to such exemptions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>