<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2000" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2000/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2000/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000"><akn:num>2000</akn:num><akn:heading>Homestead protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000. Homestead protection(a) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.

(2) The term “borrower-owner” means—(A) a borrower of a loan made or insured by the Secretary or the Administrator who meets the eligibility requirements of subsection (c)(1); or

(B) in any case in which an owner of homestead property pledged the property to secure the loan and the owner is different than the borrower, the owner.


(3) The term “farm program loan” means any loan made by the Administrator under the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.) for any of the purposes authorized for loans under subchapters 11 So in original. Probably should be “subchapter”. I or II.

(4) The term “homestead property” means the principal residence and adjoining property possessed and occupied by a borrower-owner specified in paragraph (2) of this subsection, including a reasonable number of farm outbuildings located on the adjoining land that are useful to the occupants of the homestead, and no more than 10 acres of adjoining land that is used to maintain the family of the individual.

(5) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(b) Occupancy of homestead upon foreclosure, bankruptcy, or liquidation; appraisal; period of occupancy(1) The Secretary or the Administrator shall, on application by a borrower-owner who meets the eligibility requirements of subsection (c)(1), permit the borrower-owner to retain possession and occupancy of homestead property under the terms set forth, and until the action described in this section has been completed, if—(A) the Secretary forecloses, holds in inventory on January 6, 1988, or takes into inventory, property securing a loan made or insured under this chapter;

(B) the Administrator forecloses, holds in inventory on January 6, 1988, or takes into inventory, property securing a farm program loan made under the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.); or

(C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Occupancy of homestead upon foreclosure, bankruptcy, or liquidation; appraisal; period of occupancy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Occupancy of homestead upon foreclosure, bankruptcy, or liquidation; appraisal; period of occupancy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>First right of refusal of reacquisition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) First right of refusal of reacquisition At the end of the period of occupancy described in subsection (c), the Secretary or the Administrator shall grant to the borrower-owner a first right of refusal to reacquire the homestead property on such terms and conditions (which may include payment of principal in installments) as the Secretary or the Administrator shall determine. Such terms and conditions shall not be less favorable than those intended to be offered to any other buyer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value as measure of reacquisition payment of principal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Value as measure of reacquisition payment of principal At the time any reacquisition agreement is entered into, the Secretary or the Administrator may not demand a total payment of principal that is in excess of the value of the homestead property as established under subsection (b)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contract authority The Secretary may enter into contracts authorized by this section before the Secretary acquires title to the homestead property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict between Federal and State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conflict between Federal and State law In the event of any conflict between this section and any provision of the law of any State relating to the right of a borrower-owner to designate for separate sale or redeem part or all of the real property securing a loan foreclosed on by the lender thereof, such provision of State law shall prevail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>