<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2008v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2008v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2008v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2008v"><akn:num>2008v</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic economic and community development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2008v. Strategic economic and community development(a) In generalIn the case of any program under this chapter or administered by the Secretary, acting through the rural development mission area, as determined by the Secretary (referred to in this section as a “covered program”), the Secretary shall give priority to an application for a project that, as determined and approved by the Secretary—(1) meets the applicable eligibility requirements of this chapter or the other applicable authorizing law;

(2) will be carried out in a rural area; and

(3) supports the implementation of a strategic community investment plan described in subsection (d) on a multisectoral and multijurisdictional basis, to include considerations for improving and expanding broadband services as needed.


(b) Reserve(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall reserve not more than 15 percent of the funds made available for a fiscal year for covered programs for projects that support the implementation of a strategic community investment plan described in subsection (d) on a multisectoral and multijurisdictional basis.


(2) PeriodAny funds reserved under paragraph (1) shall only be reserved for the 1-year period beginning on the date on which the funds were first made available, as determined by the Secretary.



(c) Approved applications(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), any applicant who submitted an application under a covered program that was approved before the date of enactment of this section 11 See References in Text note below. may amend the application to qualify for the funds reserved under subsection (b).


(2) Rural utilitiesAny applicant who submitted an application under paragraph (2), (14), or (24) of section 1926(a) of this title, or section 1926a or 1932(b) of this title, that was approved by the Secretary before the date of enactment of this section 1 shall be eligible for the funds reserved under subsection (b)—(A) on the same basis as an application s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of any program under this chapter or administered by the Secretary, acting through the rural development mission area, as determined by the Secretary (referred to in this section as a “covered program”), the Secretary shall give priority to an application for a project that, as determined and approved by the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reserve</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approved applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2008v_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic community investment plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Strategic community investment plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>