<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009bb"><akn:num>2009bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009bb. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) AuthorityThe term “Authority” means the Northern Great Plains Regional Authority established by section 2009bb–1 of this title.


(2) Federal grant programThe term “Federal grant program” means a Federal grant program to provide assistance in—(A) implementing the recommendations of the Northern Great Plains Rural Development Commission established by the Northern Great Plains Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 2661 note; Public Law 103–318);

(B) acquiring or developing land;

(C) constructing or equipping a highway, road, bridge, or facility;

(D) carrying out other economic development activities; or

(E) conducting research activities related to the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).


(3) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.


(4) RegionThe term “region” means the States of Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri (other than counties included in the Delta Regional Authority), Nebraska, North Dakota, and South Dakota.


(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 383A, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title VI, § 6028, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 375; amended Pub. L. 110–234, title VI, § 6026(a), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1177; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VI, § 6026(a), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1939.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Amendments2008—Par. (4). Pub. L. 110–246, § 6026(a), inserted “Missouri (other than counties included in the Delta Regional Authority),” after “Minnesota,”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2008 AmendmentAmendment of this section and repeal of Pub. L. 110–234 by Pub. L. 110–246 effective May 22, 2008, the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–234, see section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246, set out as an Effective Date note under section 8701 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Authority The term “Authority” means the Northern Great Plains Regional Authority established by section 2009bb–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Federal grant program The term “Federal grant program” means a Federal grant program to provide assistance in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Region</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Region The term “region” means the States of Iowa, Minnesota, Missouri (other than counties included in the Delta Regional Authority), Nebraska, North Dakota, and South Dakota.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>