<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009d"><akn:num>2009d</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Development Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009d. Rural Development Trust Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund which shall be known as the Rural Development Trust Fund (in this subchapter referred to as the “Trust Fund”).


(b) AccountsThere are established in the Trust Fund the following accounts:(1) The rural community facilities account.

(2) The rural utilities account.

(3) The rural business and cooperative development account.

(4) The federally recognized Indian tribe account.


(c) Deposits into accountsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, each fiscal year—(1) all amounts made available to carry out the authorities described in subsection (d)(1) for the fiscal year shall be deposited into the rural community facilities account of the Trust Fund;

(2) all amounts made available to carry out the authorities described in subsection (d)(2) for the fiscal year shall be deposited into the rural utilities account of the Trust Fund; and

(3) all amounts made available to carry out the authorities described in subsection (d)(3) for the fiscal year shall be deposited into the rural business and cooperative development account of the Trust Fund.


(d) Function categoriesThe function categories described in this subsection are the following:(1) Rural community facilitiesThe rural community development category consists of all amounts made available for—(A) community facility direct and guaranteed loans under section 1926(a)(1) of this title; or

(B) community facility grants under paragraph (19), (20), or (21) of section 1926(a) of this title.


(2) Rural utilitiesThe rural utilities category consists of all amounts made available for—(A) water or waste disposal grants or direct or guaranteed loans under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1926(a) of this title;

(B) rural water or wastewater technical assistance and training grants under section 1926(a)(14) of this title;

(C) emergency community water assistance grants under section 1926a of this tit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States a trust fund which shall be known as the Rural Development Trust Fund (in this subchapter referred to as the “Trust Fund”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accounts There are established in the Trust Fund the following accounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits into accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deposits into accounts Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Function categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Function categories The function categories described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally recognized Indian tribe account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federally recognized Indian tribe account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation among States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation among States The Secretary shall allocate the amounts in each account specified in subsection (c) among the States in a fair, reasonable, and appropriate manner that takes into consideration rural population, levels of income, unemployment, and other relevant factors, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds allocated for States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability of funds allocated for States The Secretary shall make available to each State the total amount allocated for the State under subsection (f) that remains after applying section 2009f of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>