<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009f"><akn:num>2009f</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009f. Grants to States(a) Simple grants(1) Mandatory grantThe Secretary shall make a grant to any eligible State for any fiscal year for which the State requests a grant under this section in an amount equal to 5 percent of the total amount allocated for the State under section 2009d(f) of this title.


(2) Permissive grantBefore July 15 of each fiscal year, the Secretary may make a grant to any State to defray the cost of any subsidy associated with a guarantee provided by an eligible public entity of the State under section 2009g of this title in an amount that does not exceed 5 percent of the total amount allocated for the State under section 2009d(f) of this title.


(3) Source of fundsThe Secretary shall make grants to a State under paragraphs (1) and (2) from amounts allocated for the State in the accounts specified in section 2009d(c) of this title, by reducing each such allocated amount by the same percentage.



(b) Matching grants(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall make a grant to any eligible State for any fiscal year for which the State requests a grant under this section in an amount equal to 5 percent of the amount allocated for the State for the fiscal year under section 2009d(g) of this title.


(2) EligibilityA State shall be eligible for a grant under paragraph (1) if the State makes commitments to the Secretary to—(A) expend from non-Federal sources in accordance with subsection (c) an amount that is not less than 200 percent of the amount of the grant; and

(B) maintain the amounts paid to the State under this subsection and the amount referred to in subparagraph (A) in an account separate from all other State funds until expended in accordance with subsection (c).


(3) Source of fundsIf the Secretary makes a grant under paragraph (1) before July 15 of the fiscal year, the grant shall be made from amounts allocated for the State in the accounts specified in section 2009d(c) of this title for the fiscal year, by reducin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Simple grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Simple grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matching grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds A State to which funds are provided under this section shall use the funds in rural areas for any activity authorized under the authorities described in section 2009d(d) of this title in accordance with the State strategic plan referred to in section 2009c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maintenance of effort The State shall provide assurances to the Secretary that funds provided to the State under this section will be used only to supplement, not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds otherwise expended for rural development assistance in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appeals The Secretary shall provide to a State an opportunity to appeal any action taken with respect to the State under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs Federal funds shall not be used for any administrative costs incurred by a State in carrying out this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure of funds by State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Expenditure of funds by State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No entitlement to contract, grant, or assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No entitlement to contract, grant, or assistance Nothing in this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>