<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009bb_8"><akn:num>2009bb–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of development plans and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009bb–8. Approval of development plans and projects(a) In generalA State or regional development plan or any multistate subregional plan that is proposed for development under this subchapter shall be reviewed by the Authority.


(b) Evaluation by State memberAn application for a grant or any other assistance for a project under this subchapter shall be made through and evaluated for approval by the State member of the Authority representing the applicant.


(c) CertificationAn application for a grant or other assistance for a project shall be approved only on certification by the State member that the application for the project—(1) describes ways in which the project complies with any applicable State development plan;

(2) meets applicable criteria under section 2009bb–7 of this title;

(3) provides adequate assurance that the proposed project will be properly administered, operated, and maintained; and

(4) otherwise meets the requirements of this subchapter.


(d) Votes for decisionsOn certification by a State member of the Authority of an application for a grant or other assistance for a specific project under this section, an affirmative vote of the Authority under section 2009bb–1(c) of this title shall be required for approval of the application.


(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 383J, formerly § 383I, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title VI, § 6028, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 386; renumbered § 383J and amended Pub. L. 110–234, title VI, § 6026(c)(1)(A), (2)(E), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1178, 1179, and Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VI, § 6026(c)(1)(A), (2)(E), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1940, 1941.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 383J of Pub. L. 87–128, title III, was renumbered section 383K and is classified to section 2009bb–9 of this title.

Amendments2008—Subsec. (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State or regional development plan or any multistate subregional plan that is proposed for development under this subchapter shall be reviewed by the Authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation by State member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation by State member An application for a grant or any other assistance for a project under this subchapter shall be made through and evaluated for approval by the State member of the Authority representing the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification An application for a grant or other assistance for a project shall be approved only on certification by the State member that the application for the project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Votes for decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Votes for decisions On certification by a State member of the Authority of an application for a grant or other assistance for a specific project under this section, an affirmative vote of the Authority under section 2009bb–1(c) of this title shall be required for approval of the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>