<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009bb_4"><akn:num>2009bb–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Multistate and local development districts and organizations and Northern Great Plains Inc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009bb–4. Multistate and local development districts and organizations and Northern Great Plains Inc.(a) Definition of multistate and local development district or organizationIn this section, the term “multistate and local development district or organization” means an entity—(1) that—(A) is a planning district in existence on May 13, 2002, that is recognized by the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce; or

(B) is—(i) organized and operated in a manner that ensures broad-based community participation and an effective opportunity for other nonprofit groups to contribute to the development and implementation of programs in the region;

(ii) a nonprofit incorporated body organized or chartered under the law of the State in which the entity is located;

(iii) a nonprofit agency or instrumentality of a State or local government;

(iv) a public organization established before May 13, 2002, under State law for creation of multijurisdictional, area-wide planning organizations;

(v) a nonprofit agency or instrumentality of a State that was established for the purpose of assisting with multistate cooperation; or

(vi) a nonprofit association or combination of bodies, agencies, and instrumentalities described in clauses (ii) through (v); and



(2) that has not, as certified by the Authority (in consultation with the Federal cochairperson or Secretary, as appropriate)—(A) inappropriately used Federal grant funds from any Federal source; or

(B) appointed an officer who, during the period in which another entity inappropriately used Federal grant funds from any Federal source, was an officer of the other entity.



(b) Grants to multistate, local, or regional development districts and organizations(1) In generalThe Authority may make grants for administrative expenses under this section to multistate, local, and regional development districts and organizations.


(2) Conditions for grants(A) Maximum amountThe amount of any grant awarded under par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of multistate and local development district or organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of multistate and local development district or organization In this section, the term “multistate and local development district or organization” means an entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to multistate, local, or regional development districts and organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants to multistate, local, or regional development districts and organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Northern Great Plains Inc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Northern Great Plains Inc. Northern Great Plains Inc., a nonprofit corporation incorporated in the State of Minnesota to implement the recommendations of the Northern Great Plains Rural Development Commission established by the Northern Great Plains Rural Development Act (7 U.S.C. 2661 note; Public Law 103–318)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>