<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2009bb–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2009bb_5"><akn:num>2009bb–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Distressed counties and areas and nondistressed counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2009bb–5. Distressed counties and areas and nondistressed counties(a) DesignationsNot later than 90 days after May 13, 2002, and annually thereafter, the Authority, in accordance with such criteria as the Authority may establish, shall designate—(1) as distressed counties, counties in the region that are the most severely and persistently distressed and underdeveloped and have high rates of poverty, unemployment, or outmigration;

(2) as nondistressed counties, counties in the region that are not designated as distressed counties under paragraph (1); and

(3) as isolated areas of distress, areas located in nondistressed counties (as designated under paragraph (2)) that have high rates of poverty, unemployment, or outmigration.


(b) Distressed counties(1) In generalThe Authority shall allocate at least 50 percent of the appropriations made available under section 2009bb–12 of this title for programs and projects designed to serve the needs of distressed counties and isolated areas of distress in the region.


(2) Funding limitationsThe funding limitations under section 2009bb–3(b) of this title shall not apply to a project to provide transportation or telecommunication or basic public services to residents of 1 or more distressed counties or isolated areas of distress in the region.



(c) Transportation, telecommunication, renewable energy, and basic public infrastructureThe Authority shall allocate at least 50 percent of any funds made available under section 2009bb–12 of this title for transportation, telecommunication, renewable energy, and basic public infrastructure projects authorized under paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 2009bb–2(a) of this title.


(Pub. L. 87–128, title III, § 383G, formerly § 383F, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title VI, § 6028, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 384; renumbered § 383G and amended Pub. L. 110–234, title VI, § 6026(c)(1)(A), (2)(D), (g), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1178, 1179, 1181, and Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VI, § 6026(c)(1)(A),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designations Not later than 90 days after May 13, 2002, and annually thereafter, the Authority, in accordance with such criteria as the Authority may establish, shall designate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distressed counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distressed counties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2009bb_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation, telecommunication, renewable energy, and basic public infrastructure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transportation, telecommunication, renewable energy, and basic public infrastructure The Authority shall allocate at least 50 percent of any funds made available under section 2009bb–12 of this title for transportation, telecommunication, renewable energy, and basic public infrastructure projects authorized under paragraphs (1) and (3) of section 2009bb–2(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>