<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2012" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2012/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2012/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2012"><akn:num>2012</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2012. Definitions
As used in this chapter, the term:(a) “Access device” means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access, including point of sale devices, that can be used, alone or in conjunction with another access device, to obtain payments, allotments, benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or that can be used to initiate a transfer of funds under this chapter.

(b) “Allotment” means the total value of benefits a household is authorized to receive during each month.

(c) “Allowable medical expenses” means expenditures for (1) medical and dental care, (2) hospitalization or nursing care (including hospitalization or nursing care of an individual who was a household member immediately prior to entering a hospital or nursing home), (3) prescription drugs when prescribed by a licensed practitioner authorized under State law and over-the-counter medication (including insulin) when approved by a licensed practitioner or other qualified health professional, (4) health and hospitalization insurance policies (excluding the costs of health and accident or income maintenance policies), (5) medicare premiums related to coverage under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.], (6) dentures, hearing aids, and prosthetics (including the costs of securing and maintaining a seeing eye dog), (7) eye glasses prescribed by a physician skilled in eye disease or by an optometrist, (8) reasonable costs of transportation necessary to secure medical treatment or services, and (9) maintaining an attendant, homemaker, home health aide, housekeeper, or child care services due to age, infirmity, or illness.

(d) Benefit.—The term “benefit” means the value of supplemental nutrition assistance provided to a household by means of—(1) an electronic benefit transfer under section 2016(h) of this title; or

(2) other means of providing assistance, as determined by the Secretary.


(e) Benefit Issuer.—The term “benefit issuer” means any offic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Access device” means any card, plate, code, account number, or other means of access, including point of sale devices, that can be used, alone or in conjunction with another access device, to obtain payments, allotments, benefits, money, goods, or other things of value, or that can be used to initiate a transfer of funds under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Allotment” means the total value of benefits a household is authorized to receive during each month.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Allowable medical expenses” means expenditures for (1) medical and dental care, (2) hospitalization or nursing care (including hospitalization or nursing care of an individual who was a household member immediately prior to entering a hospital or nursing home), (3) prescription drugs when prescribed by a licensed practitioner authorized under State law and over-the-counter medication (including insulin) when approved by a licensed practitioner or other qualified health professional, (4) health and hospitalization insurance policies (excluding the costs of health and accident or income maintenance policies), (5) medicare premiums related to coverage under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.], (6) dentures, hearing aids, and prosthetics (including the costs of securing and maintaining a seeing eye dog), (7) eye glasses prescribed by a physician skilled in eye disease or by an optometrist, (8) reasonable costs of transportation necessary to secure medical t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “benefit” means the value of supplemental nutrition assistance provided to a household by means of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit Issuer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “benefit issuer” means any office of the State agency or any person, partnership, corporation, organization, political subdivision, or other entity with which a State agency has contracted for, or to which it has delegated functional responsibility in connection with, the issuance of benefits to households.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Certification period” means the period for which households shall be eligible to receive benefits. The certification period shall not exceed 12 months, except that the certification period may be up to 24 months if all adult household members are elderly or disabled. A State agency shall have at least 1 contact with each certified household every 12 months. The limits specified in this subsection may be extended until the end of any transitional benefit period established under section 2020(s) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Coupon” means any coupon, stamp, type of certificate, authorization card, cash or check issued in lieu of a coupon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Drug addiction or alcoholic treatment and rehabilitation program” means any such program conducted by a private nonprofit organization or institution, or a publicly operated community mental health center, under part B of title XIX of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 300x et seq.) to provide treatment that can lead to the rehabilitation of drug addicts or alcoholics.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>EBT Card.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) EBT The term “EBT card” means an electronic benefit transfer card issued under section 2016(h) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) “Elderly or disabled member” means a member of a household who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>