<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2014" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2014/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2014/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2014"><akn:num>2014</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible households</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2014. Eligible households(a) Income and other financial resources as substantial limiting factors in obtaining more nutritious diet; recipients under Social Security ActParticipation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program shall be limited to those households whose incomes and other financial resources, held singly or in joint ownership, are determined to be a substantial limiting factor in permitting them to obtain a more nutritious diet. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter except subsections (b), (d)(2), (g), and (r) of section 2015 of this title and section 2012(m)(4) of this title, households in which each member receives benefits under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.], or aid to the aged, blind, or disabled under title I, X, XIV, or XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq., 1201 et seq., 1351 et seq., or 1381 et seq.], shall be eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program. Except for sections 2015, 2025(e)(1), and section 2012(m)(4) of this title, households in which each member receives benefits under a State or local general assistance program that complies with standards established by the Secretary for ensuring that the program is based on income criteria comparable to or more restrictive than those under subsection (c)(2), and not limited to one-time emergency payments that cannot be provided for more than one consecutive month, shall be eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program. Assistance under this program shall be furnished to all eligible households who make application for such participation.


(b) Eligibility standardsExcept as otherwise provided in this chapter, the Secretary shall establish uniform national standards of eligibility (other than the income standards for Alaska, Haw</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income and other financial resources as substantial limiting factors in obtaining more nutritious diet; recipients under Social Security Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Income and other financial resources as substantial limiting factors in obtaining more nutritious diet; recipients under Social Security Act Participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program shall be limited to those households whose incomes and other financial resources, held singly or in joint ownership, are determined to be a substantial limiting factor in permitting them to obtain a more nutritious diet. Notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter except subsections (b), (d)(2), (g), and (r) of section 2015 of this title and section 2012(m)(4) of this title, households in which each member receives benefits under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.], or aid to the aged, blind, or disabled under title I, X, XIV, or XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq., 1201 et seq., 1351 et </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility standards Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, the Secretary shall establish uniform national standards of eligibility (other than the income standards for Alaska, Hawaii, Guam, and the Virgin Islands of the United States established in accordance with subsections (c) and (e) of this section) for participation by households in the supplemental nutrition assistance program in accordance with the provisions of this section. No plan of operation submitted by a State agency shall be approved unless the standards of eligibility meet those established by the Secretary, and no State agency shall impose any other standards of eligibility as a condition for participating in the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross income standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Gross income standard The income standards of eligibility shall be adjusted each October 1 and shall provide that a household shall be ineligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program if— In no event shall the standards of eligibility for the Virgin Islands of the United States or Guam exceed those in the forty-eight contiguous States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions from income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusions from income Household income for purposes of the supplemental nutrition assistance program shall include all income from whatever source excluding only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions from income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deductions from income</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of household income; prospective or retrospective accounting basis; consistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Calculation of household income; prospective or retrospective accounting basis; consistency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable financial resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Allowable financial resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary emergency standards of eligibility; Disaster Task Force; direct assistance to State and local officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Temporary emergency standards of eligibility; Disaster Task Force; direct assistance to State and local officials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attribution of income and resources to sponsored aliens; coverage, computations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Attribution of income and resources to sponsored aliens; coverage, computations, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2014_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource exemption for otherwise exempt households</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Resource exemption for otherwise exempt households Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (i), a State agency shall consider a household member who receives supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.], aid to the aged, blind, or disabled under title I, II, X, XIV, or XVI of such Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq., 401 et seq., 1201 et seq., 1351 et seq., 1381 et seq.], or who receives benefits under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) to have satisfied the resource limitations prescribed under subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>