<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2015" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2015/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2015/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2015"><akn:num>2015</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility disqualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2015. Eligibility disqualifications(a) Additional specific conditions rendering individuals ineligibleIn addition to meeting the standards of eligibility prescribed in section 2014 of this title, households and individuals who are members of eligible households must also meet and comply with the specific requirements of this section to be eligible for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.


(b) Fraud and misrepresentation; disqualification penalties; ineligibility period; applicable procedures(1) Any person who has been found by any State or Federal court or administrative agency to have intentionally (A) made a false or misleading statement, or misrepresented, concealed or withheld facts, or (B) committed any act that constitutes a violation of this chapter, the regulations issued thereunder, or any State statute, for the purpose of using, presenting, transferring, acquiring, receiving, or possessing program benefits shall, immediately upon the rendering of such determination, become ineligible for further participation in the program—(i) for a period of 1 year upon the first occasion of any such determination;

(ii) for a period of 2 years upon—(I) the second occasion of any such determination; or

(II) the first occasion of a finding by a Federal, State, or local court of the trading of a controlled substance (as defined in section 802 of title 21) for benefits; and


(iii) permanently upon—(I) the third occasion of any such determination;

(II) the second occasion of a finding by a Federal, State, or local court of the trading of a controlled substance (as defined in section 802 of title 21) for benefits;

(III) the first occasion of a finding by a Federal, State, or local court of the trading of firearms, ammunition, or explosives for benefits; or

(IV) a conviction of an offense under subsection (b) or (c) of section 2024 of this title involving an item covered by subsection (b) or (c) of section 2024 of this title having a value of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional specific conditions rendering individuals ineligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Additional specific conditions rendering individuals ineligible In addition to meeting the standards of eligibility prescribed in section 2014 of this title, households and individuals who are members of eligible households must also meet and comply with the specific requirements of this section to be eligible for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fraud and misrepresentation; disqualification penalties; ineligibility period; applicable procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fraud and misrepresentation; disqualification penalties; ineligibility period; applicable procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal to provide necessary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Refusal to provide necessary information Except in a case in which a household is receiving transitional benefits during the transitional benefits period under section 2020(s) of this title, no household shall be eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program if it refuses to cooperate in providing information to the State agency that is necessary for making a determination of its eligibility or for completing any subsequent review of its eligibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions of participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Students No individual who is a member of a household otherwise eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program under this section shall be eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program as a member of that or any other household if the individual is enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education, unless the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Aliens No individual who is a member of a household otherwise eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program under this section shall be eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program as a member of that or any other household unless he or she is— The income (less, at State option, a pro rata share) and financial resources of the individual rendered ineligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program under this subsection shall be considered in determining the eligibility and the value of the allotment of the household of which such individual is a member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Residents of States which provide State supplementary payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Residents of States which provide State supplementary payments No individual who receives supplemental security income benefits under title XVI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.], State supplementary payments described in section 1616 of such Act [42 U.S.C. 1382e], or payments of the type referred to in section 212(a) of Public Law 93–66, as amended, shall be considered to be a member of a household for any month, if, for such month, such individual resides in a State which provides State supplementary payments (1) of the type described in section 1616(a) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1382e(a)] and section 212(a) of Public Law 93–66, and (2) the level of which has been found by the Commissioner of Social Security to have been specifically increased so as to include the bonus value of food stamps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of assets to qualify</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transfer of assets to qualify No household that knowingly transfers assets for the purpose of qualifying or attempting to qualify for the supplemental nutrition assistance program shall be eligible to participate in the program for a period of up to one year from the date of discovery of the transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparable treatment for disqualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Comparable treatment for disqualification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification for receipt of multiple benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Disqualification for receipt of multiple benefits An individual shall be ineligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program as a member of any household for a 10-year period if the individual is found by a State agency to have made, or is convicted in a Federal or State court of having made, a fraudulent statement or representation with respect to the identity or place of residence of the individual in order to receive multiple benefits simultaneously under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>