<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2016" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2016/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2016/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2016"><akn:num>2016</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance and use of program benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2016. Issuance and use of program benefits(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (i), EBT cards shall be issued only to households which have been duly certified as eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.


(b) UseBenefits issued to eligible households shall be used by them only to purchase food from retail food stores which have been approved for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program at prices prevailing in such stores: Provided, That nothing in this chapter shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to specify the prices at which food may be sold by wholesale food concerns or retail food stores.


(c) Design(1) In generalEBT cards issued to eligible households shall be simple in design and shall include only such words or illustrations as are required to explain their purpose.


(2) ProhibitionThe name of any public official shall not appear on any EBT card.



(d) Delivery and control proceduresThe Secretary shall prescribe appropriate procedures for the delivery of benefits to benefit issuers and for the subsequent controls to be placed over such benefits by benefit issuers in order to ensure adequate accountability.


(e) State issuance liabilityNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the State agency shall be strictly liable to the Secretary for any financial losses involved in the acceptance, storage and issuance of benefits, except that in the case of losses resulting from the issuance and replacement of authorizations for benefits which are sent through the mail, the State agency shall be liable to the Secretary to the extent prescribed in the regulations promulgated by the Secretary.


(f) Alternative benefit delivery(1) In generalIf the Secretary determines, in consultation with the Inspector General of the Department of Agriculture, that it would improve the integrity of the supplemental nutrition assistance program, the Secretary shall require a State agency to issue </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (i), EBT cards shall be issued only to households which have been duly certified as eligible to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use Benefits issued to eligible households shall be used by them only to purchase food from retail food stores which have been approved for participation in the supplemental nutrition assistance program at prices prevailing in such stores: Provided, That nothing in this chapter shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to specify the prices at which food may be sold by wholesale food concerns or retail food stores.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Design</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery and control procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delivery and control procedures The Secretary shall prescribe appropriate procedures for the delivery of benefits to benefit issuers and for the subsequent controls to be placed over such benefits by benefit issuers in order to ensure adequate accountability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State issuance liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State issuance liability Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the State agency shall be strictly liable to the Secretary for any financial losses involved in the acceptance, storage and issuance of benefits, except that in the case of losses resulting from the issuance and replacement of authorizations for benefits which are sent through the mail, the State agency shall be liable to the Secretary to the extent prescribed in the regulations promulgated by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative benefit delivery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Alternative benefit delivery</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staggered issuance procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Staggered issuance procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic benefit transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Electronic benefit transfers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>State option to issue benefits to certain individuals made ineligible by welfare reform</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) State option to issue benefits to certain individuals made ineligible by welfare reform</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2016_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interoperability and portability of electronic benefit transfer transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Interoperability and portability of electronic benefit transfer transactions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>