<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2026" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2026/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2026/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2026"><akn:num>2026</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, demonstration, and evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2026. Research, demonstration, and evaluations(a) Contracts or grants; issuance of aggregate allotments(1) The Secretary may enter into contracts with or make grants to public or private organizations or agencies under this section to undertake research that will help improve the administration and effectiveness of the supplemental nutrition assistance program in delivering nutrition-related benefits. The waiver authority of the Secretary under subsection (b) shall extend to all contracts and grants under this section.

(2) The Secretary may, on application, permit not more than two State agencies to establish procedures that allow households whose monthly supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits do not exceed $20, at their option, to receive, in lieu of their supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits for the initial period under section 2017 of this title and their regular allotment in following months, and at intervals of up to 3 months thereafter, aggregate allotments not to exceed $60 and covering not more than 3 months’ benefits. The allotments shall be provided in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (9) of section 2020(e) of this title (except that no household shall begin to receive combined allotments under this section until it has complied with all applicable verification requirements of section 2020(e)(3) of this title) and (with respect to the first aggregate allotment so issued) within 40 days of the last benefit issuance.


(b) Pilot projects(1)(A) The Secretary may conduct on a trial basis, in one or more areas of the United States, pilot or experimental projects designed to test program changes that might increase the efficiency of the supplemental nutrition assistance program and improve the delivery of supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits to eligible households, and may waive any requirement of this chapter to the extent necessary for the project to be conducted.

(B) Project requirements.—(i) Program goal.—The Sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts or grants; issuance of aggregate allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts or grants; issuance of aggregate allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pilot projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation measures; pilot programs for nutritional monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Evaluation measures; pilot programs for nutritional monitoring The Secretary shall develop and implement measures for evaluating, on an annual or more frequent basis, the effectiveness of the supplemental nutrition assistance program in achieving its stated objectives, including, but not limited to, the program’s impact upon the nutritional and economic status of participating households, the program’s impact upon all sectors of the agricultural economy, including farmers and ranchers, as well as retail food stores, and the program’s relative fairness to households of different income levels, different age composition, different size, and different regions of residence. Further, the Secretary shall, by way of making contracts with or grants to public or private organizations or agencies, implement pilot programs to test various means of measuring on a continuing basis the nutritional status of low income people, with special emphasis on people who are eligible for supplemental nutr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment initiatives program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Employment initiatives program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report to Congressional committees of effect of reduction of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Study and report to Congressional committees of effect of reduction of benefits The Secretary shall conduct a study of the effects of reductions made in benefits provided under this chapter pursuant to part 1 of subtitle A of title I of the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981, the Food Stamp and Commodity Distribution Amendments of 1981, the Food Stamp Act Amendments of 1982, and any other laws enacted by the Ninety-seventh Congress which affect the supplemental nutrition assistance program. The study shall include a study of the effect of retrospective accounting and periodic reporting procedures established under such Acts, including the impact on benefit and administrative costs and on error rates and the degree to which eligible households are denied supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits for failure to file complete periodic reports. The Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects for development and use of intelligent benefit cards to pay benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Demonstration projects for development and use of intelligent benefit cards to pay benefits In order to encourage States to plan, design, develop, and implement a system for making supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits available through the use of intelligent benefit cards or other automated or electronic benefit delivery systems, the Secretary may conduct one or more pilot or experimental projects, subject to the restrictions imposed by subsection (b)(1) and section 2016(f)(2) of this title, designed to test whether the use of such cards or systems can enhance the efficiency and effectiveness of program operations while ensuring that individuals receive correct benefit amounts on a timely basis. Intelligent benefit cards developed under such a demonstration project shall contain information, encoded on a computer chip embedded in a credit card medium, including the eligibility of the individual and the amount of benefits to which such individual is entitled. Any other</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of effectiveness of employment and training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study of effectiveness of employment and training programs In order to assess the effectiveness of the employment and training programs established under section 2015(d) of this title in placing individuals into the work force and withdrawing such individuals from the supplemental nutrition assistance program, the Secretary is authorized to carry out studies comparing the pre- and post-program labor force participation, wage rates, family income, level of receipt of supplemental nutrition assistance program and other transfer payments, and other relevant information, for samples of participants in such employment and training programs as compared to the appropriate control or comparison groups that did not participate in such programs. Such studies shall, to the maximum extent possible— The results of such studies and reports shall be considered in developing or updating the performance standards required under section 2015 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects for vehicle exclusion limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Demonstration projects for vehicle exclusion limits The Secretary shall conduct a sufficient number of demonstration projects to evaluate the effects, in both rural and urban areas, of including in financial resources under section 2014(g) of this title the fair market value of licensed vehicles to the extent the value of each vehicle exceeds $4,500, but excluding the value of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing resource accumulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Testing resource accumulation The Secretary shall conduct, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary shall prescribe, for a period not to exceed 4 years, projects to test allowing not more than 11,000 eligible households, in the aggregate, to accumulate resources up to $10,000 each (which shall be excluded from consideration as a resource) for later expenditure for a purpose directly related to improving the education, training, or employability (including self-employment) of household members, for the purchase of a home for the household, for a change of the household’s residence, or for making major repairs to the household’s home.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2026_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects directed at benefit trafficking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Demonstration projects directed at benefit trafficking The Secretary shall use up to $4,000,000 of the funds provided in advance in appropriations Acts for projects authorized by this section to conduct demonstration projects in which State or local supplemental nutrition assistance program agencies test innovative ideas for working with State or local law enforcement agencies to investigate and prosecute benefit trafficking.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>