<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2029" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2029/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2029/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2029"><akn:num>2029</akn:num><akn:heading>Workfare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2029. Workfare(a) Program plan; guidelines; compliance(1) The Secretary shall permit any political subdivision, in any State, that applies and submits a plan to the Secretary in compliance with guidelines promulgated by the Secretary to operate a workfare program pursuant to which every member of a household participating in the supplemental nutrition assistance program who is not exempt by virtue of the provisions of subsection (b) of this section shall accept an offer from such subdivision to perform work on its behalf, or may seek an offer to perform work, in return for compensation consisting of the allotment to which the household is entitled under section 2017(a) of this title, with each hour of such work entitling that household to a portion of its allotment equal in value to 100 per centum of the higher of the applicable State minimum wage or the Federal minimum hourly rate under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 [29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.].

(2)(A) The Secretary shall promulgate guidelines pursuant to paragraph (1) which, to the maximum extent practicable, enable a political subdivision to design and operate a workfare program under this section which is compatible and consistent with similar workfare programs operated by the subdivision.

(B) A political subdivision may comply with the requirements of this section by operating any workfare program which the Secretary determines meets the provisions and protections provided under this section.



(b) Exempt household membersA household member shall be exempt from workfare requirements imposed under this section if such member is—(1) exempt from section 2015(d)(1) of this title as the result of clause (B), (C), (D), (E), or (F) of section 2015(d)(2) of this title;

(2) at the option of the operating agency, subject to and currently actively and satisfactorily participating at least 20 hours a week in a work activity required under title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.);

(3) mentally or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program plan; guidelines; compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program plan; guidelines; compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exempt household members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exempt household members A household member shall be exempt from workfare requirements imposed under this section if such member is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Valuation or duration of work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Valuation or duration of work No operating agency shall require any participating member to work in any workfare position to the extent that such work exceeds in value the allotment to which the household is otherwise entitled or that such work, when added to any other hours worked during such week by such member for compensation (in cash or in kind) in any other capacity, exceeds thirty hours a week.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nature, conditions, and costs of work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nature, conditions, and costs of work The operating agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Job search period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Job search period The operating agency may allow a job search period, prior to making workfare assignments, of up to thirty days following a determination of eligibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disqualification An individual or a household may become ineligible under section 2015(d)(1) of this title to participate in the supplemental nutrition assistance program for failing to comply with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2029_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of administrative expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>