<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2035" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2035/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2035/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2035"><akn:num>2035</akn:num><akn:heading>Simplified supplemental nutrition assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2035. Simplified supplemental nutrition assistance program(a) “Federal costs” definedIn this section, the term “Federal costs” does not include any Federal costs incurred under section 2026 of this title.


(b) ElectionSubject to subsection (d), a State may elect to carry out a simplified supplemental nutrition assistance program (referred to in this section as a “Program”), statewide or in a political subdivision of the State, in accordance with this section.


(c) Operation of ProgramIf a State elects to carry out a Program, within the State or a political subdivision of the State—(1) a household in which no members receive assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) may not participate in the Program;

(2) a household in which all members receive assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) shall automatically be eligible to participate in the Program;

(3) if approved by the Secretary, a household in which 1 or more members but not all members receive assistance under a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) may be eligible to participate in the Program; and

(4) subject to subsection (f), benefits under the Program shall be determined under rules and procedures established by the State under—(A) a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.);

(B) the supplemental nutrition assistance program; or

(C) a combination of a State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.) and the supplemental nutrition assistance program.



(d) Approval of Program(1) State planA State agency may not operate a Program unless the Secretary approves a State plan for the operation of the Program under paragraph (2).


(2) Approval of planThe Secretary shall approve any State plan to carr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Federal costs” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Federal costs” defined In this section, the term “Federal costs” does not include any Federal costs incurred under section 2026 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election Subject to subsection (d), a State may elect to carry out a simplified supplemental nutrition assistance program (referred to in this section as a “Program”), statewide or in a political subdivision of the State, in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation of Program If a State elects to carry out a Program, within the State or a political subdivision of the State—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Approval of Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased Federal costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Increased Federal costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2035_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>