<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2036c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2036c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2036c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2036c"><akn:num>2036c</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual State report on verification of SNAP participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2036c. Annual State report on verification of SNAP participation(a) Annual reportNot later than 1 year after the date specified by the Secretary during the 180-day period beginning on February 7, 2014, and annually thereafter, each State agency that carries out the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.) shall submit to the Secretary a report containing sufficient information for the Secretary to determine whether the State agency has, for the most recently concluded fiscal year preceding that annual date, verified that the State agency in that fiscal year—(1) did not issue benefits to a deceased individual; and

(2) did not issue benefits to an individual who had been permanently disqualified from receiving benefits.


(b) Penalty for noncomplianceFor any fiscal year for which a State agency fails to comply with subsection (a), the Secretary shall impose a penalty that includes a reduction of up to 50 percent of the amount that would be otherwise payable to the State agency under section 16(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2025(a)) with respect to that fiscal year.


(c) Report of pilot program to test prevention of duplicate participationNot later than 90 days after the completion in multiple States of a temporary pilot program to test the detection and prevention of duplicate participation by beneficiaries of the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report assessing the feasibility, effectiveness, and cost for the expansion of the pilot program nationwide.


(Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4032, Feb. 7, 2014, 128 Stat. 817.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, referred to in subsecs. (a) an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2036c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report Not later than 1 year after the date specified by the Secretary during the 180-day period beginning on February 7, 2014, and annually thereafter, each State agency that carries out the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.) shall submit to the Secretary a report containing sufficient information for the Secretary to determine whether the State agency has, for the most recently concluded fiscal year preceding that annual date, verified that the State agency in that fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2036c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalty for noncompliance For any fiscal year for which a State agency fails to comply with subsection (a), the Secretary shall impose a penalty that includes a reduction of up to 50 percent of the amount that would be otherwise payable to the State agency under section 16(a) of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2025(a)) with respect to that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2036c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of pilot program to test prevention of duplicate participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report of pilot program to test prevention of duplicate participation Not later than 90 days after the completion in multiple States of a temporary pilot program to test the detection and prevention of duplicate participation by beneficiaries of the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report assessing the feasibility, effectiveness, and cost for the expansion of the pilot program nationwide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>