<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_21"><akn:num>21</akn:num><akn:heading>Registered futures associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 21. Registered futures associations(a) Registration statementAny association of persons may be registered with the Commission as a registered futures association pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, under the terms and conditions hereinafter provided in this section, by filing with the Commission for review and approval a registration statement in such form as the Commission may prescribe, setting forth the information, and accompanied by the documents, below specified:(1) Data as to its organization, membership, and rules of procedure, and such other information as the Commission may by rules and regulations require as necessary or appropriate in the public interest; and

(2) Copies of its constitution, charter, or articles of incorporation or association, with all amendments thereto, and of its bylaws, and of any rules or instruments corresponding to the foregoing, whatever the name, hereinafter in this section collectively referred to as the “rules of the association”.


(b) Standards for registration; Commission findingsAn applicant association shall not be registered as a futures association unless the Commission finds, under standards established by the Commission, that—(1) such association is in the public interest and that it will be able to comply with the provisions of this section and the rules and regulations thereunder and to carry out the purposes of this section;

(2) the rules of the association provide that any person registered under this chapter, registered entity, or any other person designated pursuant to the rules of the Commission as eligible for membership may become a member of such association, except such as are excluded pursuant to paragraph (3) or (4) of this subsection, or a rule of the association permitted under this subparagraph. The rules of the association may restrict membership in such association on such specified basis relating to the type of business done by its members, or on such other specified and appropriate basi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration statement Any association of persons may be registered with the Commission as a registered futures association pursuant to subsection (b) of this section, under the terms and conditions hereinafter provided in this section, by filing with the Commission for review and approval a registration statement in such form as the Commission may prescribe, setting forth the information, and accompanied by the documents, below specified:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for registration; Commission findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards for registration; Commission findings An applicant association shall not be registered as a futures association unless the Commission finds, under standards established by the Commission, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Suspension of registration The Commission may, after notice and opportunity for hearing, suspend the registration of any futures association if it finds that the rules thereof do not conform to the requirements of the Commission, and any such suspension shall remain in effect until the Commission issues an order determining that such rules have been modified to conform with such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fees and charges In addition to the fees and charges authorized by section 12a(1) of this title, each person registered under this chapter, who is not a member of a futures association registered pursuant to this section, shall pay to the Commission such reasonable fees and charges as may be necessary to defray the costs of additional regulatory duties required to be performed by the Commission because such person is not a member of a registered futures association. The Commission shall establish such additional fees and charges by rules and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registered persons not members of registered associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Registered persons not members of registered associations Any person registered under this chapter, who is not a member of a futures association registered pursuant to this section, in addition to the other requirements and obligations of this chapter and the regulations thereunder shall be subject to such other rules and regulations as the Commission may find necessary to protect the public interest and promote just and equitable principles of trade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Denial of registration Upon filing of an application for registration pursuant to subsection (a), the Commission may by order grant such registration if the requirements of this section are satisfied. If, after appropriate notice and opportunity for hearing, it appears to the Commission that any requirement of this section is not satisfied, the Commission shall by order deny such registration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal from registration; notice of with­drawal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Withdrawal from registration; notice of with­drawal A registered futures association may, upon such reasonable notice as the Commission may deem necessary in the public interest, withdraw from registration by filing with the Commission a written notice of withdrawal in such form as the Commission may by rules and regulations prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission review of disciplinary actions taken by registered futures associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Commission review of disciplinary actions taken by registered futures associations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice; hearing; findings; cancellation, reduction, or remission of penalties; review by court of appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Notice; hearing; findings; cancellation, reduction, or remission of penalties; review by court of appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_21_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes or additions to association rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Changes or additions to association rules Every registered futures association shall file with the Commission in accordance with such rules and regulations as the Commission may prescribe as necessary or appropriate in the public interest, copies of any changes in or additions to the rules of the association, and such other information and documents as the Commission may require to keep current or to supplement the registration statement and documents filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section. A registered futures association shall submit to the Commission any change in or addition to its rules and may make such rules effective ten days after receipt of such submission by the Commission unless, within the ten-day period, the registered futures association requests review and approval thereof by the Commission or the Commission notifies such registered futures association in writing of its determination to review such rules for approval. The Commission shall approve such rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>