<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2106"><akn:num>2106</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms and conditions in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2106. Required terms and conditions in orders
Orders issued pursuant to this chapter shall contain the following terms and conditions:(a) Providing for the establishment and selection by the Secretary, of a Cotton Board, and defining its powers and duties, which shall include only the powers:(1) To administer such order in accordance with its terms and provisions;

(2) To make rules and regulations to effectuate the terms and provisions of such order, including the designation of the person responsible for collecting the assessment;

(3) To receive, investigate, and report to the Secretary complaints of violations of such order; and

(4) To recommend to the Secretary amendments to such order.


(b) Providing that the Cotton Board shall be composed of (1) representatives of cotton producers selected by the Secretary, from nominations submitted by eligible producer organizations within a cotton-producing State, as certified pursuant to section 2113 of this title, or, if the Secretary determines that a substantial number of producers are not members of or their interests are not represented by any such eligible producer organizations, from nominations made by producers in the manner authorized by the Secretary, so that the representation of cotton producers on the Board for each cotton-producing State shall reflect, to the extent practicable, the proportion which that State’s marketings of cotton bears to the total marketings of cotton in the United States, and (2) when imports of cotton are subject to an order, an appropriate number of representatives, as determined by the Secretary, of importers of cotton on which assessments are paid under this chapter. Such importer representatives shall be appointed by the Secretary after consultation with organizations representing importers, as determined by the Secretary. Each cotton-producing State shall be entitled to at least one representative on the Cotton Board. The Secretary may appoint a number of consumer advisors to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Providing for the establishment and selection by the Secretary, of a Cotton Board, and defining its powers and duties, which shall include only the powers:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Providing that the Cotton Board shall be composed of (1) representatives of cotton producers selected by the Secretary, from nominations submitted by eligible producer organizations within a cotton-producing State, as certified pursuant to section 2113 of this title, or, if the Secretary determines that a substantial number of producers are not members of or their interests are not represented by any such eligible producer organizations, from nominations made by producers in the manner authorized by the Secretary, so that the representation of cotton producers on the Board for each cotton-producing State shall reflect, to the extent practicable, the proportion which that State’s marketings of cotton bears to the total marketings of cotton in the United States, and (2) when imports of cotton are subject to an order, an appropriate number of representatives, as determined by the Secretary, of importers of cotton on which assessments are paid under this chapter. Such importer represen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Providing that the Cotton Board shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (g) of this section, develop and submit to the Secretary for his approval any advertising or sales promotion or research and development plans or projects, and that any such plan or project must be approved by the Secretary before becoming effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Providing that the Cotton Board shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (g) of this section, submit to the Secretary for his approval, budgets on a fiscal period basis of its anticipated expenses and disbursements in the administration of the order, including probable costs of advertising and promotion and research and development projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Providing that the Cotton Board shall maintain such books and records and prepare and submit such reports from time to time, to the Secretary as he may prescribe, and for appropriate accounting by the Cotton Board with respect to the receipt and disbursement of all funds entrusted to it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Providing that the Cotton Board, with the approval of the Secretary, shall enter into contracts or agreements for the development and carrying out of the activities authorized under the order pursuant to sections 2105(a) and (b) of this title and for the payment of the costs thereof with funds collected pursuant to the order, with an organization or association whose governing body consists of cotton producers selected by the cotton producer organizations certified by the Secretary under section 2113 of this title, in such manner that the producers of each cotton-producing State will, to the extent practicable, have representation on the governing body of such organization in the proportion that the cotton marketed by the producers of such State bears to the total cotton marketed by the producers of all cotton-producing States, subject to adjustments to reflect lack of participation in the program by reason of refunds under section 2110 of this title. Any such contract or agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2106_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Providing that no funds collected by the Cotton Board under the order shall in any manner be used for the purpose of influencing governmental policy or action, except as provided by subsection (a)(4) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>