<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2121"><akn:num>2121</akn:num><akn:heading>Cotton ginning investigations; publication of results; cooperation with Federal and State department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2121. Cotton ginning investigations; publication of results; cooperation with Federal and State departments and agencies
The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to investigate the ginning of cotton; to establish and maintain experimental ginning plants and laboratories; and to make such tests, demonstrations, and experiments, and such technical and scientific studies in relation to cotton ginning as he shall deem necessary and to publish the results thereof, with a view to developing improved ginning equipment and encouraging the use of improved methods, and he may cooperate with any department or agency of the Government, any State, Territory, District, or possession, or department, agency, or political subdivision thereof, or any person, as he shall find to be necessary.
(Apr. 19, 1930, ch. 203, § 1, 46 Stat. 248.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 424 of this title prior to editorial reclassification and renumbering as this section.
Section was enacted as part of act Apr. 19, 1930, ch. 203, and not as part of the Cotton Research and Promotion Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>