<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2139" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2139/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2139/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2139"><akn:num>2139</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal-agent relationship established</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2139. Principal-agent relationship established
When construing or enforcing the provisions of this chapter, the act, omission, or failure of any person acting for or employed by a research facility, a dealer, or an exhibitor or a person licensed as a dealer or an exhibitor pursuant to the second sentence of section 2133 of this title, or an operator of an auction sale subject to section 2142 of this title, or an intermediate handler, or a carrier, within the scope of his employment or office, shall be deemed the act, omission, or failure of such research facility, dealer, exhibitor, licensee, operator of an auction sale, intermediate handler, or carrier, as well as of such person.
(Pub. L. 89–544, § 9, Aug. 24, 1966, 80 Stat. 351; Pub. L. 91–579, § 10, Dec. 24, 1970, 84 Stat. 1562; Pub. L. 94–279, § 7, Apr. 22, 1976, 90 Stat. 418.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–279 inserted “or an intermediate handler, or a carrier,” after “section 2142 of this title,” and substituted “operator of an auction sale, intermediate handler, or carrier, as well as of such person.” for “or an operator of an auction sale as well as of such person.” after “research facility, dealer, exhibitor, licensee,”.
1970—Pub. L. 91–579 inserted references to persons acting for or employed by exhibitors, persons licensed as exhibitors, and operators of auction sales subject to section 2142 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1970 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 91–579 effective one year after Dec. 24, 1970, see section 23 of Pub. L. 91–579, set out as a note under section 2131 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>