<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2156" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2156/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2156/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2156"><akn:num>2156</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal fighting venture prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2156. Animal fighting venture prohibition(a) Sponsoring or exhibiting an animal in, attending, or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend, an animal fighting venture(1) Sponsoring or exhibitingIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sponsor or exhibit an animal in an animal fighting venture.


(2) Attending or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attendIt shall be unlawful for any person to—(A) knowingly attend an animal fighting venture; or

(B) knowingly cause an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend an animal fighting venture.



(b) Buying, selling, delivering, possessing, training, or transporting animals for participation in animal fighting ventureIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, possess, train, transport, deliver, or receive any animal for purposes of having the animal participate in an animal fighting venture.


(c) Use of Postal Service or other interstate instrumentality for promoting or furthering animal fighting ventureIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly use the mail service of the United States Postal Service or any instrumentality of interstate commerce for commercial speech for purposes of advertising an animal, or an instrument described in subsection (d), for use in an animal fighting venture, promoting 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “or”. or in any other manner furthering an animal fighting venture except as performed outside the limits of the States of the United States.


(d) Buying, selling, delivering, or transporting sharp instruments for use in animal fighting ventureIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, transport, or deliver in interstate or foreign commerce a knife, a gaff, or any other sharp instrument attached, or designed or intended to be attached, to the leg of a bird for use in an animal fighting venture.


(e) Investigation of violations by Secretary; assistance by other Feder</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sponsoring or exhibiting an animal in, attending, or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend, an animal fighting venture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sponsoring or exhibiting an animal in, attending, or causing an individual who has not attained the age of 16 to attend, an animal fighting venture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buying, selling, delivering, possessing, training, or transporting animals for participation in animal fighting venture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Buying, selling, delivering, possessing, training, or transporting animals for participation in animal fighting venture It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, possess, train, transport, deliver, or receive any animal for purposes of having the animal participate in an animal fighting venture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Postal Service or other interstate instrumentality for promoting or furthering animal fighting venture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of Postal Service or other interstate instrumentality for promoting or furthering animal fighting venture It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly use the mail service of the United States Postal Service or any instrumentality of interstate commerce for commercial speech for purposes of advertising an animal, or an instrument described in subsection (d), for use in an animal fighting venture, promoting 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “or”. or in any other manner furthering an animal fighting venture except as performed outside the limits of the States of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buying, selling, delivering, or transporting sharp instruments for use in animal fighting venture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Buying, selling, delivering, or transporting sharp instruments for use in animal fighting venture It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly sell, buy, transport, or deliver in interstate or foreign commerce a knife, a gaff, or any other sharp instrument attached, or designed or intended to be attached, to the leg of a bird for use in an animal fighting venture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of violations by Secretary; assistance by other Federal agencies; issuance of search warrant; forfeiture; costs recoverable in forfeiture or civil action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Investigation of violations by Secretary; assistance by other Federal agencies; issuance of search warrant; forfeiture; costs recoverable in forfeiture or civil action The Secretary or any other person authorized by him shall make such investigations as the Secretary deems necessary to determine whether any person has violated or is violating any provision of this section, and the Secretary may obtain the assistance of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Department of the Treasury, or other law enforcement agencies of the United States, and State and local governmental agencies, in the conduct of such investigations, under cooperative agreements with such agencies. A warrant to search for and seize any animal which there is probable cause to believe was involved in any violation of this section may be issued by any judge of the United States or of a State court of record or by a United States magistrate judge within the district wherein the animal sought is located. Any United</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relationship to other provisions The conduct by any person of any activity prohibited by this section shall not render such person subject to the other sections of this chapter as a dealer, exhibitor, or otherwise.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict with State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Conflict with State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2156_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Criminal penalties The criminal penalties for violations of subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) are provided in section 49 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>