<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2160" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2160/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2160/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2160"><akn:num>2160</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on slaughter of dogs and cats for human consumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2160. Prohibition on slaughter of dogs and cats for human consumption(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (c), no person may—(1) knowingly slaughter a dog or cat for human consumption; or

(2) knowingly ship, transport, move, deliver, receive, possess, purchase, sell, or donate—(A) a dog or cat to be slaughtered for human consumption; or

(B) a dog or cat part for human consumption.



(b) ScopeSubsection (a) shall apply only with respect to conduct—(1) in or affecting interstate commerce or foreign commerce; or

(2) within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States.


(c) Exception for Indian tribesThe prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to an Indian (as defined in section 5304 of title 25) carrying out any activity described in subsection (a) for the purpose of a religious ceremony.


(d) PenaltyAny person who violates subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine in an amount not greater than $5,000 for each violation.


(e) Effect on State lawNothing in this section—(1) limits any State or local law or regulation protecting the welfare of animals; or

(2) prevents a State or unit of local government from adopting and enforcing an animal welfare law or regulation that is more stringent than this section.


(Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12515, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 5000.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018, and not as part of the Animal Welfare Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (c), no person may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope Subsection (a) shall apply only with respect to conduct—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for Indian tribes The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to an Indian (as defined in section 5304 of title 25) carrying out any activity described in subsection (a) for the purpose of a religious ceremony.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalty Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine in an amount not greater than $5,000 for each violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect on State law Nothing in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>