<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2204c"><akn:num>2204c</akn:num><akn:heading>Water management for rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2204c. Water management for rural areas(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, directly or in coordination with any other Federal agency, entity, corporation, department, unit of State or local government, cooperative, confederation, individual, public or private organization, Indian tribe, or university, to—(1) conduct research and demonstration projects;

(2) provide technical assistance and extension services;

(3) make grants, loans, and loan guarantees; and

(4) provide other forms of assistance, for the purpose of helping rural areas make better and more efficient use of water resources and to alleviate problems arising in such areas from droughts or lack of water.


(b) ActivitiesThe Secretary is authorized to provide assistance under this section for the promotion or establishment of irrigation, watersheds, and other water management and drought management activities, including water transmission, application, and activation.


(c) CooperationIn implementing this section, the Secretary—(1) should address the general, special, and unique problems of water management existing in rural areas;

(2) may take action independently or in cooperation with Federal, State, public, or private entities and agencies; and

(3) shall cooperate with—(A) cooperatives, public or private organizations, confederations, authorities, or other entities (including such entities that may be organized under multiple State agreements or compacts and entities created under State law) to carry out projects authorized under this section; and

(B) water, watershed, and sewer authorities, rural electric cooperatives, Federal agencies, and other State or local governments or agencies.



(d) Regulations(1) The Secretary shall issue regulations to carry out this section.

(2) Such regulations shall—(A) specify the terms and conditions that the entities described in subsections (a) and (c) must meet in order to participate in programs carried out under this section;

(B) es</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized, directly or in coordination with any other Federal agency, entity, corporation, department, unit of State or local government, cooperative, confederation, individual, public or private organization, Indian tribe, or university, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities The Secretary is authorized to provide assistance under this section for the promotion or establishment of irrigation, watersheds, and other water management and drought management activities, including water transmission, application, and activation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation In implementing this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“University” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “University” defined As used in this section, the term “university” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No waivers Nothing in this section shall authorize the waiver of a cost-share requirement under a program established under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>