<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2204j"><akn:num>2204j</akn:num><akn:heading>National agriculture imagery program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2204j. National agriculture imagery program(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency, shall carry out a national agriculture imagery program to annually acquire aerial imagery during agricultural growing seasons from the continental United States.


(b) DataThe aerial imagery acquired under this section shall—(1) consist of high resolution processed digital imagery;

(2) be made available in a format that can be provided to Federal, State, and private sector entities;

(3) be technologically compatible with geospatial information technology; and

(4) be consistent with the standards established by the Federal Geographic Data Committee.


(c) Supplemental satellite imageryThe Secretary of Agriculture may supplement the aerial imagery collected under this section with satellite imagery.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $23,000,000 for fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter.


(Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12612, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 5013.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Farm Service Agency, shall carry out a national agriculture imagery program to annually acquire aerial imagery during agricultural growing seasons from the continental United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data The aerial imagery acquired under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental satellite imagery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supplemental satellite imagery The Secretary of Agriculture may supplement the aerial imagery collected under this section with satellite imagery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $23,000,000 for fiscal year 2019 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>