<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2204i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2204i"><akn:num>2204i</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on land access and farmland ownership data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2204i. Reports on land access and farmland ownership data collection(a) Land accessNot later than 1 year after December 20, 2018, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Chief Economist, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report identifying—(1) the barriers that prevent or hinder the ability of beginning farmers and ranchers (as defined in section 2279(a) of this title) and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers (as defined in such section) to acquire or access farmland;

(2) the extent to which Federal programs, including agricultural conservation easement programs, land transition programs, and financing programs, are improving—(A) farmland access and tenure for beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers; and

(B) farmland transition and succession; and


(3) the regulatory, operational, or statutory changes that are necessary to improve—(A) the ability of beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers to acquire or access farmland;

(B) farmland tenure for beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers; and

(C) farmland transition and succession.



(b) Farmland ownershipThe Secretary shall collect and, not less frequently than once every 3 years report, data and analysis on farmland ownership, tenure, transition, and entry of beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers (as those terms are defined in section 2279(a) of this title). In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall, at a minimum—(1) collect and distribute comprehensive reporting of trends in farmland ownership, tenure, transition, barriers to entry, profitability, and viability of beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers;

(2) develop surveys and report statistical and economic analysis on farmland ownership, tenure, transition, barriers to entry, profitability, and viability of beg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Land access Not later than 1 year after December 20, 2018, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the Chief Economist, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report identifying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Farmland ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Farmland ownership The Secretary shall collect and, not less frequently than once every 3 years report, data and analysis on farmland ownership, tenure, transition, and entry of beginning farmers and ranchers and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers (as those terms are defined in section 2279(a) of this title). In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2204i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each fiscal 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “of”. years 2019 through 2023, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>