<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/222" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/222/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/222/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_222"><akn:num>222</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Trade Commission powers adopted for enforcement of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 222. Federal Trade Commission powers adopted for enforcement of chapter
For the efficient execution of the provisions of this chapter, and in order to provide information for the use of Congress, the provisions (including penalties) of sections 46 and 48 to 50 of title 15, are made applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Secretary in enforcing the provisions of this chapter and to any person subject to the provisions of this chapter, whether or not a corporation. The Secretary, in person or by such agents as he may designate, may prosecute any inquiry necessary to his duties under this chapter in any part of the United States.
(Aug. 15, 1921, ch. 64, title IV, § 402, 42 Stat. 168; Aug. 15, 1921, ch. 64, title V, § 503, as added Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 532, 49 Stat. 649.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1935—Act Aug. 15, 1921, § 503, as added Aug. 14, 1935, purported to insert “or any live poultry dealer or handler” after “packer” but word “packer” does not appear in this section.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Executive and administrative functions of Federal Trade Commission, with certain reservations, transferred to Chairman of such Commission by 1950 Reorg. Plan No. 8, § 1, eff. May 24, 1950, 15 F.R. 3175, 64 Stat. 1264, set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>