<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/227" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/227/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/227/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_227"><akn:num>227</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Federal Trade Commission and Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 227. Powers of Federal Trade Commission and Secretary of Agriculture(a) Omitted

(b) Jurisdiction of Federal Trade CommissionThe Federal Trade Commission shall have power and jurisdiction over any matter involving meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, or poultry products, which by this chapter is made subject to the power or jurisdiction of the Secretary, as follows:(1) When the Secretary in the exercise of his duties requests of the Commission that it make investigations and reports in any case.

(2) In any investigation of, or proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of any Act administered by the Commission, arising out of acts or transactions involving meat, meat food products, or livestock products in unmanufactured form, if the Commission determines that effective exercise of its power or jurisdiction with respect to retail sales of any such commodities is or will be impaired by the absence of power or jurisdiction over all acts or transactions involving such commodities in such investigation or proceeding. In order to avoid unnecessary duplication of effort by the Government and burdens upon the industry, the Commissioner shall notify the Secretary of such determination, the reasons therefor, and the acts or transactions involved, and shall not exercise power or jurisdiction with regard to acts or transactions (other than retail sales) involving such commodities if the Secretary within ten days from the date of receipt of the notice notifies the Commission that there is pending in his Department an investigation of, or proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of this chapter involving the same subject matter.

(3) Over all transactions in commerce in margarine, oleomargarine, or poultry products and over retail sales of meat, meat food products and livestock products in unmanufactured form.


(c) Limitation of Federal Trade Commission jurisdictionThe Federal Trade Commission shall have no power or j</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Federal Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Jurisdiction of Federal Trade Commission The Federal Trade Commission shall have power and jurisdiction over any matter involving meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, or poultry products, which by this chapter is made subject to the power or jurisdiction of the Secretary, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of Federal Trade Commission jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation of Federal Trade Commission jurisdiction The Federal Trade Commission shall have no power or jurisdiction over any matter which by this chapter is made subject to the jurisdiction of the Secretary, except as provided in subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture except for poultry products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture except for poultry products The Secretary of Agriculture shall exercise power or jurisdiction over oleomargarine or retail sales of meat, meat food products, or livestock products in unmanufactured form only when he determines, in any investigation of, or any proceeding for the prevention of, an alleged violation of this chapter, that such action is necessary to avoid impairment of his power or jurisdiction over acts or transactions involving livestock, meat, meat food products, livestock products in unmanufactured form, or poultry other than retail sales thereof. In order to avoid unnecessary duplication of effort by the Government and burdens upon the industry, the Secretary shall notify the Federal Trade Commission of such determination, the reasons therefor, and the acts or transactions involved, and shall not exercise power or jurisdiction with respect to acts or transactions involving oleomargarine or retail sales of meat, meat food pr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture regarding poultry products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Jurisdiction of Secretary of Agriculture regarding poultry products The Secretary of Agriculture shall exercise jurisdiction over poultry products only in a proceeding brought under section 197 of this title or section 228b–1 of this title when such action is necessary to avoid impairment of his jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to be included in annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information to be included in annual reports The Secretary of Agriculture and the Federal Trade Commission shall include in their respective annual reports information with respect to the administration of subsections (b), (d), and (e) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>