<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2276" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2276/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2276/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2276"><akn:num>2276</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2276. Confidentiality of information(a) In generalIn the case of information furnished under a provision of law referred to in subsection (d), neither the Secretary of Agriculture, any other officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture or agency thereof, nor any other person may—(1) use such information for a purpose other than the development or reporting of aggregate data in a manner such that the identity of the person who supplied such information is not discernible and is not material to the intended uses of such information;

(2) disclose such information to the public, unless such information has been transformed into a statistical or aggregate form that does not allow the identification of the person who supplied particular information; or

(3) in the case of information collected under the authority described in paragraph (12) or (13) of subsection (d), disclose the information to any person or any Federal, State, local, or tribal agency outside the Department of Agriculture, unless the information has been converted into a statistical or aggregate form that does not allow the identification of the person that supplied particular information.


(b) Duty of Secretary; immunity from disclosure; necessary consent(1) In carrying out a provision of law referred to in subsection (d), no department, agency, officer, or employee of the Federal Government, other than the Secretary of Agriculture, shall require a person to furnish a copy of statistical information provided to the Department of Agriculture.

(2) A copy of such information—(A) shall be immune from mandatory disclosure of any type, including legal process; and

(B) shall not, without the consent of such person, be admitted as evidence or used for any purpose in any action, suit, or other judicial or administrative proceeding.



(c) Violations; penaltiesAny person who shall publish, cause to be published, or otherwise publicly release information collected pursuant to a provision of law referr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of information furnished under a provision of law referred to in subsection (d), neither the Secretary of Agriculture, any other officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture or agency thereof, nor any other person may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Secretary; immunity from disclosure; necessary consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty of Secretary; immunity from disclosure; necessary consent</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations; penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Violations; penalties Any person who shall publish, cause to be published, or otherwise publicly release information collected pursuant to a provision of law referred to in subsection (d), in any manner or for any purpose prohibited in section 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a), shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions of law references</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provisions of law references For purposes of this section, a provision of law referred to in this subsection means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information provided to Secretary of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information provided to Secretary of Commerce This section shall not prohibit the release of information under section 2204g(f)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>