<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2279c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2279c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2279c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2279c"><akn:num>2279c</akn:num><akn:heading>Student internship programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2279c. Student internship programs(a) Student intern subsistence program(1) “Student intern” definedIn this subsection, the term “student intern” means a person who—(A) is employed by the Department of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Department”) to assist scientific, professional, administrative, or technical employees of the Department; and

(B) is a student in good standing at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20) pursuing a course of study related to the field in which the person is employed by the Department.


(2) Payment of certain expenses by the SecretaryThe Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may, out of user fee funds or funds appropriated to any agency of the Department, pay for lodging expenses, subsistence expenses, and transportation expenses of a student intern at the agency (including expenses of transportation to and from the student intern’s residence at or near the institution of higher education attended by the student intern and the official duty station at which the student intern is employed).



(b) Cooperation with associations of colleges and universities(1) Authority to cooperateNotwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements on an annual basis with 1 or more associations of institutions of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20) for the purpose of providing for Department participation in internship programs for graduate and undergraduate students who are selected by the associations from students attending member institutions of the associations and other institutions of higher education.


(2) Internship programAn internship program supported under this subsection (referred to in this subsection as an “internship program”) shall provide work assignments for students within the Department and such other activities as the association that enters into the cooperative agreement under p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student intern subsistence program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Student intern subsistence program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2279c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with associations of colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperation with associations of colleges and universities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>