<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2302"><akn:num>2302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2302. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Agricultural productsThe term “agricultural products” shall not include cotton or tobacco or their products.


(2)(2) 11 So in original. Association of producers(A) In generalThe term “association of producers” means any association of producers of agricultural products engaged in marketing, bargaining, shipping, or processing as defined in section 1141j(a) of title 12, or in section 291 of this title.


(B) InclusionThe term “association of producers” includes an organization whose membership is exclusively limited to agricultural producers and dedicated to promoting the common interest and general welfare of producers of agricultural products.



(3)(3) 1 Handler(A) In generalThe term “handler” means any person engaged in the business or practice of (i) acquiring agricultural products from producers or associations of producers for processing or sale; or (ii) grading, packaging, handling, storing, or processing agricultural products received from producers or associations of producers; or (iii) contracting or negotiating contracts or other arrangements, written or oral, with or on behalf of producers or associations of producers with respect to the production or marketing of any agricultural product; or (iv) acting as an agent or broker for a handler in the performance of any function or act specified in clause (i), (ii), or (iii).


(B) ExclusionThe term “handler” does not include a person, other than a packer (as defined in section 191 of this title), that provides custom feeding services for a producer.



(4) ProducerThe term “producer” means a person engaged in the production of agricultural products as a farmer, planter, rancher, dairyman, fruit, vegetable, or nut grower.


(Pub. L. 90–288, § 3, Apr. 16, 1968, 82 Stat. 94; Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11003, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1354; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title XI, § 11003, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2116.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural products The term “agricultural products” shall not include cotton or tobacco or their products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) (2) 11 So in original. Association of producers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) (3) 1 Handler</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Producer The term “producer” means a person engaged in the production of agricultural products as a farmer, planter, rancher, dairyman, fruit, vegetable, or nut grower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>