<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_243"><akn:num>243</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition and collection of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 243. Imposition and collection of fees(a) In generalThe Secretary shall assess persons covered by this chapter fees to cover the costs of administering this chapter.


(b) RatesThe fees under this section shall be set at a rate determined by the Secretary.


(c) Treatment of feesAll fees collected under this section shall be credited to the account that incurs the costs of administering this chapter and shall be available to the Secretary without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.


(d) InterestFunds collected under this section may be deposited in an interest-bearing account with a financial institution, and any interest earned on the account shall be credited under subsection (c).


(e) Efficiencies and cost effectiveness(1) In generalThe Secretary shall seek to minimize the fees established under this section by improving efficiencies and reducing costs, including the efficient use of personnel to the extent practicable and consistent with the effective implementation of this chapter.


(2) ReportThe Secretary shall publish an annual report on the actions taken by the Secretary to comply with paragraph (1).



(Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 4, as added Pub. L. 106–472, title II, § 201, Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2064.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 243, act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 3, 39 Stat. 486, authorized investigation of warehousing, weighing, classifying, and certification of agricultural products, inspection of warehouses, and prescription of duties of warehousemen by Secretary of Agriculture, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 106–472. See section 242 of this title.
A prior section 4 of act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, was classified to section 244 of this title, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 106–472.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall assess persons covered by this chapter fees to cover the costs of administering this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rates The fees under this section shall be set at a rate determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of fees All fees collected under this section shall be credited to the account that incurs the costs of administering this chapter and shall be available to the Secretary without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_243_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Interest Funds collected under this section may be deposited in an interest-bearing account with a financial institution, and any interest earned on the account shall be credited under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_243_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Efficiencies and cost effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Efficiencies and cost effectiveness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>