<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/245" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/245/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/245/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_245"><akn:num>245</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonding and other financial assurance requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 245. Bonding and other financial assurance requirements(a) In generalAs a condition of receiving a license or approval under this chapter (including regulations promulgated under this chapter), the person applying for the license or approval shall execute and file with the Secretary a bond, or provide such other financial assurance as the Secretary determines appropriate, to secure the person’s performance of the activities so licensed or approved.


(b) Service of processTo qualify as a suitable bond or other financial assurance under subsection (a), the surety, sureties, or financial institution shall be subject to service of process in suits on the bond or other financial assurance in the State, district, or territory in which the warehouse is located.


(c) Additional assurancesIf the Secretary determines that a previously approved bond or other financial assurance is insufficient, the Secretary may suspend or revoke the license or approval covered by the bond or other financial assurance if the person that filed the bond or other financial assurance does not provide such additional bond or other financial assurance as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(d) Third party actionsAny person injured by the breach of any obligation arising under this chapter for which a bond or other financial assurance has been obtained as required by this section may sue with respect to the bond or other financial assurance in a district court of the United States to recover the damages that the person sustained as a result of the breach.


(Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 6, as added Pub. L. 106–472, title II, § 201, Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2064.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 245, acts Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 5, 39 Stat. 486; Feb. 23, 1923, ch. 106, 42 Stat. 1282, related to term and renewal of license, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 106–472.
A prior section 6 of act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, was classified to sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As a condition of receiving a license or approval under this chapter (including regulations promulgated under this chapter), the person applying for the license or approval shall execute and file with the Secretary a bond, or provide such other financial assurance as the Secretary determines appropriate, to secure the person’s performance of the activities so licensed or approved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Service of process To qualify as a suitable bond or other financial assurance under subsection (a), the surety, sureties, or financial institution shall be subject to service of process in suits on the bond or other financial assurance in the State, district, or territory in which the warehouse is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional assurances If the Secretary determines that a previously approved bond or other financial assurance is insufficient, the Secretary may suspend or revoke the license or approval covered by the bond or other financial assurance if the person that filed the bond or other financial assurance does not provide such additional bond or other financial assurance as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third party actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Third party actions Any person injured by the breach of any obligation arising under this chapter for which a bond or other financial assurance has been obtained as required by this section may sue with respect to the bond or other financial assurance in a district court of the United States to recover the damages that the person sustained as a result of the breach.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>