<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/250" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/250/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/250/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_250"><akn:num>250</akn:num><akn:heading>Warehouse receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 250. Warehouse receipts(a) In generalAt the request of the depositor of an agricultural product stored or handled in a warehouse licensed under this chapter, the warehouse operator shall issue a receipt to the depositor as prescribed by the Secretary.


(b) Actual storage requiredA receipt may not be issued under this section for an agricultural product unless the agricultural product is actually stored in the warehouse at the time of the issuance of the receipt.


(c) ContentsEach receipt issued for an agricultural product stored or handled in a warehouse licensed under this chapter shall contain such information, for each agricultural product covered by the receipt, as the Secretary may require by regulation.


(d) Prohibition on additional receipts or other documents(1) ReceiptsWhile a receipt issued under this chapter is outstanding and uncanceled by the warehouse operator, an additional receipt may not be issued for the same agricultural product (or any portion of the same agricultural product) represented by the outstanding receipt, except as authorized by the Secretary.


(2) Other documentsIf a document is transferred under this section, no duplicate document in any form may be transferred by any person with respect to the same agricultural product represented by the document, except as authorized by the Secretary.



(e) Electronic receipts and electronic documentsExcept as provided in section 242(h)(2) of this title, notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law:(1) In generalThe Secretary may promulgate regulations that authorize the issuance, recording, and transfer of electronic receipts, and the transfer of other electronic documents, in accordance with this subsection.


(2) Electronic receipt or electronic document systemsElectronic receipts may be issued, recorded, and transferred, and electronic documents may be transferred, under this subsection with respect to an agricultural product under, a system or systems maintained in one or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_250_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general At the request of the depositor of an agricultural product stored or handled in a warehouse licensed under this chapter, the warehouse operator shall issue a receipt to the depositor as prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_250_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actual storage required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Actual storage required A receipt may not be issued under this section for an agricultural product unless the agricultural product is actually stored in the warehouse at the time of the issuance of the receipt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_250_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents Each receipt issued for an agricultural product stored or handled in a warehouse licensed under this chapter shall contain such information, for each agricultural product covered by the receipt, as the Secretary may require by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_250_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on additional receipts or other documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on additional receipts or other documents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_250_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic receipts and electronic documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Electronic receipts and electronic documents Except as provided in section 242(h)(2) of this title, notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>