<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_251"><akn:num>251</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for delivery of agricultural products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 251. Conditions for delivery of agricultural products(a) Prompt deliveryIn the absence of a lawful excuse, a warehouse operator shall, without unnecessary delay, deliver the agricultural product stored or handled in the warehouse on a demand made by—(1) the holder of the receipt for the agricultural product; or

(2) the person that deposited the product, if no receipt has been issued.


(b) Payment to accompany demandPrior to delivery of the agricultural product, payment of the accrued charges associated with the storage of the agricultural product, including satisfaction of the warehouseman’s lien, shall be made if requested by the warehouse operator.


(c) Surrender of receiptWhen the holder of a receipt requests delivery of an agricultural product covered by the receipt, the holder shall surrender the receipt to the warehouse operator, in the manner prescribed by the Secretary, to obtain the agricultural product.


(d) Cancellation of receiptA warehouse operator shall cancel each receipt returned to the warehouse operator upon the delivery of the agricultural product for which the receipt was issued.


(Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 12, as added Pub. L. 106–472, title II, § 201, Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2067.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 251, acts Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, § 10, 39 Stat. 487; Mar. 2, 1931, ch. 366, § 5, 46 Stat. 1464; Pub. L. 97–35, title I, § 158(a)(1), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 375, authorized fee for warehouse examination, inspection, and licensing, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 106–472. See section 243 of this title.
A prior section 12 of act Aug. 11, 1916, ch. 313, pt. C, was classified to section 253 of this title, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 106–472.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt delivery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prompt delivery In the absence of a lawful excuse, a warehouse operator shall, without unnecessary delay, deliver the agricultural product stored or handled in the warehouse on a demand made by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to accompany demand</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment to accompany demand Prior to delivery of the agricultural product, payment of the accrued charges associated with the storage of the agricultural product, including satisfaction of the warehouseman’s lien, shall be made if requested by the warehouse operator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surrender of receipt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Surrender of receipt When the holder of a receipt requests delivery of an agricultural product covered by the receipt, the holder shall surrender the receipt to the warehouse operator, in the manner prescribed by the Secretary, to obtain the agricultural product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_251_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of receipt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cancellation of receipt A warehouse operator shall cancel each receipt returned to the warehouse operator upon the delivery of the agricultural product for which the receipt was issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>