<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2543" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2543/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2543/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2543"><akn:num>2543</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to save seed; crop exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2543. Right to save seed; crop exemption
Except to the extent that such action may constitute an infringement under subsections (3) and (4) of section 2541 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, it shall not infringe any right hereunder for a person to save seed produced by the person from seed obtained, or descended from seed obtained, by authority of the owner of the variety for seeding purposes and use such saved seed in the production of a crop for use on the farm of the person, or for sale as provided in this section. A bona fide sale for other than reproductive purposes, made in channels usual for such other purposes, of seed produced on a farm either from seed obtained by authority of the owner for seeding purposes or from seed produced by descent on such farm from seed obtained by authority of the owner for seeding purposes shall not constitute an infringement. A purchaser who diverts seed from such channels to seeding purposes shall be deemed to have notice under section 2567 of this title that the actions of the purchaser constitute an infringement.
(Pub. L. 91–577, title III, § 113, Dec. 24, 1970, 84 Stat. 1555; Pub. L. 103–349, §§ 10, 13(s), Oct. 6, 1994, 108 Stat. 3142, 3144.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSubsections (3) and (4) of section 2541 of this title, referred to in text, probably means paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 2541 of this title, which were redesignated subsection (a)(3) and (4) of section 2541 of this title by Pub. L. 102–560, § 3(a), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4231.

Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–349, §§ 10, 13(s)(1), in first sentence substituted “produced by the person” for “produced by him”, “the farm of the person” for “his farm”, and “section.” for “section: Provided, That without regard to the provisions of section 2541(3) of this title it shall not infringe any right hereunder for a person, whose primary farming occupation is the growing of crops for sale for other than reproductive purposes, to sell such sav</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>