<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2662" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2662/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2662/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2662"><akn:num>2662</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2662. Programs authorized
The Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) may conduct, in cooperation and coordination with colleges and universities, the following programs to carry out the purposes and achieve the goals of this subchapter.(a) Rural development extension programsRural development extension programs shall consist of the collection, interpretation, and dissemination of useful information and knowledge from research and other sources to units of multistate regional agencies, State, county, municipal, and other units of government, multicounty planning and development districts, organizations of citizens contributing to community and rural development, businesses, Indian tribes on Federal or State reservations or other federally recognized Indian tribal groups, and industries that employ or may employ people in rural areas. The rural development extension programs shall also promote coordinated and integrated rural community initiatives that advance and empower capacity building through leadership development, entrepreneurship, business development and management training, and strategic planning to increase jobs, income, and quality of life in rural communities. These programs also shall include technical services and educational activities, including instruction for persons not enrolled as students in colleges or universities, to facilitate and encourage the use and practical application of this information. These programs may also include feasibility studies and planning assistance.


(b) Rural development researchRural development research shall consist of research, investigations, and basic feasibility studies in any field or discipline that may develop principles, facts, scientific and technical knowledge, new technology, and other information that may be useful to agencies of Federal, State, and local government, industries in rural areas, Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations or other federally recogn</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural development extension programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rural development extension programs Rural development extension programs shall consist of the collection, interpretation, and dissemination of useful information and knowledge from research and other sources to units of multistate regional agencies, State, county, municipal, and other units of government, multicounty planning and development districts, organizations of citizens contributing to community and rural development, businesses, Indian tribes on Federal or State reservations or other federally recognized Indian tribal groups, and industries that employ or may employ people in rural areas. The rural development extension programs shall also promote coordinated and integrated rural community initiatives that advance and empower capacity building through leadership development, entrepreneurship, business development and management training, and strategic planning to increase jobs, income, and quality of life in rural communities. These programs also shall include technical s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural development research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rural development research Rural development research shall consist of research, investigations, and basic feasibility studies in any field or discipline that may develop principles, facts, scientific and technical knowledge, new technology, and other information that may be useful to agencies of Federal, State, and local government, industries in rural areas, Indian tribes on Federal and State reservations or other federally recognized Indian tribal groups, and other organizations involved in community and rural development programs and activities in planning and carrying out such programs and activities or otherwise be practical and useful in achieving the purposes and goals of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small farm research programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Small farm research programs Small farm research programs shall consist of programs of research to develop new approaches for initiating and upgrading small farm operations through management techniques, agricultural production techniques, farm machinery technology, new products, new marketing techniques, and small farm finance; to develop new enterprises that can use labor, skills, or natural resources available to the small farm family; or that will help to increase the quality and availability of services and facilities needed by the small farm family.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small farm extension programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small farm extension programs Small farm extension programs shall consist of extension programs to improve small farm operations, including management techniques, agricultural production techniques, farm machinery technology, marketing techniques and small farm finance; to increase use by small farm families of existing services offered by the Department of Agriculture and other public and private agencies and organizations; to assist small farm families in establishing and operating cooperatives for the purpose of improving their family income from farming or other economic activities; to increase the quality and availability of services and facilities needed by small farm families; and to develop new enterprises that can use labor, skills, or natural resources available to the small farm family.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special grants programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special grants programs Special grants programs shall consist of extension and research programs to strengthen research and education on national and regional issues in rural development, including the assessment of alternative policies and strategies for rural development and balanced growth; to develop alternative strategies for national and regional investment, and the creation of employment, in rural areas; to develop alternative energy policies to meet rural development needs; and to strengthen rural development programs of agencies of the Department of Agriculture and those in other Federal departments and agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (g) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 792(a), title VIII, § 871, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1152, 1175</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) , (g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural development extension work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rural development extension work</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2662_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural health and safety education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rural health and safety education programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>