<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2708"><akn:num>2708</akn:num><akn:heading>Referendum among egg producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2708. Referendum among egg producers(a) Producer approval of orderThe Secretary shall conduct a referendum among egg producers not exempt hereunder who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production of commercial eggs, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of an order is approved or favored by such producers. No order issued pursuant to this chapter shall be effective unless the Secretary determines that the issuance of such order is approved or favored by not less than two-thirds of the producers voting in such referendum, or by a majority of the producers voting in such referendum if such majority produced not less than two-thirds of the commercial eggs produced during a representative period defined by the Secretary.


(b) Request by Egg Board for referendum(1) If the Egg Board determines, based on a scientific study, marketing analysis, or other similar competent evidence, that an increase in the assessment rate is needed to ensure that assessments under the order are set at an appropriate level to effectuate the policy declared in section 2701 of this title, the Egg Board may request that the Secretary conduct a referendum, as provided in paragraph (2).

(2)(A) If the Egg Board requests the Secretary to conduct a referendum under paragraph (1) or (3), the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among egg producers not exempt from this chapter who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production of commercial eggs, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the producers approve the change in the assessment rate proposed by the Egg Board.

(B) The change in the assessment rate shall become effective if the change is approved or favored by—(i) not less than two-thirds of the producers voting in the referendum; or

(ii) a majority of the producers voting in the referendum, if the majority produced not less than two-thirds of all the commercial eggs produced</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer approval of order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Producer approval of order The Secretary shall conduct a referendum among egg producers not exempt hereunder who, during a representative period determined by the Secretary, have been engaged in the production of commercial eggs, for the purpose of ascertaining whether the issuance of an order is approved or favored by such producers. No order issued pursuant to this chapter shall be effective unless the Secretary determines that the issuance of such order is approved or favored by not less than two-thirds of the producers voting in such referendum, or by a majority of the producers voting in such referendum if such majority produced not less than two-thirds of the commercial eggs produced during a representative period defined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request by Egg Board for referendum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Request by Egg Board for referendum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapproval of amendments as not invalidating order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonapproval of amendments as not invalidating order The failure of egg producers to approve an amendment to any Egg Research and Promotion Order shall not be deemed to invalidate such order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>