<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2715" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2715/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2715/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2715"><akn:num>2715</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of organizations; required contents of report as criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2715. Certification of organizations; required contents of report as criteria
The eligibility of any organization to represent commercial egg producers of any egg producing area of the United States to request the issuance of an order under section 2704 of this title, and to participate in the making of nominations under section 2707(b) of this title shall be certified by the Secretary. Certification shall be based, in addition to other available information, upon a factual report submitted by the organization which shall contain information deemed relevant and specified by the Secretary for the making of such determination, including, but not limited to, the following:(a) Geographic territory covered by the organization’s active membership.

(b) Nature and size of the organization’s active membership, proportion of total of such active membership accounted for by producers of commercial eggs, a chart showing the egg production by State in which the organization has members, and the volume of commercial eggs produced by the organization’s active membership in each such State,

(c) The extent to which the commercial egg producer membership of such organization is represented in setting the organization’s policies,

(d) Evidence of stability and permanency of the organization,

(e) Sources from which the organization’s operating funds are derived,

(f) Functions of the organization, and

(g) The organization’s ability and willingness to further the aims and objectives of this chapter: Provided, however, That the primary consideration in determining the eligibility of an organization shall be whether its commercial egg producer membership consists of a substantial number of egg producers who produce a substantial volume of commercial eggs. The Secretary shall certify any organization which he finds to be eligible under this section and his determination as to eligibility shall be final. Where more than one organization is certified in any geographic area, such organi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Geographic territory covered by the organization’s active membership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nature and size of the organization’s active membership, proportion of total of such active membership accounted for by producers of commercial eggs, a chart showing the egg production by State in which the organization has members, and the volume of commercial eggs produced by the organization’s active membership in each such State,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The extent to which the commercial egg producer membership of such organization is represented in setting the organization’s policies,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evidence of stability and permanency of the organization,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sources from which the organization’s operating funds are derived,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Functions of the organization, and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The organization’s ability and willingness to further the aims and objectives of this chapter: Provided, however, That the primary consideration in determining the eligibility of an organization shall be whether its commercial egg producer membership consists of a substantial number of egg producers who produce a substantial volume of commercial eggs. The Secretary shall certify any organization which he finds to be eligible under this section and his determination as to eligibility shall be final. Where more than one organization is certified in any geographic area, such organizations may caucus to determine the area’s nominations under section 2707(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>