<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/27c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/27c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/27c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_27c"><akn:num>27c</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain other identified banking products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 27c. Exclusion of certain other identified banking products(a) In generalNo provision of the Commodity Exchange Act [7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.] shall apply to, and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall not exercise regulatory authority with respect to, a banking product if the product is a hybrid instrument that is predominantly a banking product under the predominance test set forth in subsection (b).


(b) Predominance testA hybrid instrument shall be considered to be predominantly a banking product for purposes of this section if—(1) the issuer of the hybrid instrument receives payment in full of the purchase price of the hybrid instrument substantially contemporaneously with delivery of the hybrid instrument;

(2) the purchaser or holder of the hybrid instrument is not required to make under the terms of the instrument, or any arrangement referred to in the instrument, any payment to the issuer in addition to the purchase price referred to in paragraph (1), whether as margin, settlement payment, or otherwise during the life of the hybrid instrument or at maturity;

(3) the issuer of the hybrid instrument is not subject by the terms of the instrument to mark-to-market margining requirements; and

(4) the hybrid instrument is not marketed as a contract of sale of a commodity for future delivery (or option on such a contract) subject to the Commodity Exchange Act [7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.].


(c) Mark-to-market margining requirementFor purposes of subsection (b)(3) of this title, mark-to-market margining requirements shall not include the obligation of an issuer of a secured debt instrument to increase the amount of collateral held in pledge for the benefit of the purchaser of the secured debt instrument to secure the repayment obligations of the issuer under the secured debt instrument.


(Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(5) [title IV, § 405], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–459.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Commodity Exchange Act, referred to in subsecs. (a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_27c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general No provision of the Commodity Exchange Act [7 U.S.C. 1 et seq.] shall apply to, and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission shall not exercise regulatory authority with respect to, a banking product if the product is a hybrid instrument that is predominantly a banking product under the predominance test set forth in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_27c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Predominance test</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Predominance test A hybrid instrument shall be considered to be predominantly a banking product for purposes of this section if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_27c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mark-to-market margining requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mark-to-market margining requirement For purposes of subsection (b)(3) of this title, mark-to-market margining requirements shall not include the obligation of an issuer of a secured debt instrument to increase the amount of collateral held in pledge for the benefit of the purchaser of the secured debt instrument to secure the repayment obligations of the issuer under the secured debt instrument.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>