<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/281" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/281/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/281/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_281"><akn:num>281</akn:num><akn:heading>Honeybee importation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 281. Honeybee importation(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to prohibit or restrict the importation or entry of honeybees and honeybee semen into or through the United States in order to prevent the introduction and spread of diseases and parasites harmful to honeybees, the introduction of genetically undesirable germ plasm of honeybees, or the introduction and spread of undesirable species or subspecies of honeybees and the semen of honeybees.


(b) RegulationsThe Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury are each authorized to prescribe such regulations as the respective Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.


(c) EnforcementHoneybees or honeybee semen offered for importation into, intercepted entering, or having entered the United States, other than in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be destroyed or immediately exported.


(d) “Honeybee” definedAs used in this chapter, the term “honeybee” means all life stages and the germ plasm of honeybees of the genus Apis, except honeybee semen.


(Aug. 31, 1922, ch. 301, § 1, 42 Stat. 833; Pub. L. 87–539, § 1, July 19, 1962, 76 Stat. 169; Pub. L. 94–319, § 1, June 25, 1976, 90 Stat. 709; Pub. L. 103–182, title III, § 361(d)(2), Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2123; Pub. L. 103–465, title IV, § 431(e), Dec. 8, 1994, 108 Stat. 4968.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–465 amended section generally, substituting present provisions for former subsecs. (a) to (e) restricting importation of honeybees and honeybee semen into United States, providing for promulgation of rules and regulations as to such importation, providing for destruction or immediate exportation of nonexcepted honeybees or honeybee semen offered for import or intercepted, and defining “honeybee”.
1993—Subsec. (a)(3). Pub. L. 103–182, § 361(d)(2)(A), added par. (3).
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 103–182, § 361(d)(2)(B), inserted “(1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to prohibit or restrict the importation or entry of honeybees and honeybee semen into or through the United States in order to prevent the introduction and spread of diseases and parasites harmful to honeybees, the introduction of genetically undesirable germ plasm of honeybees, or the introduction and spread of undesirable species or subspecies of honeybees and the semen of honeybees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations The Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury are each authorized to prescribe such regulations as the respective Secretary determines necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement Honeybees or honeybee semen offered for importation into, intercepted entering, or having entered the United States, other than in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be destroyed or immediately exported.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Honeybee” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Honeybee” defined As used in this chapter, the term “honeybee” means all life stages and the germ plasm of honeybees of the genus Apis, except honeybee semen.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>