<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2904"><akn:num>2904</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2904. Required terms in orders
An order issued under section 2903(b) of this title shall contain the following terms and conditions:(1) The order shall provide for the establishment and selection of a Cattlemen’s Beef Promotion and Research Board. Members of the Board shall be cattle producers and importers appointed by the Secretary from (A) nominations submitted by eligible State organizations certified under section 2905 of this title (or, if the Secretary determines that there is no eligible State organization in a State, the Secretary may provide for nominations from such State to be made in a different manner), and (B) nominations submitted by importers under such procedures as the Secretary determines appropriate. In determining geographic representation for cattle producers on the Board, whole States shall be considered as a unit. Each State that has a total cattle inventory greater than five hundred thousand head shall be entitled to at least one representative on the Board. A State that has a total inventory of fewer than 500,000 cattle shall be grouped, as far as practicable, with other States each of which has a combined total inventory of not less than 500,000 cattle, into geographically contiguous units in a manner prescribed in the order. A unit may be represented on the Board by more than one member. For each additional million head of cattle within a unit, such unit shall be entitled to an additional member on the Board. The Board may recommend a change in the level of inventory per unit necessary for representation on the Board and, on such recommendation, the Secretary may change the level necessary for representation on the Board. The number of members on the Board that represent importers shall be determined by the Secretary on a proportional basis, by converting the volume of imported beef and beef products into live animal equivalencies.

(2) The order shall define the powers and duties of the Board, which shall be exercised at an annual mee</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The order shall provide for the establishment and selection of a Cattlemen’s Beef Promotion and Research Board. Members of the Board shall be cattle producers and importers appointed by the Secretary from (A) nominations submitted by eligible State organizations certified under section 2905 of this title (or, if the Secretary determines that there is no eligible State organization in a State, the Secretary may provide for nominations from such State to be made in a different manner), and (B) nominations submitted by importers under such procedures as the Secretary determines appropriate. In determining geographic representation for cattle producers on the Board, whole States shall be considered as a unit. Each State that has a total cattle inventory greater than five hundred thousand head shall be entitled to at least one representative on the Board. A State that has a total inventory of fewer than 500,000 cattle shall be grouped, as far as practicable, with other States each of wh</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The order shall define the powers and duties of the Board, which shall be exercised at an annual meeting, and shall include only the following powers: In addition, the order shall determine the circumstances under which special meetings of the Board may be held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The order shall provide that the term of appointment to the Board shall be three years with no member serving more than two consecutive terms, except that initial appointments shall be proportionately for one-year, two-year, and three-year terms; and that Board members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for their reasonable expenses incurred in performing their duties as members of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The order shall provide that terms of appointment to the Committee shall be one year, and that no person may serve on the Committee for more than six consecutive terms. Committee members shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for their reasonable expenses incurred in performing their duties as members of the Committee. The Committee may utilize the resources, staffs, and facilities of the Board and industry organizations. An employee of an industry organization may not receive compensation for work performed for the Committee, but shall be reimbursed from assessments collected by the Board for reasonable expenses incurred in performing such work.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The order shall provide that, to ensure coordination and efficient use of funds, the Committee shall enter into contracts or agreements for implementing and carrying out the activities authorized by this chapter with established national nonprofit industry-governed organizations, including the federation referred to in paragraph (4), to implement programs of promotion, research, consumer information, and industry information. Any such contract or agreement shall provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The order shall require the Board and the Committee to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The order shall provide that the Board, with the approval of the Secretary, may invest, pending disbursement, funds collected through assessments only in obligations of the United States or any agency thereof, in general obligations of any State or any political subdivision thereof, in any interest-bearing account or certificate of deposit of a bank that is a member of the Federal Reserve System, or in obligations fully guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2904_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The order shall prohibit any funds collected by the Board under the order from being used in any manner for the purpose of influencing governmental action or policy, with the exception of recommending amendments to the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>