<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2907"><akn:num>2907</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2907. Refunds(a) Establishment of escrow accountDuring the period prior to the approval of the continuation of an order pursuant to the referendum required under section 2906(a) of this title, subject to subsection (f), the Board shall—(1) establish an escrow account to be used for assessment refunds;

(2) place funds in such account in accordance with subsection (b); and

(3) refund assessments to persons in accordance with this section.


(b) Funding escrow accountSubject to subsection (f), the Board shall place in such account, from assessments collected under section 2906 of this title during the period referred to in subsection (a), an amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—(1) the total amount of assessments collected under section 2906 of this title during such period; by

(2) the greater of—(A) the average rate of assessment refunds provided to producers under State beef promotion, research, and consumer information programs financed through producer assessments, as determined by the Board; or

(B) 15 percent.



(c) Demand and receipt of one-time refundSubject to subsections (d), (e), and (f) and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter,11 See References in Text note below. any person shall have the right to demand and receive from the Board a one-time refund of all assessments collected under section 2906 of this title from such person during the period referred to in subsection (a) if such person—(1) is responsible for paying such assessment; and

(2) does not support the program established under this chapter.


(d) Form and time period for demand for one-time refundSuch demand shall be made in accordance with regulations, on a form, and within a time period prescribed by the Board.


(e) Submission of proof for one-time refundSuch refund shall be made on submission of proof satisfactory to the Board that the producer, person, or importer—(1) paid the assessment for which refund is sought; and

(2) did not collect such assessmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of escrow account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of escrow account During the period prior to the approval of the continuation of an order pursuant to the referendum required under section 2906(a) of this title, subject to subsection (f), the Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding escrow account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding escrow account Subject to subsection (f), the Board shall place in such account, from assessments collected under section 2906 of this title during the period referred to in subsection (a), an amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demand and receipt of one-time refund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Demand and receipt of one-time refund Subject to subsections (d), (e), and (f) and notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter,11 See References in Text note below. any person shall have the right to demand and receive from the Board a one-time refund of all assessments collected under section 2906 of this title from such person during the period referred to in subsection (a) if such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and time period for demand for one-time refund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Form and time period for demand for one-time refund Such demand shall be made in accordance with regulations, on a form, and within a time period prescribed by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of proof for one-time refund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Submission of proof for one-time refund Such refund shall be made on submission of proof satisfactory to the Board that the producer, person, or importer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insufficiency of funds in escrow account; pro­ration of funds among eligible persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Insufficiency of funds in escrow account; pro­ration of funds among eligible persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>