<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2908" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2908/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/2908/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2908"><akn:num>2908</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2908. Enforcement(a) Restraining order; civil penaltyIf the Secretary believes that the administration and enforcement of this chapter or an order would be adequately served by such procedure, following an opportunity for an administrative hearing on the record, the Secretary may—(1) issue an order to restrain or prevent a person from violating an order; and

(2) assess a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 for violation of such order.


(b) Jurisdiction of district courtThe district courts of the United States are vested with jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to prevent and restrain a person from violating, an order or regulation made or issued under this chapter.


(c) Civil action to be referred to Attorney GeneralA civil action authorized to be brought under this section shall be referred to the Attorney General for appropriate action.


(Pub. L. 94–294, § 9, May 28, 1976, 90 Stat. 534; Pub. L. 95–334, title III, § 302, Aug. 4, 1978, 92 Stat. 433; Pub. L. 99–198, title XVI, § 1601(b), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1605.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1985—Pub. L. 99–198 amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to enforcement for provisions relating to referendum and cattle producer approval of orders, reimbursement of expenses by Secretary, procedural requirements, and bonding requirements.
1978—Pub. L. 95–334 substituted “a majority” for “not less than two-thirds”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1985 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 99–198 effective Jan. 1, 1986, see section 1601(c) of Pub. L. 99–198, set out as a note under section 2901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2908_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restraining order; civil penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Restraining order; civil penalty If the Secretary believes that the administration and enforcement of this chapter or an order would be adequately served by such procedure, following an opportunity for an administrative hearing on the record, the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2908_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of district court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Jurisdiction of district court The district courts of the United States are vested with jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to prevent and restrain a person from violating, an order or regulation made or issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2908_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil action to be referred to Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil action to be referred to Attorney General A civil action authorized to be brought under this section shall be referred to the Attorney General for appropriate action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>