<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3007"><akn:num>3007</akn:num><akn:heading>Seniors farmers’ market nutrition program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3007. Seniors farmers’ market nutrition program(a) FundingOf the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary of Agriculture shall use to carry out and expand the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program $20,600,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.


(b) Program purposesThe purposes of the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program are—(1) to provide resources in the form of fresh, nutritious, unprepared, locally grown fruits, vegetables, honey, and herbs from farmers’ markets, roadside stands, and community supported agriculture programs to low-income seniors;

(2) to increase the domestic consumption of agricultural commodities by expanding or aiding in the expansion of domestic farmers’ markets, roadside stands, and community supported agriculture programs; and

(3) to develop or aid in the development of new and additional farmers’ markets, roadside stands, and community supported agriculture programs.


(c) Exclusion of benefits in determining eligibility for other programsThe value of any benefit provided to any eligible seniors farmers’ market nutrition program recipient under this section shall not be considered to be income or resources for any purposes under any Federal, State, or local law.


(d) Prohibition on collection of sales taxEach State shall ensure that no State or local tax is collected within the State on a purchase of food with a benefit distributed under the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program.


(e) RegulationsThe Secretary may promulgate such regulations as the Secretary considers to be necessary to carry out the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program.


(f) Federal law not applicableSection 1693o–2 of title 15 shall not apply to electronic benefit transfer systems established under this section.


(Pub. L. 107–171, title IV, § 4402, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 334; Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, §§ 4231, 4406(c)(1), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1124, 1142; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title IV, §§ 4231, 4406(c)(1), June 18</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Funding Of the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary of Agriculture shall use to carry out and expand the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program $20,600,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program purposes The purposes of the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of benefits in determining eligibility for other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of benefits in determining eligibility for other programs The value of any benefit provided to any eligible seniors farmers’ market nutrition program recipient under this section shall not be considered to be income or resources for any purposes under any Federal, State, or local law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on collection of sales tax</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on collection of sales tax Each State shall ensure that no State or local tax is collected within the State on a purchase of food with a benefit distributed under the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary may promulgate such regulations as the Secretary considers to be necessary to carry out the seniors farmers’ market nutrition program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3007_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal law not applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal law not applicable Section 1693o–2 of title 15 shall not apply to electronic benefit transfer systems established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>