<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3123a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3123a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3123a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3123a"><akn:num>3123a</akn:num><akn:heading>Specialty crop committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3123a. Specialty crop committee(a) Establishment(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after December 21, 2004, the executive committee of the Advisory Board shall establish, and appoint the initial members of, a permanent specialty crops committee that will be responsible for studying the scope and effectiveness of research, extension, and economics programs affecting the specialty crop industry.


(2) Citrus disease subcommittee(A) In generalNot later than 45 days after February 7, 2014, the Secretary shall establish within the specialty crops committee, and appoint the initial members of, a citrus disease subcommittee to carry out the responsibilities of the subcommittee described in subsection (g) in accordance with subsection (j)(3) of section 7632 of this title.


(B) CompositionThe citrus disease subcommittee shall be composed of 11 members, each of whom is a domestic producer of citrus in a State, represented as follows:(i) Five of such members shall represent Arizona or California.

(ii) Five of such members shall represent Florida.

(iii) One of such members shall represent Texas.


(C) MembershipThe Secretary may appoint individuals who are not members of the specialty crops committee or the Advisory Board established under section 3123 of this title as members of the citrus disease subcommittee 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(D) TerminationThe subcommittee established under subparagraph (A) shall terminate on September 30, 2023.


(E) Chapter 10 of title 5The subcommittee established under subparagraph (A) shall be covered by the exemption to section 1008(c) of title 5 applicable to the Advisory Board under section 3123(f) of this title.




(b) Members(1) EligibilityIndividuals who are not members of the Advisory Board may be appointed as members of the specialty crops committee.


(2) ServiceMembers of the specialty crops committee shall serve at the discretion of the executive committee.


(3) DiversityMembership of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual committee report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual committee report Not later than 180 days after the establishment of the specialty crops committee, and annually thereafter, the specialty crops committee shall submit to the Advisory Board a report containing the findings of its study under subsection (a). The specialty crops committee shall include in each report recommendations regarding the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with specialty crop industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation with specialty crop industry In studying the scope and effectiveness of programs under subsection (a), the specialty crops committee shall consult on an ongoing basis with diverse sectors of the specialty crop industry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consideration by Secretary In preparing the annual budget recommendations for the Department of Agriculture, the Secretary shall take into consideration those findings and recommendations contained in the most-recent report of the specialty crops committee that are adopted by the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report by Secretary In the budget material submitted to Congress by the Secretary in connection with the budget submitted pursuant to section 1105 of title 31 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall include a report describing how the Secretary addressed each recommendation of the specialty crops committee described in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3123a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citrus disease subcommittee duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Citrus disease subcommittee duties For the purposes of subsection (j) of section 7632 of this title, the citrus disease subcommittee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>