<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3125a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3125a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3125a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3125a"><akn:num>3125a</akn:num><akn:heading>National Agricultural Library</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3125a. National Agricultural Library(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to consolidate and expand the statutory authority for the operation of the library of the Department of Agriculture established pursuant to section 2201 of this title as the primary agricultural information resource of the United States.


(b) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department of Agriculture the National Agricultural Library to serve as the primary agricultural information resource of the United States.


(c) DirectorThe Secretary shall appoint a Director for the National Agricultural Library who shall be subject to the direction of the Secretary.


(d) Functions of DirectorThe Director may—(1) acquire, preserve, and manage information and information products and services in all phases of agriculture and allied sciences;

(2) organize agricultural information and information products and services by cataloging, indexing, bibliographical listing, and other appropriate techniques;

(3) provide agricultural information and information products and services to agencies of the Department of Agriculture and the Federal Government, public and private organizations, and individuals, within the United States and internationally;

(4) plan for, coordinate, and evaluate information and library needs related to agricultural research and education;

(5) cooperate with and coordinate efforts among agricultural college and university libraries, in conjunction with private industry and other agricultural library and information centers, toward the development of a comprehensive agricultural library and information network; and

(6) coordinate the development of specialized subject information services among the agricultural and library information communities.


(e) Library products and servicesThe Director may—(1) make copies of the bibliographies prepared by the National Agricultural Library;

(2) make microforms and other reproductions of books and other library materials in the De</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to consolidate and expand the statutory authority for the operation of the library of the Department of Agriculture established pursuant to section 2201 of this title as the primary agricultural information resource of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established in the Department of Agriculture the National Agricultural Library to serve as the primary agricultural information resource of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Director The Secretary shall appoint a Director for the National Agricultural Library who shall be subject to the direction of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions of Director The Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Library products and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Library products and services The Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Receipts Funds received from sales under subsection (e) shall be deposited in the Treasury of the United States to the credit of the applicable appropriation and shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3125a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>