<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3127" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3127/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3127/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3127"><akn:num>3127</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3127. Support for Advisory Board(a) Appointment of staffTo assist the Advisory Board in the performance of its duties, the Secretary may appoint, after consultation with the chairperson of the Advisory Board—(1) a full-time executive director who shall perform such duties as the chairperson of the Advisory Board may direct and who shall receive compensation at a rate not to exceed the rate payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule established in section 5332 of title 5; and

(2) a professional staff of not more than five full-time employees qualified in the food and agricultural sciences, of which one shall serve as the executive secretary to the Advisory Board.


(b) Additional clerical assistance and staff personnelThe Secretary shall provide such additional clerical assistance and staff personnel as may be required to assist the Advisory Board in carrying out its duties.


(c) Assistance of outside personnelIn formulating its recommendations to the Secretary, the Advisory Board may obtain the assistance of Department of Agriculture employees, and, to the maximum extent practicable, the assistance of employees of other Federal departments and agencies conducting related programs of agricultural research, extension, and teaching and of appropriate representatives of colleges and universities, including State agricultural experiment stations, cooperative extension services, and other non-Federal organizations conducting significant programs in the food and agricultural sciences.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1412, Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 991; Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1413, Dec. 22, 1981, 95 Stat. 1302; Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1605(b)(1), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3713; Pub. L. 102–237, title IV, § 402(5), Dec. 13, 1991, 105 Stat. 1863; Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, §§ 852(b)(3), 853(b)(4), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1171, 1172; Pub. L. 105–185, title VI, § 606(c)(1), June 23, 1998, 112 Stat. 603.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Subsecs. (a), (b). Pub. L. 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3127_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment of staff To assist the Advisory Board in the performance of its duties, the Secretary may appoint, after consultation with the chairperson of the Advisory Board—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3127_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional clerical assistance and staff personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional clerical assistance and staff personnel The Secretary shall provide such additional clerical assistance and staff personnel as may be required to assist the Advisory Board in carrying out its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3127_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance of outside personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance of outside personnel In formulating its recommendations to the Secretary, the Advisory Board may obtain the assistance of Department of Agriculture employees, and, to the maximum extent practicable, the assistance of employees of other Federal departments and agencies conducting related programs of agricultural research, extension, and teaching and of appropriate representatives of colleges and universities, including State agricultural experiment stations, cooperative extension services, and other non-Federal organizations conducting significant programs in the food and agricultural sciences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>