<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3151a"><akn:num>3151a</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterinary medicine loan repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3151a. Veterinary medicine loan repayment(a) Program(1) Service in shortage situationsThe Secretary shall carry out a program of entering into agreements with veterinarians under which the veterinarians agree to provide, for a period of time as determined by the Secretary and specified in the agreement, veterinary services in veterinarian shortage situations. For each year of such service under an agreement under this paragraph, the Secretary shall pay an amount, as determined by the Secretary and specified in the agreement, of the principal and interest of qualifying educational loans of the veterinarians.


(2) Service to Federal Government in emergency situations(A) In generalThe Secretary may enter into agreements of 1 year duration with veterinarians who have agreements pursuant to paragraph (1) for such veterinarians to provide services to the Federal Government in emergency situations, as determined by the Secretary, under terms and conditions specified in the agreement. Pursuant to an agreement under this paragraph, the Secretary shall pay an amount, in addition to the amount paid pursuant to the agreement in paragraph (1), as determined by the Secretary and specified in the agreement, of the principal and interest of qualifying educational loans of the veterinarians.


(B) RequirementsAgreements entered into under this paragraph shall include the following:(i) A veterinarian shall not be required to serve more than 60 working days per year of the agreement.

(ii) A veterinarian who provides service pursuant to the agreement shall receive a salary commensurate with the duties and shall be reimbursed for travel and per diem expenses as appropriate for the duration of the service.




(b) Determination of veterinarian shortage situationsIn determining “veterinarian shortage situations”, the Secretary may consider—(1) geographical areas that the Secretary determines have a shortage of veterinarians; and

(2) areas of veterinary practice that the Secretary det</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of veterinarian shortage situations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of veterinarian shortage situations In determining “veterinarian shortage situations”, the Secretary may consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds None of the funds appropriated to the Secretary under subsection (f) may be used to carry out section 5379 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations Notwithstanding subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5, not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for carrying out this section such sums as may be necessary and such sums shall remain available to the Secretary for the purposes of this section until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>