<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3151b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3151b"><akn:num>3151b</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterinary services grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3151b. Veterinary services grant program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Qualified entityThe term “qualified entity” means—(A) a for-profit or nonprofit entity located in the United States that, or an individual who, operates a veterinary clinic providing veterinary services—(i) in a rural area, as defined in section 1991(a) of this title; and

(ii) in a veterinarian shortage situation;


(B) a State, national, allied, or regional veterinary organization or specialty board recognized by the American Veterinary Medical Association;

(C) a college or school of veterinary medicine accredited by the American Veterinary Medical Association;

(D) a university research foundation or veterinary medical foundation;

(E) a department of veterinary science or department of comparative medicine accredited by the Department of Education;

(F) a State agricultural experiment station; or

(G) a State, local, or tribal government agency.


(2) Veterinarian shortage situationThe term “veterinarian shortage situation” means a veterinarian shortage situation as determined by the Secretary under section 3151a of this title.



(b) Establishment(1) Competitive grantsThe Secretary shall carry out a program to make competitive grants to qualified entities that carry out programs or activities described in paragraph (2) for the purpose of developing, implementing, and sustaining veterinary services.


(2) Eligibility requirementsA qualified entity shall be eligible to receive a grant described in paragraph (1) if the entity carries out programs or activities that the Secretary determines will—(A) substantially relieve veterinarian shortage situations;

(B) support or facilitate private veterinary practices engaged in public health activities; or

(C) support or facilitate the practices of veterinarians who are providing or have completed providing services under an agreement entered into with the Secretary under section 3151a(a)(2) of this title.



(c) Award processes and preferences(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award processes and preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award processes and preferences</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grants to relieve veterinarian shortage situations and support veterinary services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of grants to relieve veterinarian shortage situations and support veterinary services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special requirements for certain grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special requirements for certain grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of grant funds for construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on use of grant funds for construction Except as provided in subsection (d)(2), funds made available for grants under this section may not be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations Not later than 1 year after February 7, 2014, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3151b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>