<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3153"><akn:num>3153</akn:num><akn:heading>National Agricultural Science Award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3153. National Agricultural Science Award(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish the National Agricultural Science Award for research or advanced studies in the food and agricultural sciences, including the social sciences. Two such awards, one for each of the categories described in subsection (d) of this section, shall be made in each fiscal year.


(b) Amount and termThe awards shall not exceed $50,000 per year for a period of not to exceed three years to support research or study by the recipient.


(c) EligibilityThe awards shall be open to persons in agricultural research, extension, teaching, or any combination thereof.


(d) CategoriesAwards under this section shall be made in each fiscal year in two categories as follows:(1) to a scientist in recognition of outstanding contributions to the advancement of the food and agricultural sciences; and

(2) to a research scientist in early career development or a graduate student, in recognition of demonstrated capability and promise of significant future achievement in the food and agricultural sciences.


(e) Nominating and selection committeesThe Secretary may establish such nominating and selection committees, to consist of scientists and others, to receive nominations and make recommendations for awards under this section, as the Secretary deems appropriate.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1418, Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 997; Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1420(a), Dec. 22, 1981, 95 Stat. 1306.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1981—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 97–98, § 1420(a)(2), substituted “Science Award” for “Research Award”, and “subsection (d)” for “subsection (c)”.
Subsecs. (c) to (e). Pub. L. 97–98, § 1420(a)(3), (4), added subsec. (c) and redesignated former subsecs. (c) and (d) as (d) and (e), respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1981 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 97–98 effective Dec. 22, 1981, see section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98, set out as an Effective Date note under sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish the National Agricultural Science Award for research or advanced studies in the food and agricultural sciences, including the social sciences. Two such awards, one for each of the categories described in subsection (d) of this section, shall be made in each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount and term The awards shall not exceed $50,000 per year for a period of not to exceed three years to support research or study by the recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility The awards shall be open to persons in agricultural research, extension, teaching, or any combination thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Categories Awards under this section shall be made in each fiscal year in two categories as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3153_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominating and selection committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nominating and selection committees The Secretary may establish such nominating and selection committees, to consist of scientists and others, to receive nominations and make recommendations for awards under this section, as the Secretary deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>