<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3157" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3157/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3157/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3157"><akn:num>3157</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive, special, and facilities research grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3157. Competitive, special, and facilities research grants(a) Establishment of grant program(1) In order to promote research in food, agriculture, and related areas, a research grants program is hereby established in the Department of Agriculture.

(2) Short Title.—This section may be cited as the “Competitive, Special, and Facilities Research Grant Act”.


(b) Agriculture and food research initiative(1) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department of Agriculture an Agriculture and Food Research Initiative under which the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this subsection as “the Secretary”) may make competitive grants for fundamental and applied research, extension, and education to address food and agricultural sciences (as defined under section 3103 of this title).


(2) Priority areasThe competitive grants program established under this subsection shall address the following areas:(A) Plant health and production and plant productsPlant systems, including—(i) plant genome structure and function;

(ii) molecular and cellular genetics and plant biotechnology;

(iii) conventional breeding, including cultivar and breed development, selection theory, applied quantitative genetics, breeding for improved food quality, breeding for improved local adaptation to biotic stress and abiotic stress, and participatory breeding;

(iv) plant-pest interactions and biocontrol systems;

(v) crop plant response to environmental stresses;

(vi) unproved nutrient qualities of plant products; and

(vii) new food and industrial uses of plant products.


(B) Animal health and production and animal productsAnimal systems, including—(i) aquaculture;

(ii) cellular and molecular basis of animal reproduction, growth, disease, and health;

(iii) animal biotechnology;

(iv) conventional breeding, including breed development, selection theory, applied quantitative genetics, breeding for improved food quality, breeding for improved local adaptation to biotic stress and abiotic stre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agriculture and food research initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agriculture and food research initiative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension design and demonstration initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Extension design and demonstration initiative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inter-Regional Research Project Number 4</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inter-Regional Research Project Number 4</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record keeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Record keeping Each recipient of assistance under this section shall keep such records as the Secretary of Agriculture shall, by regulation, prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such grants, the total cost of the project or undertaking in connection with which such funds are given or used, and the amount of that portion of the costs of the project or undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit. The Secretary of Agriculture and the Comptroller General of the United States or any of their duly authorized representatives shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipients that are pertinent to the grants received under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits on overhead costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limits on overhead costs The Secretary of Agriculture shall limit allowable overhead costs, with respect to grants awarded under this section, to those necessary to carry out the purposes of the grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations Except as otherwise provided in subsections (b), (d), and (e), there are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Rules The Secretary of Agriculture may issue such rules and regulations as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3157_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Application of other laws Chapter 10 of title 5 and title XVIII of the Food and Agriculture Act of 1977 (7 U.S.C. 2281 et seq.) shall not apply to a panel or board created for the purpose of reviewing applications or proposals submitted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>