<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3159" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3159/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3159/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3159"><akn:num>3159</akn:num><akn:heading>Land-grant designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3159. Land-grant designation(a) Prohibition on designation(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), beginning on December 20, 2018, no additional entity may be designated as eligible to receive funds under a covered program.


(2) 1994 institutionsThe prohibition under paragraph (1) with respect to the designation of an entity eligible to receive funds under a covered program shall not apply in the case of the certification of a 1994 Institution under section 2 of Public Law 87–788 (commonly known as the “McIntire-Stennis Cooperative Forestry Act”) (16 U.S.C. 582a–1).


(3) Extraordinary circumstancesIn the case of extraordinary circumstances or a situation that would lead to an inequitable result, as determined by the Secretary, the Secretary may determine that an entity designated after December 20, 2018, is eligible to receive funds under a covered program.



(b) State fundingNo State shall receive an increase in funding under a covered program as a result of the State’s designation of additional entities as eligible to receive such funding.


(c) Covered program definedFor purposes of this section, the term “covered program” means agricultural research, extension, education, and related programs or grants established or available under any of the following:(1) Subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 343 of this title.

(2) The Hatch Act of 1887 (7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.).

(3) Sections 3221, 3222, and 3222b of this title.

(4) Public Law 87–788 (commonly known as the McIntire-Stennis Cooperative Forestry Act; 16 U.S.C. 582a et seq.).


(d) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed as limiting eligibility for a capacity and infrastructure program specified in section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title that is not a covered program.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1419D, as added Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7111, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4784.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3159_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3159_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State funding No State shall receive an increase in funding under a covered program as a result of the State’s designation of additional entities as eligible to receive such funding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3159_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered program defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Covered program defined For purposes of this section, the term “covered program” means agricultural research, extension, education, and related programs or grants established or available under any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3159_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting eligibility for a capacity and infrastructure program specified in section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title that is not a covered program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>