<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3173" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3173/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3173/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3173"><akn:num>3173</akn:num><akn:heading>Research by Department of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3173. Research by Department of Agriculture(a) Increase in level of supportThe Secretary shall establish research into food and human nutrition as a separate and distinct mission of the Department of Agriculture, and the Secretary shall increase support for such research to a level that provides resources adequate to meet the policy of this subchapter.


(b) Periodic consultation with administrators of other Federal departments and agenciesThe Secretary, in administering the food and human nutrition research program, shall periodically consult with the administrators of the other Federal departments and agencies that have responsibility for programs dealing with human food and nutrition, as to the specific research needs of those departments and agencies.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1423, Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 999.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1977, see section 1901 of Pub. L. 95–113, set out as an Effective Date of 1977 Amendment note under section 1307 of this title.

National Food and Human Nutrition Research Program; Congressional Findings; Comprehensive Plan; Annual Report; Joint Dietary Assessment, Studies and Reports; Submission of Plan and Reports to Congressional CommitteesPub. L. 99–198, title XIV, subtitle B, §§ 1451–1453, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1561, 1562, as amended by Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 872, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1175, provided that:
“findings“Sec. 1451. Congress finds that—“(1) nutrition and health considerations are important to United States agricultural policy;

“(2) section 1405 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (7 U.S.C. 3121) designates the Department of Agriculture as the lead agency of the Federal Government for human nutrition research (except with respect to the biomedical aspects of human nutrition concerned with diagnosis or treatment of disease);

“(3) section 1423 of such Act (7 U.S.C. 3173) requires the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3173_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase in level of support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Increase in level of support The Secretary shall establish research into food and human nutrition as a separate and distinct mission of the Department of Agriculture, and the Secretary shall increase support for such research to a level that provides resources adequate to meet the policy of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3173_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic consultation with administrators of other Federal departments and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic consultation with administrators of other Federal departments and agencies The Secretary, in administering the food and human nutrition research program, shall periodically consult with the administrators of the other Federal departments and agencies that have responsibility for programs dealing with human food and nutrition, as to the specific research needs of those departments and agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>