<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3175b"><akn:num>3175b</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of effective food, nutrition, and consumer education services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3175b. Expansion of effective food, nutrition, and consumer education services
The purpose of the program provided for under sections 3175a through 3175e of this title is to expand effective food, nutrition, and consumer education services to the greatest practicable number of low-income individuals, including those participating in or eligible to participate in the programs under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 [7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.], to assist them to—(1) increase their ability to manage their food budgets, including food stamps and other food assistance;

(2) increase their ability to buy food that satisfies nutritional needs and promotes good health; and

(3) improve their food preparation, storage, safety, preservation, and sanitation practices.

(Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1585, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1596.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Food Stamp Act of 1977, referred to in text, subsequently renamed the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, is Pub. L. 88–525, Aug. 31, 1964, 78 Stat. 703, which is classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2011 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Food Security Act of 1985, and not as part of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3175b_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) increase their ability to manage their food budgets, including food stamps and other food assistance;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3175b_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) increase their ability to buy food that satisfies nutritional needs and promotes good health; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3175b_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) improve their food preparation, storage, safety, preservation, and sanitation practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>