<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3175d"><akn:num>3175d</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of program of food, nutrition, and consumer education by State cooperative extension </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3175d. Administration of program of food, nutrition, and consumer education by State cooperative extension services(a) Administration by Secretary of AgricultureThe program provided for under section 3175c of this title shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, in consultation with the Food and Nutrition Service and the Human Nutrition Information Service. The Secretary shall ensure that the National Institute of Food and Agriculture coordinates activities carried out under this subtitle with the ongoing food, nutrition, and consumer education activities of other agencies of the Department of Agriculture.


(b) Evaluation and reportThe Secretary of Agriculture, not later than April 1, 1989, shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report evaluating the effectiveness of the program provided for under section 3175c of this title.


(Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1587, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1596; Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7511(c)(11), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1268; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, § 7511(c)(11), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2029.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subtitle, referred to in subsec. (a), is subtitle C (§§ 1581–1589) of title XV of Pub. L. 99–198, which is classified as follows: sections 1581 and 1582 are not classified to the Code; section 1583 is set out as a note under section 2011 of this title; sections 1584 through 1588 are classified, respectively, to sections 3175a to 3175e of this title; and section 1589 is classified to section 3178a of this title.

Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.
Section was enacted as part of the Food Security Act of 1985, and not as part of the National Agricultural Research, E</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3175d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration by Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration by Secretary of Agriculture The program provided for under section 3175c of this title shall be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture through the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, in consultation with the Food and Nutrition Service and the Human Nutrition Information Service. The Secretary shall ensure that the National Institute of Food and Agriculture coordinates activities carried out under this subtitle with the ongoing food, nutrition, and consumer education activities of other agencies of the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3175d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation and report The Secretary of Agriculture, not later than April 1, 1989, shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report evaluating the effectiveness of the program provided for under section 3175c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>