<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3175a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3175a"><akn:num>3175a</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutrition and consumer education; Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3175a. Nutrition and consumer education; Congressional findings
Congress finds that individuals in households eligible to participate in programs under the Food Stamp Act of 1977 [7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.] and other low-income individuals, including those residing in rural areas, should have greater access to nutrition and consumer education to enable them to use their food budgets, including food assistance, effectively and to select and prepare foods that satisfy their nutritional needs and improve their diets.
(Pub. L. 99–198, title XV, § 1584, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1596.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Food Stamp Act of 1977, referred to in text, subsequently renamed the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008, is Pub. L. 88–525, Aug. 31, 1964, 78 Stat. 703, which is classified generally to chapter 51 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2011 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Food Security Act of 1985, and not as part of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>