<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3179" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3179/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3179/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3179"><akn:num>3179</akn:num><akn:heading>Research on strategies to promote the selection and consumption of healthy foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3179. Research on strategies to promote the selection and consumption of healthy foods(a) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a research, demonstration, and technical assistance program to promote healthy eating and reduce the prevalence of obesity, among all population groups but especially among children, by applying the principles and insights of behavioral economics research in schools, child care programs, and other settings.


(b) PrioritiesThe Secretary shall—(1) identify and assess the impacts of specific presentation, placement, and other strategies for structuring choices on selection and consumption of healthful foods in a variety of settings, consistent with the most recent version of the Dietary Guidelines for Americans published under section 5341 of this title;

(2) demonstrate and rigorously evaluate behavioral economics-related interventions that hold promise to improve diets and promote health, including through demonstration projects that may include evaluation of the use of portion size, labeling, convenience, and other strategies to encourage healthy choices; and

(3) encourage adoption of the most effective strategies through outreach and technical assistance.


(c) AuthorityIn carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may—(1) enter into competitively awarded contracts or cooperative agreements; or

(2) provide grants to States or public or private agencies or organizations, as determined by the Secretary.


(d) ApplicationTo be eligible to enter into a contract or cooperative agreement or receive a grant under this section, a State or public or private agency or organization shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(e) CoordinationThe solicitation and evaluation of contracts, cooperative agreements, and grant proposals considered under this section shall be </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish a research, demonstration, and technical assistance program to promote healthy eating and reduce the prevalence of obesity, among all population groups but especially among children, by applying the principles and insights of behavioral economics research in schools, child care programs, and other settings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priorities The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application To be eligible to enter into a contract or cooperative agreement or receive a grant under this section, a State or public or private agency or organization shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination The solicitation and evaluation of contracts, cooperative agreements, and grant proposals considered under this section shall be coordinated with the Food and Nutrition Service as appropriate to ensure that funded projects are consistent with the operations of Federally supported nutrition assistance programs and related laws (including regulations).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual reports Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that includes a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3179_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>