<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3191" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3191/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3191/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3191"><akn:num>3191</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes and findings relating to animal health and disease research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3191. Purposes and findings relating to animal health and disease research(a) PurposesThe purposes of this subchapter are to—(1) promote the general welfare through the improved health and productivity of domestic livestock, poultry, aquatic animals, and other income-producing animals that are essential to the food supply of the United States and the welfare of producers and consumers of animal products;

(2) improve the health of horses;

(3) facilitate the effective treatment of, and, to the extent possible, prevent animal and poultry diseases in both domesticated and wild animals that, if not controlled, would be disastrous to the United States livestock and poultry industries and endanger the food supply of the United States;

(4) improve methods for the control of organisms and residues in food products of animal origin that could endanger the human food supply;

(5) improve the housing and management of animals to improve the well-being of livestock production species;

(6) minimize livestock and poultry losses due to transportation and handling;

(7) protect human health through control of animal diseases transmissible to humans;

(8) improve methods of controlling the births of predators and other animals; and

(9) otherwise promote the general welfare through expanded programs of research and extension to improve animal health.


(b) FindingsCongress finds that—(1) the total animal health and disease research and extension efforts of State colleges and universities and of the Federal Government would be more effective if there were close coordination between the efforts; and

(2) colleges and universities having accredited schools or colleges of veterinary medicine and State agricultural experiment stations that conduct animal health and disease research are especially vital in training research workers in animal health and related disciplines.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1429, Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 1001; Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1426, Dec. 22, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purposes of this subchapter are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3191_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>