<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_322"><akn:num>322</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 322. Annual appropriation
There is annually appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to be paid as provided in section 324 of this title, to each State and Territory for the more complete endowment and maintenance of colleges for the benefit of agriculture and the mechanic arts established in accordance with the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter, $50,000 to be applied only to instruction in food and agricultural sciences, and to the facilities for such instruction: Provided, That said colleges may use a portion of this money for providing courses for the special preparation of instructors for teaching the elements of food and agricultural sciences.
(Aug. 30, 1890, ch. 841, § 1, 26 Stat. 417; Mar. 4, 1907, ch. 2907, 34 Stat. 1281, 1282; Pub. L. 97–98, title XIV, § 1421, Dec. 22, 1981, 95 Stat. 1306.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is based on a part of section 1 of act Aug. 30, 1890, and the tenth and eleventh pars. under the heading “Emergency Appropriations” of act Mar. 4, 1907. Remainder of section 1 of act Aug. 30, 1890, is classified to section 323 of this title.

Amendments1981—Pub. L. 97–98 substituted “food and agricultural sciences” for “agriculture, the mechanic arts, the English language, and the various branches of mathematical, physical, natural, and economic science, with special reference to their applications in the industries of life” and “the elements of food and agricultural sciences” for “the elements of agriculture and the mechanic arts”.
1907—Act Mar. 4, 1907, substituted “$50,000” for “$25,000”, and inserted proviso.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1981 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 97–98 effective Dec. 22, 1981, see section 1801 of Pub. L. 97–98, set out as an Effective Date note under section 4301 of this title.


Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions under this section to Secretary of Agriculture, see note set out under section 321 of this title.

Avail</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>