<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3222" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3222/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3222/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3222"><akn:num>3222</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural research at 1890 land-grant colleges, including Tuskegee University</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3222. Agricultural research at 1890 land-grant colleges, including Tuskegee University(a) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalThere are hereby authorized to be appropriated annually such sums as Congress may determine necessary to support continuing agricultural research at colleges eligible to receive funds under the Act of August 30, 1890 (26 Stat. 417–419, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 321–326 and 328), including Tuskegee University (hereinafter referred to in this section as “eligible institutions”).


(2) Minimum amountBeginning with fiscal year 2003, there shall be appropriated under this section for each fiscal year an amount that is not less than 30 percent of the total appropriations for the fiscal year under section 361c of this title.


(3) UsesFunds appropriated under this section shall be used for expenses of conducting agricultural research, printing, disseminating the results of such research, contributing to the retirement of employees subject to the provisions of section 331 of this title, administrative planning and direction, and purchase and rental of land and the construction, acquisition, alteration, or repair of buildings necessary for conducting agricultural research.


(4) CoordinationThe eligible institutions are authorized to plan and conduct agricultural research in cooperation with each other and such agencies, institutions, and individuals as may contribute to the solution of agricultural problems, and moneys appropriated pursuant to this section shall be available for paying the necessary expenses of planning, coordinating, and conducting such cooperative research.


(5) Carryover(A) In generalThe balance of any annual funds provided to an eligible institution for a fiscal year under this section that remains unexpended at the end of the fiscal year may be carried over for use during the following fiscal year.


(B) Failure to expend full amount(i) In generalIf any unexpended balance carried over by an eligible institution is not exp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distribution of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program and plans of work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program and plans of work</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of funds to eligible institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of funds to eligible institutions Sums available for allotment to the eligible institutions under the terms of this section shall be paid to such institutions in equal quarterly payments beginning on or about the first day of October of each year upon vouchers approved by the Secretary. The President of each eligible institution shall appoint a research director who shall be responsible for administration of the program authorized herein. Each eligible institution shall designate a treasurer or other officer who shall receive and account for all funds allotted to such institution under the provisions of this section and shall report, with the approval of the research director, to the Secretary on or before the first day of December of each year a detailed statement of the amount received under the provisions of this section during the preceding fiscal year and its disbursement on schedules prescribed by the Secretary. If any portion of the allotted moneys received by any el</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mailing of bulletins, reports, periodicals, reprints, articles, and other publications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mailing of bulletins, reports, periodicals, reprints, articles, and other publications Bulletins, reports, periodicals, reprints or articles, and other publications necessary for the dissemination of results of the research and experiments funded under this section, including lists of publications available for distribution by the eligible institutions, shall be transmitted in the mails of the United States. Such publications may be mailed from the principal place of business of each eligible institution or from an established subunit of such institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration; rules and regulations; cooperation by and between institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration; rules and regulations; cooperation by and between institutions The Secretary shall be responsible for the proper administration of this section, and is authorized and directed to prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out its provisions. It shall be the duty of the Secretary to furnish such advice and assistance as will best promote the purposes of this section, including participation in coordination of research initiated under this section by the eligible institutions, from time to time to indicate such lines of inquiry as to the Secretary seem most important, and to encourage and assist in the establishment and maintenance of cooperation by and between the several eligible institutions, the State agricultural experiment stations, and between them and the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Entitlement On or before the first day of October in each year after September 29, 1977, the Secretary shall ascertain whether each eligible institution is entitled to receive its share of the annual appropriations under this section and the amount which thereupon each is entitled, respectively, to receive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3222_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing legal relationships not impaired or modified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Existing legal relationships not impaired or modified Nothing in this section shall be construed to impair or modify the legal relationship existing between any of the eligible institutions and the government of the States in which they are respectively located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>