<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3243"><akn:num>3243</akn:num><akn:heading>Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3243. Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities(a) Definition of endowment fundIn this section, the term “endowment fund” means the Hispanic-Serving Agricultural Colleges and Universities Fund established under subsection (b).


(b) Endowment(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall establish in accordance with this subsection a Hispanic-Serving Agricultural Colleges and Universities Fund.


(2) AgreementsThe Secretary of the Treasury may enter into such agreements as are necessary to carry out this subsection.


(3) Deposit to the endowment fundThe Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit in the endowment fund any—(A) amounts made available through Acts of appropriations, which shall be the endowment fund corpus; and

(B) interest earned on the endowment fund corpus.


(4) InvestmentsThe Secretary of the Treasury shall invest the endowment fund corpus and income in interest-bearing obligations of the United States.


(5) Withdrawals and expenditures(A) CorpusThe Secretary of the Treasury may not make a withdrawal or expenditure from the endowment fund corpus.


(B) WithdrawalsOn September 30, 2008, and each September 30 thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall withdraw the amount of the income from the endowment fund for the fiscal year and warrant the funds to the Secretary of Agriculture who, after making adjustments for the cost of administering the endowment fund, shall distribute the adjusted income as follows:(i) 60 percent shall be distributed among the Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities on a pro rata basis based on the Hispanic enrollment count of each institution.

(ii) 40 percent shall be distributed in equal shares to the Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities.



(6) EndowmentsAmounts made available under this subsection shall be held and considered to be granted to Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities to establish an endowment in accordance with this subsection.


(7</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of endowment fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of endowment fund In this section, the term “endowment fund” means the Hispanic-Serving Agricultural Colleges and Universities Fund established under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Endowment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for annual payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization for annual payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional capacity-building grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Institutional capacity-building grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grants program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Competitive grants program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>