<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3293" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3293/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3293/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3293"><akn:num>3293</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural fellowship program for middle income countries, emerging democracies, and emerging mark</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3293. Agricultural fellowship program for middle income countries, emerging democracies, and emerging markets(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a fellowship program for,11 So in original. The word “for” probably should not appear. to be known as the “Cochran Fellowship Program”, to provide fellowships to individuals from eligible countries (as determined under subsection (b)) who specialize in agriculture for study—(1) in the United States; or

(2) at a college or university located in an eligible country that the Secretary determines—(A) has sufficient scientific and technical facilities;

(B) has established a partnership with at least one college or university in the United States; and

(C) has substantial participation by faculty members of the United States college or university in the design of the fellowship curriculum and classroom instruction under the fellowship.



(b) Eligible countriesCountries described in any of the following paragraphs shall be eligible to participate in the program established under this section:(1) Middle-income countryA country that has developed economically to the point where it no longer qualifies for bilateral foreign aid assistance from the United States because its per capita income level exceeds the eligibility requirements of such assistance programs (hereafter referred to in this section as a “middle-income” country).


(2) Ongoing relationshipA middle-income country that has never qualified for bilateral foreign aid assistance from the United States, but with respect to which an ongoing relationship with the United States, including technical assistance and training, would provide mutual benefits to such country and the United States.


(3) Type of governmentA country that has recently begun the transformation of its system of government from a non-representative type of government to a representative democracy and that is encouraging democratic institution building, and the cultural values, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a fellowship program for,11 So in original. The word “for” probably should not appear. to be known as the “Cochran Fellowship Program”, to provide fellowships to individuals from eligible countries (as determined under subsection (b)) who specialize in agriculture for study—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible countries Countries described in any of the following paragraphs shall be eligible to participate in the program established under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose of fellowships Fellowships under this section shall be provided to permit the recipients to gain knowledge and skills that will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals who may receive fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Individuals who may receive fellowships The Secretary shall utilize the expertise of United States agricultural counselors, trade officers, and commodity trade promotion groups working in participating countries to help identify program candidates for fellowships under this section from both the public and private sectors of those countries. The Secretary may provide fellowships under the program authorized by this section to private agricultural producers from eligible countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program implementation The Secretary shall consult with other United States Government agencies, United States universities, and the private agribusiness sector, as appropriate, to design and administer training programs to accomplish the objectives of the program established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated without fiscal year limitation such sums as may be necessary to carry out the program established under this section, except that the amount of such funds in any fiscal year shall not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3293_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complementary funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Complementary funds If the Secretary of Agriculture determines that it is advisable in furtherance of the purposes of the program established under this section, the Secretary may accept money, funds, property, and services of every kind by gift, devise, bequest, grant, or otherwise, and may, in any manner, dispose of all such holdings and use the receipts generated from such disposition as general program funds under this section. All funds so designated for the program established under this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>