<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3311"><akn:num>3311</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3311. Authorization of appropriations(a) Existing programsNotwithstanding any authorization for appropriations for agricultural research in any Act enacted prior to September 29, 1977, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, except sections 3152,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. and 2669 of this title, and the competitive grants program provided for in section 1414,22 See References in Text note below. and except that the authorization for moneys provided under the Act of March 2, 1887 (24 Stat. 440–442, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 361a–361i), is excluded and is provided for in subsection (b) of this section, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 1991 through 2023.


(b) Agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stationsNotwithstanding any authorization for appropriations for agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations in any Act enacted prior to September 29, 1977, there are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of conducting agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations pursuant to the Act of March 2, 1887 (24 Stat. 440–442, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 361a–361i), such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 1991 through 2023.


(c) Funding requirements for programsNotwithstanding any other provision of law effective beginning October 1, 1983, not less than 25 per centum of the total funds appropriated to the Secretary in any fiscal year for the conduct of the cooperative research program provided for under the Act of March 2, 1887, commonly known as the Hatch Act (7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.); the cooperative forestry research program provided for under the Act of October 10, 1962, commonly known as the McIntire-Stennis Act (16 U.S.C. 582a et seq.); the special and competitive grants programs provided for in sections 2(b) and 2(c) of the Act of August 4, 1965 (7 U.S.C. 450i); 2 the animal health researc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing programs Notwithstanding any authorization for appropriations for agricultural research in any Act enacted prior to September 29, 1977, there are hereby authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, except sections 3152,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. and 2669 of this title, and the competitive grants program provided for in section 1414,22 See References in Text note below. and except that the authorization for moneys provided under the Act of March 2, 1887 (24 Stat. 440–442, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 361a–361i), is excluded and is provided for in subsection (b) of this section, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 1991 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations Notwithstanding any authorization for appropriations for agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations in any Act enacted prior to September 29, 1977, there are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of conducting agricultural research at State agricultural experiment stations pursuant to the Act of March 2, 1887 (24 Stat. 440–442, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 361a–361i), such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 1991 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding requirements for programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding requirements for programs Notwithstanding any other provision of law effective beginning October 1, 1983, not less than 25 per centum of the total funds appropriated to the Secretary in any fiscal year for the conduct of the cooperative research program provided for under the Act of March 2, 1887, commonly known as the Hatch Act (7 U.S.C. 361a et seq.); the cooperative forestry research program provided for under the Act of October 10, 1962, commonly known as the McIntire-Stennis Act (16 U.S.C. 582a et seq.); the special and competitive grants programs provided for in sections 2(b) and 2(c) of the Act of August 4, 1965 (7 U.S.C. 450i); 2 the animal health research program provided for under sections 3195(a) and 3196 of this title; the native latex research program provided for in the Native Latex Commercialization and Economic Development Act of 1978 (7 U.S.C. 178 et seq.); and the research provided for under various statutes for which funds are appropriated under the Agric</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>