<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3319k"><akn:num>3319k</akn:num><akn:heading>Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority pilot</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3319k. Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority pilot(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Advanced research and developmentThe term “advanced research and development” means research and development activities used to address research challenges in agriculture and food through—(A) targeted acceleration of novel, early stage innovative agricultural research with promising technology applications and products; or

(B) development of qualified products and projects, agricultural technologies, or innovative research tools, which may include—(i) prototype testing, preclinical development, or field experimental use;

(ii) assessing and assisting with product approval, clearance, or need for a license under an applicable law, as determined by the Director; or

(iii) manufacturing and commercialization of a product.



(2) Agricultural technologyThe term “agricultural technology” means machinery and other equipment engineered for an applicable and novel use in agriculture, natural resources, and food relating to the research and development of qualified products and projects.


(3) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority established under subsection (b)(1).


(4) Other transactionThe term “other transaction” means a transaction other than a procurement contract, grant, or cooperative agreement, including a transaction described in subsection (b)(6)(A).


(5) PersonThe term “person” means—(A) an individual;

(B) a partnership;

(C) a corporation;

(D) an association;

(E) an entity;

(F) a public or private corporation;

(G) a Federal, State, or local government agency or department; and

(H) an institution of higher education, including a land-grant college or university and a non-land-grant college of agriculture.


(6) Qualified product or projectThe term “qualified product or project” means—(A) engineering, mechanization, or technology improvements that will address challenges relating t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agriculture Advanced Research and Development Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Strategic plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of effectiveness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>