<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3319e"><akn:num>3319e</akn:num><akn:heading>New Era Rural Technology Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3319e. New Era Rural Technology Program(a) Definition of community collegeIn this section, the term “community college” means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20)—(1) that admits as regular students individuals who—(A) are beyond the age of compulsory school attendance in the State in which the institution is located; and

(B) have the ability to benefit from the training offered by the institution;


(2) that does not provide an educational program for which the institution awards a bachelor’s degree or an equivalent degree; and

(3) that—(A) provides an educational program of not less than 2 years that is acceptable for full credit toward such a degree; or

(B) offers a 2-year program in engineering, technology, mathematics, or the physical, chemical, or biological sciences, designed to prepare a student to work as a technician or at the semiprofessional level in engineering, scientific, or other technological fields requiring the understanding and application of basic engineering, scientific, or mathematical principles of knowledge.



(b) Functions(1) Establishment(A) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program to be known as the “New Era Rural Technology Program”, to make grants available for technology development, applied research, and training to aid in the development of an agriculture-based renewable energy workforce.


(B) SupportThe initiative under this section shall support the fields of—(i) bioenergy;

(ii) pulp and paper manufacturing;

(iii) agriculture-based renewable energy resources; and

(iv) precision agriculture.



(2) Requirements for fundingTo receive funding under this section, an entity shall—(A) be a community college or advanced technological center, located in a rural area and in existence on the date of the enactment of this section, that participates in agricultural or bioenergy research and applied research;

(B) have a proven record of development and implementation of programs to meet</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of community college</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of community college In this section, the term “community college” means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant priority In providing grants under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to eligible entities working in partnership—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>