<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3319d"><akn:num>3319d</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental and alternative crops</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3319d. Supplemental and alternative crops(a) Research and pilot project programNotwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period beginning October 1, 1986, and ending September 30, 2023, the Secretary shall develop and implement a research project program for the development of supplemental and alternative crops (including canola), using such funds as are appropriated to the Secretary each fiscal year under this chapter.


(b) Importance to producersThe development of supplemental and alternative crops for agronomic rotational purposes and as a habitat for honey bees and other pollinators is of critical importance to producers of agricultural commodities.


(c) Research funding, special or competitive grants, etc.; program requirements; agreements, grants and other arrangements(1) The Secretary shall make competitive grants to further the purposes of this section in the implementation of a comprehensive and integrated program.

(2) The program developed and implemented by the Secretary shall include—(A) an examination of the adaptation of supplemental and alternative crops;

(B) the establishment and extension of various methods of planting, cultivating, harvesting, and processing supplemental and alternative crops;

(C) the transfer of such applied research to on-farm practice as soon as practicable;

(D) the establishment through grants, cooperative agreements, or other means of such processing, storage, and transportation facilities for supplemental and alternative crops as the Secretary determines will facilitate the achievement of a successful program; and

(E) the application of such other resources and expertise as the Secretary considers appropriate to support the program.


(3) The program may include, but shall not be limited to, agreements, grants, and other arrangements—(A) to conduct comprehensive resource and infrastructure assessments;

(B) to develop and introduce supplemental and alternative income-producing crops;

(C) to develop and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and pilot project program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research and pilot project program Notwithstanding any other provision of law, during the period beginning October 1, 1986, and ending September 30, 2023, the Secretary shall develop and implement a research project program for the development of supplemental and alternative crops (including canola), using such funds as are appropriated to the Secretary each fiscal year under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importance to producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Importance to producers The development of supplemental and alternative crops for agronomic rotational purposes and as a habitat for honey bees and other pollinators is of critical importance to producers of agricultural commodities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research funding, special or competitive grants, etc.; program requirements; agreements, grants and other arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Research funding, special or competitive grants, etc.; program requirements; agreements, grants and other arrangements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of expertise and resources of other Federal agencies and land-grant colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of expertise and resources of other Federal agencies and land-grant colleges and universities The Secretary shall use the expertise and resources of the Agricultural Research Service, the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, and the land-grant colleges and universities for the purpose of carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>