<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3319b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3319b"><akn:num>3319b</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint requests for proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3319b. Joint requests for proposals(a) In generalIn carrying out any competitive agricultural research, education, or extension grant program authorized under this or any other Act, the Secretary may cooperate with 1 or more other Federal agencies (including the National Science Foundation) in issuing joint requests for proposals, awarding grants, and administering grants, for similar or related research, education, or extension projects or activities.


(b) Administration(1) SecretaryThe Secretary may delegate authority to issue requests for proposals, make grant awards, or administer grants, in whole or in part, to a cooperating Federal agency.


(2) Cooperating Federal agencyThe cooperating Federal agency may delegate to the Secretary authority to issue requests for proposals, make grant awards, or administer grants, in whole or in part.



(c) RegulationsThe Secretary and a cooperating Federal agency may agree to make applicable to recipients of grants—(1) the post-award grant administration regulations applicable to recipients of grants from the Secretary; or

(2) the post-award grant administration regulations applicable to recipients of grants from the cooperating Federal agency.


(d) Joint peer review panelsSubject to section 3129a of this title, the Secretary and a cooperating Federal agency may establish joint peer review panels for the purpose of evaluating grant proposals.


(Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1473B, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7403(b), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 456.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 3319b, Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1473B, as added Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1427, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1553, provided for technology development for small- and medium-sized farming operations, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1601(f)(1)(E), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3704.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
PurposesPub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7403(a), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 456, provided </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In carrying out any competitive agricultural research, education, or extension grant program authorized under this or any other Act, the Secretary may cooperate with 1 or more other Federal agencies (including the National Science Foundation) in issuing joint requests for proposals, awarding grants, and administering grants, for similar or related research, education, or extension projects or activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Secretary and a cooperating Federal agency may agree to make applicable to recipients of grants—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint peer review panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Joint peer review panels Subject to section 3129a of this title, the Secretary and a cooperating Federal agency may establish joint peer review panels for the purpose of evaluating grant proposals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>