<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3362" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3362/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/3362/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3362"><akn:num>3362</akn:num><akn:heading>Distance education grants for insular areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3362. Distance education grants for insular areas(a) In generalThe Secretary may make competitive grants to eligible institutions in insular areas to strengthen the capacity of such institutions to carry out distance food and agricultural education programs using digital network technologies.


(b) UseGrants made under this section shall be used—(1) to acquire the equipment, instrumentation, networking capability, hardware and software, digital network technology, and infrastructure necessary to teach students and teachers about technology in the classroom;

(2) to develop and provide educational services (including faculty development) to prepare students or faculty seeking a degree or certificate that is approved by the State or a regional accrediting body recognized by the Secretary of Education;

(3) to provide teacher education, library and media specialist training, and preschool and teacher aid certification to individuals who seek to acquire or enhance technology skills in order to use technology in the classroom or instructional process;

(4) to implement a joint project to provide education regarding technology in the classroom with a local educational agency, community-based organization, national nonprofit organization, or business; or

(5) to provide leadership development to administrators, board members, and faculty of eligible institutions with institutional responsibility for technology education.


(c) Limitation on use of grant fundsFunds provided under this section shall not be used for the planning, acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, or repair of a building or facility.


(d) Administration of programThe Secretary may carry out this section in a manner that recognizes the different needs and opportunities for eligible institutions in the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans.


(e) Matching requirement(1) In generalThe Secretary may establish a requirement that an eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall provide matching f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make competitive grants to eligible institutions in insular areas to strengthen the capacity of such institutions to carry out distance food and agricultural education programs using digital network technologies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use Grants made under this section shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on use of grant funds Funds provided under this section shall not be used for the planning, acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, or repair of a building or facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration of program The Secretary may carry out this section in a manner that recognizes the different needs and opportunities for eligible institutions in the Atlantic and Pacific Oceans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3362_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>