<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_342"><akn:num>342</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agricultural extension work; cooperation with Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 342. Cooperative agricultural extension work; cooperation with Secretary of Agriculture
Cooperative agricultural extension work shall consist of the development of practical applications of research knowledge and giving of instruction and practical demonstrations of existing or improved practices or technologies in agriculture, uses of solar energy with respect to agriculture, home economics, and rural energy and subjects relating thereto to persons not attending or resident in said colleges in the several communities, and imparting information on said subjects through demonstrations, publications, and otherwise and for the necessary printing and distribution of information in connection with the foregoing; and this work shall be carried on in such manner as may be mutually agreed upon by the Secretary of Agriculture and the State agricultural college or colleges or Territory or possession receiving the benefits of this subchapter.
(May 8, 1914, ch. 79, § 2, 38 Stat. 373; June 26, 1953, ch. 157, § 1, 67 Stat. 84; Pub. L. 87–749, § 1(a), Oct. 5, 1962, 76 Stat. 745; Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1447(3), Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 1011; Pub. L. 96–294, title II, § 256(2), June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 708; Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1435(a), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1557.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Another section 1447 of Pub. L. 95–113 is classified to section 3222b of this title.

Amendments1985—Pub. L. 99–198 substituted “shall consist of the development of practical applications of research knowledge and giving of instruction and practical demonstrations of existing or improved practices or technologies” for “shall consist of the giving of instructions and practical demonstrations”.
1980—Pub. L. 96–294 inserted reference to rural energy.
1977—Pub. L. 95–113 inserted reference to uses of solar energy with respect to agriculture.
1962—Pub. L. 87–749 inserted “or Territory or possession” after “college or colleges”.
1953—Act June 26, 1953, inserted “and subjects relati</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>