<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/361c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/361c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/361c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_361c"><akn:num>361c</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations and allotments of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 361c. Authorization of appropriations and allotments of grants(a) AuthorizationThere are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of sections 361a to 361i of this title such sums as Congress may from time to time determine to be necessary.


(b) Allotments to States; authorization of appropriations for Virgin Islands and Guam; limitation(1) Out of such sums each State shall be entitled to receive annually a sum of money equal to and subject to the same requirement as to use for marketing research projects as the sums received from Federal appropriations for State agricultural experiment stations for the fiscal year 1955, except that amounts heretofore made available from the fund known as the “Regional research fund, Office of Experiment Stations” shall continue to be available for the support of cooperative regional projects as defined in subsection (c)(3), and the said fund shall be designated “Regional research fund, State agricultural experiment stations,” and the Secretary of Agriculture shall be entitled to receive annually for the administration of sections 361a to 361i of this title, a sum not less than that available for this purpose for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1955: Provided, That if the appropriations hereunder available for distribution in any fiscal year are less than those for the fiscal year 1955 the allotment to each State and the amounts for Federal administration and the regional research fund shall be reduced in proportion to the amount of such reduction.

(2) There is authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1973, and for each fiscal year thereafter, for payment to the Virgin Islands and Guam, $100,000 each, which sums shall be in addition to the sums appropriated for the several States of the United States and Puerto Rico under the provisions of this section. The amount paid by the Federal Government to the Virgin Islands and Guam pursuant to this paragraph shall not exceed during any fiscal year, except </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of sections 361a to 361i of this title such sums as Congress may from time to time determine to be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments to States; authorization of appropriations for Virgin Islands and Guam; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allotments to States; authorization of appropriations for Virgin Islands and Guam; limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of additional sums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allotment of additional sums Any sums made available by the Congress in addition to those provided for in subsection (b) of this section for State agricultural experiment station work shall be distributed as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Administration” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Administration” defined “Administration” as used in this section shall include participation in planning and coordinating cooperative regional research as defined in subsection (c)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Adjustment of payments In making payments to States, the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to adjust any such payment to the nearest dollar.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions and reapportionments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reductions and reapportionments If in any year the amount made available by a State from its own funds (including any revenue-sharing funds) to a State agricultural experiment station is reduced because of an increase in the allotment made available under sections 361a to 361i of this title, the allotment to the State agricultural experiment station from the appropriation in the next succeeding fiscal year shall be reduced in an equivalent amount. The Secretary shall reapportion the amount of such reduction to other States for use by their agricultural experiment stations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Peer review Research carried out under subsection (c)(3) shall be subject to scientific peer review. The review of a project conducted under this subsection shall be considered to satisfy the merit review requirements of section 7613(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_361c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of research and extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Integration of research and extension</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>