<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/390" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/390/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/390/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_390"><akn:num>390</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 390. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Agricultural research facilityThe term “agricultural research facility” means a proposed facility for research in food and agricultural sciences for which Federal funds are requested by an entity eligible to receive funds under a capacity and infrastructure program (as defined in section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title) to assist in the construction, alteration, acquisition, modernization, renovation, or remodeling of the facility.


(2) Congressional agriculture committeesThe term “congressional agriculture committees” means the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.


(3) Food and agricultural sciencesThe term “food and agricultural sciences” has the meaning given that term in section 3103 of this title.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(Pub. L. 88–74, § 2, as added Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 884(a), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1176; amended Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, §§ 7214, 7308(b), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 448, 455; Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7101(b)(1), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1213; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, § 7101(b)(1), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1974; Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7503(a)(1), Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4821.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 390, Pub. L. 88–74, § 1, July 22, 1963, 77 Stat. 90; Pub. L. 95–113, title XIV, § 1416(3), Sept. 29, 1977, 91 Stat. 996; Pub. L. 99–198, title XIV, § 1411(a), Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1547, related to congressional declaration of policy, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 104–127.
A prior section 2 of Pub. L. 88–74 was classified to sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural research facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural research facility The term “agricultural research facility” means a proposed facility for research in food and agricultural sciences for which Federal funds are requested by an entity eligible to receive funds under a capacity and infrastructure program (as defined in section 6971(f)(1)(C) of this title) to assist in the construction, alteration, acquisition, modernization, renovation, or remodeling of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional agriculture committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Congressional agriculture committees The term “congressional agriculture committees” means the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Food and agricultural sciences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Food and agricultural sciences The term “food and agricultural sciences” has the meaning given that term in section 3103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_390_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>