<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_391"><akn:num>391</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of bureau; appointment of chief; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 391. Establishment of bureau; appointment of chief; duties
There shall be in the Department of Agriculture a Bureau of Animal Industry. The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized to appoint a chief thereof, who shall be a competent veterinary surgeon, and whose duty it shall be to investigate and report upon the condition of the domestic animals and live poultry of the United States, their protection and use, and also inquire into and report the causes of contagious, infectious, and communicable diseases among them, and the means for the prevention and cure of the same, and to collect such information on these subjects as shall be valuable to the agricultural and commercial interests of the country.
(May 29, 1884, ch. 60, § 1, 23 Stat. 31; July 14, 1890, ch. 707, 26 Stat. 288; Feb. 7, 1928, ch. 30, 45 Stat. 59.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section is composed of part of section 1 of act May 29, 1884.
Section 1 of that act as originally enacted contained this further provision: “And the Commissioner of Agriculture is hereby authorized to employ a force sufficient for the purpose, not to exceed 20 persons at any one time.”
 This provision was practically superseded by subsequent appropriations for an enlarged force.
Section 1 also contained a provision as to salary of the Chief of the Bureau and a clerk for said bureau, that has been omitted as obsolete. The salaries are now fixed under chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.

Amendments1928—Joint Res. Feb. 7, 1928, inserted “and live poultry” after “domestic animals”.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Section 301 of 1947 Reorg. Plan No. 1, eff. July 1, 1947, 12 F.R. 4534, 61 Stat. 952, provided: “The functions of the following agencies of the Department of Agriculture, namely, the Bureau of Animal Industry, the Bureau of Dairy Industry, the Bureau of Plant Industry, Soils, and Agricultural Engineering, the Bureau of Entomology and Plant Quarantine, </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>