<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4306"><akn:num>4306</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4306. Required terms in orders
Orders issued pursuant to this chapter shall contain the following terms and conditions and, except as provided in section 4307 of this title, no others:(1) Providing for the establishment and appointment by the Secretary of a board to be named “Floraboard”, which shall consist of not more than seventy-five voting members, and defining its powers and duties, which shall include only the powers to (A) administer such order in accordance with its terms and provisions, (B) make rules and regulations to effectuate the terms and provisions of such order, (C) receive, investigate, and report to the Secretary complaints of violations of such order, and (D) recommend to the Secretary amendments of such order. The term of an appointment to the Floraboard shall be for three years with no member serving more than two consecutive three-year terms: Provided, That of the initial appointments, one-third shall be for a term of one year and one-third shall be for a term of two years. The Floraboard shall appoint from its members an executive committee, consisting of not more than fifteen members, whose membership shall, to the maximum extent practicable, reflect the membership composition of the Floraboard, and whose commodity group representation shall be proportional to that of the Floraboard. Such executive committee shall have the authority to employ a staff and conduct routine business within the policies determined by the Floraboard.

(2) Providing that the Floraboard shall be composed of producers and importers appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted by organizations certified pursuant to section 4315 of this title or if the Secretary determines that a substantial number of producers or importers are not members of or their interests are not represented by any such certified organization then from nominations made by such producers or importers in a manner authorized by the Secretary. Certified organizations shall submit one nomi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Providing for the establishment and appointment by the Secretary of a board to be named “Floraboard”, which shall consist of not more than seventy-five voting members, and defining its powers and duties, which shall include only the powers to (A) administer such order in accordance with its terms and provisions, (B) make rules and regulations to effectuate the terms and provisions of such order, (C) receive, investigate, and report to the Secretary complaints of violations of such order, and (D) recommend to the Secretary amendments of such order. The term of an appointment to the Floraboard shall be for three years with no member serving more than two consecutive three-year terms: Provided, That of the initial appointments, one-third shall be for a term of one year and one-third shall be for a term of two years. The Floraboard shall appoint from its members an executive committee, consisting of not more than fifteen members, whose membership shall, to the maximum extent practicabl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Providing that the Floraboard shall be composed of producers and importers appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted by organizations certified pursuant to section 4315 of this title or if the Secretary determines that a substantial number of producers or importers are not members of or their interests are not represented by any such certified organization then from nominations made by such producers or importers in a manner authorized by the Secretary. Certified organizations shall submit one nomination for each position on the Floraboard. Initially, the Floraboard shall be composed of one-third producers and importers of cut flowers, one-third producers and importers of potted flowering plants, and one-third producers and importers of foliage plants. Two years after assessment of funds commences pursuant to an order, and periodically thereafter, the Floraboard shall adjust the commodity group representation of these commodity groups on the basis of the amount of asses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Providing that the Floraboard shall, subject to the provisions of paragraph 8 of this section, develop and submit to the Secretary for approval advertising, sales promotion, consumer education, research, and development plans or projects and that any such plan or project must be approved by the Secretary before becoming effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Providing that the Floraboard shall, subject to the provisions of paragraph 8 of this section, submit to the Secretary for approval budgets on a fiscal period basis of its anticipated expenses and disbursements in the administration of the order, including probable costs of advertising, promotion, consumer education, research, and development projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Providing that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Providing that the initial rate of assessment, which rate shall remain in effect for the first two years after an order is approved in a referendum, shall not exceed one-half of 1 per centum of the value of flowers and plants sold, as determined under the provisions of paragraph (5) of this section: Provided, That the Floraboard may thereafter increase or decrease the rate of assessment prescribed by the order by no more than one-quarter of 1 per centum of the value of flowers and plants sold per year: Provided further, That in no event shall the rate of assessment exceed 1½ per centum of the value of flowers and plants sold.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Providing that the Floraboard shall maintain such books and records and shall prepare and submit to the Secretary, from time to time, such reports as the Secretary may prescribe, and providing for appropriate accounting by the Floraboard with respect to the receipt and disbursement of all funds entrusted to it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Providing that the Floraboard, with the approval of the Secretary, may enter into contracts or agreements for development and carrying out of the activities authorized under the order pursuant to sections 4307(1) and (2) of this title and for the payment of the cost thereof with funds collected pursuant to the order. The Floraboard may contract with industry groups, profit or nonprofit companies, private and State colleges and universities, and governmental groups. Any such contract or agreement shall provide (A) that the contracting party shall develop and submit to the Floraboard a plan  or  project  together  with  a  budget  or budgets which shall show estimated costs to be incurred for such plan or project, (B) that any such plan or project shall become effective upon the approval of the Secretary, and (C) that the contracting party shall keep accurate records of all its transactions and make periodic reports to the Floraboard of activities carried out and an accounting for fu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Providing that the Floraboard may convene, from time to time, advisory panels drawn from the production, importation, wholesale, and retail segments of the flower and plant industry to assist in the development of marketing and research programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Providing that no funds collected or received by the Floraboard shall in any manner be used for the purpose of influencing governmental policy or action, except as provided by paragraph (1)(D) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>