<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4604" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4604/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4604/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4604"><akn:num>4604</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4604. Notice and hearing(a) Notice and commentIn issuing an order under this chapter, an amendment to an order, or a regulation to carry out this chapter, the Secretary shall comply with section 553 of title 5.


(b) Formal agency actionSections 556 and 557 of that title shall not apply with respect to the issuance of an order, an amendment to an order, or a regulation under this chapter.


(c) Proposal of an orderA proposal for an order may be submitted to the Secretary by any organization or interested person affected by this chapter.


(Pub. L. 98–590, § 5, Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 3117; Pub. L. 105–185, title VI, § 605(d), June 23, 1998, 112 Stat. 589.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–185 reenacted section catchline without change and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that the issuance of an order will assist in carrying out the purpose of this chapter, the Secretary shall provide due notice of and opportunity for a hearing upon a proposed order. Such hearing may be requested and a proposal for an order submitted by any organization or interested person affected by the provisions of this chapter.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4604_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice and comment In issuing an order under this chapter, an amendment to an order, or a regulation to carry out this chapter, the Secretary shall comply with section 553 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4604_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formal agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Formal agency action Sections 556 and 557 of that title shall not apply with respect to the issuance of an order, an amendment to an order, or a regulation under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4604_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposal of an order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Proposal of an order A proposal for an order may be submitted to the Secretary by any organization or interested person affected by this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>