<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4608" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4608/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4608/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4608"><akn:num>4608</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of assessments; refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4608. Collection of assessments; refunds(a) HandlersExcept as otherwise provided in this section, a first handler of honey shall be responsible, at the time of first purchase—(1) for the collection, and payment to the Honey Board, of the assessment payable by a producer under section 4606(e)(2)(A) of this title or, if approved in a referendum conducted under this chapter, under section 4606(e)(3)(A)(i) of this title; and

(2) if approved in a referendum conducted under this chapter, for the payment to the Honey Board of an additional assessment payable by the handler under section 4606(e)(3)(A)(ii) of this title.


(b) RecordsThe first handler shall maintain a separate record on each producer’s honey so handled, including honey owned by the handler.


(c) ImportersExcept as otherwise provided in this section, at the time of entry of honey and honey products into the United States, an importer shall remit to the Honey Board through the United States Customs Service—(1) the assessment on the imported honey and honey products required under section 4606(e)(2)(B) of this title; or

(2) if approved in a referendum conducted under this chapter, the assessment on the imported honey and honey products required under section 4606(e)(3)(B) of this title, of which the amount payable under section 4606(e)(3)(A)(ii) of this title represents the assessment due from the handler to be paid by the importer on behalf of the handler.


(d) Loan and loan deficiency payments; deduction from disbursement of loan funds or loan deficiency payment made to producerIn any case in which a loan, or a loan deficiency payment is made with respect to honey under the honey price support loan program established under the Agricultural Act of 1949 [7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.], or successor statute, the Secretary shall provide for the assessment to be deducted from the disbursement of any loan funds or from the loan deficiency payment made to the producer and for the amount of such assessment to be forwa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Handlers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Handlers Except as otherwise provided in this section, a first handler of honey shall be responsible, at the time of first purchase—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Records The first handler shall maintain a separate record on each producer’s honey so handled, including honey owned by the handler.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Importers Except as otherwise provided in this section, at the time of entry of honey and honey products into the United States, an importer shall remit to the Honey Board through the United States Customs Service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan and loan deficiency payments; deduction from disbursement of loan funds or loan deficiency payment made to producer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Loan and loan deficiency payments; deduction from disbursement of loan funds or loan deficiency payment made to producer In any case in which a loan, or a loan deficiency payment is made with respect to honey under the honey price support loan program established under the Agricultural Act of 1949 [7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.], or successor statute, the Secretary shall provide for the assessment to be deducted from the disbursement of any loan funds or from the loan deficiency payment made to the producer and for the amount of such assessment to be forwarded to the Honey Board. The Secretary shall provide for the producer to receive a statement of the amount of the assessment deducted from the loan funds or loan deficiency payment promptly after each occasion when an assessment is deducted from any such loan funds or payment under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer-packers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Producer-packers Except as otherwise provided in this section, a producer-packer shall be responsible for the collection, and payment to the Honey Board, of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection; books and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Inspection; books and records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information; disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Confidentiality of information; disclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and remittance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administration and remittance Administration and remittance of the assessments under this chapter shall be conducted—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4608_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Liability for assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>