<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4612"><akn:num>4612</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4612. Termination or suspension(a) “Person” definedIn this section, the term “person” means a producer, importer, or handler.


(b) Authority of SecretaryIf the Secretary finds that an order issued under this chapter, or any provision of the order, obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary shall terminate or suspend the operation of the order or provision.


(c) Periodic referendaExcept as provided in subsection (d)(3) and section 4613(g) of this title, on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Secretary issues an order authorizing the collection of assessments on honey or honey products under this chapter, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum to determine if the persons subject to assessment under the order approve continuation of the order in accordance with section 4611 of this title.


(d) Referenda on request(1) In generalOn the request of the Honey Board or the petition of at least 10 percent of the total number of persons subject to assessment under the order, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum to determine if the persons subject to assessment under the order approve continuation of the order in accordance with section 4611 of this title.


(2) LimitationReferenda conducted under paragraph (1) may not be held more than once every 2 years.


(3) Effect on periodic referendaIf a referendum is conducted under this subsection and the Secretary determines that continuation of the order is approved under section 4611 of this title, any referendum otherwise required to be conducted under subsection (c) shall not be held before the date that is 5 years after the date of the referendum conducted under this subsection.



(e) Timing and requirements for termination or suspension(1) In generalThe Secretary shall terminate or suspend an order at the end of the marketing year during which a referendum is conducted under subsection (c) or (d) if the Secretary determines that </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Person” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Person” defined In this section, the term “person” means a producer, importer, or handler.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Secretary If the Secretary finds that an order issued under this chapter, or any provision of the order, obstructs or does not tend to effectuate the purposes of this chapter, the Secretary shall terminate or suspend the operation of the order or provision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Periodic referenda Except as provided in subsection (d)(3) and section 4613(g) of this title, on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Secretary issues an order authorizing the collection of assessments on honey or honey products under this chapter, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum to determine if the persons subject to assessment under the order approve continuation of the order in accordance with section 4611 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referenda on request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Referenda on request</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4612_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing and requirements for termination or suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Timing and requirements for termination or suspension</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>