<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4805" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4805/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4805/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4805"><akn:num>4805</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings and issuance of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4805. Findings and issuance of orders(a) Necessary findingsAfter notice and opportunity for public comment have been provided in accordance with section 4804 of this title, the Secretary shall issue and publish an order if the Secretary finds, and sets forth in such order, that the issuance of such order and all terms and conditions thereof will assist in carrying out this chapter.


(b) Number of orders in effect at a timeNot more than one order may be in effect at a time.


(c) Effective dateAn order shall become effective on a date that is not more than 90 days following the publication of such order.


(d) Terms and conditionsAn order shall contain such terms and conditions as are required in sections 4806 through 4809 of this title and, except as provided in section 4810 of this title, no others.


(Pub. L. 99–198, title XVI, § 1616, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1609.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 1986, see section 1631 of Pub. L. 99–198, set out as a note under section 4801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4805_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Necessary findings After notice and opportunity for public comment have been provided in accordance with section 4804 of this title, the Secretary shall issue and publish an order if the Secretary finds, and sets forth in such order, that the issuance of such order and all terms and conditions thereof will assist in carrying out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4805_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number of orders in effect at a time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Number of orders in effect at a time Not more than one order may be in effect at a time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4805_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effective date An order shall become effective on a date that is not more than 90 days following the publication of such order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4805_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions An order shall contain such terms and conditions as are required in sections 4806 through 4809 of this title and, except as provided in section 4810 of this title, no others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>