<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4806" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4806/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4806/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4806"><akn:num>4806</akn:num><akn:heading>National Pork Producers Delegate Body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4806. National Pork Producers Delegate Body(a) Establishment and appointmentThe order shall provide for the establishment and appointment by the Secretary, not later than 60 days after the effective date of such order, of a National Pork Producers Delegate Body.


(b) Membership; number of producer members; number of importer members(1) The Delegate Body shall consist of—(A) producers, as appointed by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (2), from nominees submitted as follows:(i) in the case of the initial Delegate Body appointed by each State in accordance with section 4807 of this title.

(ii) in the case of each succeeding Delegate Body, each State association shall submit nominations selected by such association pursuant to a selection process that—(I) is approved by the Secretary;

(II) requires public notice of the process to be given at least one week in advance by publication in a newspaper or newspaper of general circulation in such State and in pork production and agriculture trade publications; and

(III) that provides complete and equal access to the nominating process to every producer who has paid all assessments due under section 4809 of this title and not demanded a refund under section 4813 of this title,


or pursuant to an election of nominees conducted in accordance with section 4807 of this title.

(iii) In the case of a State that has a State association that does not submit nominations or that does not have a State association, such State shall submit nominations in a manner prescribed by the Secretary; and


(B) importers, as appointed by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (3).


(2) The number of producer members appointed to the Delegate Body from each State shall equal at least two members, and additional members, allocated as follows:(A) Shares shall be assigned to each State—(i) for the 1986 calendar year, on the basis of one share for each $400,000 of farm market value of porcine animals marketed from such State (as det</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and appointment The order shall provide for the establishment and appointment by the Secretary, not later than 60 days after the effective date of such order, of a National Pork Producers Delegate Body.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; number of producer members; number of importer members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; number of producer members; number of importer members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting; quorum; votes necessary for decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Voting; quorum; votes necessary for decision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term of office A member of the Delegate Body shall serve for a term of 1 year, except that the term of a member of the Delegate Body shall continue until the successor of such member, if any, is appointed in accordance with subsection (b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chairman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation A member of the Delegate Body shall serve without compensation, but may be reimbursed by the Board from assessments collected under section 4809 of this title for transportation expenses incurred in performing duties as a member of the Delegate Body.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nomination of members to National Pork Board; annual meeting; majority vote in person to nominate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nomination of members to National Pork Board; annual meeting; majority vote in person to nominate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4806_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Duties and functions The Delegate Body shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>