<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4810" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4810/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4810/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4810"><akn:num>4810</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissive provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4810. Permissive provisions(a) Recordkeeping and reporting requirements; incidental and necessary terms and conditionsOn the recommendation of the Board, and with the approval of the Secretary, an order may contain one or more of the following provisions:(1) Each person purchasing a porcine animal from a producer for commercial use, and each importer, shall—(A) maintain and make available for inspection such books and records as may be required by the order; and

(B) file reports at the time, in the manner, and having the content prescribed by the order,


including documentation of the State of origin of a purchased porcine animal or the place of origin of an imported porcine animal, pork, or pork product.

(2) A term or condition—(A) incidental to, and not inconsistent with, the terms and conditions specified in this chapter; and

(B) necessary to effectuate the other provisions of such order.



(b) Availability of information to Secretary and Board; confidentiality; disclosure; issuance of general statement, statistical data, or name of violator of order(1) Information referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall be made available to the Secretary and the Board as is appropriate or necessary for the effectuation, administration, or enforcement of this chapter or an order.

(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (C), information obtained under subsection (a)(1) shall be kept confidential by officers or employees of the Department of Agriculture or the Board.

(B) Such information may be disclosed only—(i) in a suit or administrative hearing involving the order with respect to which the information was furnished or acquired—(I) brought at the direction or on the request of the Secretary; or

(II) to which the Secretary or an officer of the United States is a party; and


(ii) if the Secretary considers such information to be relevant to such suit or hearing.


(C) Nothing in this section prohibits—(i) the issuance of a general statement based on the report</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4810_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping and reporting requirements; incidental and necessary terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recordkeeping and reporting requirements; incidental and necessary terms and conditions On the recommendation of the Board, and with the approval of the Secretary, an order may contain one or more of the following provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4810_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information to Secretary and Board; confidentiality; disclosure; issuance of general statement, statistical data, or name of violator of order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of information to Secretary and Board; confidentiality; disclosure; issuance of general statement, statistical data, or name of violator of order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4810_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for willful violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalty for willful violations A person who willfully violates subsection (a)(1) or (b) shall, on conviction, be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>