<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4813" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4813/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4813/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4813"><akn:num>4813</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4813. Refunds(a) Demand for refund; persons eligibleNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, prior to the approval of the continuation of an order pursuant to the referendum required under section 4811(a) of this title, any person shall have the right to demand and receive from the Board a refund of an assessment collected under section 4809 of this title if such person—(1) is responsible for paying such assessment; and

(2) does not support the program established under this chapter.


(b) Form and time within which demand to be madeSuch demand shall be made in accordance with regulations, on a form, and within a time period prescribed by the Board and approved by the Secretary, but not later than 30 days after the end of the month in which the assessment was paid.


(c) Payment of refund on submission of satisfactory proofSuch refund shall be made not later than 30 days after demand is received therefore 11 So in original. Probably should be “therefor”. on submission of proof satisfactory to the Board that the producer, person, or importer—(1) paid the assessment for which refund is sought; and

(2) did not collect such assessment from another producer, person, or importer.


(Pub. L. 99–198, title XVI, § 1624, Dec. 23, 1985, 99 Stat. 1619.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 1986, see section 1631 of Pub. L. 99–198, set out as a note under section 4801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4813_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demand for refund; persons eligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Demand for refund; persons eligible Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, prior to the approval of the continuation of an order pursuant to the referendum required under section 4811(a) of this title, any person shall have the right to demand and receive from the Board a refund of an assessment collected under section 4809 of this title if such person—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4813_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and time within which demand to be made</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form and time within which demand to be made Such demand shall be made in accordance with regulations, on a form, and within a time period prescribed by the Board and approved by the Secretary, but not later than 30 days after the end of the month in which the assessment was paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4813_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of refund on submission of satisfactory proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of refund on submission of satisfactory proof Such refund shall be made not later than 30 days after demand is received therefore 11 So in original. Probably should be “therefor”. on submission of proof satisfactory to the Board that the producer, person, or importer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>