<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4815" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4815/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4815/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4815"><akn:num>4815</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4815. Enforcement(a) Jurisdiction of district court; referral of civil actions to Attorney General(1) A district court of the United States shall have jurisdiction specifically to enforce, and to prevent and restrain a person from violating an order, rule, or regulation issued under this chapter.

(2) A civil action authorized to be brought under this subsection shall be referred to the Attorney General for appropriate action, except that the Secretary is not required to refer to the Attorney General a violation of this chapter if the Secretary believes that the administration and enforcement of this chapter would be adequately served by providing a suitable written notice or warning to a person who committed such violation or by administrative action under subsection (b).


(b) Penalties for willful violations; issuance of cease-and-desist orders; judicial review of orders; penalty for failure to obey cease-and-desist order(1)(A) A person who willfully violates an order, rule, or regulation issued by the Secretary under this chapter may be assessed—(i) a civil penalty by the Secretary of not more than $1,000 for each such violation; and

(ii) in the case of a willful failure to pay, collect, or remit an assessment as required by an order, an additional penalty equal to the amount of such assessment.


(B) Each such violation shall be a separate offense.

(C) In addition to or in lieu of such civil penalty, the Secretary may issue an order requiring such person to cease and desist from violating such order, rule, or regulation.

(D) No penalty may be assessed or cease-and-desist order issued unless the Secretary gives such person notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record with respect to such violation.

(E) An order issued under this paragraph by the Secretary shall be final and conclusive unless such person files an appeal from such order with the appropriate United States court of appeals not later than 30 days after such person receives notice of such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of district court; referral of civil actions to Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Jurisdiction of district court; referral of civil actions to Attorney General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for willful violations; issuance of cease-and-desist orders; judicial review of orders; penalty for failure to obey cease-and-desist order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties for willful violations; issuance of cease-and-desist orders; judicial review of orders; penalty for failure to obey cease-and-desist order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4815_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of additional remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of additional remedies The remedies provided in subsections (a) and (b) shall be in addition to, and not exclusive of, other remedies that may be available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>