<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/4907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4907"><akn:num>4907</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissive terms in plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4907. Permissive terms in plans(a) Description of terms and provisions; prohibitionAny plan issued under this chapter may contain one or more of the terms and provisions described in this section, but except as provided in section 4906 of this title no others.


(b) ExemptionsThe plan may provide for the exemption, from the provisions of the plan, of watermelons used for nonfood uses, and authority for the Board to establish satisfactory safeguards against improper use of such exemption.


(c) Designation of different handler payment and reporting schedules for assessmentsThe plan may provide for the designation of different handler payment and reporting schedules with respect to assessments, as provided for in sections 4906 and 4908 of this title, to recognize differences in marketing practices and procedures used in different production areas.


(d) Advertising and sales promotion programs or projectsThe plan may provide for the establishment, issuance, effectuation, and administration of appropriate programs or projects for the advertising and other sales promotion of watermelons and for the disbursement of necessary funds for such purposes. Any such program or project shall be directed toward increasing the general demand for watermelons, and promotional activities shall comply with the provisions of section 4906(g) of this title.


(e) Marketing objectives of research and development projects and studiesThe plan may provide for establishing and carrying out research and development projects and studies to the end that the marketing and use of watermelons may be encouraged, expanded, improved, or made more efficient, and for the disbursement of necessary funds for such purposes.


(f) Reserve funds; limitationThe plan may provide authority for the accumulation of reserve funds from assessments collected under this chapter, to permit an effective and continuous coordinated program of research, development, advertising, and promotion in years when watermelon pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of terms and provisions; prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Description of terms and provisions; prohibition Any plan issued under this chapter may contain one or more of the terms and provisions described in this section, but except as provided in section 4906 of this title no others.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exemptions The plan may provide for the exemption, from the provisions of the plan, of watermelons used for nonfood uses, and authority for the Board to establish satisfactory safeguards against improper use of such exemption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of different handler payment and reporting schedules for assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of different handler payment and reporting schedules for assessments The plan may provide for the designation of different handler payment and reporting schedules with respect to assessments, as provided for in sections 4906 and 4908 of this title, to recognize differences in marketing practices and procedures used in different production areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising and sales promotion programs or projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advertising and sales promotion programs or projects The plan may provide for the establishment, issuance, effectuation, and administration of appropriate programs or projects for the advertising and other sales promotion of watermelons and for the disbursement of necessary funds for such purposes. Any such program or project shall be directed toward increasing the general demand for watermelons, and promotional activities shall comply with the provisions of section 4906(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing objectives of research and development projects and studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Marketing objectives of research and development projects and studies The plan may provide for establishing and carrying out research and development projects and studies to the end that the marketing and use of watermelons may be encouraged, expanded, improved, or made more efficient, and for the disbursement of necessary funds for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve funds; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reserve funds; limitation The plan may provide authority for the accumulation of reserve funds from assessments collected under this chapter, to permit an effective and continuous coordinated program of research, development, advertising, and promotion in years when watermelon production and assessment income may be reduced, except that the total reserve fund may not exceed the amount budgeted for two years operation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign market sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Foreign market sales The plan may provide for the use of funds from assessments collected under this chapter, with the approval of the Secretary, for the development and expansion of sales of watermelons in foreign markets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4907_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Other terms and conditions The plan may contain terms and conditions incidental to and not inconsistent with the terms and conditions specified in this chapter and necessary to effectuate the other provisions of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>