<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/511s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/511s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/511s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_511s"><akn:num>511s</akn:num><akn:heading>Grading of tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 511s. Grading of tobacco(1) In generalNot later than March 31, 2002, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall conduct referenda among producers of each kind of tobacco that is eligible for price support under the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.) to determine whether such producers favor the mandatory grading of that kind of tobacco by the Secretary.


(2) Mandatory grading(A) In generalIf the Secretary determines that mandatory grading is favored by a majority of the producers of a kind of tobacco voting in the referendum, the Secretary is authorized and directed to ensure that the kind of tobacco is graded at the time of sale effective for the 2002 and subsequent marketing years.


(B) FeesTo the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall establish, collect, and use fees for the grading of tobacco required under this section in the same manner as user fees for the grading of tobacco sold at auction authorized under the Tobacco Inspection Act (7 U.S.C. 511 et seq.).



(3) Judicial reviewA determination by the Secretary under this section shall not be subject to judicial review.


(Pub. L. 107–76, title VII, § 759(a), Nov. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 741.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Agricultural Act of 1949, referred to in par. (1), is act Oct. 31, 1949, ch. 792, 63 Stat. 1051, which is classified principally to chapter 35A (§ 1421 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1421 of this title and Tables.
The Tobacco Inspection Act, referred to in par. (2)(B), is act Aug. 23, 1935, ch. 623, 49 Stat. 731, which is classified generally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 511q of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002, and not as part of The</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511s_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) In general Not later than March 31, 2002, the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall conduct referenda among producers of each kind of tobacco that is eligible for price support under the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.) to determine whether such producers favor the mandatory grading of that kind of tobacco by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511s_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory grading</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Mandatory grading</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_511s_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Judicial review A determination by the Secretary under this section shall not be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>