<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_518b"><akn:num>518b</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract payments for producers of quota tobacco</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 518b. Contract payments for producers of quota tobacco(a) Contract offeredThe Secretary shall offer to enter into a contract with each producer of quota tobacco under which the producer of quota tobacco shall be entitled to receive payments under this section in exchange for the termination of tobacco marketing quotas and related price support under the amendments made by sections 611 and 612.11 See References in Text note below. The contract payments shall constitute full and fair consideration for the termination of such tobacco marketing quotas and related price support.


(b) Eligibility(1) Application and determinationTo be eligible to enter into a contract to receive a contract payment under this section, a person shall submit to the Secretary an application containing such information as the Secretary may require to demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the person is a producer of quota tobacco. The application shall be submitted within such time, in such form, and in such manner as the Secretary may require.


(2) Effect of multiple producers for same quota tobaccoIf, on the basis of the applications submitted under paragraph (1) or other information, the Secretary determines that two or more persons are a producer of the same quota tobacco, the Secretary shall provide for an equitable distribution among the persons of the contract payments made under this section with respect to that quota tobacco, based on relative share of such persons in the risk of producing the quota tobacco and such other factors as the Secretary considers appropriate.



(c) Base quota level(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a base quota level applicable to each producer of quota tobacco, as determined under this subsection.


(2) Flue-cured and burley tobaccoIn the case of Flue-cured tobacco (types 11, 12, 13, and 14) and Burley tobacco (type 31), the base quota level for each producer of quota tobacco shall be equal to the effective tobacco marketing q</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract offered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contract offered The Secretary shall offer to enter into a contract with each producer of quota tobacco under which the producer of quota tobacco shall be entitled to receive payments under this section in exchange for the termination of tobacco marketing quotas and related price support under the amendments made by sections 611 and 612.11 See References in Text note below. The contract payments shall constitute full and fair consideration for the termination of such tobacco marketing quotas and related price support.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Base quota level</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Base quota level</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contract payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death of tobacco producer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Death of tobacco producer If a producer of quota tobacco who is entitled to contract payments under this section dies and is survived by a spouse or one or more dependents, the right to receive the contract payments shall transfer to the surviving spouse or, if there is no surviving spouse, to the estate of the producer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>