<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/518d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_518d"><akn:num>518d</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of assessments as source of funds for payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 518d. Use of assessments as source of funds for payments(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Base periodThe term “base period’ 11 So in original. means the one-year period ending the June 30 before the beginning of a fiscal year.


(2) Gross domestic volumeThe term “gross domestic volume” means the volume of tobacco products—(A) removed (as defined by section 5702 of title 26); and

(B) not exempt from tax under chapter 52 of title 26 at the time of their removal under that chapter or the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.


(3) Market shareThe term “market share” means the share of each manufacturer or importer of a class of tobacco product (expressed as a decimal to the fourth place) of the total volume of domestic sales of the class of tobacco product during the base period for a fiscal year for an assessment under this section.



(b) Quarterly assessments(1) Imposition of assessmentThe Secretary, acting through the Commodity Credit Corporation, shall impose quarterly assessments during each of fiscal years 2005 through 2014, calculated in accordance with this section, on each tobacco product manufacturer and tobacco product importer that sells tobacco products in domestic commerce in the United States during that fiscal year.


(2) AmountsBeginning with the calendar quarter ending on December 31 of each of fiscal years 2005 through 2014, the assessment payments over each four-calendar quarter period shall be sufficient to cover—(A) the contract payments made under sections 518a and 518b of this title during that period; and

(B) other expenditures from the Tobacco Trust Fund made during the base quarter periods corresponding to the four calendar quarters of that period.


(3) DepositAssessments collected under this section shall be deposited in the Tobacco Trust Fund.



(c) Assessments for classes of tobacco products(1) Initial allocationThe percentage of the total amount required by subsection (b) to be assessed against, and paid by, the manufac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarterly assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Quarterly assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments for classes of tobacco products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assessments for classes of tobacco products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification and timing of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification and timing of assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of assessment within each class of tobacco product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocation of assessment within each class of tobacco product</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of total assessments by market share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation of total assessments by market share The amount of the assessment for each class of tobacco product specified in subsection (c)(1) to be paid by each manufacturer or importer of that class of tobacco product shall be determined for each quarterly payment period by multiplying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of volume of domestic sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Determination of volume of domestic sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measurement of volume of domestic sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Measurement of volume of domestic sales</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Challenge to assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Challenge to assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_518d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>