<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5331"><akn:num>5331</akn:num><akn:heading>Structure of Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5331. Structure of Council(a) In general(1) EstablishmentThe President shall establish, within ninety days after October 22, 1990, a National Nutrition Monitoring Advisory Council. The Council shall assist in carrying out the purposes of this chapter, provide scientific and technical advice on the development and implementation of the coordinated program and comprehensive plan, and serve in an advisory capacity to the Secretaries.


(2) MembershipThe Council shall consist of nine voting members, of whom—(A) five members shall be appointed by the President based upon recommendations from the Secretaries; and

(B) four members shall be appointed by Congress, of whom—(i) one shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;

(ii) one shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives;

(iii) one shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate; and

(iv) one shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate.



(3) Ex officio membersThe Council also shall include the joint chairpersons of the Board as ex officio nonvoting members.



(b) Selection criteriaEach person appointed to the Council shall be selected solely on the basis of an established record of distinguished service and shall be eminent in one of the following fields:(1) public health, including clinical dietetics, public health nutrition, epidemiology, clinical medicine, health education, or nutrition education;

(2) nutrition monitoring research, including nutrition monitoring and surveillance, food consumption patterns, nutritional anthropology, community nutrition research, nutritional biochemistry, food composition analysis, survey statistics, dietary-intake methodology, or nutrition status methodology; or

(3) food production and distribution, including agriculture, biotechnology, food technology, food engineering, economics, consumer psychology or sociology, food-system management, or food assistance.


(c) Particular representation require</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection criteria Each person appointed to the Council shall be selected solely on the basis of an established record of distinguished service and shall be eminent in one of the following fields:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Particular representation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Particular representation requirements The Council membership, at all times, shall include at least two representatives from each of the three areas of specialization listed in subsection (b), and shall have representatives from various geographic areas, the private sector, academia, scientific and professional societies, agriculture, minority organizations, and public interest organizations and shall include a State or local government employee with a specialized interest in nutrition monitoring.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chairperson The Chairperson of the Council shall be elected from and by the Council membership. The term of office of the Chairperson shall not exceed 5 years. If a vacancy occurs in the Chairpersonship, the Council shall elect a member to fill such vacancy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Term of office The term of office of each of the voting members of the Council shall be 5 years, except that of the 5 members first appointed by the President, 2 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, 2 for terms of 3 years, and one for a term of 4 years, as designated by the President at the time of appointment. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which the predecessor of such member was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of such term. No voting member shall be eligible to serve continuously for more than 2 consecutive terms.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Initial appointment The initial members of the Council shall be appointed or designated not later than ninety days after October 22, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings The Council shall meet on a regular basis at the call of the Chairperson, or on the written request of one-third of the members. A majority of the appointed members of the Council shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Federal employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on Federal employment Appointed members of the Council may not be employed by the Federal Government and shall be allowed travel expenses as authorized by section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Executive Secretary The Administrator of Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research (if appointed under section 5311(d) of this title) shall serve as the Executive Secretary of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5331_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination The Council shall terminate 10 years after the final comprehensive plan is prepared under section 5313 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>