<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5602"><akn:num>5602</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5602. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(1) Agricultural commodityThe term “agricultural commodity” means any agricultural commodity, food, feed, fiber, or livestock (including livestock as it is defined in section 1471(2) of this title and insects), and any product thereof.


(2) Developing countryThe term “developing country” means a country that—(A) has a shortage of foreign exchange earnings and has difficulty accessing sufficient commercial credit to meet all of its food needs, as determined by the Secretary; and

(B) has the potential to become a commercial market for agricultural commodities.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(4) ServiceThe term “Service” means the Foreign Agricultural Service of the Department of Agriculture.


(5) Unfair trade practice(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), the term “unfair trade practice” means any act, policy, or practice of a foreign country that—(i) violates, or is inconsistent with, the provisions of, or otherwise denies benefits to the United States under, any trade agreement to which the United States is a party;

(ii) in the case of a monopolistic state trading enterprise engaged in the export sale of an agricultural commodity, implements a pricing practice that is inconsistent with sound commercial practice;

(iii) provides a subsidy that—(I) decreases market opportunities for United States exports; or

(II) unfairly distorts an agricultural market to the detriment of United States exporters;


(iv) imposes an unfair technical barrier to trade, including—(I) a trade restriction or commercial requirement (such as a labeling requirement) that adversely affects a new technology (including biotechnology); and

(II) an unjustified sanitary or phytosanitary restriction (including any restriction that, in violation of the Uruguay Round Agreements, is not based on scientific principles; 11 So in original. There probably should be a closing parenthesis.


(v) imposes a rule tha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural commodity The term “agricultural commodity” means any agricultural commodity, food, feed, fiber, or livestock (including livestock as it is defined in section 1471(2) of this title and insects), and any product thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developing country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Developing country The term “developing country” means a country that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Service The term “Service” means the Foreign Agricultural Service of the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfair trade practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Unfair trade practice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) United States The term “United States” includes each of the States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States agricultural commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) United States agricultural commodity The term “United States agricultural commodity” means— For purposes of this paragraph, fish entirely produced in the United States include fish harvested by a documented fishing vessel as defined in title 46 in waters that are not waters (including the territorial sea) of a foreign country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5602_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent states of the former Soviet Union</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Independent states of the former Soviet Union The term “independent states of the former Soviet Union” means the following: Armenia, Azerbaijan, Belarus, Georgia, Kazakhstan, Kyrgyzstan, Moldova, Russia, Tajikistan, Turkmenistan, Ukraine, and Uzbekistan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>