<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5603"><akn:num>5603</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural export promotion strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5603. Agricultural export promotion strategy(a) In generalThe Secretary shall develop a strategy for implementing Federal agricultural export promotion programs that takes into account the new market opportunities for agricultural products, including opportunities that result from—(1) the North American Free Trade Agreement and the Uruguay Round Agreements;

(2) any accession to membership in the World Trade Organization;

(3) the continued economic growth in the Pacific Rim; and

(4) other developments.


(b) Purpose of strategyThe strategy developed under subsection (a) shall encourage the maintenance, development, and expansion of export markets for United States agricultural commodities and related products, including high-value and value-added products.


(c) Goals of strategyThe strategy developed under subsection (a) shall have the following goals:(1) Increase the value of United States agricultural exports each year.

(2) Increase the value of United States agricultural exports each year at a faster rate than the rate of increase in the value of overall world export trade in agricultural products.

(3) Increase the value of United States high-value and value-added agricultural exports each year.

(4) Increase the value of United States high-value and value-added agricultural exports each year at a faster rate than the rate of increase in the value of overall world export trade in high-value and value-added agricultural products.

(5) Ensure that to the extent practicable—(A) all obligations undertaken in the Uruguay Round Agreement on Agriculture that significantly increase access for United States agricultural commodities are implemented to the extent required by the Uruguay Round Agreements; or

(B) applicable United States laws are used to secure United States rights under the Uruguay Round Agreement on Agriculture.



(d) Priority markets(1) Identification of marketsIn developing the strategy required under subsection (a), the Secretary shall annually </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall develop a strategy for implementing Federal agricultural export promotion programs that takes into account the new market opportunities for agricultural products, including opportunities that result from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of strategy The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall encourage the maintenance, development, and expansion of export markets for United States agricultural commodities and related products, including high-value and value-added products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals of strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Goals of strategy The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall have the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority markets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority markets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>