<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5679" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5679/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5679/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5679"><akn:num>5679</akn:num><akn:heading>Biotechnology and agricultural trade program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5679. Biotechnology and agricultural trade program(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department the biotechnology and agricultural trade program.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the program shall be to remove, resolve, or mitigate significant regulatory nontariff barriers to the export of United States agricultural commodities (as defined in section 5602 of this title) into foreign markets through public and private sector projects funded by grants that address—(1) quick response intervention regarding nontariff barriers to United States exports involving—(A) United States agricultural commodities produced through biotechnology or new agricultural production technologies;

(B) food safety;

(C) disease; or

(D) other sanitary or phytosanitary concerns; or


(2) developing protocols as part of bilateral negotiations with other countries on issues such as animal health, grain quality, and genetically modified commodities.


(c) Eligible programsDepending on need, as determined by the Secretary, activities authorized under this section may be carried out through—(1) this section;

(2) the emerging markets program under section 1542 11 See References in Text note below. and section 5623(d) of this title; or

(3) the Cochran Fellowship Program under section 3293 of this title.


(d) FundingThere is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XV, § 1543A, as added Pub. L. 107–171, title III, § 3204, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 300; amended Pub. L. 115–334, title III, §§ 3201(b)(3)(C), 3301, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4617.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1542, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), is section 1542 of title XV of Pub. L. 101–624, which is set out as a note under section 5622 of this title.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990, and not as part of the Agricultural Trade Act of 1978 which comprises this chapter.

Amendme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5679_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Department the biotechnology and agricultural trade program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5679_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the program shall be to remove, resolve, or mitigate significant regulatory nontariff barriers to the export of United States agricultural commodities (as defined in section 5602 of this title) into foreign markets through public and private sector projects funded by grants that address—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5679_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible programs Depending on need, as determined by the Secretary, activities authorized under this section may be carried out through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5679_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding There is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>