<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5712"><akn:num>5712</akn:num><akn:heading>Export reporting and contract sanctity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5712. Export reporting and contract sanctity(a) Export sales reports(1) In generalAll exporters of wheat and wheat flour, feed grains, oil seeds, cotton, pork, beef, and products thereof, and other commodities that the Secretary may designate produced in the United States shall report to the Secretary of Agriculture, on a weekly basis, the following information regarding any contract for export sales entered into or subsequently modified in any manner during the reporting period:(A) type, class, and quantity of the commodity sought to be exported;

(B) the marketing year of shipment; and

(C) destination, if known.


(2) Confidentiality and compilation of reportsIndividual reports shall remain confidential but shall be compiled by the Secretary and published in compilation form each week following the week of reporting.


(3) Immediate reportingAll exporters of agricultural commodities produced in the United States shall, upon request of the Secretary, immediately report to the Secretary any information with respect to export sales of agricultural commodities and at such times as the Secretary may request. When the Secretary requires that such information be reported by exporters on a daily basis, the information compiled from individual reports shall be made available to the public daily.


(4) Monthly reporting permittedThe Secretary may, with respect to any commodity or type or class thereof during any period in which the Secretary determines that—(A) there is a domestic supply of such commodity substantially in excess of the quantity needed to meet domestic requirements,

(B) total supplies of such commodity in the exporting countries are estimated to be in surplus,

(C) anticipated exports will not result in excessive drain on domestic supplies, and

(D) to require the reports to be made will unduly hamper export sales,


provide for such reports by exporters and publishing of such data to be on a monthly basis rather than on a weekly basis.


(b) Failure to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Export sales reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Export sales reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Failure to report Any person who knowingly fails to make any report required under this section shall be fined not more than $25,000 or imprisoned for not more than 1 year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract sanctity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contract sanctity Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall not prohibit or curtail the export of any agricultural commodity under an export sales contract— except that the President may prohibit or curtail the export of any agricultural commodity during a period for which the President has declared a national emergency or for which the Congress has declared war.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>