<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5843" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5843/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5843/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5843"><akn:num>5843</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5843. Advisory council(a) Establishment and membership(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish an advisory council for the program for the purpose of advising, assisting, consulting with, and making recommendations to, the Secretary and Director concerning matters related to the activities, policies and operations of the program.


(2) MembershipThe advisory council shall consist of ex officio members and not more than 13 members appointed by the Secretary.


(3) Recommendations(A) In generalIn making recommendations under paragraph (1), the advisory council shall include recommendations on—(i) the state of public cultivar development, including—(I) an analysis of existing cultivar research investments;

(II) the research gaps relating to the development of cultivars across a diverse range of crops; and

(III) an assessment of the state of commercialization of federally funded cultivars;


(ii) the training and resources needed to meet future breeding challenges;

(iii) the appropriate levels of Federal funding for cultivar development for underserved crops and geographic areas; and

(iv) the development of the plan described in section 5841(d)(6) of this title.




(b) Ex officio membersThe ex officio members of the advisory council shall consist of the following persons (or their designees):(1) The Director.

(2) The Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Science and Education.

(3) The Director of the National Agricultural Library.

(4) The Director of the National Institutes of Health.

(5) The Director of the National Science Foundation.

(6) The Secretary of Energy.

(7) The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.

(8) Such additional officers and employees of the United States as the Secretary determines are necessary for the advisory council to effectively carry out its functions.


(c) Appointment of other membersThe members of the advisory council who are not ex officio members shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows:(1) 6 of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex officio members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ex officio members The ex officio members of the advisory council shall consist of the following persons (or their designees):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of other members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment of other members The members of the advisory council who are not ex officio members shall be appointed by the Secretary as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation Members of the advisory council shall serve without compensation, if not otherwise officers or employees of the United States, except that they shall, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the advisory council, be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under sections 5701 through 5707 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office of appointees; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Term of office of appointees; vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chair The Secretary shall select as the chair of the advisory council one of the members appointed under subsection (c). The term of office of the chair shall be two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings The advisory council shall meet at the call of the chair or on the request of the Director, but at least two times each fiscal year. The location of the meetings of the advisory council shall be subject to the approval of the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Staff The Director shall make available to the advisory council such staff, information, and other assistance as it may require to carry out its functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orientation and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Orientation and training The Director shall provide such orientation and training for new members of the advisory council as may be appropriate for their effective participation in the functions of the advisory council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5843_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comments and recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Comments and recommendations The advisory council may prepare, for inclusion in a report submitted under section 5842 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>