<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/585" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/585/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/585/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_585"><akn:num>585</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for inspection and certification; certificates as prima facie evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 585. Fees for inspection and certification; certificates as prima facie evidence
For inspecting and certifying the grade, quality, and/or condition of apples, the Secretary shall cause to be collected a reasonable fee which shall as nearly as may be cover the cost of the service rendered: Provided, That when cooperative arrangements satisfactory to the Secretary, or his designated representative, for carrying out the purposes of this chapter cannot be made the fees collected hereunder in such cases shall be available until expended to defray the cost of the service rendered, and in such cases the limitations on the amounts expended for the purchase and maintenance of motor-propelled passenger-carrying vehicles shall not be applicable: Provided further, That certificates issued by the authorized agents of the United States Department of Agriculture shall be received in all courts of the United States as prima facie evidence of the truth of the statements therein contained.
(June 10, 1933, ch. 59, § 5, 48 Stat. 124; Pub. L. 106–96, § 1(c)(1), Nov. 12, 1999, 113 Stat. 1321.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1999—Pub. L. 106–96 struck out “and/or pears” after “of apples”.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Functions of all officers, agencies, and employees of Department of Agriculture transferred, with certain exceptions, to Secretary of Agriculture by 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 1, eff. June 4, 1953, 18 F.R. 3219, 67 Stat. 633, set out as a note under section 2201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>