<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5855" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5855/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5855/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5855"><akn:num>5855</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5855. Funding(a) Allocation of funds(1) Cooperative workNot less than 15 percent and not more than 25 percent of the funds appropriated for a fiscal year to carry out this subchapter shall be used for cooperative work with the National Weather Service entered into under section 5852(b)(1) of this title.


(2) Competitive grants programNot less than 15 percent and not more than 25 percent of such funds shall be used by the National Institute of Food and Agriculture for a competitive grants program under section 5852(c) of this title.


(3) Weather information systemsNot less than 25 percent and not more than 35 percent of such funds shall be divided equally between the participating States selected for that fiscal year under section 5854 of this title.


(4) Other purposesThe remaining funds shall be allocated for use by the Agricultural Weather Office and the National Institute of Food and Agriculture in carrying out generally the provisions of this subchapter.



(b) Limitations on use of fundsFunds provided under the authority of this subchapter shall not be used for the construction of facilities. Each State or agency receiving funds shall not use more than 30 percent of such funds for equipment purchases. Any use of the funds in facilitating the distribution of agricultural and climate information to producers shall be done with consideration for the role that the private meteorological sector can play in such information delivery.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012 and $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1641, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 3750; Pub. L. 104–127, title VIII, § 833, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1168; Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, §§ 7202, 7511(c)(20), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1233, 1269; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, §§ 7202, 7511(c)(20), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1994</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5855_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5855_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on use of funds Funds provided under the authority of this subchapter shall not be used for the construction of facilities. Each State or agency receiving funds shall not use more than 30 percent of such funds for equipment purchases. Any use of the funds in facilitating the distribution of agricultural and climate information to producers shall be done with consideration for the role that the private meteorological sector can play in such information delivery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5855_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subchapter $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2012 and $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>