<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5921" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5921/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5921/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5921"><akn:num>5921</akn:num><akn:heading>Biotechnology risk assessment research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5921. Biotechnology risk assessment research(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section—(1) to authorize and support environmental assessment research to help identify and analyze environmental effects of biotechnology; and

(2) to authorize research to help regulators develop long-term policies concerning the introduction of such technology.


(b) Grant programThe Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a grant program within the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the Agricultural Research Service to provide the necessary funding for environmental assessment research concerning the introduction of genetically engineered animals, plants, and microorganisms into the environment.


(c) Research prioritiesThe following types of research shall be given priority for funding:(1) Research designed to identify and develop appropriate management practices to minimize physical and biological risks associated with genetically engineered animals, plants, and microorganisms.

(2) Research designed to develop methods to monitor the dispersal of genetically engineered animals, plants, and microorganisms.

(3) Research designed to further existing knowledge with respect to the characteristics, rates, and methods of gene transfer that may occur between genetically engineered animals, plants, and microorganisms and related wild and agricultural organisms.

(4) Environmental assessment research designed to provide analysis which compares the relative impacts of animals, plants, and microorganisms modified through genetic engineering to other types of production systems.

(5) Other areas of research designed to further the purposes of this section.


(d) Eligibility requirementsGrants under this section shall be—(1) made on the basis of the quality of the proposed research project; and

(2) available to any public or private research or educational institution or organization.


(e) ConsultationIn considering specific areas of research for funding under this section, th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant program The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a grant program within the National Institute of Food and Agriculture and the Agricultural Research Service to provide the necessary funding for environmental assessment research concerning the introduction of genetically engineered animals, plants, and microorganisms into the environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Research priorities The following types of research shall be given priority for funding:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility requirements Grants under this section shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation In considering specific areas of research for funding under this section, the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service and the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Program coordination The Secretary of Agriculture shall coordinate research funded under this section with the Office of Research and Development of the Environmental Protection Agency in order to avoid duplication of research activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5921_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>