<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5925b"><akn:num>5925b</akn:num><akn:heading>Organic agriculture research and extension initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5925b. Organic agriculture research and extension initiative(a) Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorizedIn consultation with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board, using funds made available under subsection (e), the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may make competitive grants in each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to support research, education, and extension activities regarding organically grown and processed agricultural commodities for the purposes of—(1) facilitating the development and improvement of organic agriculture production, breeding, and processing methods;

(2) evaluating the potential economic benefits of organic agricultural production and methods to producers, processors, and rural communities;

(3) exploring international trade opportunities for organically grown and processed agricultural commodities;

(4) determining desirable traits for organic commodities;

(5) identifying marketing and policy constraints on the expansion of organic agriculture;

(6) conducting advanced on-farm research and development that emphasizes observation of, experimentation with, and innovation for working organic farms, including research relating to production, marketing, food safety, socioeconomic conditions, and farm business management;

(7) examining optimal conservation, soil health, and environmental outcomes relating to organically produced agricultural products; and

(8) developing new and improved seed varieties that are particularly suited for organic agriculture.


(b) Grant types and process, prohibition on constructionParagraphs (4), (7), (8), and (11)(B) of subsection (b) of section 3157 of this title shall apply with respect to the making of grants under this section.


(c) Matching requirement(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (3), an entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall provide non-Federal matching funds (including f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorized In consultation with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board, using funds made available under subsection (e), the Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may make competitive grants in each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023 to support research, education, and extension activities regarding organically grown and processed agricultural commodities for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant types and process, prohibition on construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant types and process, prohibition on construction Paragraphs (4), (7), (8), and (11)(B) of subsection (b) of section 3157 of this title shall apply with respect to the making of grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matching requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships encouraged</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Partnerships encouraged Following the completion of a peer review process for grant proposals received under this section, the Secretary may provide a priority to those grant proposals, found in the peer review process to be scientifically meritorious, that involve the cooperation of multiple entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding On October 1, 2003, and each October 1 thereafter through October 1, 2007, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer $3,000,000 to the Secretary of Agriculture for this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>