<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5925"><akn:num>5925</akn:num><akn:heading>High-priority research and extension initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5925. High-priority research and extension initiatives(a) Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorized(1) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) may make competitive grants to support research and extension activities specified in subsections (d) through (g).


(2) Matching funds requirement(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (C), an entity receiving a grant under paragraph (1) shall provide non-Federal matching funds (including funds from an agricultural commodity promotion, research, and information program) equal to not less than the amount of the grant.


(B) In-kind supportNon-Federal matching funds described in subparagraph (A) may include in-kind support.


(C) WaiverThe Secretary may waive the matching funds requirement under subparagraph (A) with respect to a research project if the Secretary determines that—(i) the results of the project are of a particular benefit to a specific agricultural commodity, but those results are likely to be applicable to agricultural commodities generally; or

(ii)(I) the project—(aa) involves a minor commodity; and

(bb) deals with scientifically important research; and


(II) the recipient is unable to satisfy the matching funds requirement.




(3) ConsultationThe Secretary shall make the grants in consultation with the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board.



(b) Administration(1) In generalExcept as otherwise provided in this section, paragraphs (4), (7), (8), and (11)(B) of subsection (b) of section 3157 of this title shall apply with respect to the making of grants under this section.


(2) Use of task forcesTo facilitate the making of research and extension grants under this section in the research and extension areas specified in subsections (d) through (g), the Secretary may appoint a task force for each such area to make recommendations to the Secretary. The Secretary may not incur costs in excess o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Competitive specialized research and extension grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships encouraged</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Partnerships encouraged Following the completion of a peer review process for grant proposals received under this section, the Secretary shall provide a priority to those grant proposals, found in the peer review process to be scientifically meritorious, that involve the cooperation of multiple entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-priority research and extension areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) High-priority research and extension areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pulse crop health initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pulse crop health initiative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training coordination for food and agriculture protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Training coordination for food and agriculture protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pollinator protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Pollinator protection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 1999 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>