<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5925f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5925f"><akn:num>5925f</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm business management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5925f. Farm business management(a) In generalThe Secretary may make competitive research and extension grants for the purpose of improving the farm management knowledge and skills of agricultural producers by maintaining and expanding a national, publicly available farm financial management database to support improved farm management.


(b) Selection criteriaIn allocating funds made available to carry out this section, the Secretary may give priority to grants that—(1) demonstrate an ability to work directly with agricultural producers;

(2) collaborate with farm management educational programs and associations;

(3) address the farm management needs of a variety of crops and regions of the United States; and

(4) contribute data to the national farm financial management database.


(c) AdministrationParagraphs (4), (7), (8), and (11)(B) of subsection (b) of section 3157 of this title shall apply with respect to the making of grants under this section.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—(1) such sums as are necessary for fiscal year 2013; and

(2) $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2023.


(Pub. L. 101–624, title XVI, § 1672D, as added Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7208, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1241; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, § 7208, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2002; amended Pub. L. 113–79, title VII, § 7213, Feb. 7, 2014, 128 Stat. 886; Pub. L. 115–334, title VII, § 7211, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4811.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 enacted identical sections. Pub. L. 110–234 was repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Amendments2018—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 115–334, § 7211(1), amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Secretary may make competitive research and extension grants for the purpose of—
“(1) improving the farm management knowledge and skills of agricultural producers; and
“(2) establi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make competitive research and extension grants for the purpose of improving the farm management knowledge and skills of agricultural producers by maintaining and expanding a national, publicly available farm financial management database to support improved farm management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection criteria In allocating funds made available to carry out this section, the Secretary may give priority to grants that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration Paragraphs (4), (7), (8), and (11)(B) of subsection (b) of section 3157 of this title shall apply with respect to the making of grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5925f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>