<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5936a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5936a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/5936a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5936a"><akn:num>5936a</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for farm stress programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5936a. Support for farm stress programs(a) In generalThe Secretary shall make grants to State departments of agriculture (or such equivalent department) to expand or sustain stress assistance programs for individuals who are engaged in farming, ranching, and other agriculture-related occupations, including—(1) programs that meet the criteria specified in section 5936(b)(1) of this title; and

(2) any State initiatives carried out as of December 27, 2020, that provide stress assistance for such individuals.


(b) Grant timing and amountIn making grants under subsection (a), not later than 60 days after December 27, 2020, and subject to subsection (c), the Secretary shall—(1) make awards to States submitting State plans that meet the criteria specified in paragraph (1) of such subsection within the time period specified by the Secretary; and

(2) of the amounts made available under subsection (f), allocate among such States, an amount to be determined by the Secretary, which in no case may exceed $500,000 for each State.


(c) State plan(1) In generalA State department of agriculture seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit to the Secretary a State plan to expand or sustain stress assistance programs described in that subsection that includes—(A) a description of each activity and the estimated amount of funding to support each program and activity carried out through such a program;

(B) an estimated timeline for the operation of each such program and activity;

(C) the total amount of funding sought; and

(D) an assurance that the State department of agriculture will comply with the reporting requirement under subsection (e).


(2) GuidanceNot later than 20 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall issue guidance for States with respect to the submission of a State plan under paragraph (1) and the allocation criteria under subsection (b).


(3) ReallocationIf, after the first grants are awarded pursuant to allocation under subsection (b), any fund</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall make grants to State departments of agriculture (or such equivalent department) to expand or sustain stress assistance programs for individuals who are engaged in farming, ranching, and other agriculture-related occupations, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant timing and amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant timing and amount In making grants under subsection (a), not later than 60 days after December 27, 2020, and subject to subsection (c), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Collaboration The Secretary may issue guidance to encourage State departments of agriculture to use funds provided under this section to support programs described in subsection (a) that are operated by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting Not later than 180 days after the COVID–19 public health emergency ends, each State receiving additional grants under subsection (b) shall submit a report to the Secretary describing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding Out of the funds of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to carry out this section $28,000,000, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5936a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State defined In this section, the term “State” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>