<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6105"><akn:num>6105</akn:num><akn:heading>Referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6105. Referenda(a) Initial referendum(1) In generalWithin the 60-day period immediately preceding the effective date of an order issued under section 6103(b) of this title, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among mushroom producers and importers to ascertain whether the order shall go into effect.


(2) Approval of orderThe order shall become effective, as provided in section 6103(b) of this title, if the Secretary determines that the order has been approved by a majority of the producers and importers voting in the referendum, which majority, on average, annually produces and imports into the United States more than 50 percent of the mushrooms annually produced and imported by all those voting in the referendum.



(b) Succeeding referenda(1) Determination concerning order(A) In generalEffective 5 years after the date on which an order becomes effective under section 6103(b) of this title, the Secretary shall conduct a referendum among mushroom producers and importers to ascertain whether they favor continuation, termination, or suspension of the order.


(B) Request for referendumEffective beginning 3 years after the date on which an order becomes effective under section 6103(b) of this title, the Secretary, on request of a representative group comprising 30 percent or more of the number of mushroom producers and importers, may conduct a referendum to ascertain whether producers and importers favor termination or suspension of the order.



(2) Suspension or terminationIf, as a result of any referendum conducted under paragraph (1), the Secretary determines that suspension or termination of an order is favored by a majority of the producers and importers voting in the referendum, which majority, on average, annually produces and imports into the United States more than 50 percent of the mushrooms annually produced and imported by all those voting in the referendum, the Secretary shall—(A) within 6 months after making such determination, suspend or termina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial referendum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial referendum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Succeeding referenda</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Succeeding referenda</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Manner Referenda conducted pursuant to this section shall be conducted in such a manner as is determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>