<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/612c–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/612c–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/612c–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_612c_4"><akn:num>612c–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of specialty crops</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 612c–4. Purchase of specialty crops(a) General purchase authorityOf the funds made available under section 612c of this title, for fiscal year 2002 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall use not less than $200,000,000 each fiscal year to purchase fruits, vegetables, and other specialty food crops.


(b) Purchase of fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutionsThe Secretary of Agriculture shall purchase fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions in accordance with section 1755(a) of title 42 using, of the amount specified in subsection (a), not less than $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.


(c) DefinitionsIn this section, the terms “fruits”, “vegetables”, and “other specialty food crops” shall have the meaning given the terms by the Secretary of Agriculture.


(Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10603, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 511; Pub. L. 110–234, title IV, § 4404(c), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1138; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title IV, § 4404(c), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1899; Pub. L. 113–79, title IV, § 4201, Feb. 7, 2014, 128 Stat. 821; Pub. L. 115–334, title IV, § 4202, Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4655.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The authorities provided by each provision of, and each amendment made by, Pub. L. 115–334, as in effect on Sept. 30, 2023, to continue, and authorities to be carried out, until the later of Sept. 30, 2024, or the date specified in the provision of, or amendment made by, Pub. L. 115–334, see section 102(a) of Pub. L. 118–22, set out in an Extension of Agricultural Programs note under section 9001 of this title.
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.
Section was enacted as part of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002, and not as part of the Agricultural Adjustment Act which comprises t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612c_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General purchase authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General purchase authority Of the funds made available under section 612c of this title, for fiscal year 2002 and each subsequent fiscal year, the Secretary of Agriculture shall use not less than $200,000,000 each fiscal year to purchase fruits, vegetables, and other specialty food crops.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612c_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purchase of fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions The Secretary of Agriculture shall purchase fresh fruits and vegetables for distribution to schools and service institutions in accordance with section 1755(a) of title 42 using, of the amount specified in subsection (a), not less than $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612c_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section, the terms “fruits”, “vegetables”, and “other specialty food crops” shall have the meaning given the terms by the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>