<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6302"><akn:num>6302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6302. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) BoardThe term “Board” means the United Soybean Board established under section 6304(b) of this title.


(2) CommerceThe term “commerce” includes interstate, foreign, and intrastate commerce.


(3) CommitteeThe term “Committee” means the Soybean Program Coordinating Committee established under section 6304(g) of this title.


(4) Consumer informationThe term “consumer information” means information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of soybeans or soybean products.


(5) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.


(6) First purchaserThe term “first purchaser” means—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), any person buying or otherwise acquiring from a producer soybeans produced by such producer; or

(B) the Commodity Credit Corporation, in any case in which soybeans are pledged as collateral for a loan issued under any price support loan program administered by the Commodity Credit Corporation.


(7) Industry informationThe term “industry information” means information and programs that will lead to the development of new markets, new marketing strategies, or increased efficiency for the soybean industry, and activities to enhance the image of the soybean industry.


(8) MarketingThe term “marketing” means the sale or other disposition of soybeans or soybean products in any channel of commerce.


(9) Net market priceThe term “net market price” means—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), the sales price or other value received by a producer for soybeans after adjustments for any premium or discount based on grading or quality factors, as determined by the Secretary; or

(B) for soybeans pledged as collateral for a loan issued under any price support loan program administered by the Commodity Credit Corporation, the principal amount of the loan.


(10) OrderThe term “order” means an order issued </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Board The term “Board” means the United Soybean Board established under section 6304(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Commerce The term “commerce” includes interstate, foreign, and intrastate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Committee The term “Committee” means the Soybean Program Coordinating Committee established under section 6304(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Consumer information The term “consumer information” means information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of soybeans or soybean products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>First purchaser</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) First purchaser The term “first purchaser” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Industry information The term “industry information” means information and programs that will lead to the development of new markets, new marketing strategies, or increased efficiency for the soybean industry, and activities to enhance the image of the soybean industry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Marketing The term “marketing” means the sale or other disposition of soybeans or soybean products in any channel of commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net market price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Net market price The term “net market price” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6302_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Order The term “order” means an order issued under section 6303 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>