<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6304"><akn:num>6304</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6304. Required terms in orders(a) In generalAny order issued under this chapter shall contain the terms and conditions specified in this section.


(b) Establishment and membership of United Soybean Board(1) In generalThe order shall provide for the establishment of, and appointment of members to, a United Soybean Board to administer the order. Members of the Board shall be soybean producers appointed by the Secretary, on a geographic basis, from State or combined units, as provided in this subsection. The cumulative number of seats on the Board shall be the total number of seats to which all the units are entitled.


(2) SeatsThe Secretary shall establish State units and combined units and seats on the Board for such units, as follows:(A) State unitsExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), each State shall be considered as a unit.


(B) Combined unitsA State in which average annual soybean production is less than 3,000,000 bushels shall be grouped with other States into a combined unit. To the extent practicable, each State with average annual soybean production of less than 3,000,000 bushels shall be grouped with other States with average annual soybean production of less than 3,000,000 bushels into a combined unit, in a manner prescribed in the order, and each combined unit shall consist of geographically contiguous States. To the extent practicable, each combined unit shall have an average annual production of soybeans of at least 3,000,000 bushels.


(C) Number of seats per unitSubject to subparagraph (F), each unit, as established under subparagraph (A) or (B)—(i) if its average annual soybean production is less than 15,000,000 bushels, shall be entitled to one seat on the Board;

(ii) if its average annual soybean production is 15,000,000 bushels or more but less than 70,000,000 bushels, shall be entitled to 2 seats on the Board;

(iii) if its average annual soybean production is 70,000,000 bushels or more but less than 200,000,000 bushels, shall be entitled</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any order issued under this chapter shall contain the terms and conditions specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and membership of United Soybean Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and membership of United Soybean Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers and duties of Board The order shall define the powers and duties of the Board and shall include the power and duty—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board voting procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board voting procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Budgets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plans and projects The order shall provide that the Board shall review or, on its own initiative, develop plans or projects of promotion, research, consumer information, and industry information, to be paid for with funds received by the Board. Such plans or projects shall not become effective until approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Soybean Program Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Soybean Program Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Powers and duties of Committee The order shall define the powers and duties that the Board may assign to the Committee, which may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6304_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contracts and agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>