<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6308"><akn:num>6308</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations and power to subpoena</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6308. Investigations and power to subpoena(a) InvestigationsThe Secretary may make such investigations as the Secretary considers necessary—(1) for the effective administration of this chapter; and

(2) to determine whether any person has engaged or is engaging in any act that constitutes a violation of this chapter, or any order, rule, or regulation issued under this chapter.


(b) Subpoenas, oaths, and affirmations(1) In generalFor the purpose of an investigation under subsection (a), the Secretary may administer oaths and affirmations, and issue a subpoena to require the production of any records that are relevant to the inquiry. The production of any such records may be required from any place in the United States.


(2) Administrative hearingsFor the purpose of an administrative hearing held under section 6306 or 6307 of this title, the presiding officer is authorized to administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any records that are relevant to the inquiry. Such attendance of witnesses and the production of any such records may be required from any place in the United States.



(c) Aid of courtsIn the case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Secretary may invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which such investigation or proceeding is carried on, or where such person resides or carries on business, in order to enforce a subpoena issued by the Secretary under subsection (b). The court may issue an order requiring such person to comply with such a subpoena.


(d) ContemptAny failure to obey an order of the court under this section may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.


(e) ProcessProcess in any such case may be served in the judicial district in which such person resides or conducts business or wherever such person may be found.


(f) Hearing siteThe site of any hearings held under section</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Investigations The Secretary may make such investigations as the Secretary considers necessary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoenas, oaths, and affirmations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subpoenas, oaths, and affirmations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aid of courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Aid of courts In the case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Secretary may invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction of which such investigation or proceeding is carried on, or where such person resides or carries on business, in order to enforce a subpoena issued by the Secretary under subsection (b). The court may issue an order requiring such person to comply with such a subpoena.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contempt Any failure to obey an order of the court under this section may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Process Process in any such case may be served in the judicial district in which such person resides or conducts business or wherever such person may be found.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6308_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hearing site The site of any hearings held under section 6306 or 6307 of this title shall be within the judicial district where such person resides or has a principal place of business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>