<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6407"><akn:num>6407</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6407. Required terms in orders(a) In generalEach order issued under this chapter shall contain the terms and conditions prescribed in this section.


(b) National Processor Advertising and Promotion Board(1) EstablishmentThe order shall establish a National Processor Advertising and Promotion Board to administer the order.


(2) Service to entire industryIn administering the order, the Board shall carry out programs and projects that will provide maximum benefit to the fluid milk industry and promote only fluid milk products. The Board shall, to the extent practicable, ensure that advertising coverage in each region is proportionate to the funds collected from each region.


(3) RegionsThe Secretary shall establish not less than 12 nor more than 15 regions in order to ensure appropriate geographic representation on the Board.


(4) Board membershipThe Board shall consist of one member appointed by the Secretary, from among fluid milk processors, to represent each of the regions established under paragraph (3), with the membership representing, to the extent practicable, differing sizes of operations. The Secretary shall appoint five additional at-large members to the Board, of which at least three shall be fluid milk processors and at least one shall be from the general public.


(5) Terms of officeThe members of the Board shall serve for terms of 3 years, except that the members appointed to the initial Board shall serve, proportionately, for terms of 1, 2, and 3 years, as determined by the Secretary. No member shall serve for more than 2 consecutive terms, except that the members that are selected to serve for the initial term of 1 or 2 years shall be eligible to be reappointed for a 3-year term.


(6) CompensationEach member of the Board shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed for necessary and reasonable expenses incurred in the performance of duties of the Board.



(c) Powers and duties of BoardThe order shall define the powers and duties o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each order issued under this chapter shall contain the terms and conditions prescribed in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Processor Advertising and Promotion Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Processor Advertising and Promotion Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers and duties of Board The order shall define the powers and duties of the Board, which shall include the power and duty—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans and budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plans and budgets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on branded advertising</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on branded advertising A program or project conducted under this chapter shall not make any reference to private brand names or use false or unwarranted claims on behalf of fluid milk products, or false or unwarranted statements with respect to the attributes or use of any competing products, except that this subsection shall not preclude the Board from offering its programs and projects for use by commercial parties, under such terms and conditions as the Board may prescribe as approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contracts and agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Investment of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Books and records of Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records of processors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Books and records of processors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6407_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds to influence governmental action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Prohibition on use of funds to influence governmental action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>