<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6515"><akn:num>6515</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of certifying agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6515. Requirements of certifying agents(a) Ability to implement requirementsTo be accredited as a certifying agent under section 6514 of this title, a governing State official or a person shall be able to fully implement the applicable organic certification program established under this chapter.


(b) InspectorsAny certifying agent shall employ a sufficient number of inspectors to implement the applicable organic certification program established under this chapter, as determined by the Secretary.


(c) AgreementAny certifying agent shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary under which such agent shall—(1) agree to carry out the provisions of this chapter; and

(2) agree to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(d) Private certifying agent agreementAny certifying agent that is a private person shall, in addition to the agreement required in subsection (c)—(1) agree to hold the Secretary harmless for any failure on the part of the certifying agent to carry out the provisions of this chapter; and

(2) furnish reasonable security, in an amount determined by the Secretary, for the purpose of protecting the rights of participants in the applicable organic certification program established under this chapter.


(e) Compliance with programAny certifying agent shall fully comply with the terms and conditions of the applicable organic certification program implemented under this chapter.


(f) ConfidentialityExcept as provided in section 6506(a)(9) of this title, any certifying agent shall maintain strict confidentiality with respect to its clients under the applicable organic certification program and may not disclose to third parties (with the exception of the Secretary or the applicable governing State official) any business related information concerning such client obtained while implementing this chapter.


(g) Conflict of interestAny certifying agent shall not—(1) carry out any inspections of any operation in which such c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ability to implement requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Ability to implement requirements To be accredited as a certifying agent under section 6514 of this title, a governing State official or a person shall be able to fully implement the applicable organic certification program established under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspectors Any certifying agent shall employ a sufficient number of inspectors to implement the applicable organic certification program established under this chapter, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement Any certifying agent shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary under which such agent shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private certifying agent agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Private certifying agent agreement Any certifying agent that is a private person shall, in addition to the agreement required in subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compliance with program Any certifying agent shall fully comply with the terms and conditions of the applicable organic certification program implemented under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Confidentiality Except as provided in section 6506(a)(9) of this title, any certifying agent shall maintain strict confidentiality with respect to its clients under the applicable organic certification program and may not disclose to third parties (with the exception of the Secretary or the applicable governing State official) any business related information concerning such client obtained while implementing this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conflict of interest Any certifying agent shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrator A certifying agent that is a private person shall nominate the individual who controls the day-to-day operation of the agent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loss of accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Loss of accreditation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6515_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Notice Not later than 90 days after the date on which a new certifying office performing certification activities opens, an accredited certifying agent shall notify the Secretary of the opening.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>