<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6518" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6518/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6518/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6518"><akn:num>6518</akn:num><akn:heading>National Organic Standards Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6518. National Organic Standards Board(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a National Organic Standards Board (hereafter referred to in this section as the “Board”) in accordance with chapter 10 of title 5 to assist in the development of standards for substances to be used in organic production and to advise the Secretary on any other aspects of the implementation of this chapter.


(b) Composition of BoardThe Board shall be composed of 15 members, of which—(1) four shall be individuals who own or operate an organic farming operation, or employees of such individuals;

(2) two shall be individuals who own or operate an organic handling operation, or employees of such individuals;

(3) one shall be an individual who owns or operates a retail establishment with significant trade in organic products, or an employee of such individual;

(4) three shall be individuals with expertise in areas of environmental protection and resource conservation;

(5) three shall be individuals who represent public interest or consumer interest groups;

(6) one shall be an individual with expertise in the fields of toxicology, ecology, or biochemistry; and

(7) one shall be an individual who is a certifying agent as identified under section 6515 of this title.


(c) AppointmentNot later than 180 days after November 28, 1990, the Secretary shall appoint the members of the Board under paragraph (1) through (6) of subsection (b) (and under subsection (b)(7) at an appropriate date after the certification of individuals as certifying agents under section 6515 of this title) from nominations received from organic certifying organizations, States, and other interested persons and organizations.


(d) TermA member of the Board shall serve for a term of 5 years, except that the Secretary shall appoint the original members of the Board for staggered terms. A member cannot serve consecutive terms unless such member served an original term that was less than 5 years.


(e) MeetingsThe Secret</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a National Organic Standards Board (hereafter referred to in this section as the “Board”) in accordance with chapter 10 of title 5 to assist in the development of standards for substances to be used in organic production and to advise the Secretary on any other aspects of the implementation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition of Board The Board shall be composed of 15 members, of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment Not later than 180 days after November 28, 1990, the Secretary shall appoint the members of the Board under paragraph (1) through (6) of subsection (b) (and under subsection (b)(7) at an appropriate date after the certification of individuals as certifying agents under section 6515 of this title) from nominations received from organic certifying organizations, States, and other interested persons and organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term A member of the Board shall serve for a term of 5 years, except that the Secretary shall appoint the original members of the Board for staggered terms. A member cannot serve consecutive terms unless such member served an original term that was less than 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings The Secretary shall convene a meeting of the Board not later than 60 days after the appointment of its members and shall convene subsequent meetings on a periodic basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation and expenses A member of the Board shall serve without compensation. While away from their homes or regular places of business on the business of the Board, members of the Board may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as is authorized under section 5703 of title 5 for persons employed intermittently in the Government service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Chairperson The Board shall select a Chairperson for the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Quorum A majority of the members of the Board shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisive votes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Decisive votes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6518_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Other terms and conditions The Secretary shall authorize the Board to hire a staff director and shall detail staff of the Department of Agriculture or allow for the hiring of staff and may, subject to necessary appropriations, pay necessary expenses incurred by such Board in carrying out the provisions of this chapter, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>