<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6523"><akn:num>6523</akn:num><akn:heading>National organic certification cost-share program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6523. National organic certification cost-share program(a) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a national organic certification cost-share program to assist producers and handlers of agricultural products in obtaining certification under the national organic production program established under the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (7 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.).


(b) Federal share(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall pay under this section not more than 75 percent of the costs incurred by a producer or handler in obtaining certification under the national organic production program, as certified to and approved by the Secretary.


(2) Maximum amountThe maximum amount of a payment made to a producer or handler under this section shall be $750.



(c) ReportingNot later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that describes the requests by, disbursements to, and expenditures for each State under the program during the current and previous fiscal year, including the number of producers and handlers served by the program in the previous fiscal year.


(d) Mandatory funding(1) In generalOf the funds of the Commodity Credit Corporation, the Secretary shall make available to carry out this section—(A) $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 and 2020;

(B) $4,000,000 for fiscal year 2021; and

(C) $8,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2031.


(2) AvailabilityAmounts made available under paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.



(Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10606, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 514; Pub. L. 110–234, title X, § 10301, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1346; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title X, § 10301, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2108; Pub. L. 112–240, title VII, § 701(g)(3), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2366; Pub. L. 113–79, title X, § 10004(c), Feb. 7, 2014</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a national organic certification cost-share program to assist producers and handlers of agricultural products in obtaining certification under the national organic production program established under the Organic Foods Production Act of 1990 (7 U.S.C. 6501 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report that describes the requests by, disbursements to, and expenditures for each State under the program during the current and previous fiscal year, including the number of producers and handlers served by the program in the previous fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6523_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mandatory funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>