<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6711"><akn:num>6711</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbon cycle research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6711. Carbon cycle research(a) In generalTo the extent funds are made available for this purpose, the Secretary shall provide a grant to the Consortium for Agricultural Soils Mitigation of Greenhouse Gases, acting through Kansas State University, to develop, analyze, and implement, through the land grant universities described in subsection (b), carbon cycle research at the national, regional, and local levels.


(b) Land grant universitiesThe land grant universities referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) Colorado State University.

(2) Iowa State University.

(3) Kansas State University.

(4) Michigan State University.

(5) Montana State University.

(6) Purdue University.

(7) Ohio State University.

(8) Texas A&amp;M University.

(9) University of Nebraska.


(c) UseLand grant universities described in subsection (b) shall use funds made available under this section—(1) to conduct research to improve the scientific basis of using land management practices to increase soil carbon sequestration, including research on the use of new technologies to increase carbon cycle effectiveness, such as biotechnology and nanotechnology;

(2) to enter into partnerships to identify, develop, and evaluate agricultural best practices, including partnerships between—(A) Federal, State, or private entities; and

(B) the Department of Agriculture;


(3) to develop necessary computer models to predict and assess the carbon cycle;

(4) to estimate and develop mechanisms to measure carbon levels made available as a result of—(A) voluntary Federal conservation programs;

(B) private and Federal forests; and

(C) other land uses;


(5) to develop outreach programs, in coordination with Extension Services, to share information on carbon cycle and agricultural best practices that is useful to agricultural producers; and

(6) to collaborate with the Great Plains Regional Earth Science Application Center to develop a space-based carbon cycle remote sensing technology program to—(A)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To the extent funds are made available for this purpose, the Secretary shall provide a grant to the Consortium for Agricultural Soils Mitigation of Greenhouse Gases, acting through Kansas State University, to develop, analyze, and implement, through the land grant universities described in subsection (b), carbon cycle research at the national, regional, and local levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land grant universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Land grant universities The land grant universities referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use Land grant universities described in subsection (b) shall use funds made available under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Extension projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs Not more than 3 percent of the funds made available for this section may be used by the Secretary to pay administrative costs incurred in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6711_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>