<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6802"><akn:num>6802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6802. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) Consumer informationThe term “consumer information” means any action or program that provides information to consumers and other persons on appropriate uses under varied circumstances, and on the care and handling, of cut flowers or cut greens.


(2) Cut flowers and cut greens(A) In general(i) Cut flowersThe term “cut flowers” includes all flowers cut from growing plants that are used as fresh-cut flowers and that are produced under cover or in field operations.


(ii) Cut greensThe term “cut greens” includes all cultivated or noncultivated decorative foliage cut from growing plants that are used as fresh-cut decorative foliage (except Christmas trees) and that are produced under cover or in field operations.


(iii) ExclusionsThe terms “cut flowers” and “cut greens” do not include a foliage plant, floral supply, or flowering plant.



(B) Substantial portionIn any case in which a handler packages cut flowers or cut greens with hard goods in an article (such as a gift basket or similar presentation) for sale to a retailer, the PromoFlor Council may determine, under procedures specified in the order, that the cut flowers or cut greens in the article do not constitute a substantial portion of the value of the article and that, based on the determination, the article shall not be treated as an article of cut flowers or cut greens subject to assessment under the order.



(3) Gross sales priceThe term “gross sales price” means the total amount of the transaction in a sale of cut flowers or cut greens from a handler to a retailer or exempt handler.


(4) Handler(A) Qualified handler(i) In generalThe term “qualified handler” means a person (including a cooperative) operating in the cut flowers or cut greens marketing system—(I) that sells domestic or imported cut flowers or cut greens to retailers and exempt handlers; and

(II) whose annual sales of cut flowers and cut greens to retailers and exempt handlers are $750,000 or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Consumer information The term “consumer information” means any action or program that provides information to consumers and other persons on appropriate uses under varied circumstances, and on the care and handling, of cut flowers or cut greens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cut flowers and cut greens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cut flowers and cut greens</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gross sales price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Gross sales price The term “gross sales price” means the total amount of the transaction in a sale of cut flowers or cut greens from a handler to a retailer or exempt handler.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Handler</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Handler</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Order The term “order” means an order issued under this chapter (other than sections 6808, 6809, and 6811 of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Person The term “person” means any individual, group of individuals, firm, partnership, corporation, joint stock company, association, society, cooperative, or other legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>PromoFlor Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) PromoFlor Council The term “PromoFlor Council” means the Fresh Cut Flowers and Fresh Cut Greens Promotion Council established under section 6804(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Promotion The term “promotion” means any action determined by the Secretary to advance the image, desirability, or marketability of cut flowers or cut greens, including paid advertising.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Research The term “research” means market research and studies limited to the support of advertising, market development, and other promotion efforts and consumer information efforts relating to cut flowers or cut greens, including educational activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6802_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retailer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Retailer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>