<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6804"><akn:num>6804</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6804. Required terms in orders(a) In generalAn order shall contain the terms and provisions specified in this section.


(b) PromoFlor Council(1) Establishment and membership(A) EstablishmentThe order shall provide for the establishment of a Fresh Cut Flowers and Fresh Cut Greens Promotion Council, consisting of 25 members, to administer the order.


(B) Membership(i) AppointmentThe order shall provide that members of the PromoFlor Council shall be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).


(ii) CompositionThe PromoFlor Council shall consist of—(I) participating qualified handlers representing qualified wholesale handlers and producers and importers that are qualified handlers;

(II) representatives of traditional retailers; and

(III) representatives of persons who produce fresh cut flowers and fresh cut greens.




(2) Distribution of appointments(A) In generalThe order shall provide that the membership of the PromoFlor Council shall consist of—(i) 14 members representing qualified wholesale handlers of domestic or imported cut flowers and cut greens;

(ii) 3 members representing producers that are qualified handlers of cut flowers and cut greens;

(iii) 3 members representing importers that are qualified handlers of cut flowers and cut greens;

(iv) 3 members representing traditional cut flowers and cut greens retailers; and

(v) 2 members representing persons who produce fresh cut flowers and fresh cut greens, of whom—(I) 1 member shall represent persons who produce the flowers or greens in locations that are east of the Mississippi River; and

(II) 1 member shall represent persons who produce the flowers or greens in locations that are west of the Mississippi River.



(B) DefinitionsAs used in this subsection:(i) Importer that is a qualified handlerThe term “importer that is a qualified handler” means an entity—(I) whose principal activity is the importation of cut flowers or cut greens into the United Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An order shall contain the terms and provisions specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>PromoFlor Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) PromoFlor Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General responsibilities of PromoFlor Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General responsibilities of PromoFlor Council The order shall define the general responsibilities of the PromoFlor Council, which shall include the responsibility to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgets; plans and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Budgets; plans and projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contracts and agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records of PromoFlor Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Books and records of PromoFlor Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control of administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Control of administrative costs The order shall provide that the PromoFlor Council shall, as soon as practicable after the order becomes effective and after consultation with the Secretary and other appropriate persons, implement a system of cost controls based on normally accepted business practices that will ensure that the annual budgets of the PromoFlor Council include only amounts for administrative expenses that cover the minimum administrative activities and personnel needed to properly administer and enforce the order, and conduct, supervise, and evaluate plans and projects under the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition The order shall prohibit the use of any funds received by the PromoFlor Council in any manner for the purpose of influencing legislation or government action or policy, except that the funds may be used by the PromoFlor Council for the development and recommendation to the Secretary of amendments to the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6804_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records; reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Books and records; reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>