<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6810" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6810/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6810/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6810"><akn:num>6810</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6810. Confidentiality(a) ProhibitionNo information on how a person voted in a referendum conducted under this chapter shall be made public.


(b) PenaltyAny person who knowingly violates subsection (a) or the confidentiality terms of an order, as described in section 6804(j)(2) of this title, shall be subject to a fine of not less than $1,000 nor more than $10,000 or to imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both. If the person is an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture or the PromoFlor Council, the person shall be removed from office.


(c) Additional prohibitionNo information obtained under this chapter may be made available to any agency or officer of the Federal Government for any purpose other than the implementation of this chapter or an investigatory or enforcement action necessary for the implementation of this chapter.


(d) Withholding information from Congress prohibitedNothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize the withholding of information from Congress.


(Pub. L. 103–190, § 11, Dec. 14, 1993, 107 Stat. 2288.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6810_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition No information on how a person voted in a referendum conducted under this chapter shall be made public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6810_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalty Any person who knowingly violates subsection (a) or the confidentiality terms of an order, as described in section 6804(j)(2) of this title, shall be subject to a fine of not less than $1,000 nor more than $10,000 or to imprisonment for not more than 1 year, or both. If the person is an officer or employee of the Department of Agriculture or the PromoFlor Council, the person shall be removed from office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6810_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional prohibition No information obtained under this chapter may be made available to any agency or officer of the Federal Government for any purpose other than the implementation of this chapter or an investigatory or enforcement action necessary for the implementation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6810_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding information from Congress prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withholding information from Congress prohibited Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize the withholding of information from Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>