<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6812" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6812/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6812/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6812"><akn:num>6812</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6812. Construction(a) Termination or suspension not an orderThe termination or suspension of an order, or a provision of an order, shall not be considered an order under the meaning of this chapter.


(b) Producer rightsThis chapter—(1) may not be construed to provide for control of production or otherwise limit the right of individual cut flowers and cut greens producers to produce cut flowers and cut greens; and

(2) shall be construed to treat all persons producing cut flowers and cut greens fairly and to implement any order in an equitable manner.


(c) Other programsNothing in this chapter may be construed to preempt or supersede any other program relating to cut flowers or cut greens promotion and consumer information organized and operated under the laws of the United States or a State.


(Pub. L. 103–190, § 13, Dec. 14, 1993, 107 Stat. 2289.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6812_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination or suspension not an order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Termination or suspension not an order The termination or suspension of an order, or a provision of an order, shall not be considered an order under the meaning of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6812_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Producer rights This chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6812_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other programs Nothing in this chapter may be construed to preempt or supersede any other program relating to cut flowers or cut greens promotion and consumer information organized and operated under the laws of the United States or a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>