<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6918" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6918/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6918/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6918"><akn:num>6918</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Secretaries of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6918. Assistant Secretaries of Agriculture(a) AuthorizationThe Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the positions of—(1) Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Congressional Relations and Intergovernmental Affairs;

(2) Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Administration; and

(3) Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights.


(b) Confirmation requiredIf the Secretary establishes any position of Assistant Secretary authorized under paragraph (1) or (3) of subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(c) Duties of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil RightsThe Secretary may delegate to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights responsibility for—(1) ensuring compliance with all civil rights and related laws by all agencies and under all programs of the Department;

(2) coordinating administration of civil rights laws (including regulations) within the Department for employees of, and participants in, programs of the Department; and

(3) ensuring that necessary and appropriate civil rights components are properly incorporated into all strategic planning initiatives of the Department and agencies of the Department.


(Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 218, Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3212; Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(a) [title X, § 1001(1)], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681, 2681–41; Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10704(a), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 518; Pub. L. 112–166, § 2(a)(1), Aug. 10, 2012, 126 Stat. 1283; Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, §§ 12401(a), 12415(b)(1), Dec. 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 4971, 4981.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 115–334, § 12401(a), substituted “Relations and Intergovernmental Affairs” for “Relations”.
Subsecs. (c), (d). Pub. L. 115–334, § 12415(b)(1), amended this section, as in effect on the day before the effective date of the amendments made by section 2(a)(1) of Pub. L. 112–166, by redesignating subsec. (d) as (c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6918_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The Secretary is authorized to establish in the Department the positions of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6918_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confirmation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Confirmation required If the Secretary establishes any position of Assistant Secretary authorized under paragraph (1) or (3) of subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6918_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Civil Rights The Secretary may delegate to the Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights responsibility for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>