<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6941a"><akn:num>6941a</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6941a. Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas (in this section referred to as the “Coordinator”), to be located in the Rural Development Mission Area.


(b) MissionThe mission of the Coordinator shall be to direct Department of Agriculture resources to high need, high poverty rural areas.


(c) DutiesThe Coordinator shall consult with other offices in directing technical assistance, strategic regional planning, at the State and local level, for developing rural economic development that leverages the resources of State and local governments and non-profit and community development organizations.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as necessary to carry out this section for fiscal years 2008 through 2012.


(Pub. L. 110–234, title XIV, § 14218, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1482; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title XIV, § 14218, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2244.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 enacted identical sections. Pub. L. 110–234 was repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.
Section was enacted as part of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, and not as part of the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994, which in part comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateEnactment of this section and repeal of Pub. L. 110–234 by Pub. L. 110–246 effective May 22, 2008, the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–234, see section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246, set out as a note under section 8701 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Agriculture shall establish a Coordinator for Chronically Underserved Rural Areas (in this section referred to as the “Coordinator”), to be located in the Rural Development Mission Area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mission The mission of the Coordinator shall be to direct Department of Agriculture resources to high need, high poverty rural areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Coordinator shall consult with other offices in directing technical assistance, strategic regional planning, at the State and local level, for developing rural economic development that leverages the resources of State and local governments and non-profit and community development organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as necessary to carry out this section for fiscal years 2008 through 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>