<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6941/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6941"><akn:num>6941</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6941. Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development(a) AuthorizationThe Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development.


(b) Confirmation requiredThe Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(c) Functions of Under Secretary(1) Principal functionsUpon establishment, the Secretary shall delegate to the Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development those functions under the jurisdiction of the Department that are related to rural economic and community development.


(2) Additional functionsThe Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development shall perform such other functions as may be required by law or prescribed by the Secretary.



(d) SuccessionAny official who is serving as Under Secretary of Agriculture for Small Community and Rural Development on October 13, 1994, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after October 13, 1994 (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).


(e) Loan approval authorityApproval authority for loans and loan guarantees in connection with the electric and telephone loan and loan guarantee programs authorized by the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (7 U.S.C. 901 et seq.) shall not be transferred to, or conditioned on review of, a State director or other employee whose primary duty is not the review and approval of such loans or the provision of assistance to such borrowers.


(Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 231, Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3218; Pub. L. 104–127, title VII, § 794(a), Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 1155; Pub. L. 115–334, title XII, § 12407, Dec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The Secretary shall establish in the Department the position of Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confirmation required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Confirmation required The Under Secretary of Agriculture for Rural Development shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Under Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of Under Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Succession</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Succession Any official who is serving as Under Secretary of Agriculture for Small Community and Rural Development on October 13, 1994, and who was appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall not be required to be reappointed under subsection (b) to the successor position authorized under subsection (a) if the Secretary establishes the position, and the official occupies the new position, within 180 days after October 13, 1994 (or such later date set by the Secretary if litigation delays rapid succession).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6941_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan approval authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Loan approval authority Approval authority for loans and loan guarantees in connection with the electric and telephone loan and loan guarantee programs authorized by the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 (7 U.S.C. 901 et seq.) shall not be transferred to, or conditioned on review of, a State director or other employee whose primary duty is not the review and approval of such loans or the provision of assistance to such borrowers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>