<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6b_1"><akn:num>6b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6b–1. Enforcement authority(a) Commodity Futures Trading CommissionExcept as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Commission shall have exclusive authority to enforce the provisions of subtitle A of the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010 with respect to any person.


(b) Prudential regulatorsThe prudential regulators shall have exclusive authority to enforce the provisions of section 6s(e) of this title with respect to swap dealers or major swap participants for which they are the prudential regulator.


(c) Referrals(1) Prudential regulatorsIf the prudential regulator for a swap dealer or major swap participant has cause to believe that the swap dealer or major swap participant, or any affiliate or division of the swap dealer or major swap participant, may have engaged in conduct that constitutes a violation of the nonprudential requirements of this chapter (including section 6s of this title or rules adopted by the Commission under that section), the prudential regulator may promptly notify the Commission in a written report that includes—(A) a request that the Commission initiate an enforcement proceeding under this chapter; and

(B) an explanation of the facts and circumstances that led to the preparation of the written report.


(2) CommissionIf the Commission has cause to believe that a swap dealer or major swap participant that has a prudential regulator may have engaged in conduct that constitutes a violation of any prudential requirement of section 6s of this title or rules adopted by the Commission under that section, the Commission may notify the prudential regulator of the conduct in a written report that includes—(A) a request that the prudential regulator initiate an enforcement proceeding under this chapter or any other Federal law (including regulations); and

(B) an explanation of the concerns of the Commission, and a description of the facts and circumstances, that led to the preparation of the written report.



(d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity Futures Trading Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Commodity Futures Trading Commission Except as provided in subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Commission shall have exclusive authority to enforce the provisions of subtitle A of the Wall Street Transparency and Accountability Act of 2010 with respect to any person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prudential regulators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prudential regulators The prudential regulators shall have exclusive authority to enforce the provisions of section 6s(e) of this title with respect to swap dealers or major swap participants for which they are the prudential regulator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6b_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referrals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Referrals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6b_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Backstop enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Backstop enforcement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>