<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/6r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6r"><akn:num>6r</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and recordkeeping for uncleared swaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6r. Reporting and recordkeeping for uncleared swaps(a) Required reporting of swaps not accepted by any derivatives clearing organization(1) In generalEach swap that is not accepted for clearing by any derivatives clearing organization shall be reported to—(A) a swap data repository described in section 24a of this title; or

(B) in the case in which there is no swap data repository that would accept the swap, to the Commission pursuant to this section within such time period as the Commission may by rule or regulation prescribe.


(2) Transition rule for preenactment swaps(A) Swaps entered into before July 21, 2010Each swap entered into before July 21, 2010, the terms of which have not expired as of July 21, 2010, shall be reported to a registered swap data repository or the Commission by a date that is not later than—(i) 30 days after issuance of the interim final rule; or

(ii) such other period as the Commission determines to be appropriate.


(B) Commission rulemakingThe Commission shall promulgate an interim final rule within 90 days of July 21, 2010, providing for the reporting of each swap entered into before July 21, 2010.


(C) Effective dateThe reporting provisions described in this section shall be effective upon the enactment of this section.



(3) Reporting obligations(A) Swaps in which only 1 counterparty is a swap dealer or major swap participantWith respect to a swap in which only 1 counterparty is a swap dealer or major swap participant, the swap dealer or major swap participant shall report the swap as required under paragraphs (1) and (2).


(B) Swaps in which 1 counterparty is a swap dealer and the other a major swap participantWith respect to a swap in which 1 counterparty is a swap dealer and the other a major swap participant, the swap dealer shall report the swap as required under paragraphs (1) and (2).


(C) Other swapsWith respect to any other swap not described in subparagraph (A) or (B), the counterparties to the swap shall select a c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required reporting of swaps not accepted by any derivatives clearing organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required reporting of swaps not accepted by any derivatives clearing organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of certain individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of certain individuals Any individual or entity that enters into a swap shall meet each requirement described in subsection (c) if the individual or entity did not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements An individual or entity described in subsection (b) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identical data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identical data In prescribing rules under this section, the Commission shall require individuals and entities described in subsection (b) to submit to the Commission a report that contains data that is not less comprehensive than the data required to be collected by swap data repositories under section 24a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>