<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7102"><akn:num>7102</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7102. Definitions
As used in this chapter (unless the context clearly requires otherwise):(1) BoardThe term “Board” means the National Sheep Promotion, Research, and Information Board established under section 7104(b) of this title.


(2) Carbonized woolThe term “carbonized wool” means wool that has been immersed in a bath, usually of mineral acids or acid salts, that destroys vegetable matter in the wool, but does not affect the wool fibres.11 So in original. Probably should be “fibers.”


(3) Consumer informationThe term “consumer information” means nutritional data and other information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, or use of sheep products.


(4) Customs ServiceThe term “Customs Service” means United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury.


(5) Degreased woolThe term “degreased wool” means wool from which the bulk of impurities has been removed by processing.


(6) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the United States Department of Agriculture.


(7) EducationThe term “education” means activities providing information relating to the sheep industry or sheep products to producers, feeders, importers, consumers, and other persons.


(8) Executive CommitteeThe term “Executive Committee” means the Executive Committee established under section 7104(g) of this title.


(9) ExporterThe term “exporter” means any person who exports domestic live sheep or greasy wool from the United States.


(10) FeederThe term “feeder” means a person who feeds lambs until the lambs reach slaughter weight.


(11) Greasy woolThe term “greasy wool” means wool that has not been washed or otherwise cleaned.


(12) HandlerThe term “handler” means any person who purchases and markets greasy wool.


(13) ImporterThe term “importer” means any person who imports sheep or sheep products into the United States.


(14) Industry informationThe term “industry information” means information an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Board The term “Board” means the National Sheep Promotion, Research, and Information Board established under section 7104(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbonized wool</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Carbonized wool The term “carbonized wool” means wool that has been immersed in a bath, usually of mineral acids or acid salts, that destroys vegetable matter in the wool, but does not affect the wool fibres.11 So in original. Probably should be “fibers.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Consumer information The term “consumer information” means nutritional data and other information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, or use of sheep products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Customs Service The term “Customs Service” means United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Degreased wool</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Degreased wool The term “degreased wool” means wool from which the bulk of impurities has been removed by processing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Department The term “Department” means the United States Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Education The term “education” means activities providing information relating to the sheep industry or sheep products to producers, feeders, importers, consumers, and other persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Executive Committee The term “Executive Committee” means the Executive Committee established under section 7104(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exporter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Exporter The term “exporter” means any person who exports domestic live sheep or greasy wool from the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7102_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Feeder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Feeder The term “feeder” means a person who feeds lambs until the lambs reach slaughter weight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>