<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7202"><akn:num>7202</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7202. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Agricultural Act of 1949Except in section 7301 of this title, the term “Agricultural Act of 1949” means the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.), as in effect prior to the suspensions under section 7301(b)(1) of this title.


(2) Considered plantedThe term “considered planted” means acreage that is considered planted under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1461 et seq.) and such other acreage as the Secretary considers fair and equitable.


(3) ContractThe terms “contract” and “production flexibility contract” mean a production flexibility contract entered into under section 7211 of this title.


(4) Contract acreageThe term “contract acreage” means 1 or more crop acreage bases established for contract commodities under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1461 et seq.) that would have been in effect for the 1996 crop (but for suspension under section 7301(b)(1) of this title).


(5) Contract commodityThe term “contract commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, and rice.


(6) Contract paymentThe term “contract payment” means a payment made under this subchapter 11 So in original. Probably should be “chapter”. pursuant to a contract.


(7) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.


(8) Extra long staple cottonThe term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—(A) is produced from pure strain varieties of the Barbadense species or any hybrid thereof, or other similar types of extra long staple cotton, designated by the Secretary, having characteristics needed for various end uses for which United States upland cotton is not suitable and grown in irrigated cotton-growing regions of the United States designated by the Secretary or other areas designated by the Secretary as suitable for the production of the varieties or types; and

(B) is ginned on a roller-type gin or, if authorized by the Secretary, ginned on another type gin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural Act of 1949</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural Act of 1949 Except in section 7301 of this title, the term “Agricultural Act of 1949” means the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1421 et seq.), as in effect prior to the suspensions under section 7301(b)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considered planted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Considered planted The term “considered planted” means acreage that is considered planted under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1461 et seq.) and such other acreage as the Secretary considers fair and equitable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Contract The terms “contract” and “production flexibility contract” mean a production flexibility contract entered into under section 7211 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Contract acreage The term “contract acreage” means 1 or more crop acreage bases established for contract commodities under title V of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1461 et seq.) that would have been in effect for the 1996 crop (but for suspension under section 7301(b)(1) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Contract commodity The term “contract commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, and rice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Contract payment The term “contract payment” means a payment made under this subchapter 11 So in original. Probably should be “chapter”. pursuant to a contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extra long staple cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Extra long staple cotton The term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm program payment yield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Farm program payment yield The term “farm program payment yield” means the farm program payment yield established for the 1995 crop of a contract commodity under section 505 of the Agricultural Act of 1949 (7 U.S.C. 1465). The Secretary shall adjust the farm program payment yield for the 1995 crop of a contract commodity to account for any additional yield payments made with respect to that crop under subsection (b)(2) of the section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7202_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Loan commodity The term “loan commodity” means each contract commodity, extra long staple cotton, and oilseed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>