<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7212"><akn:num>7212</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7212. Elements of contracts(a) Time for contracting(1) CommencementTo the extent practicable, the Secretary shall commence entering into contracts not later than 45 days after April 4, 1996.


(2) DeadlineExcept as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary may not enter into a contract after August 1, 1996.


(3) Conservation reserve lands(A) In generalAt the beginning of each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allow an eligible owner or producer on a farm covered by a conservation reserve contract entered into under section 3831 of title 16 that terminates after the date specified in paragraph (2) to enter into or expand a production flexibility contract to cover the contract acreage of the farm that was subject to the former conservation reserve contract.


(B) AmountContract payments made for contract acreage under this paragraph shall be made at the rate and amount applicable to the annual contract payment level for the applicable crop. For the fiscal year in which the conservation reserve contract is terminated, the owner or producer subject to the production flexibility contract may elect to receive either contract payments or a prorated payment under the conservation reserve contract, but not both.




(b) Duration of contract(1) Beginning dateThe term of a contract shall begin with—(A) the 1996 crop of a contract commodity; or

(B) in the case of acreage that was subject to a conservation reserve contract described in subsection (a)(3), the date the production flexibility contract was entered into or expanded to cover the acreage.


(2) Ending dateThe term of a contract shall extend through the 2002 crop, unless earlier terminated by the owner or producer.



(c) Estimation of contract paymentsAt the time the Secretary enters into a contract, the Secretary shall provide an estimate of the minimum contract payments anticipated to be made during at least the first fiscal year for which contract payments will be made.


(d) Time for payment(1) In generalAn annua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Time for contracting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duration of contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimation of contract payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Estimation of contract payments At the time the Secretary enters into a contract, the Secretary shall provide an estimate of the minimum contract payments anticipated to be made during at least the first fiscal year for which contract payments will be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>