<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7233" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7233/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7233/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7233"><akn:num>7233</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7233. Term of loans(a) Term of loanIn the case of each loan commodity (other than upland cotton or extra long staple cotton), a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title shall have a term of 9 months beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.


(b) Special rule for cottonA marketing assistance loan for upland cotton or extra long staple cotton shall have a term of 10 months beginning on the first day of the month in which the loan is made.


(c) Extensions prohibitedThe Secretary may not extend the term of a marketing assistance loan for any loan commodity.


(Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 133, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 907.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7233_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Term of loan In the case of each loan commodity (other than upland cotton or extra long staple cotton), a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title shall have a term of 9 months beginning on the first day of the first month after the month in which the loan is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7233_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rule for cotton A marketing assistance loan for upland cotton or extra long staple cotton shall have a term of 10 months beginning on the first day of the month in which the loan is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7233_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensions prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extensions prohibited The Secretary may not extend the term of a marketing assistance loan for any loan commodity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>