<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7234" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7234/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7234/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7234"><akn:num>7234</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7234. Repayment of loans(a) Repayment rates for wheat, feed grains, and oilseedsThe Secretary shall permit a producer to repay a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title for wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, and oilseeds at a rate that is the lesser of—(1) the loan rate established for the commodity under section 7232 of this title, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary); or

(2) a rate that the Secretary determines will—(A) minimize potential loan forfeitures;

(B) minimize the accumulation of stocks of the commodity by the Federal Government;

(C) minimize the cost incurred by the Federal Government in storing the commodity; and

(D) allow the commodity produced in the United States to be marketed freely and competitively, both domestically and internationally.



(b) Repayment rates for upland cotton and riceThe Secretary shall permit producers to repay a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title for upland cotton and rice at a rate that is the lesser of—(1) the loan rate established for the commodity under section 7232 of this title, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary); or

(2) the prevailing world market price for the commodity (adjusted to United States quality and location), as determined by the Secretary.


(c) Repayment rates for extra long staple cottonRepayment of a marketing assistance loan for extra long staple cotton shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity under section 7232 of this title, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary).


(d) Prevailing world market priceFor purposes of this section and section 7236 of this title, the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation—(1) a formula to determine the prevailing world market price for each loan commodity, adjusted to United States quality and location; and

(2) a mechanism by which the Secretary shall announce periodically the prevailing world market price for each loan commodity.


(e) Adjustment of prevailing world mar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7234_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment rates for wheat, feed grains, and oilseeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repayment rates for wheat, feed grains, and oilseeds The Secretary shall permit a producer to repay a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title for wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, and oilseeds at a rate that is the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7234_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment rates for upland cotton and rice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repayment rates for upland cotton and rice The Secretary shall permit producers to repay a marketing assistance loan under section 7231 of this title for upland cotton and rice at a rate that is the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7234_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment rates for extra long staple cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repayment rates for extra long staple cotton Repayment of a marketing assistance loan for extra long staple cotton shall be at the loan rate established for the commodity under section 7232 of this title, plus interest (as determined by the Secretary).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7234_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevailing world market price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prevailing world market price For purposes of this section and section 7236 of this title, the Secretary shall prescribe by regulation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7234_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of prevailing world market price for upland cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Adjustment of prevailing world market price for upland cotton</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>