<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7236" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7236/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7236/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7236"><akn:num>7236</akn:num><akn:heading>Special marketing loan provisions for upland cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7236. Special marketing loan provisions for upland cotton(a) Cotton user marketing certificates(1) IssuanceDuring the period ending July 31, 2003, the Secretary shall issue marketing certificates or cash payments, at the option of the recipient, to domestic users and exporters for documented purchases by domestic users and sales for export by exporters made in the week following a consecutive 4-week period in which—(A) the Friday through Thursday average price quotation for the lowest-priced United States growth, as quoted for Middling (M) 13⁄32-inch cotton, delivered C.I.F. Northern Europe exceeds the Northern Europe price by more than 1.25 cents per pound; and

(B) the prevailing world market price for upland cotton (adjusted to United States quality and location) does not exceed 134 percent of the loan rate for upland cotton established under section 7232 of this title.


(2) Value of certificates or paymentsThe value of the marketing certificates or cash payments shall be based on the amount of the difference (reduced by 1.25 cents per pound) in the prices during the 4th week of the consecutive 4-week period multiplied by the quantity of upland cotton included in the documented sales.


(3) Administration of marketing certificates(A) Redemption, marketing, or exchangeThe Secretary shall establish procedures for redeeming marketing certificates for cash or marketing or exchange of the certificates for agricultural commodities owned by the Commodity Credit Corporation or pledged to the Commodity Credit Corporation as collateral for a loan in such manner, and at such price levels, as the Secretary determines will best effectuate the purposes of cotton user marketing certificates, including enhancing the competitiveness and marketability of United States cotton. Any price restrictions that would otherwise apply to the disposition of agricultural commodities by the Commodity Credit Corporation shall not apply to the redemption of certificates under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7236_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cotton user marketing certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cotton user marketing certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7236_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special import quota</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special import quota</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7236_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited global import quota for upland cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limited global import quota for upland cotton</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>