<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7251"><akn:num>7251</akn:num><akn:heading>Milk price support program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7251. Milk price support program(a) Support activitiesThe Secretary of Agriculture shall support the price of milk produced in the 48 contiguous States through the purchase of cheese, butter, and nonfat dry milk produced from the milk.


(b) RateThe price of milk shall be supported at the following rates per hundredweight for milk containing 3.67 percent butterfat:(1) During calendar year 1996, $10.35.

(2) During calendar year 1997, $10.20.

(3) During calendar year 1998, $10.05.

(4) During each of calendar years 1999 through 2001, $9.90.

(5) During the period beginning on January 1, 2002, and ending on May 31, 2002, $9.90.


(c) Purchase pricesThe support purchase prices under this section for each of the products of milk (butter, cheese, and nonfat dry milk) announced by the Secretary shall be the same for all of that product sold by persons offering to sell the product to the Secretary. The purchase prices shall be sufficient to enable plants of average efficiency to pay producers, on average, a price that is not less than the rate of price support for milk in effect under subsection (b).


(d) Special rule for butter and nonfat dry milk purchase prices(1) Allocation of purchase pricesThe Secretary may allocate the rate of price support between the purchase prices for nonfat dry milk and butter in a manner that will result in the lowest level of expenditures by the Commodity Credit Corporation or achieve such other objectives as the Secretary considers appropriate. Not later than 10 days after making or changing an allocation, the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate of the allocation. Section 553 of title 5 shall not apply with respect to the implementation of this section.


(2) Timing of purchase price adjustmentsThe Secretary may make any such adjustments in the purchase prices for nonfat dry milk and butter the Secretary considers to be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Support activities The Secretary of Agriculture shall support the price of milk produced in the 48 contiguous States through the purchase of cheese, butter, and nonfat dry milk produced from the milk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rate The price of milk shall be supported at the following rates per hundredweight for milk containing 3.67 percent butterfat:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purchase prices The support purchase prices under this section for each of the products of milk (butter, cheese, and nonfat dry milk) announced by the Secretary shall be the same for all of that product sold by persons offering to sell the product to the Secretary. The purchase prices shall be sufficient to enable plants of average efficiency to pay producers, on average, a price that is not less than the rate of price support for milk in effect under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for butter and nonfat dry milk purchase prices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rule for butter and nonfat dry milk purchase prices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunds of 1995 and 1996 assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Refunds of 1995 and 1996 assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Commodity Credit Corporation The Secretary shall carry out the program authorized by this section through the Commodity Credit Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7251_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Period of effectiveness This section (other than subsection (g)) shall be effective only during the period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning after April 4, 1996, and ending on May 31, 2002. The program authorized by this section shall terminate on May 31, 2002, and shall be considered to have expired notwithstanding section 907 of title 2.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>