<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7253"><akn:num>7253</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7253. Consolidation and reform of Federal milk marketing orders(a) Amendment of orders(1) Required consolidationThe Secretary shall amend Federal milk marketing orders issued under section 608c of this title to limit the number of Federal milk marketing orders to not less than 10 and not more than 14 orders.


(2) Inclusion of California as separate orderUpon the petition and approval of California dairy producers in the manner provided in section 608c of this title, the Secretary shall designate the State of California as a separate Federal milk marketing order. The order covering California shall have the right to reblend and distribute order receipts to recognize quota value. Subsection (b) does not apply to the authority of the Secretary under this subsection.


(3) Related issues addressed in consolidationAmong the issues the Secretary is authorized to implement as part of the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders are the following:(A) The use of utilization rates and multiple basing points for the pricing of fluid milk.

(B) The use of uniform multiple component pricing when developing 1 or more basic formula prices for manufacturing milk.


(4) Effect of existing lawIn implementing the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under this subsection, the Secretary may not consider, or base any decision on, the table contained in section 608c(5)(A) of this title.



(b) Expedited process(1) Use of informal rulemakingTo implement the consolidation of Federal milk marketing orders and related reforms under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use the notice and comment procedures provided in section 553 of title 5.


(2) Time limitations(A) Proposed amendmentsThe Secretary shall announce the proposed amendments to be made under subsection (a) not later than 2 years after April 4, 1996.


(B) Final amendmentsThe Secretary shall implement the amendments not later than 3 years after April 4, 1996.



(3) Effect of court orderThe ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amendment of orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expedited process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to timely consolidate orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to timely consolidate orders If the Secretary fails to implement the consolidation required under subsection (a)(1) within the time period required under subsection (b)(2)(B) (plus any additional period provided under subsection (b)(3)), the Secretary may not assess or collect assessments from milk producers or handlers under such section 608c of this title for marketing order administration and services provided under such section after the end of that period until the consolidation is completed. The Secretary may not reduce the level of services provided under the section on account of the prohibition against assessments, but shall rather cover the cost of marketing order administration and services through funds available for the Agricultural Marketing Service of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report regarding further reforms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report regarding further reforms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>