<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7259" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7259/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7259/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7259"><akn:num>7259</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report regarding potential impact of Uruguay Round on prices, income, and government purch</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7259. Study and report regarding potential impact of Uruguay Round on prices, income, and government purchases(a) StudyThe Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study, on a variety by variety of cheese basis, to determine the potential impact on milk prices in the United States, dairy producer income, and Federal dairy program costs, of the allocation of additional cheese granted access to the United States as a result of the obligations of the United States as a member of the World Trade Organization.


(b) ReportNot later than June 30, 1997, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives the results of the study conducted under this section.


(c) Rule of constructionAny limitation imposed by Act of Congress on the conduct or completion of studies or reports to Congress shall not apply to the study and report required under this section, unless the limitation specifically refers to this section.


(Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 151, Apr. 4, 1996, 110 Stat. 922.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7259_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Study The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a study, on a variety by variety of cheese basis, to determine the potential impact on milk prices in the United States, dairy producer income, and Federal dairy program costs, of the allocation of additional cheese granted access to the United States as a result of the obligations of the United States as a member of the World Trade Organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7259_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Not later than June 30, 1997, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate and the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives the results of the study conducted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7259_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction Any limitation imposed by Act of Congress on the conduct or completion of studies or reports to Congress shall not apply to the study and report required under this section, unless the limitation specifically refers to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>