<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7287" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7287/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7287/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7287"><akn:num>7287</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity Credit Corporation storage payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7287. Commodity Credit Corporation storage payments(a) In generalFor the 2025 crop year and each subsequent crop year, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in an amount that is not less than—(1) in the case of refined sugar, 34 cents per hundredweight per month; and

(2) in the case of raw cane sugar, 27 cents per hundredweight per month.


(b) Prior crop yearsFor each of the 2012 through 2024 crop years, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in the same manner as was used on the day before the date of enactment of this section.


(Pub. L. 104–127, title I, § 167, as added Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1405, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 990, and Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title I, § 1405, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1718; Pub. L. 119–21, title I, § 10312(b), July 4, 2025, 139 Stat. 96.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date of enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (b), is the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–246, which was approved June 18, 2008.

Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 enacted identical sections. Pub. L. 110–234 was repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.
Section 1405 of Pub. L. 110–246, which directed that this section be added at the end of subtitle E of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, was executed by adding this section at the end of subtitle E of title I of that Act, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments
2025—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 119–21, § 10312(b)(1), added subsec. (a) and struck out former subsec. (a) which related to rates for the storage of forfeited sugar for 2008 to 2011 crop years.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 119–21, § 10312(b)(2), substituted “Prior” for “Subsequent” in heading and “through 2024” for “and subsequent” in text.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateEnactment of this section and repeal of Pub. L. 110–234 by Pub. L. 110–246 effective Ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7287_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the 2025 crop year and each subsequent crop year, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in an amount that is not less than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7287_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior crop years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prior crop years For each of the 2012 through 2024 crop years, the Commodity Credit Corporation shall establish rates for the storage of forfeited sugar in the same manner as was used on the day before the date of enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>