<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7401"><akn:num>7401</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity promotion and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7401. Commodity promotion and evaluation(a) “Commodity promotion law” definedIn this section, the term “commodity promotion law” means a Federal law that provides for the establishment and operation of a promotion program regarding an agricultural commodity that includes a combination of promotion, research, industry information, or consumer information activities, is funded by mandatory assessments on producers or processors, and is designed to maintain or expand markets and uses for the commodity (as determined by the Secretary). The term includes—(1) the marketing promotion provisions under section 608c(6)(I) of this title;

(2) Public Law 89–502 (7 U.S.C. 2101 et seq.);

(3) title III of Public Law 91–670 (7 U.S.C. 2611 et seq.);

(4) Public Law 93–428 (7 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.);

(5) Public Law 94–294 (7 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.);

(6) subtitle B of title I of Public Law 98–180 (7 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.);

(7) Public Law 98–590 (7 U.S.C. 4601 et seq.);

(8) subtitle B of title XVI of Public Law 99–198 (7 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.);

(9) subtitle C of title XVI of Public Law 99–198 (7 U.S.C. 4901 et seq.);

(10) subtitle B of title XIX of Public Law 101–624 (7 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.);

(11) subtitle E of title XIX of Public Law 101–624 (7 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.);

(12) subtitle H of title XIX of Public Law 101–624 (7 U.S.C. 6401 et seq.);

(13) Public Law 103–190 (7 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.);

(14) Public Law 103–407 (7 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.);

(15) subchapter II;

(16) subchapter III;

(17) subchapter IV;

(18) subchapter V; or

(19) any other provision of law enacted after April 4, 1996, that provides for the establishment and operation of a promotion program described in the first sentence.


(b) FindingsCongress finds the following:(1) It is in the national public interest and vital to the welfare of the agricultural economy of the United States to maintain and expand existing markets and develop new markets and uses for agricultural commodities through industry-funded, Government-supe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Commodity promotion law” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Commodity promotion law” defined In this section, the term “commodity promotion law” means a Federal law that provides for the establishment and operation of a promotion program regarding an agricultural commodity that includes a combination of promotion, research, industry information, or consumer information activities, is funded by mandatory assessments on producers or processors, and is designed to maintain or expand markets and uses for the commodity (as determined by the Secretary). The term includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent evaluation of promotion program effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Independent evaluation of promotion program effectiveness Except as otherwise provided by law, each commodity board established under the supervision and oversight of the Secretary of Agriculture pursuant to a commodity promotion law shall, not less often than every 5 years, authorize and fund, from funds otherwise available to the board, an independent evaluation of the effectiveness of the generic commodity promotion programs and other programs conducted by the board pursuant to a commodity promotion law. The board shall submit to the Secretary, and make available to the public, the results of each periodic independent evaluation conducted under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative costs The Secretary shall annually provide to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate information on administrative expenses on programs established under commodity promotion laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of certified organic products from promotion order assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption of certified organic products from promotion order assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organic commodity promotion order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Organic commodity promotion order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>