<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7412"><akn:num>7412</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7412. Definitions
In this subchapter (unless the context otherwise requires):(1) Agricultural commodityThe term “agricultural commodity” means—(A) agricultural, horticultural, viticultural, and dairy products;

(B) livestock and the products of livestock;

(C) the products of poultry and bee raising;

(D) the products of forestry;

(E) products, as a class, that are—(i) produced on a certified organic farm (as defined in section 6502 of this title); and

(ii) certified to be sold or labeled as “organic” or “100 percent organic” (as defined in part 205 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation));


(F) other commodities raised or produced on farms, as determined appropriate by the Secretary; and

(G) products processed or manufactured from products specified in the preceding subparagraphs, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(2) BoardThe term “board” means a board established under an order issued under section 7413 of this title.


(3) Conflict of interestThe term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member or employee of a board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, a board for anything of economic value.


(4) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.


(5) First handlerThe term “first handler” means the first person who buys or takes possession of an agricultural commodity from a producer for marketing. If a producer markets the agricultural commodity directly to consumers, the producer shall be considered to be the first handler with respect to the agricultural commodity produced by the producer.


(6) ImporterThe term “importer” means any person who imports an agricultural commodity from outside the United States for sale in the United States as a principal or as an agent, broker, or consignee of any person.


(7) InformationThe term “information” means information and programs that are designed to increas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agricultural commodity The term “agricultural commodity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Board The term “board” means a board established under an order issued under section 7413 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Conflict of interest The term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member or employee of a board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, a board for anything of economic value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>First handler</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) First handler The term “first handler” means the first person who buys or takes possession of an agricultural commodity from a producer for marketing. If a producer markets the agricultural commodity directly to consumers, the producer shall be considered to be the first handler with respect to the agricultural commodity produced by the producer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Importer The term “importer” means any person who imports an agricultural commodity from outside the United States for sale in the United States as a principal or as an agent, broker, or consignee of any person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Information The term “information” means information and programs that are designed to increase—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Market</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Market The term “market” means to sell or to otherwise dispose of an agricultural commodity in interstate, foreign, or intrastate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Order The term “order” means an order issued by the Secretary under section 7413 of this title that provides for a program of generic promotion, research, and information regarding agricultural commodities designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7412_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Person The term “person” means any individual, group of individuals, partnership, corporation, association, cooperative, or any other legal entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>