<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7414"><akn:num>7414</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7414. Required terms in orders(a) In generalEach order shall contain the terms and conditions specified in this section.


(b) Board(1) EstablishmentEach order shall establish a board to carry out a program of generic promotion, research, and information regarding the agricultural commodity covered by the order and intended to effectuate the purpose of this subchapter.


(2) Board membership(A) Number of membersEach board shall consist of the number of members considered by the Secretary, in consultation with the agricultural commodity industry involved, to be appropriate to administer the order. In addition to members, the Secretary may also provide for alternates on the board.


(B) AppointmentThe Secretary shall appoint the members and any alternates of a board from among producers of the agricultural commodity and first handlers and others in the marketing chain as appropriate. If imports of the agricultural commodity covered by an order are subject to assessment under section 7415(f) of this title, the Secretary shall also appoint importers as members of the board and as alternates if alternates are included on the board. The Secretary may appoint 1 or more members of the general public to each board.


(C) NominationsThe Secretary may make appointments from nominations made pursuant to the method set forth in the order.


(D) Geographical representationTo ensure fair and equitable representation of the agricultural commodity industry covered by an order, the composition of each board shall reflect the geographical distribution of the production of the agricultural commodity involved in the United States and the quantity or value of the agricultural commodity imported into the United States.



(3) Reapportionment of board membershipIn accordance with rules issued by the Secretary, at least once in each 5-year period, but not more frequently than once in each 3-year period, each board shall—(A) review the geographical distribution in the United States of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each order shall contain the terms and conditions specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties of board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers and duties of board Each order shall specify the powers and duties of the board established under the order, which shall include the power and duty—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibited activities A board may not engage in, and shall prohibit the employees and agents of the board from engaging in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities and budgets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Activities and budgets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Contracts and agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records of board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Records of board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Periodic evaluation In accordance with section 7401(c) of this title, each order shall require the board established under the order to provide for the independent evaluation of all generic promotion, research, and information activities undertaken under the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7414_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records of persons covered by order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Books and records of persons covered by order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>