<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7415"><akn:num>7415</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissive terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7415. Permissive terms in orders(a) ExemptionsAn order issued under this subchapter may contain—(1) authority for the Secretary to exempt from the order any de minimis quantity of an agricultural commodity otherwise covered by the order; and

(2) authority for the board established under the order to require satisfactory safeguards against improper use of the exemption.


(b) Different payment and reporting schedulesAn order issued under this subchapter may contain authority for the board established under the order to designate different payment and reporting schedules to recognize differences in agricultural commodity industry marketing practices and procedures used in different production and importing areas.


(c) ActivitiesAn order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to develop and carry out research, promotion, and information activities designed to expand, improve, or make more efficient the marketing or use of the agricultural commodity covered by the order in domestic and foreign markets. Section 7414(e) of this title shall apply with respect to activities authorized under this subsection.


(d) Reserve fundsAn order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to reserve funds from assessments collected under section 7416 of this title to permit an effective and continuous coordinated program of research, promotion, and information in years when the yield from assessments may be reduced, except that the amount of funds reserved may not exceed the greatest aggregate amount of the anticipated disbursements specified in budgets approved under section 7414(e) of this title by the Secretary for any 2 fiscal years.


(e) Credits(1) Generic activitiesAn order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to provide credits of assessments for those individuals who contribute to other similar generic research, promotion, and information programs at the State, regional, or local level.


(2) Branded activities(A) In generalThe Secretary m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exemptions An order issued under this subchapter may contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Different payment and reporting schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Different payment and reporting schedules An order issued under this subchapter may contain authority for the board established under the order to designate different payment and reporting schedules to recognize differences in agricultural commodity industry marketing practices and procedures used in different production and importing areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities An order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to develop and carry out research, promotion, and information activities designed to expand, improve, or make more efficient the marketing or use of the agricultural commodity covered by the order in domestic and foreign markets. Section 7414(e) of this title shall apply with respect to activities authorized under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reserve funds An order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to reserve funds from assessments collected under section 7416 of this title to permit an effective and continuous coordinated program of research, promotion, and information in years when the yield from assessments may be reduced, except that the amount of funds reserved may not exceed the greatest aggregate amount of the anticipated disbursements specified in budgets approved under section 7414(e) of this title by the Secretary for any 2 fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of imports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assessment of imports An order issued under this subchapter may contain authority for the board established under the order to assess under section 7416 of this title an imported agricultural commodity, or products of such an agricultural commodity, at a rate comparable to the rate determined by the appropriate board for the domestic agricultural commodity covered by the order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7415_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other authority An order issued under this subchapter may contain authority to take any other action that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>