<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7416a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7416a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7416a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7416a"><akn:num>7416a</akn:num><akn:heading>Confirmation of authority of Secretary of Agriculture to collect State commodity assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7416a. Confirmation of authority of Secretary of Agriculture to collect State commodity assessments(a) Collection from marketing assistance loansThe Secretary of Agriculture shall collect commodity assessments from the proceeds of a marketing assistance loan for a producer if the assessment is required to be paid by the producer or the first purchaser of a commodity pursuant to a State law or pursuant to an authority administered by the Secretary. This collection authority does not extend to a State tax or other revenue collection activity by a State.


(b) Collection pursuant to agreementThe collection of an assessment under subsection (a) shall be made as specified in an agreement between the Secretary of Agriculture and the State requesting the collection.


(c) Prohibition on charging certain feesThe Secretary may not charge any fees or related costs for the collection of commodity assessments pursuant to this section.


(Pub. L. 108–470, § 1, Dec. 21, 2004, 118 Stat. 3894; Pub. L. 110–234, title I, § 1616, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1021; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title I, § 1616, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1749.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.
Section was not enacted as part of the Commodity Promotion, Research, and Information Act of 1996 which comprises this subchapter.

Amendments2008—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 110–246, § 1616(1), substituted “shall” for “may”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 110–246, § 1616(2), added subsec. (c).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2008 AmendmentAmendment of this section and repeal of Pub. L. 110–234 by Pub. L. 110–246 effective May 22, 2008, the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–234, see section 4 of Pub. L. 110–246, set out as an Effective Date note under section 8701 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7416a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection from marketing assistance loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Collection from marketing assistance loans The Secretary of Agriculture shall collect commodity assessments from the proceeds of a marketing assistance loan for a producer if the assessment is required to be paid by the producer or the first purchaser of a commodity pursuant to a State law or pursuant to an authority administered by the Secretary. This collection authority does not extend to a State tax or other revenue collection activity by a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7416a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection pursuant to agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collection pursuant to agreement The collection of an assessment under subsection (a) shall be made as specified in an agreement between the Secretary of Agriculture and the State requesting the collection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7416a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on charging certain fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on charging certain fees The Secretary may not charge any fees or related costs for the collection of commodity assessments pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>