<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7442" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7442/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7442/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7442"><akn:num>7442</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7442. Definitions
In this subchapter (unless the context otherwise requires):(1) BoardThe term “Board” means the National Canola and Rapeseed Board established under section 7444(b) of this title.


(2) Canola; rapeseedThe terms “canola” and “rapeseed” mean any brassica plant grown in the United States for the production of an oilseed, the oil of which is used for a food or nonfood use.


(3) Canola or rapeseed productThe term “canola or rapeseed product” means a product produced, in whole or in part, from canola or rapeseed.


(4) CommerceThe term “commerce” includes interstate, foreign, and intrastate commerce.


(5) Conflict of interestThe term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member of the Board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, joint venture, or other business entity dealing directly or indirectly with the Board.


(6) Consumer informationThe term “consumer information” means information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of canola, rapeseed, or canola or rapeseed products.


(7) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.


(8) First purchaserThe term “first purchaser” means—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), a person who buys or otherwise acquires canola, rapeseed, or canola or rapeseed products produced by a producer; or

(B) the Commodity Credit Corporation, in a case in which canola or rapeseed is forfeited to the Commodity Credit Corporation as collateral for a loan issued under a price support loan program administered by the Commodity Credit Corporation.


(9) Industry informationThe term “industry information” means information or a program that will lead to the development of new markets, new marketing strategies, or increased efficiency for the canola and rapeseed industry, or an activity to enhance the image of the canola or rapeseed industry.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Board The term “Board” means the National Canola and Rapeseed Board established under section 7444(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Canola; rapeseed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Canola; rapeseed The terms “canola” and “rapeseed” mean any brassica plant grown in the United States for the production of an oilseed, the oil of which is used for a food or nonfood use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Canola or rapeseed product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Canola or rapeseed product The term “canola or rapeseed product” means a product produced, in whole or in part, from canola or rapeseed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Commerce The term “commerce” includes interstate, foreign, and intrastate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Conflict of interest The term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member of the Board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, joint venture, or other business entity dealing directly or indirectly with the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Consumer information The term “consumer information” means information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of canola, rapeseed, or canola or rapeseed products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>First purchaser</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) First purchaser The term “first purchaser” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Industry information The term “industry information” means information or a program that will lead to the development of new markets, new marketing strategies, or increased efficiency for the canola and rapeseed industry, or an activity to enhance the image of the canola or rapeseed industry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7442_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Industry member The term “industry member” means a member of the canola and rapeseed industry who represents—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>