<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7464" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7464/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7464/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7464"><akn:num>7464</akn:num><akn:heading>National Kiwifruit Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7464. National Kiwifruit Board(a) MembershipAn order issued by the Secretary under section 7463 of this title shall provide for the establishment of a National Kiwifruit Board that consists of the following 11 members:(1) 10 members who are producers, exporters, or importers (or their representatives), based on a proportional representation of the level of domestic production and imports of kiwifruit (as determined by the Secretary).

(2) 1 member appointed from the general public.


(b) Adjustment of membershipSubject to the 11-member limit, the Secretary may adjust membership on the Board to accommodate changes in production and import levels of kiwifruit.


(c) Appointment and nomination(1) AppointmentThe Secretary shall appoint the members of the Board from nominations submitted in accordance with this subsection.


(2) ProducersThe members who are producers referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall be appointed from individuals nominated by producers.


(3) Importers and exportersThe members who are importers or exporters referred to in subsection (a)(1) shall be appointed from individuals nominated by importers or exporters.


(4) Public representativeThe public representative shall be appointed from nominations submitted by other members of the Board.


(5) Failure to nominateIf producers, importers, and exporters fail to nominate individuals for appointment, the Secretary may appoint members and alternates on a basis provided for in the order. If the Board fails to nominate a public representative, the member and alternate may be appointed by the Secretary without a nomination.



(d) AlternatesThe Secretary shall appoint an alternate for each member of the Board. An alternate shall—(1) be appointed in the same manner as the member for whom the individual is an alternate; and

(2) serve on the Board if the member is absent from a meeting or is disqualified under subsection (f).


(e) TermsA member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. No memb</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Membership An order issued by the Secretary under section 7463 of this title shall provide for the establishment of a National Kiwifruit Board that consists of the following 11 members:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustment of membership Subject to the 11-member limit, the Secretary may adjust membership on the Board to accommodate changes in production and import levels of kiwifruit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and nomination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appointment and nomination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Alternates The Secretary shall appoint an alternate for each member of the Board. An alternate shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Terms A member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 3 years. No member may serve more than 2 consecutive 3-year terms, except that of the members first appointed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disqualification If a member or alternate of the Board who was appointed as a producer, importer, exporter, or public representative member ceases to belong to the group for which the member was appointed, the member or alternate shall be disqualified from serving on the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation A member or alternate of the Board shall serve without pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7464_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) General powers and duties The Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>