<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7465" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7465/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7465/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7465"><akn:num>7465</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7465. Required terms in order(a) Budgets and plans(1) In generalAn order issued under section 7463 of this title shall provide for periodic budgets and plans in accordance with this subsection.


(2) BudgetsThe Board shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a budget prior to the beginning of the fiscal year of the anticipated expenses and disbursements of the Board in the administration of the order, including probable costs of research, promotion, and consumer information. A budget shall become effective on a ⅔-vote of a quorum of the Board and approval by the Secretary.


(3) PlansEach budget shall include a plan for research, promotion, and consumer information regarding kiwifruit. A plan under this paragraph shall become effective on approval by the Secretary. The Board may enter into contracts and agreements, on approval by the Secretary, for—(A) the development and carrying out of the plan; and

(B) the payment of the cost of the plan, with funds collected pursuant to this subchapter.



(b) Assessments(1) In generalThe order shall provide for the imposition and collection of assessments with regard to the production and importation of kiwifruit in accordance with this subsection.


(2) RateThe assessment rate shall be the rate that is recommended by a ⅔-vote of a quorum of the Board and approved by the Secretary, except that the rate shall not exceed $0.10 per 7-pound tray of kiwifruit or an equivalent rate.


(3) Collection by first handlersExcept as provided in paragraph (5), the first handler of kiwifruit shall—(A) be responsible for the collection from the producer, and payment to the Board, of assessments required under this subsection; and

(B) maintain a separate record of the kiwifruit of each producer whose kiwifruit are so handled, including the kiwifruit owned by the handler.


(4) ImportersThe assessment on imported kiwifruit shall be paid by the importer to the United States Customs Service at the time of entry into the United States and shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgets and plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Budgets and plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>False claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) False claims The order shall provide that any promotion funded with assessments collected under subsection (b) may not make—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on use of funds The order shall provide that funds collected by the Board under this subchapter through assessments may not, in any manner, be used for the purpose of influencing legislation or governmental policy or action, except for making recommendations to the Secretary as provided for under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books, records, and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Books, records, and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Confidentiality</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7465_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Withholding of information Nothing in this subchapter authorizes the withholding of information from Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>