<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7515"><akn:num>7515</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment and delivery of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7515. Allotment and delivery of commodities(a) Mandatory allotmentsIn each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot—(1) 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 60 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the number of persons in households within the State having incomes below the poverty line bears to the total number of persons in households within all States having incomes below such poverty line, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities; and

(2) 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities provided to States in a manner such that the value of additional commodities allocated to each State bears the same ratio to 40 percent of the total value of additional commodities as the average monthly number of unemployed persons within the State bears to the average monthly number of unemployed persons within all States during the same fiscal year, and each State shall be entitled to receive such value of additional commodities.


(b) ReallocationThe Secretary shall notify each State of the amount of the additional commodities that such State is allotted to receive under subsection (a), and each State shall promptly notify the Secretary if such State determines that it will not accept any or all of the commodities made available under such allocation. On such a notification by a State, the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute the amount the State was allocated to receive under the formula prescribed in subsection (a) but declined to accept. The Secretary shall further establish procedures to permit States to decline to receive portions of such allocation during each fiscal year as the State determines is appropriate and the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute such allocation. In the event of any drought, flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster affecting </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mandatory allotments In each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reallocation The Secretary shall notify each State of the amount of the additional commodities that such State is allotted to receive under subsection (a), and each State shall promptly notify the Secretary if such State determines that it will not accept any or all of the commodities made available under such allocation. On such a notification by a State, the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute the amount the State was allocated to receive under the formula prescribed in subsection (a) but declined to accept. The Secretary shall further establish procedures to permit States to decline to receive portions of such allocation during each fiscal year as the State determines is appropriate and the Secretary shall reallocate and distribute such allocation. In the event of any drought, flood, hurricane, or other natural disaster affecting substantial numbers of persons in a State, county or parish, the Secretary may request that States unaffected by such a disaster consider assisti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maintenance of effort If a State uses its own funds to provide commodities or services to organizations receiving funds or services under this section, such State shall not diminish the level of support it provides to such organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>