<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7614" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7614/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7614/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7614"><akn:num>7614</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7614. Definitions
Except as otherwise provided in this section and sections 7614a to 7614c of this title,11 See References in Text note below. in this section and sections 7614a to 7614c of this title: 1(1) Capacity and infrastructure programThe term “capacity and infrastructure program” has the meaning given the term in subsection (f)(1) of section 6971 of this title (as added by section 7511(a)(4)).1


(2) Capacity and infrastructure program critical base fundingThe term “capacity and infrastructure program critical base funding” means the aggregate amount of Federal funds made available for capacity and infrastructure programs for fiscal year 2006, as appropriate.


(3) Competitive programThe term “competitive program” has the meaning given the term in subsection (f)(1) of section 6971 of this title (as added by section 7511(a)(4)).1


(4) Competitive program critical base fundingThe term “competitive program critical base funding” means the aggregate amount of Federal funds made available for competitive programs for fiscal year 2006, as appropriate.


(5) Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universitiesThe term “Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities” has the meaning given the term in section 3103 of this title.


(6) NLGCA InstitutionThe term “NLGCA Institution” has the meaning given the term in section 3103 of this title.


(7) 1862 Institution; 1890 Institution; 1994 InstitutionThe terms “1862 Institution”, “1890 Institution”, and “1994 Institution” have the meanings given the terms in section 7601 of this title.


(Pub. L. 110–234, title VII, § 7501, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1256; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VII, § 7501, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2018.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis section and sections 7614a to 7614c of this title, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, and was translated as meaning “this part”, meaning part I (§§ 7501 to 7506) of subtitle E of title VII of Pub. L. 110–246, Jun</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capacity and infrastructure program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Capacity and infrastructure program The term “capacity and infrastructure program” has the meaning given the term in subsection (f)(1) of section 6971 of this title (as added by section 7511(a)(4)).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capacity and infrastructure program critical base funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Capacity and infrastructure program critical base funding The term “capacity and infrastructure program critical base funding” means the aggregate amount of Federal funds made available for capacity and infrastructure programs for fiscal year 2006, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Competitive program The term “competitive program” has the meaning given the term in subsection (f)(1) of section 6971 of this title (as added by section 7511(a)(4)).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive program critical base funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Competitive program critical base funding The term “competitive program critical base funding” means the aggregate amount of Federal funds made available for competitive programs for fiscal year 2006, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities The term “Hispanic-serving agricultural colleges and universities” has the meaning given the term in section 3103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>NLGCA Institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) NLGCA Institution The term “NLGCA Institution” has the meaning given the term in section 3103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7614_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>1862 Institution; 1890 Institution; 1994 Institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) 1862 Institution; 1890 Institution; 1994 Institution The terms “1862 Institution”, “1890 Institution”, and “1994 Institution” have the meanings given the terms in section 7601 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>