<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7657" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7657/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7657/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7657"><akn:num>7657</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Scientific Research Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7657. Senior Scientific Research Service(a) In generalThere is established in the Department of Agriculture the Senior Scientific Research Service (referred to in this section as the “Service”).


(b) Members(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) through (4), the Secretary shall appoint the members of the Service.


(2) QualificationsTo be eligible for appointment to the Service, an individual shall—(A) have conducted outstanding research in the field of agriculture or forestry;

(B) have earned a doctoral level degree at an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20); and

(C) meet qualification standards prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management for appointment to a position at level GS–15 of the General Schedule.


(3) NumberNot more than 100 individuals may serve as members of the Service at any 1 time.


(4) Other requirements(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B) and subsection (d)(2), the Secretary may appoint and employ a member of the Service without regard to—(i) the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service;

(ii) the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 35 of title 5 relating to retention preference;

(iii) the provisions of chapter 43 of title 5 relating to performance appraisal and performance actions;

(iv) the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates; and

(v) the provisions of chapter 75 of title 5 relating to adverse actions.


(B) ExceptionA member of the Service appointed and employed by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall have the same right of appeal to the Merit Systems Protection Board and the same right to file a complaint with the Office of Special Counsel as an employee appointed to a position at level GS–15 of the General Schedule.




(c) Performance appraisal systemThe Secretary shall develop a performance appraisal system for members of the Service that is </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established in the Department of Agriculture the Senior Scientific Research Service (referred to in this section as the “Service”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance appraisal system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Performance appraisal system The Secretary shall develop a performance appraisal system for members of the Service that is designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Retirement contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7657_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Involuntary separation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Involuntary separation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>