<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7711"><akn:num>7711</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of movement of plant pests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7711. Regulation of movement of plant pests(a) Prohibition of unauthorized movement of plant pestsExcept as provided in subsection (c), no person shall import, enter, export, or move in interstate commerce any plant pest, unless the importation, entry, exportation, or movement is authorized under general or specific permit and is in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may issue to prevent the introduction of plant pests into the United States or the dissemination of plant pests within the United States.


(b) Requirements for processesThe Secretary shall ensure that the processes used in developing regulations under subsection (a) governing consideration of import requests are based on sound science and are transparent and accessible.


(c) Authorization of movement of plant pests by regulation(1) Exception to permit requirementThe Secretary may issue regulations to allow the importation, entry, exportation, or movement in interstate commerce of specified plant pests without further restriction if the Secretary finds that a permit under subsection (a) is not necessary.


(2) Petition to add or remove plant pests from regulationAny person may petition the Secretary to add a plant pest to, or remove a plant pest from, the regulations issued by the Secretary under paragraph (1).


(3) Response to petition by the SecretaryIn the case of a petition submitted under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall act on the petition within a reasonable time and notify the petitioner of the final action the Secretary takes on the petition. The Secretary’s determination on the petition shall be based on sound science.



(d) Prohibition of unauthorized mailing of plant pests(1) In generalAny letter, parcel, box, or other package containing any plant pest, whether sealed as letter-rate postal matter or not, is nonmailable and shall not knowingly be conveyed in the mail or delivered from any post office or by any mail carrier, unless the letter, parcel, box, or other packag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of unauthorized movement of plant pests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition of unauthorized movement of plant pests Except as provided in subsection (c), no person shall import, enter, export, or move in interstate commerce any plant pest, unless the importation, entry, exportation, or movement is authorized under general or specific permit and is in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may issue to prevent the introduction of plant pests into the United States or the dissemination of plant pests within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for processes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for processes The Secretary shall ensure that the processes used in developing regulations under subsection (a) governing consideration of import requests are based on sound science and are transparent and accessible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of movement of plant pests by regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of movement of plant pests by regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of unauthorized mailing of plant pests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of unauthorized mailing of plant pests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations Regulations issued by the Secretary to implement subsections (a), (c), and (d) may include provisions requiring that any plant pest imported, entered, to be exported, moved in interstate commerce, mailed, or delivered from any post office—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>