<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7731"><akn:num>7731</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections, seizures, and warrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7731. Inspections, seizures, and warrants(a) Role of Attorney GeneralThe activities authorized by this section shall be carried out consistent with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.


(b) Warrantless inspectionsThe Secretary may stop and inspect, without a warrant, any person or means of conveyance moving—(1) into the United States to determine whether the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article subject to this chapter;

(2) in interstate commerce, upon probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article subject to this chapter; and

(3) in intrastate commerce from or within any State, portion of a State, or premises quarantined as part of a extraordinary emergency declared under section 7715 of this title upon probable cause to believe that the person or means of conveyance is carrying any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, or article regulated under that section or is moving subject to that section.


(c) Inspections with a warrant(1) General authorityThe Secretary may enter, with a warrant, any premises in the United States for the purpose of conducting investigations or making inspections and seizures under this chapter.


(2) Application and issuance of a warrantUpon proper oath or affirmation showing probable cause to believe that there is on certain premises any plant, plant product, biological control organism, plant pest, noxious weed, article, facility, or means of conveyance regulated under this chapter, a United States judge, a judge of a court of record in the United States, or a United States magistrate judge may, within the judge’s or magistrate’s 11 So in original. Probably should be “magistrate judges’s”. jurisdiction, issue a warrant for the entry upon the premises to conduct any investi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Role of Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Role of Attorney General The activities authorized by this section shall be carried out consistent with guidelines approved by the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warrantless inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Warrantless inspections The Secretary may stop and inspect, without a warrant, any person or means of conveyance moving—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections with a warrant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inspections with a warrant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>