<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7753" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7753/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7753/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7753"><akn:num>7753</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursable agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7753. Reimbursable agreements(a) Authority to enter into agreementsThe Secretary may enter into reimbursable fee agreements with persons for preclearance of plants, plant products, biological control organisms, and articles at locations outside the United States for movement into the United States.


(b) Funds collected for preclearanceFunds collected for preclearance shall be credited to accounts which may be established by the Secretary for this purpose and shall remain available until expended for the preclearance activities without fiscal year limitation.


(c) Payment of employees(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other law, the Secretary may pay employees of the Department of Agriculture performing services relating to imports into and exports from the United States, for all overtime, night, or holiday work performed by them, at rates of pay established by the Secretary.


(2) Reimbursement of the Secretary(A) In generalThe Secretary may require persons for whom the services are performed to reimburse the Secretary for any sums of money paid by the Secretary for the services.


(B) Use of fundsAll funds collected under this paragraph shall be credited to the account that incurs the costs and shall remain available until expended without fiscal year limitation.




(d) Late payment penalties(1) CollectionUpon failure to reimburse the Secretary in accordance with this section, the Secretary may assess a late payment penalty, and the overdue funds shall accrue interest, as required by section 3717 of title 31.


(2) Use of fundsAny late payment penalty and any accrued interest shall be credited to the account that incurs the costs and shall remain available until expended without fiscal year limitation.



(Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 433, June 20, 2000, 114 Stat. 452.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions of the Secretary of Agriculture relating to agricultural import and entry inspection activities under t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7753_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to enter into agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to enter into agreements The Secretary may enter into reimbursable fee agreements with persons for preclearance of plants, plant products, biological control organisms, and articles at locations outside the United States for movement into the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7753_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds collected for preclearance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funds collected for preclearance Funds collected for preclearance shall be credited to accounts which may be established by the Secretary for this purpose and shall remain available until expended for the preclearance activities without fiscal year limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7753_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7753_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Late payment penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Late payment penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>