<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7772" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7772/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7772/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7772"><akn:num>7772</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7772. Transfer authority(a) Authority to transfer certain fundsIn connection with an emergency in which a plant pest or noxious weed threatens any segment of the agricultural production of the United States, the Secretary may transfer from other appropriations or funds available to the agencies or corporations of the Department of Agriculture such amounts as the Secretary considers necessary to be available in the emergency for the arrest, control, eradication, and prevention of the spread of the plant pest or noxious weed and for related expenses.


(b) AvailabilityAny funds transferred under this section shall remain available for such purposes without fiscal year limitation.


(c) Secretarial discretionThe action of any officer, employee, or agent of the Secretary in carrying out this Act, including determining the amount of and making any payment authorized to be made under this chapter, shall not be subject to a review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 442, June 20, 2000, 114 Stat. 455; Pub. L. 107–171, title VII, § 7504(b), May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 466; Pub. L. 110–234, title X, § 10203(b), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1342; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title X, § 10203(b), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2104.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is Pub. L. 106–224, June 20, 2000, 114 Stat. 358, known as the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2000 Amendment note set out under section 1501 of this title and Tables.
This chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this title”, meaning title IV of Pub. L. 106–224, June 20, 2000, 114 Stat. 438, known as the Plant Protection Act, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title IV to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 7701 of this t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7772_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer certain funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to transfer certain funds In connection with an emergency in which a plant pest or noxious weed threatens any segment of the agricultural production of the United States, the Secretary may transfer from other appropriations or funds available to the agencies or corporations of the Department of Agriculture such amounts as the Secretary considers necessary to be available in the emergency for the arrest, control, eradication, and prevention of the spread of the plant pest or noxious weed and for related expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7772_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability Any funds transferred under this section shall remain available for such purposes without fiscal year limitation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7772_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial discretion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretarial discretion The action of any officer, employee, or agent of the Secretary in carrying out this Act, including determining the amount of and making any payment authorized to be made under this chapter, shall not be subject to a review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>