<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7781" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7781/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7781/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7781"><akn:num>7781</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7781. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Indian tribeThe term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304 of title 25.


(2) Weed management entityThe term “weed management entity” means an entity that—(A) is recognized by the State in which it is established;

(B) is established for the purpose of or has demonstrable expertise and significant experience in controlling or eradicating noxious weeds and increasing public knowledge and education concerning the need to control or eradicate noxious weeds;

(C) may be multijurisdictional and multidisciplinary in nature;

(D) may include representatives from Federal, State, local, or, where applicable, Indian Tribe governments, private organizations, individuals, and State-recognized conservation districts or State-recognized weed management districts; and

(E) has existing authority to perform land management activities on Federal land if the proposed project or activity is on Federal lands.


(3) Federal landsThe term “Federal lands” means those lands owned and managed by the United States Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management.


(Pub. L. 106–224, title IV, § 452, as added Pub. L. 108–412, § 1, Oct. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2320.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitleFor short title of this subchapter as the “Noxious Weed Control and Eradication Act of 2004”, see section 451 of Pub. L. 106–224, set out as a note under section 7701 of this title.

Salt Cedar and Russian Olive ControlPub. L. 109–320, Oct. 11, 2006, 120 Stat. 1748, provided that:
“SECTION 1. SHORT TITLE.“This Act may be cited as the ‘Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act’.


“SEC. 2. SALT CEDAR AND RUSSIAN OLIVE CONTROL DEMONSTRATION PROGRAM.“(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this Act as the ‘Secretary’), acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation and the Director of the United States Geological Survey and in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7781_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Indian tribe The term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given that term in section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7781_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weed management entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Weed management entity The term “weed management entity” means an entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7781_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Federal lands The term “Federal lands” means those lands owned and managed by the United States Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>