<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7802"><akn:num>7802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7802. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) BoardThe terms “Avocado Board” and “Board” mean the Hass Avocado Board established under section 7804 of this title.


(2) Conflict of interestThe term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member or employee of the Board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, the Board for anything of economic value.


(3) Consumer informationThe term “consumer information” means any action or program that provides information to consumers and other persons on the use, nutritional attributes, and other information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of Hass avocados.


(4) CustomsThe term “Customs” means the United States Customs Service.


(5) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the United States Department of Agriculture.


(6) Hass avocado(A) In generalThe term “Hass avocado” includes—(i) the fruit of any Hass variety avocado tree; and

(ii) any other type of avocado fruit that the Board, with the approval of the Secretary, determines is so similar to the Hass variety avocado as to be indistinguishable to consumers in fresh form.


(B) Form of fruitExcept as provided in subparagraph (C), the term includes avocado fruit described in subparagraph (A) whether in fresh, frozen, or any other processed form.


(C) ExceptionsIn any case in which a handler further processes avocados described in subparagraph (A), or products of such avocados, for sale to a retailer, the Board, with the approval of the Secretary, may determine that such further processed products do not constitute a substantial value of the product and that, based on its determination, the product shall not be treated as a product of Hass avocados subject to assessment under the order. In addition, the Board, with the approval of the Secretary, may exempt certain frozen avocado products from a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Board The terms “Avocado Board” and “Board” mean the Hass Avocado Board established under section 7804 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Conflict of interest The term “conflict of interest” means a situation in which a member or employee of the Board has a direct or indirect financial interest in a person that performs a service for, or enters into a contract with, the Board for anything of economic value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Consumer information The term “consumer information” means any action or program that provides information to consumers and other persons on the use, nutritional attributes, and other information that will assist consumers and other persons in making evaluations and decisions regarding the purchase, preparation, and use of Hass avocados.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Customs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Customs The term “Customs” means the United States Customs Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Department The term “Department” means the United States Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hass avocado</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Hass avocado</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Handler</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Handler</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Importer The term “importer” means any person who imports Hass avocados into the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Industry information The term “industry information” means information and programs that are designed to increase efficiency in processing, enhance the development of new markets and marketing strategies, increase marketing efficiency, and activities to enhance the image of Hass avocados and the Hass avocado industry domestically.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Order The term “order” means the Hass avocado promotion, research, and information order issued under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>