<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7804"><akn:num>7804</akn:num><akn:heading>Required terms in orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7804. Required terms in orders(a) In generalAn order shall contain the terms and provisions specified in this section.


(b) Hass Avocado Board(1) Establishment and membership(A) EstablishmentThe order shall provide for the establishment of a Hass Avocado Board, consisting of 12 members, to administer the order.


(B) Membership(i) AppointmentThe order shall provide that members of the Board shall be appointed by the Secretary from nominations submitted as provided in this subsection.


(ii) CompositionThe Board shall consist of participating domestic producers and importers.



(C) Special definition of importerIn this subsection, the term “importer” means a person who is involved in, as a substantial activity, the importation, sale, and marketing of Hass avocados in the United States (either directly or as an agent, broker, or consignee of any person or nation that produces or handles Hass avocados outside the United States for sale in the United States), and who is subject to assessments under the order.



(2) Distribution of appointments(A) In generalThe order shall provide that the membership of the Board shall consist of the following:(i) Seven members who are domestic producers of Hass avocados and are subject to assessments under the order.

(ii) Two members who represent importers of Hass avocados and are subject to assessments under the order.

(iii) Three members who are domestic producers of Hass avocados and are subject to assessments under the order, or are importers of Hass avocados and are subject to assessments under the order, to reflect the proportion of domestic production and imports supplying the United States market, which shall be based on the Secretary’s determination of the average volume of domestic production of Hass avocados proportionate to the average volume of imports of Hass avocados in the United States over the previous 3 years.


(B) Adjustment in Board representationThree years after the assessment of Hass avocados commences p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general An order shall contain the terms and provisions specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hass Avocado Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hass Avocado Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General responsibilities of the Avocado Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General responsibilities of the Avocado Board The order shall define the general responsibilities of the Avocado Board, which shall include the responsibility to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgets; plans and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Budgets; plans and projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contracts and agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Books and records of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Books and records of Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Control of administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Control of administrative costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Secretary expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reimbursement of Secretary expenses The order shall provide for reimbursing the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7804_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on brand advertising and certain claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Prohibition on brand advertising and certain claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>