<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7931" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7931/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7931/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7931"><akn:num>7931</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7931. Availability of nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities(a) Nonrecourse loans available(1) AvailabilityFor each of the 2002 through 2007 crops of each loan commodity, the Secretary shall make available to producers on a farm nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for loan commodities produced on the farm.


(2) Terms and conditionsThe marketing assistance loans shall be made under terms and conditions that are prescribed by the Secretary and at the loan rate established under section 7932 of this title for the loan commodity.



(b) Eligible productionThe producers on a farm shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a) for any quantity of a loan commodity produced on the farm.


(c) Treatment of certain commingled commoditiesIn carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall make loans to producers on a farm that would be eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan, but for the fact the loan commodity owned by the producers on the farm commingled with loan commodities of other producers in facilities unlicensed for the storage of agricultural commodities by the Secretary or a State licensing authority, if the producers obtaining the loan agree to immediately redeem the loan collateral in accordance with section 166 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (7 U.S.C. 7286).


(d) Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirementsAs a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3811 et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of the Act (16 U.S.C. 3821 et seq.) during the term of the loan.


(e) Termination of superseded loan authorityNotwithstanding section 131 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (7 U.S.C. 7231), nonrecourse marketing assistance l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7931_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonrecourse loans available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonrecourse loans available</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7931_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible production The producers on a farm shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a) for any quantity of a loan commodity produced on the farm.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7931_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of certain commingled commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of certain commingled commodities In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall make loans to producers on a farm that would be eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan, but for the fact the loan commodity owned by the producers on the farm commingled with loan commodities of other producers in facilities unlicensed for the storage of agricultural commodities by the Secretary or a State licensing authority, if the producers obtaining the loan agree to immediately redeem the loan collateral in accordance with section 166 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (7 U.S.C. 7286).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7931_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements As a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3811 et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of the Act (16 U.S.C. 3821 et seq.) during the term of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7931_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of superseded loan authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of superseded loan authority Notwithstanding section 131 of the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 (7 U.S.C. 7231), nonrecourse marketing assistance loans shall not be made for the 2002 crop of loan commodities under subtitle C of title I of such Act [7 U.S.C. 7231 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>