<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7951" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7951/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7951/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7951"><akn:num>7951</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7951. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Base acres for peanutsThe term “base acres for peanuts” means the number of acres assigned to a farm by historic peanut producers pursuant to section 7952(b) of this title.


(2) Counter-cyclical paymentThe term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made under section 7954 of this title.


(3) Effective priceThe term “effective price” means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 7954 of this title for peanuts to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made under that section for a crop year.


(4) Direct paymentThe term “direct payment” means a payment made under section 7953 of this title.


(5) Historic peanut producerThe term “historic peanut producer” means a producer on a farm in the United States that produced or was prevented from planting peanuts during any or all of the 1998 through 2001 crop years.


(6) Payment acresThe term “payment acres” means—(A) for the 2002 crop of peanuts, 85 percent of the average acreage determined under section 7952(a)(2) of this title for an historic peanut producer; and

(B) for the 2003 through 2007 crops of peanuts, 85 percent of the base acres for peanuts assigned to a farm under section 7952(b) of this title.


(7) Payment yieldThe term “payment yield” means the yield assigned to a farm by historic peanut producers pursuant to section 7952(b) of this title.


(8) ProducerThe term “producer” means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper that shares in the risk of producing a crop on a farm and is entitled to share in the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared had the crop been produced. In determining whether a grower of hybrid seed is a producer, the Secretary shall not take into consideration the existence of a hybrid seed contract and shall ensure that program requirements do not adversely affect the ability of the grower to receive a payment under this subchapter.


(9) SecretaryThe term “Secretary</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Base acres for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Base acres for peanuts The term “base acres for peanuts” means the number of acres assigned to a farm by historic peanut producers pursuant to section 7952(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counter-cyclical payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Counter-cyclical payment The term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made under section 7954 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Effective price The term “effective price” means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 7954 of this title for peanuts to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made under that section for a crop year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Direct payment The term “direct payment” means a payment made under section 7953 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Historic peanut producer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Historic peanut producer The term “historic peanut producer” means a producer on a farm in the United States that produced or was prevented from planting peanuts during any or all of the 1998 through 2001 crop years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Payment acres The term “payment acres” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment yield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Payment yield The term “payment yield” means the yield assigned to a farm by historic peanut producers pursuant to section 7952(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Producer The term “producer” means an owner, operator, landlord, tenant, or sharecropper that shares in the risk of producing a crop on a farm and is entitled to share in the crop available for marketing from the farm, or would have shared had the crop been produced. In determining whether a grower of hybrid seed is a producer, the Secretary shall not take into consideration the existence of a hybrid seed contract and shall ensure that program requirements do not adversely affect the ability of the grower to receive a payment under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7951_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) State The term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>