<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7952" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7952/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7952/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7952"><akn:num>7952</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of payment yield and base acres for peanuts for a farm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7952. Establishment of payment yield and base acres for peanuts for a farm(a) Average yield and acreage average for historic peanut producers(1) Determination of average yield(A) In generalThe Secretary shall determine, for each historic peanut producer, the average yield for peanuts on each farm on which the historic peanut producer planted peanuts for harvest for the 1998 through 2001 crop years, excluding any crop year in which the producer did not plant or was prevented from planting peanuts.


(B) Assigned yieldsFor the purposes of determining the 4-year average yield for an historic peanut producer under this paragraph, the historic peanut producer may elect to substitute for a farm, for not more than 3 of the 1998 through 2001 crop years in which the producer planted peanuts on the farm, the average yield for peanuts produced in the county in which the farm is located for the 1990 through 1997 crop years.



(2) Determination of acreage average(A) In generalThe Secretary shall determine, for each historic peanut producer, the 4-year average of the following:(i) Acreage planted to peanuts on each farm on which the historic peanut producer planted peanuts for harvest for the 1998 through 2001 crop years.

(ii) Any acreage on each farm that the historic peanut producer was prevented from planting to peanuts during the 1998 through 2001 crop years because of drought, flood, or other natural disaster, or other condition beyond the control of the historic peanut producer, as determined by the Secretary.


(B) Inclusion of all 4 years in averageFor the purposes of determining the 4-year acreage average for an historic peanut producer under this paragraph, the Secretary shall not exclude any crop year in which the producer did not plant peanuts.


(C) Proportional sharesIf more than 1 historic peanut producer shared in the risk of producing the crop on a farm, the historic peanut producers shall receive their proportional share of the number of acres planted (or pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Average yield and acreage average for historic peanut producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Average yield and acreage average for historic peanut producers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of average yields and average acreage to farms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assignment of average yields and average acreage to farms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment yield</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment yield The average of all of the yields assigned by historic peanut producers under subsection (b) to a farm shall be considered to be the payment yield for that farm for the purpose of making direct payments and counter-cyclical payments under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Base acres for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Base acres for peanuts Subject to subsection (e), the total number of acres assigned by historic peanut producers under subsection (b) to a farm shall be considered to be the farm’s base acres for peanuts for the purpose of making direct payments and counter-cyclical payments under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of conservation reserve contract acreage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Treatment of conservation reserve contract acreage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7952_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent reduction in base acres for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Permanent reduction in base acres for peanuts The owner of a farm may reduce, at any time, the base acres for peanuts assigned to the farm. The reduction shall be permanent and made in the manner prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>