<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7954" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7954/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7954/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7954"><akn:num>7954</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of counter-cyclical payments for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7954. Availability of counter-cyclical payments for peanuts(a) Payment required(1) In generalDuring the 2002 through 2007 crop years for peanuts, the Secretary shall make counter-cyclical payments under this section with respect to peanuts if the Secretary determines that the effective price for peanuts is less than the target price for peanuts.


(2) 2002 crop yearIf counter-cyclical payments are required for the 2002 crop year, the Secretary shall make the payments to historic peanut producers.


(3) Subsequent crop yearsIf counter-cyclical payments are required for any of the 2003 through 2007 crop years for peanuts, the Secretary shall make the payments to the producers on a farm to which a payment yield and base acres for peanuts are assigned under section 7952 of this title.



(b) Effective priceFor purposes of subsection (a), the effective price for peanuts is equal to the sum of the following:(1) The higher of the following:(A) The national average market price for peanuts received by producers during the 12-month marketing year for peanuts, as determined by the Secretary.

(B) The national average loan rate for a marketing assistance loan for peanuts in effect for the applicable period under this subchapter.


(2) The payment rate in effect under section 7953 of this title for the purpose of making direct payments.


(c) Target priceFor purposes of subsection (a), the target price for peanuts shall be equal to $495 per ton.


(d) Payment rateThe payment rate used to make counter-cyclical payments for a crop year shall be equal to the difference between—(1) the target price; and

(2) the effective price determined under subsection (b).


(e) Payment amount for 2002 crop yearIf counter-cyclical payments are required to be paid for the 2002 crop of peanuts, the amount of the counter-cyclical payment to be paid to an historic peanut producer for that crop year shall be equal to the product of the following:(1) The payment rate specified in subsection (d).

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payment required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective price For purposes of subsection (a), the effective price for peanuts is equal to the sum of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Target price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Target price For purposes of subsection (a), the target price for peanuts shall be equal to $495 per ton.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment rate The payment rate used to make counter-cyclical payments for a crop year shall be equal to the difference between—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment amount for 2002 crop year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment amount for 2002 crop year If counter-cyclical payments are required to be paid for the 2002 crop of peanuts, the amount of the counter-cyclical payment to be paid to an historic peanut producer for that crop year shall be equal to the product of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment amount for subsequent crop years</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payment amount for subsequent crop years If counter-cyclical payments are required to be paid for any of the 2003 through 2007 crops of peanuts, the amount of the counter-cyclical payment to be paid to the producers on a farm for that crop year shall be equal to the product of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7954_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Time for payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>