<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7957" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7957/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7957/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7957"><akn:num>7957</akn:num><akn:heading>Marketing assistance loans and loan deficiency payments for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7957. Marketing assistance loans and loan deficiency payments for peanuts(a) Nonrecourse loans available(1) AvailabilityFor each of the 2002 through 2007 crops of peanuts, the Secretary shall make available to producers on a farm nonrecourse marketing assistance loans for peanuts produced on the farm. The loans shall be made under terms and conditions that are prescribed by the Secretary and at the loan rate established under subsection (b).


(2) Eligible productionThe producers on a farm shall be eligible for a marketing assistance loan under this subsection for any quantity of peanuts produced on the farm.


(3) Treatment of certain commingled commoditiesIn carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall make loans to producers on a farm that would be eligible to obtain a marketing assistance loan, but for the fact the peanuts owned by the producers on the farm are commingled with other peanuts in facilities unlicensed for the storage of agricultural commodities by the Secretary or a State licensing authority, if the producers obtaining the loan agree to immediately redeem the loan collateral in accordance with section 7286 of this title.


(4) Options for obtaining loanA marketing assistance loan under this subsection, and loan deficiency payments under subsection (e), may be obtained at the option of the producers on a farm through—(A) a designated marketing association or marketing cooperative of producers that is approved by the Secretary; or

(B) the Farm Service Agency.


(5) Storage of loan peanutsAs a condition on the Secretary’s approval of an individual or entity to provide storage for peanuts for which a marketing assistance loan is made under this section, the individual or entity shall agree—(A) to provide such storage on a nondiscriminatory basis; and

(B) to comply with such additional requirements as the Secretary considers appropriate to accomplish the purposes of this section and promote fairness in the administration of the benefits of this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonrecourse loans available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nonrecourse loans available</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Loan rate The loan rate for a marketing assistance loan under for peanuts subsection (a) shall be equal to $355 per ton.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term of loan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repayment rate</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan deficiency payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Loan deficiency payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compliance with conservation and wetlands requirements As a condition of the receipt of a marketing assistance loan under subsection (a), the producer shall comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3811 et seq.) and applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (16 U.S.C. 3821 et seq.) during the term of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7957_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursable agreements and payment of administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reimbursable agreements and payment of administrative expenses The Secretary may implement any reimbursable agreements or provide for the payment of administrative expenses under this subchapter only in a manner that is consistent with such activities in regard to other commodities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>