<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7958" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7958/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7958/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7958"><akn:num>7958</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7958. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Mandatory inspectionAll peanuts marketed in the United States shall be officially inspected and graded by Federal or Federal-State inspectors.


(b) Termination of Peanut Administrative CommitteeThe Peanut Administrative Committee established under Marketing Agreement No. 146 issued pursuant to the Agricultural Adjustment Act (7 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, is terminated.


(c) Peanut Standards Board(1) Establishment and purposeThe Secretary shall establish a Peanut Standards Board for the purpose of advising the Secretary regarding the establishment of quality and handling standards for domestically produced and imported peanuts.


(2) Membership and appointment(A) Total membersThe Board shall consist of 18 members, with representation equally divided between peanut producers and peanut industry representatives.


(B) Appointment process for producersThe Secretary shall appoint—(i) 3 producers from the Southeast (Alabama, Georgia, and Florida) peanut producing region;

(ii) 3 producers from the Southwest (Texas, Oklahoma, and New Mexico) peanut producing region; and

(iii) 3 producers from the Virginia/Carolina (Virginia, North Carolina, and South Carolina) peanut producing region.


(C) Appointment process for industry representativesThe Secretary shall appoint 3 peanut industry representatives from each of the 3 peanut producing regions in the United States.



(3) Terms(A) In generalA member of the Board shall serve a 3-year term.


(B) Initial appointmentIn making the initial appointments to the Board, the Secretary shall stagger the terms of the members so that—(i) 1 producer member and peanut industry member from each peanut producing region serves a 1-year term;

(ii) 1 producer member and peanut industry member from each peanut producing region serves a 2-year term; and

(iii) 1 producer member and peanut industry member from each peanut producing regi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mandatory inspection All peanuts marketed in the United States shall be officially inspected and graded by Federal or Federal-State inspectors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Peanut Administrative Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of Peanut Administrative Committee The Peanut Administrative Committee established under Marketing Agreement No. 146 issued pursuant to the Agricultural Adjustment Act (7 U.S.C. 601 et seq.), reenacted with amendments by the Agricultural Marketing Agreement Act of 1937, is terminated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peanut Standards Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Peanut Standards Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority The Secretary shall make identifying and combating the presence of all quality concerns related to peanuts a priority in the development of quality and handling standards for peanuts and in the inspection of domestically produced and imported peanuts. The Secretary shall consult with appropriate Federal and State agencies to provide adequate safeguards against all quality concerns related to peanuts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistent standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consistent standards Imported peanuts shall be subject to the same quality and handling standards as apply to domestically produced peanuts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transition rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7958_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective date This section shall take effect with the 2002 crop of peanuts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>