<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7959" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7959/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7959/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7959"><akn:num>7959</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of marketing quota programs for peanuts and compensation to peanut quota holders for los</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7959. Termination of marketing quota programs for peanuts and compensation to peanut quota holders for loss of quota asset value(a) Repeal of marketing quota(1) Omitted

(2) Treatment of 2001 cropPart VI of subtitle B of title III of the Agricultural Adjustment Act of 1938 (7 U.S.C. 1357–1359a), as in effect on the day before May 13, 2002, shall continue to apply with respect to the 2001 crop of peanuts notwithstanding the amendment made by paragraph (1). Section 7958(g)(2) of this title shall also apply to the 2001 crop of peanuts.



(b) Compensation contract required(1) In generalThe Secretary shall offer to enter into a contract with each person that the Secretary determines is an eligible peanut quota holder under subsection (f) for the purpose of providing compensation for the lost value of the quota on account of the repeal of the marketing quota program for peanuts under subsection (a).


(2) Payment periodThe Secretary shall make payments under the contracts during fiscal years 2002 through 2006.



(c) Time for payment(1) Payment in installmentsThe payments required under the contracts shall be provided in 5 equal installments not later than September 30 of each of fiscal years 2002 through 2006.


(2) Single paymentAt the request of an eligible peanut quota holder entitled to payments under a contract, the Secretary shall provide the entire payment amount determined under subsection (d) with respect to the eligible peanut quota holder for the 5 fiscal years in a single lump sum during the fiscal year specified by the eligible peanut quota holder.



(d) Payment amountThe amount of the payment for a fiscal year to an eligible peanut quota holder under a contract shall be equal to the product obtained by multiplying—(1) $0.11 per pound; by

(2) the number of pounds of quota with respect to which the person qualifies as a peanut quota holder under subsection (f).


(e) Assignment of paymentsThe provisions of section 590h(g) of title 16, relating to assignm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repeal of marketing quota</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repeal of marketing quota</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation contract required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation contract required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time for payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment amount The amount of the payment for a fiscal year to an eligible peanut quota holder under a contract shall be equal to the product obtained by multiplying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assignment of payments The provisions of section 590h(g) of title 16, relating to assignment of payments, shall apply to the payments made under the contracts. A person making an assignment of the payment, or the assignee, shall provide the Secretary with notice, in such manner as the Secretary may require, of any assignment made under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible peanut quota holder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible peanut quota holder</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7959_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Successions in payment eligibility and attachment of eligibility to persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Successions in payment eligibility and attachment of eligibility to persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>