<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7983" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7983/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7983/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7983"><akn:num>7983</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of national dairy policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7983. Study of national dairy policy(a) Study requiredThe Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a comprehensive economic evaluation of the potential direct and indirect effects of the various elements of the national dairy policy, including an examination of the effect of the national dairy policy on—(1) farm price stability, farm profitability and viability, and local rural economies in the United States;

(2) child, senior, and low-income nutrition programs, including impacts on schools and institutions participating in the programs, on program recipients, and other factors; and

(3) the wholesale and retail cost of fluid milk, dairy farms, and milk utilization.


(b) ReportNot later than 1 year after May 13, 2002, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the results of the study required by this section.


(c) National dairy policy definedIn this section, the term “national dairy policy” means the dairy policy of the United States as evidenced by the following policies and programs:(1) Federal milk marketing orders issued under section 608c of this title.

(2) Interstate dairy compacts (including proposed compacts described in H.R. 1827 and S. 1157, as introduced in the 107th Congress).

(3) Over-order premiums and State pricing programs.

(4) Direct payments to milk producers.

(5) Federal milk price support program established under section 7981 of this title.11 See References in Text note below.

(6) Export programs regarding milk and dairy products, such as the dairy export incentive program established under section 713a–14 of title 15.1


(Pub. L. 107–171, title I, § 1507, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 210.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextH.R. 1827, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), which would have granted consent to the Northeast Interstate Dairy Compact, the Southern Dairy Compact, the Pacific Northwest Dairy Compac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7983_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Study required The Secretary of Agriculture shall conduct a comprehensive economic evaluation of the potential direct and indirect effects of the various elements of the national dairy policy, including an examination of the effect of the national dairy policy on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7983_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Not later than 1 year after May 13, 2002, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report describing the results of the study required by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7983_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National dairy policy defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National dairy policy defined In this section, the term “national dairy policy” means the dairy policy of the United States as evidenced by the following policies and programs:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>