<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7991" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7991/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7991/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7991"><akn:num>7991</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7991. Administration generally(a) Use of Commodity Credit CorporationThe Secretary shall use the funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this chapter.


(b) Determinations by SecretaryA determination made by the Secretary under this chapter shall be final and conclusive.


(c) Regulations(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after May 13, 2002, the Secretary and the Commodity Credit Corporation, as appropriate, shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to implement this chapter.


(2) ProcedureThe promulgation of the regulations and administration of this chapter shall be made without regard to—(A) chapter 35 of title 44 (commonly know 11 So in original. Probably should be “known”. as the “Paperwork Reduction Act”);

(B) the Statement of Policy of the Secretary of Agriculture effective July 24, 1971 (36 Fed. Reg. 13804), relating to notices of proposed rulemaking and public participation in rulemaking; and

(C) the notice and comment provisions of section 553 of title 5.


(3) Congressional review of agency rulemakingIn carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall use the authority provided under section 808 of title 5.



(d) Treatment of advance payment optionThe protection that was afforded producers that had an option to elect to accelerate the receipt of any payment under a production flexibility contract payable under the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, as provided by section 525 of Public 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by “Law”. 106–170 (113 Stat. 1928; 7 U.S.C. 7212 note), shall also apply to the option to receive—(1) the advance payment of direct payments and counter-cyclical payments under subchapter I and subchapter III;

(2) the single payment of compensation for eligible peanut quota holders under section 7960 of this title; and

(3) the advance payment of direct payments and counter-cyclical payments under title I of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7991_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Commodity Credit Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of Commodity Credit Corporation The Secretary shall use the funds, facilities, and authorities of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7991_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determinations by Secretary A determination made by the Secretary under this chapter shall be final and conclusive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7991_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7991_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of advance payment option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of advance payment option The protection that was afforded producers that had an option to elect to accelerate the receipt of any payment under a production flexibility contract payable under the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996, as provided by section 525 of Public 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by “Law”. 106–170 (113 Stat. 1928; 7 U.S.C. 7212 note), shall also apply to the option to receive—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7991_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment authority related to Uruguay Round compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Adjustment authority related to Uruguay Round compliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>