<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/79a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/79a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/79a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_79a"><akn:num>79a</akn:num><akn:heading>Weighing authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 79a. Weighing authority(a) Official weighing in accordance with prescribed regulationsThe Secretary shall cause official weighing under standards or procedures provided for in section 76 of this title to be made of all grain required to be officially weighed as provided in section 77 of this title, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.


(b) Official weighing or supervision of weighing at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities located other than at export elevators at export port locationsThe Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures provided in section 76 of this title to be performed at any grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility located other than at export elevators at export port locations at which official inspection is provided pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, in such manner as the Secretary deems appropriate and under such regulations as the Secretary may provide.


(c) Personnel performing official weighing or supervision of weighing at locations at which official inspection is provided(1) With respect to official weighing or supervision of weighing for locations at which official inspection is provided by the Secretary, the Secretary shall cause such official weighing or supervision of weighing to be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary.

(2) With respect to official weighing or supervision of weighing for any location at which official inspection is provided other than by the Secretary, the Secretary is authorized, with respect to export port locations, to delegate authority to perform official weighing or supervision of weighing to the State agency providing official inspection service at such location, and with respect to any other location, to designate the agency or person providing official inspection service at such location to perform official weighing or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official weighing in accordance with prescribed regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Official weighing in accordance with prescribed regulations The Secretary shall cause official weighing under standards or procedures provided for in section 76 of this title to be made of all grain required to be officially weighed as provided in section 77 of this title, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official weighing or supervision of weighing at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities located other than at export elevators at export port locations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Official weighing or supervision of weighing at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities located other than at export elevators at export port locations The Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures provided in section 76 of this title to be performed at any grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility located other than at export elevators at export port locations at which official inspection is provided pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, in such manner as the Secretary deems appropriate and under such regulations as the Secretary may provide.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel performing official weighing or supervision of weighing at locations at which official inspection is provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Personnel performing official weighing or supervision of weighing at locations at which official inspection is provided</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official weighing in Canadian ports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Official weighing in Canadian ports The Secretary is authorized to cause official weighing under this chapter to be made, as provided in subsection (a) of section 77 of this title, in Canadian ports of United States export grain transshipped through Canada; and pursuant thereto the Secretary is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Canadian Government for such official weighing. All or specified functions of such weighing shall be performed by official inspection personnel employed by the Secretary or, except for appeals, by persons operating under a contract with the Secretary or as otherwise provided by agreement with the Canadian Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official weighing or supervision of weighing upon request of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Official weighing or supervision of weighing upon request of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities The Secretary is further authorized to cause official weighing or supervision of weighing under standards or procedures provided for in section 76 of this title to be made at grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities not subject to subsection (a) or (b) of this section, upon request of the operator of such grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility and in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstrated willingness of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities to meet equipment and personnel requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Demonstrated willingness of operators of grain elevators, warehouses, or other storage or handling facilities to meet equipment and personnel requirements No official weighing or supervision of weighing shall be provided for the purposes of this chapter at any grain elevator, warehouse, or other storage or handling facility until such time as the operator of the facility has demonstrated to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the operator (1) has and will maintain, in good order, suitable grain-handling equipment and accurate scales for all weighing of grain at the facility, in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary; (2) will permit only competent persons with a reputation for honesty and integrity and who are approved by the Secretary to operate the scales and to handle grain in connection with weighing of the grain, in accordance with this chapter; (3) when weighing is to be done by persons other than official inspection personnel, will require such persons to operat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Official certificates as evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Official certificates as evidence Official certificates setting out the results of official weighing or supervision of weighing, issued and not cancelled under this chapter, shall be received by all officers and all courts of the United States as prima facie evidence of the truth of the facts stated therein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weighing prohibited when not in accordance with prescribed procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Weighing prohibited when not in accordance with prescribed procedures No State or local governmental agency or person shall weigh or state in any document the weight of grain determined at a location where official weighing is required to be performed as provided for in this section except in accordance with the procedures prescribed pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unauthorized weighing prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Unauthorized weighing prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_79a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority under United States Warehouse Act not limited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authority under United States Warehouse Act not limited The provisions of this section shall not limit any authority vested in the Secretary under the United States Warehouse Act (39 Stat. 486, as amended; 7 U.S.C. 241 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>