<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7b–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7b–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/7b–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7b_3"><akn:num>7b–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Swap execution facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7b–3. Swap execution facilities(a) Registration(1) In generalNo person may operate a facility for the trading or processing of swaps unless the facility is registered as a swap execution facility or as a designated contract market under this section.


(2) Dual registrationAny person that is registered as a swap execution facility under this section shall register with the Commission regardless of whether the person also is registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission as a swap execution facility.



(b) Trading and trade processing(1) In generalExcept as specified in paragraph (2), a swap execution facility that is registered under subsection (a) may—(A) make available for trading any swap; and

(B) facilitate trade processing of any swap.


(2) Agricultural swapsA swap execution facility may not list for trading or confirm the execution of any swap in an agricultural commodity (as defined by the Commission) except pursuant to a rule or regulation of the Commission allowing the swap under such terms and conditions as the Commission shall prescribe.



(c) Identification of facility used to trade swaps by contract marketsA board of trade that operates a contract market shall, to the extent that the board of trade also operates a swap execution facility and uses the same electronic trade execution system for listing and executing trades of swaps on or through the contract market and the swap execution facility, identify whether the electronic trading of such swaps is taking place on or through the contract market or the swap execution facility.


(d) Rule-writing(1) The Securities and Exchange Commission and Commodity Futures Trading Commission may promulgate rules defining the universe of swaps that can be executed on a swap execution facility. These rules shall take into account the price and nonprice requirements of the counterparties to a swap and the goal of this section as set forth in subsection (e).

(2) For all swaps that are not required to be e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Registration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trading and trade processing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Trading and trade processing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of facility used to trade swaps by contract markets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification of facility used to trade swaps by contract markets A board of trade that operates a contract market shall, to the extent that the board of trade also operates a swap execution facility and uses the same electronic trade execution system for listing and executing trades of swaps on or through the contract market and the swap execution facility, identify whether the electronic trading of such swaps is taking place on or through the contract market or the swap execution facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule-writing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule-writing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction The goal of this section is to promote the trading of swaps on swap execution facilities and to promote pre-trade price transparency in the swaps market.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Core principles for swap execution facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Core principles for swap execution facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exemptions The Commission may exempt, conditionally or unconditionally, a swap execution facility from registration under this section if the Commission finds that the facility is subject to comparable, comprehensive supervision and regulation on a consolidated basis by the Securities and Exchange Commission, a prudential regulator, or the appropriate governmental authorities in the home country of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7b_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules The Commission shall prescribe rules governing the regulation of alternative swap execution facilities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>