<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8102"><akn:num>8102</akn:num><akn:heading>Biobased markets program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8102. Biobased markets program(a) Federal procurement of biobased products(1) Definition of procuring agencyIn this subsection, the term “procuring agency” means—(A) any Federal agency that is using Federal funds for procurement; or

(B) a person that is a party to a contract with any Federal agency, with respect to work performed under such a contract.


(2) Procurement preference(A) In general(i) Procuring agency dutiesExcept as provided in clause (ii) and subparagraph (B), after the date specified in applicable guidelines prepared pursuant to paragraph (3), each procuring agency shall—(I) establish a procurement program, develop procurement specifications, and procure biobased products identified under the guidelines described in paragraph (3) in accordance with this section;

(II) with respect to items described in the guidelines, give a procurement preference to those items that—(aa) are composed of the highest percentage of biobased products practicable; or

(bb) comply with the regulations issued under section 6914b–1 of title 42; and


(III) establish a targeted biobased-only procurement requirement under which the procuring agency shall issue a certain number of biobased-only contracts when the procuring agency is purchasing products, or purchasing services that include the use of products, that are included in a biobased product category designated by the Secretary.


(ii) ExceptionThe requirements of clause (i)(I) to establish a procurement program and develop procurement specifications shall not apply to a person described in paragraph (1)(B).



(B) FlexibilityNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), a procuring agency may decide not to procure items described in that subparagraph if the procuring agency determines that the items—(i) are not reasonably available within a reasonable period of time;

(ii) fail to meet—(I) the performance standards set forth in the applicable specifications; or

(II) the reasonable performance standards of the procuring agencie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal procurement of biobased products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal procurement of biobased products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Labeling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recognition The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation Nothing in this section shall apply to the procurement of motor vehicle fuels, heating oil, or electricity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inclusion Effective beginning on the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, the Architect of the Capitol, the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate, and the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives shall consider the biobased product designations made under this section in making procurement decisions for the Capitol Complex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturers of renewable chemicals and biobased products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Manufacturers of renewable chemicals and biobased products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forest products laboratory coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Forest products laboratory coordination In determining whether products are eligible for the “USDA Certified Biobased Product” label, the Secretary (acting through the Forest Products Laboratory) shall provide appropriate technical and other assistance to the program and applicants for forest products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Streamlining</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Streamlining</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of procuring agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirement of procuring agencies A procuring agency (as defined in subsection (a)(1)) shall not establish regulations, guidance, or criteria regarding the procurement of biobased products, pursuant to this section or any other law, that impose limitations on that procurement that are more restrictive than the limitations established by the Secretary under the regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>