<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8108"><akn:num>8108</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomass research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8108. Biomass research and development(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Biobased productThe term “biobased product” means—(A) an industrial product (including chemicals, materials, and polymers) produced from biomass;

(B) a commercial or industrial product (including animal feed and electric power) derived in connection with the conversion of biomass to fuel; or

(C) carbon dioxide that—(i) is intended for permanent sequestration or utilization; and

(ii) is a byproduct of the production of the products described in subparagraphs (A) and (B).



(2) DemonstrationThe term “demonstration” means demonstration of technology in a pilot plant or semi-works scale facility, including a plant or facility located on a farm.


(3) InitiativeThe term “Initiative” means the Biomass Research and Development Initiative established under subsection (e).



(b) Cooperation and coordination in biomass research and development(1) In generalThe Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Energy shall coordinate policies and procedures that promote research and development regarding the production of biofuels and biobased products.


(2) Points of contactTo coordinate research and development programs and activities relating to biofuels and biobased products that are carried out by their respective departments—(A) the Secretary of Agriculture shall designate, as the point of contact for the Department of Agriculture, an officer of the Department of Agriculture appointed by the President to a position in the Department before the date of the designation, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and

(B) the Secretary of Energy shall designate, as the point of contact for the Department of Energy, an officer of the Department of Energy appointed by the President to a position in the Department before the date of the designation, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.



(c) Biomass Research and Development Board(1) EstablishmentThere is established the Biomass Re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation and coordination in biomass research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperation and coordination in biomass research and development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomass Research and Development Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Biomass Research and Development Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomass Research and Development Technical Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Biomass Research and Development Technical Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomass Research and Development Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Biomass Research and Development Initiative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative support and funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative support and funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports For each fiscal year for which funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly submit to Congress a detailed report on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8108_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>