<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8111"><akn:num>8111</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomass Crop Assistance Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8111. Biomass Crop Assistance Program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BCAPThe term “BCAP” means the Biomass Crop Assistance Program established under this section.


(2) BCAP project areaThe term “BCAP project area” means an area that—(A) has specified boundaries that are submitted to the Secretary by the project sponsor and subsequently approved by the Secretary;

(B) includes producers with contract acreage that will supply a portion of the renewable biomass needed by a biomass conversion facility; and

(C) is physically located within an economically practicable distance from the biomass conversion facility.


(3) Contract acreageThe term “contract acreage” means eligible land that is covered by a BCAP contract entered into with the Secretary.


(4) Eligible crop(A) In generalThe term “eligible crop” means a crop of renewable biomass.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “eligible crop” does not include—(i) any crop that is eligible to receive payments under title I of the Agricultural Act of 2014 [7 U.S.C. 9001 et seq.] or an amendment made by that title; or

(ii) any plant that is invasive or noxious or species or varieties of plants that credible risk assessment tools or other credible sources determine are potentially invasive, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with other appropriate Federal or State departments and agencies.



(5) Eligible land(A) In generalThe term “eligible land” includes—(i) agricultural and nonindustrial private forest lands (as defined in section 2103a(c) of title 16); and

(ii) land enrolled in the conservation reserve program established under subchapter B of chapter I of subtitle D of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3831 et seq.), or the Agricultural Conservation Easement Program established under subtitle H of title XII of that Act [16 U.S.C. 3865 et seq.], under a contract that will expire at the end of the current fiscal year.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “eligible land” does not include—(i) Federal- or Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and purpose The Secretary shall establish and administer a Biomass Crop Assistance Program to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>BCAP project area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) BCAP project area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance with collection, harvest, storage, and transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance with collection, harvest, storage, and transportation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Not later than 4 years after February 7, 2014, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on the dissemination by the Secretary of the best practice data and information gathered from participants receiving assistance under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>