<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8113"><akn:num>8113</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Wood Energy and Wood Innovation Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8113. Community Wood Energy and Wood Innovation Program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Community wood energy system(A) In generalThe term “community wood energy system” means an energy system that—(i) produces thermal energy or combined thermal energy and electricity where thermal is the primary energy output;

(ii) services public facilities owned or operated by State or local governments (including schools, town halls, libraries, and other public buildings) or private or nonprofit facilities (including commercial and business facilities, such as hospitals, office buildings, apartment buildings, and manufacturing and industrial buildings); and

(iii) uses woody biomass, including residuals—(I) that have not been adulterated with glue or other chemical treatments from wood processing facilities, as the primary fuel; and

(II) for which the use of that biomass for energy production does not cause conversion of forests to nonforest use.



(B) InclusionsThe term “community wood energy system” includes single-facility central heating, district heating systems serving multiple buildings, combined heat and electric systems where thermal energy is the primary energy output, and other related biomass energy systems.



(2) Innovative wood product facilityThe term “innovative wood product facility” means a manufacturing or processing plant or mill that produces—(A) building components or systems that use large panelized wood construction, including mass timber;

(B) wood products derived from nanotechnology or other new technology processes, as determined by the Secretary; or

(C) other innovative wood products that use low-value, low-quality wood, as determined by the Secretary.


(3) Mass timberThe term “mass timber” includes—(A) cross-laminated timber;

(B) nail-laminated timber;

(C) glue-laminated timber;

(D) laminated strand lumber; and

(E) laminated veneer lumber.


(4) ProgramThe term “Program” means the Community Wood Energy and Wood Innovation Program estab</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Competitive grant program The Secretary, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, shall establish a competitive grant program to be known as the “Community Wood Energy and Wood Innovation Program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matching grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project cap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project cap The total amount of grants under the Program for a community wood energy system project or innovative wood product facility project may not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Selection criteria In selecting applicants for grants under the Program, the Secretary shall consider the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grant priorities In selecting applicants for grants under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to proposals that use the most stringent control technology that has been required or achieved in practice for a wood-fired boiler and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8113_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>