<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8308a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8308a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8308a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8308a"><akn:num>8308a</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal disease prevention and management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8308a. Animal disease prevention and management(a) National Animal Health Laboratory Network(1) Definition of eligible laboratoryIn this subsection, the term “eligible laboratory” means a diagnostic laboratory that meets specific criteria developed by the Secretary, in consultation with State animal health officials, State veterinary diagnostic laboratories, and veterinary diagnostic laboratories at institutions of higher education (as defined in section 1001 of title 20).


(2) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with State veterinarians, shall offer to enter into contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or other legal instruments with eligible laboratories for any of the following purposes:(A) To enhance the capability of the Secretary to respond in a timely manner to emerging or existing bioterrorist threats to animal health.

(B) To provide the capacity and capability for standardized—(i) test procedures, reference materials, and equipment;

(ii) laboratory biosafety and biosecurity levels;

(iii) quality management system requirements;

(iv) interconnected electronic reporting and transmission of data; and

(v) evaluation for emergency preparedness.


(C) To coordinate the development, implementation, and enhancement of national veterinary diagnostic laboratory capabilities, with special emphasis on surveillance planning and vulnerability analysis, technology development and validation, training, and outreach.


(3) PriorityTo the extent practicable and to the extent capacity and specialized expertise may be necessary, the Secretary shall give priority to existing Federal facilities, State facilities, and facilities at institutions of higher education.



(b) National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program(1) Program requiredThe Secretary shall establish a program, to be known as the National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program (referred to in this section as “the Program”), to address the increasing risk of the introduction and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8308a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Animal Health Laboratory Network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Animal Health Laboratory Network</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8308a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Animal Disease Preparedness and Response Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8308a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Animal Vaccine Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Animal Vaccine Bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8308a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8308a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability and purpose of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability and purpose of funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>