<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8310"><akn:num>8310</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8310. Cooperation(a) In generalTo carry out this chapter, the Secretary may cooperate with other Federal agencies, States or political subdivisions of States, national governments of foreign countries, local governments of foreign countries, domestic or international organizations, domestic or international associations, Indian tribes, and other persons.


(b) ResponsibilityThe person or other entity cooperating with the Secretary shall be responsible for the authority necessary to carry out operations or measures—(1) on all land and property within a foreign country or State, or under the jurisdiction of an Indian tribe, other than on land and property owned or controlled by the United States; and

(2) using other facilities and means, as determined by the Secretary.


(c) Screwworms(1) In generalThe Secretary may, independently or in cooperation with national governments of foreign countries or international organizations or associations, produce and sell sterile screwworms to any national government of a foreign country or international organization or association, if the Secretary determines that the livestock industry and related industries of the United States will not be adversely affected by the production and sale.


(2) Proceeds(A) Independent production and saleIf the Secretary independently produces and sells sterile screwworms under paragraph (1), the proceeds of the sale shall be—(i) deposited into the Treasury of the United States; and

(ii) credited to the account from which the operating expenses of the facility producing the sterile screwworms have been paid.


(B) Cooperative production and sale(i) In generalIf the Secretary cooperates to produce and sell sterile screwworms under paragraph (1), the proceeds of the sale shall be divided between the United States and the cooperating national government or international organization or association in a manner determined by the Secretary.


(ii) AccountThe United States portion of the proceeds shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To carry out this chapter, the Secretary may cooperate with other Federal agencies, States or political subdivisions of States, national governments of foreign countries, local governments of foreign countries, domestic or international organizations, domestic or international associations, Indian tribes, and other persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibility The person or other entity cooperating with the Secretary shall be responsible for the authority necessary to carry out operations or measures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Screwworms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Screwworms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8310_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation in program administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperation in program administration The Secretary may cooperate with State authorities, Indian tribe authorities, or other persons in the administration of regulations for the improvement of livestock and livestock products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8310_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and coordination with other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation and coordination with other Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>