<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8313"><akn:num>8313</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8313. Penalties(a) Criminal penalties(1) Offenses(A) In generalA person that knowingly violates this chapter, or knowingly forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the Secretary, uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate, permit, or other document provided for in this chapter shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 1 year, or both.


(B) Distribution or saleA person that knowingly imports, enters, exports, or moves any animal or article, for distribution or sale, in violation of this chapter, shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.



(2) Multiple violationsOn the second and any subsequent conviction of a person of a violation of this chapter under paragraph (1), the person shall be fined under title 18, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both.



(b) Civil penalties(1) In generalExcept as provided in section 8309(d) of this title, any person that violates this chapter, or that forges, counterfeits, or, without authority from the Secretary, uses, alters, defaces, or destroys any certificate, permit, or other document provided under this chapter may, after notice and opportunity for a hearing on the record, be assessed a civil penalty by the Secretary that does not exceed the greater of—(A)(i) $50,000 in the case of any individual, except that the civil penalty may not exceed $1,000 in the case of an initial violation of this chapter by an individual moving regulated articles not for monetary gain;

(ii) $250,000 in the case of any other person for each violation; and

(iii) for all violations adjudicated in a single proceeding—(I) $500,000 if the violations do not include a willful violation; or

(II) $1,000,000 if the violations include 1 or more willful violations.



(B) twice the gross gain or gross loss for any violation or forgery, counterfeiting, or unauthorized use, alteration, defacing or destruction of a certificate, permit, or other document provided under this chapter that results in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criminal penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for acts of agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liability for acts of agents In the construction and enforcement of this chapter, the act, omission, or failure of any officer, agent, or person acting for or employed by any other person within the scope of the employment or office of the officer, agent, or person, shall be deemed also to be the act, omission, or failure of the other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines for civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidelines for civil penalties Subject to the approval of the Attorney General, the Secretary shall establish guidelines to determine under what circumstances the Secretary may issue a civil penalty or suitable notice of warning in lieu of prosecution by the Attorney General of a violation of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>