<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8316" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8316/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8316/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8316"><akn:num>8316</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8316. Authorization of appropriations(a) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.


(b) Transfer of funds(1) In generalIn connection with an emergency under which a pest or disease of livestock threatens any segment of agricultural production in the United States, the Secretary may transfer from other appropriations or funds available to the agencies or corporations of the Department of Agriculture such funds as the Secretary determines are necessary for the arrest, control, eradication, or prevention of the spread of the pest or disease of livestock and for related expenses.


(2) AvailabilityAny funds transferred under this subsection shall remain available until expended, without fiscal year limitation.


(3) ReviewabilityThe action of any officer, employee, or agent of the Secretary in carrying out this section (including determining the amount of and making any payment authorized to be made under this chapter) shall not be subject to review by any officer or employee of the Federal Government other than the Secretary or the designee of the Secretary.



(c) Use of fundsIn carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may use funds made available to carry out this chapter for—(1) the employment of civilian nationals in foreign countries; and

(2) the construction and operation of research laboratories, quarantine stations, and other buildings and facilities for special purposes.


(Pub. L. 107–171, title X, § 10417, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 507; Pub. L. 110–234, title XI, § 11011(3), May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1360; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title XI, § 11011(3), June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 2122.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle E (§§ 10401–10418) of title X of Pub. L. 107–171, May 13, 2002, 116 Stat. 494, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of subtitle E to the Code, see S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8316_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8316_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8316_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds In carrying out this chapter, the Secretary may use funds made available to carry out this chapter for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>