<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8354"><akn:num>8354</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures for cooperative agreements to lease aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8354. Expenditures for cooperative agreements to lease aircraft
On and after November 10, 2005, notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Agriculture may use appropriations available to the Secretary for activities authorized under sections 8351 to 8353 11 See Reference in Text note below. of this title, under this or any other Act, to enter into cooperative agreements, with a State, political subdivision, or agency thereof, a public or private agency, organization, or any other person, to lease aircraft if the Secretary determines that the objectives of the agreement will: (1) serve a mutual interest of the parties to the agreement in carrying out the programs administered by the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, Wildlife Services; and (2) all parties will contribute resources to the accomplishment of these objectives; award of a cooperative agreement authorized by the Secretary may be made for an initial term not to exceed 5 years.
(Pub. L. 109–97, title VII, § 749, Nov. 10, 2005, 119 Stat. 2156.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 8351 to 8353 of this title, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to “sections 426–426c of title 7, United States Code” and was translated as meaning act Mar. 2, 1931, ch. 370, 46 Stat. 1468, and Pub. L. 100–202, §101(k) [title I], Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1329–322, 1329–331, which were formerly classified to sections 426 to 426c of this title. Sections 1 and 3 of the act of Mar. 2, 1931, which were formerly classified to sections 426 and 426b of this title, were editorially reclassified as sections 8351 and 8352, respectively, of this title. Section 2 of the act of Mar. 2, 1931, which was formerly classified to section 426a of this title, was omitted from the Code as obsolete. Pub. L. 100–202, §101(k) [title I], Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1329–322, 1329–331, which was formerly classified to section 426c of this title, was editorially reclassified as section 8353 of this title.

Codi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>