<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8355" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8355/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8355/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8355"><akn:num>8355</akn:num><akn:heading>Losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8355. Losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Depredation(A) In generalThe term “depredation” means actual death, injury, or destruction of livestock that is caused by a federally protected species.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “depredation” does not include damage to real or personal property other than livestock, including—(i) damage to—(I) other animals;

(II) vegetation;

(III) motor vehicles; or

(IV) structures;


(ii) diseases;

(iii) lost profits; or

(iv) consequential damages.



(2) Federally protected speciesThe term “federally protected species” means a species that is or previously was protected under—(A) the Act of June 8, 1940 (commonly known as the “Bald and Golden Eagle Protection Act”) (54 Stat. 250, chapter 278; 16 U.S.C. 668 et seq.);

(B) the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.); or

(C) the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.).


(3) Indian TribeThe term “Indian Tribe” has the meaning given to the term “Indian tribe” in section 5304 of title 25.


(4) Livestock(A) In generalThe term “livestock” means horses, mules and asses, rabbits, llamas, cattle, bison, swine, sheep, goats, poultry, bees, honey and beehives, or any other animal generally used for food or in the production of food or fiber.


(B) InclusionThe term “livestock” includes guard animals actively engaged in the protection of livestock described in subparagraph (A).



(5) ProgramThe term “program” means the grant program established under subsection (b)(1).


(6) SecretariesThe term “Secretaries” means—(A) the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service; and

(B) the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Administrator of the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service.



(b) Grant program for losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species(1) In generalThe Secretaries shall establish a program to provid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8355_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8355_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program for losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant program for losses of livestock due to depredation by federally protected species</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8355_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8355_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030, of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>