<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8411"><akn:num>8411</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8411. Interagency coordination(a) In general(1) CoordinationThe Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall in accordance with this section coordinate activities regarding overlap agents and toxins.


(2) Overlap agents and toxins; other termsFor purposes of this section:(A) The term “overlap agent or toxin” means a biological agent or toxin that—(i) is listed pursuant to section 315A(a)(1) 11 So in original. Probably should be “351A(a)(1)”. of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262a(a)(1)], as added by section 201 of this Act; and

(ii) is listed pursuant to section 212(a)(1) of this Act [7 U.S.C. 8401(a)(1)].


(B) The term “section 351A program” means the program under section 351A of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 262a].

(C) The term “section 212 program” means the program under section 212 of this Act [7 U.S.C. 8401].



(b) Certain mattersIn carrying out the section 351A program and the section 212 program, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, to the greatest extent practicable, coordinate activities to achieve the following purposes:(1) To minimize any conflicts between the regulations issued under, and activities carried out under, such programs.

(2) To minimize the administrative burden on persons subject to regulation under both of such programs.

(3) To ensure the appropriate availability of biological agents and toxins for legitimate biomedical, agricultural or veterinary research, education, or other such purposes.

(4) To ensure that registration information for overlap agents and toxins under the section 351A and section 212 programs is contained in both the national database under the section 351A program and the national database under the section 212 program.


(c) Memorandum of understanding(1) In generalPromptly after June 12, 2002, the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into a memorandum of understa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain matters In carrying out the section 351A program and the section 212 program, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, to the greatest extent practicable, coordinate activities to achieve the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Memorandum of understanding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Joint regulations Not later than 18 months after the date on which the single system of registration under subsection (c)(2) is implemented, the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly issue regulations for the possession, use, and transfer of overlap agents and toxins that meet the requirements of both the section 351A program and the section 212 program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>