<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8501"><akn:num>8501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8501. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Brown tree snakeThe term “brown tree snake” means the species of the snake Boiga irregularis.


(2) Compact of Free AssociationThe term “Compact of Free Association” means the Compacts of Free Association entered into between the United States and the governments of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands, as approved by and contained in Public Law 108–188 (117 Stat. 2720; 48 U.S.C. 1921 et seq.), and the Compact of Free Association entered into between the United States and the government of the Republic of Palau, as approved by and contained in Public Law 99–658 (100 Stat. 3673; 48 U.S.C. 1931 et seq.).


(3) Freely Associated StatesThe term “Freely Associated States” means the Republic of Palau, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of the Marshall Islands.


(4) IntroductionThe terms “introduce” and “introduction” refer to the expansion of the brown tree snake outside of the range where this species is endemic.


(5) SecretaryThe term “Secretary concerned” means—(A) the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to matters under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior; and

(B) the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to matters under the jurisdiction of the Department of Agriculture.


(6) SecretariesThe term “Secretaries” means both the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture.


(7) Technical Working GroupThe term “Technical Working Group” means Brown Tree Snake Technical Working Group established under the authority of section 4728 of title 16.


(8) TerritorialThe term “territorial”, when used to refer to a government, means the Government of Guam, the Government of American Samoa, and the Government of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, as well as autonomous agencies and instrumentalities of such a government.


(9) United StatesThe term “United States”, when used in the geographic sense, means the several States, the Distri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brown tree snake</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Brown tree snake The term “brown tree snake” means the species of the snake Boiga irregularis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compact of Free Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Compact of Free Association The term “Compact of Free Association” means the Compacts of Free Association entered into between the United States and the governments of the Federated States of Micronesia and the Republic of the Marshall Islands, as approved by and contained in Public Law 108–188 (117 Stat. 2720; 48 U.S.C. 1921 et seq.), and the Compact of Free Association entered into between the United States and the government of the Republic of Palau, as approved by and contained in Public Law 99–658 (100 Stat. 3673; 48 U.S.C. 1931 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Freely Associated States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Freely Associated States The term “Freely Associated States” means the Republic of Palau, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of the Marshall Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Introduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Introduction The terms “introduce” and “introduction” refer to the expansion of the brown tree snake outside of the range where this species is endemic.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Secretary The term “Secretary concerned” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Secretaries The term “Secretaries” means both the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Working Group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Technical Working Group The term “Technical Working Group” means Brown Tree Snake Technical Working Group established under the authority of section 4728 of title 16.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Territorial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Territorial The term “territorial”, when used to refer to a government, means the Government of Guam, the Government of American Samoa, and the Government of the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, as well as autonomous agencies and instrumentalities of such a government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8501_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) United States The term “United States”, when used in the geographic sense, means the several States, the District of Colombia,11 So in original. Probably should be “Columbia,”. American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, any other possession of the United States, and any waters within the jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>