<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8504"><akn:num>8504</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of quarantine protocols to control the introduction and spread of the brown tree snake</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8504. Establishment of quarantine protocols to control the introduction and spread of the brown tree snake(a) Establishment of quarantine protocolsNot later than two years after October 30, 2004, but subject to the memorandum of agreement required by subsection (b) with respect to Guam, the Secretaries shall establish and cause to be operated at Federal expense a system of pre-departure quarantine protocols for cargo and other items being shipped from Guam and any other United States location where the brown tree snake may become established to prevent the introduction or spread of the brown tree snake. The Secretaries shall establish the quarantine protocols system by regulation. Under the quarantine protocols system, Federal quarantine, natural resource, conservation, and law enforcement officers and inspectors may enforce State and territorial laws regarding the transportation, possession, or introduction of any brown tree snake.


(b) Cooperation and consultationThe activities of the Secretaries under subsection (a) shall be carried out in cooperation with other Federal agencies and the appropriate State and territorial quarantine, natural resource, conservation, and law enforcement officers. In the case of Guam, as a precondition on the establishment of the system of pre-departure quarantine protocols under such subsection, the Secretaries shall enter into a memorandum of agreement with the Government of Guam to obtain the assistance and cooperation of the Government of Guam in establishing the system of pre-departure quarantine protocols.


(c) ImplementationThe system of pre-departure quarantine protocols to be established under subsection (a) shall not be implemented until funds are specifically appropriated for that purpose.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section the following amounts:(1) To the Secretary of Agriculture, not more than $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2006 through 2010.
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of quarantine protocols</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of quarantine protocols Not later than two years after October 30, 2004, but subject to the memorandum of agreement required by subsection (b) with respect to Guam, the Secretaries shall establish and cause to be operated at Federal expense a system of pre-departure quarantine protocols for cargo and other items being shipped from Guam and any other United States location where the brown tree snake may become established to prevent the introduction or spread of the brown tree snake. The Secretaries shall establish the quarantine protocols system by regulation. Under the quarantine protocols system, Federal quarantine, natural resource, conservation, and law enforcement officers and inspectors may enforce State and territorial laws regarding the transportation, possession, or introduction of any brown tree snake.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation and consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperation and consultation The activities of the Secretaries under subsection (a) shall be carried out in cooperation with other Federal agencies and the appropriate State and territorial quarantine, natural resource, conservation, and law enforcement officers. In the case of Guam, as a precondition on the establishment of the system of pre-departure quarantine protocols under such subsection, the Secretaries shall enter into a memorandum of agreement with the Government of Guam to obtain the assistance and cooperation of the Government of Guam in establishing the system of pre-departure quarantine protocols.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation The system of pre-departure quarantine protocols to be established under subsection (a) shall not be implemented until funds are specifically appropriated for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section the following amounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>