<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8702"><akn:num>8702</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8702. Definitions
In this chapter (other than subchapter III):(1) Average crop revenue election paymentThe term “average crop revenue election payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8715 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(2) Base acres(A) In generalThe term “base acres”, with respect to a covered commodity on a farm, means the number of acres established under section 7911 of this title as in effect on September 30, 2007, subject to any adjustment under section 8711 of this title.


(B) PeanutsThe term “base acres for peanuts” has the meaning given the term in section 8751 of this title.



(3) Counter-cyclical paymentThe term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8714 1 of this title.


(4) Covered commodityThe term “covered commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, pulse crops, soybeans, and other oilseeds.


(5) Direct paymentThe term “direct payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8713 1 of this title.


(6) Effective priceThe term “effective price”, with respect to a covered commodity for a crop year, means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 8714 1 of this title to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made for that crop year.


(7) Extra long staple cottonThe term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—(A) is produced from pure strain varieties of the Barbadense species or any hybrid of the species, or other similar types of extra long staple cotton, designated by the Secretary, having characteristics needed for various end uses for which United States upland cotton is not suitable and grown in irrigated cotton-growing regions of the United States designated by the Secretary or other areas designated by the Secretary as suitable for the production of the varieties or types; and

(B) is ginned on a roller-type gin or, if aut</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Average crop revenue election payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Average crop revenue election payment The term “average crop revenue election payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8715 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Base acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Base acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counter-cyclical payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Counter-cyclical payment The term “counter-cyclical payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8714 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Covered commodity The term “covered commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, pulse crops, soybeans, and other oilseeds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Direct payment The term “direct payment” means a payment made to producers on a farm under section 8713 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Effective price The term “effective price”, with respect to a covered commodity for a crop year, means the price calculated by the Secretary under section 8714 1 of this title to determine whether counter-cyclical payments are required to be made for that crop year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extra long staple cotton</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Extra long staple cotton The term “extra long staple cotton” means cotton that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan commodity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Loan commodity The term “loan commodity” means wheat, corn, grain sorghum, barley, oats, upland cotton, extra long staple cotton, long grain rice, medium grain rice, soybeans, other oilseeds, graded wool, nongraded wool, mohair, honey, dry peas, lentils, small chickpeas, and large chickpeas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medium grain rice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Medium grain rice The term “medium grain rice” includes short grain rice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8702_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other oilseed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Other oilseed The term “other oilseed” means a crop of sunflower seed, rapeseed, canola, safflower, flaxseed, mustard seed, crambe, sesame seed, or any oilseed designated by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>