<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8716" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8716/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8716/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8716"><akn:num>8716</akn:num><akn:heading>Producer agreement required as condition of provision of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8716. Producer agreement required as condition of provision of payments(a) Compliance with certain requirements(1) RequirementsBefore the producers on a farm may receive direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments with respect to the farm, the producers shall agree, during the crop year for which the payments are made and in exchange for the payments—(A) to comply with applicable conservation requirements under subtitle B of title XII of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3811 et seq.);

(B) to comply with applicable wetland protection requirements under subtitle C of title XII of that Act (16 U.S.C. 3821 et seq.);

(C) to comply with the planting flexibility requirements of section 8717 of this title;

(D) to use the land on the farm, in a quantity equal to the attributable base acres for the farm and any base acres for peanuts for the farm under subchapter III, for an agricultural or conserving use, and not for a nonagricultural commercial, industrial, or residential use, as determined by the Secretary; and

(E) to effectively control noxious weeds and otherwise maintain the land in accordance with sound agricultural practices, as determined by the Secretary, if the agricultural or conserving use involves the noncultivation of any portion of the land referred to in subparagraph (D).


(2) ComplianceThe Secretary may issue such rules as the Secretary considers necessary to ensure producer compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1).


(3) ModificationAt the request of the transferee or owner, the Secretary may modify the requirements of this subsection if the modifications are consistent with the objectives of this subsection, as determined by the Secretary.



(b) Transfer or change of interest in farm(1) Termination(A) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), a transfer of (or change in) the interest of the producers on a farm in base acres for which direct payments or counter-cyclical payments are mad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with certain requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with certain requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or change of interest in farm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer or change of interest in farm</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenants and sharecroppers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tenants and sharecroppers In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary shall provide adequate safeguards to protect the interests of tenants and sharecroppers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sharing of payments The Secretary shall provide for the sharing of direct payments, counter-cyclical payments, or average crop revenue election payments among the producers on a farm on a fair and equitable basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8716_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of 2008 signup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Extension of 2008 signup</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>