<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8752" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8752/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8752/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8752"><akn:num>8752</akn:num><akn:heading>Base acres for peanuts for a farm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8752. Base acres for peanuts for a farm(a) Adjustment of base acreage for peanuts(1) In generalThe Secretary shall provide for an adjustment, as appropriate, in the base acres for peanuts for a farm whenever any of the following circumstances occur:(A) A conservation reserve contract entered into under section 1231 of the Food Security Act of 1985 (16 U.S.C. 3831) with respect to the farm expires or is voluntarily terminated, or was terminated or expired during the period beginning on October 1, 2007, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.

(B) Cropland is released from coverage under a conservation reserve contract by the Secretary, or was released during the period beginning on October 1, 2007, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act.

(C) The producer has eligible pulse crop acreage, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under section 7911(a)(2) of this title.

(D) The producer has eligible oilseed acreage as the result of the Secretary designating additional oilseeds, which shall be determined in the same manner as eligible oilseed acreage under section 7911(a)(2) of this title.


(2) Special conservation reserve acreage payment rulesFor the crop year in which a base acres for peanuts adjustment under subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) is first made, the owner of the farm shall elect to receive either direct payments and counter-cyclical payments with respect to the acreage added to the farm under this subsection or a prorated payment under the conservation reserve contract, but not both.



(b) Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts(1) Required reductionIf the sum of the base acres for peanuts for a farm, together with the acreage described in paragraph (2), exceeds the actual cropland acreage of the farm, the Secretary shall reduce the base acres for peanuts for the farm or the base acres for 1 or more covered commodities for the farm so that the sum of the base acres for peanuts and acreage des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8752_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of base acreage for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Adjustment of base acreage for peanuts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8752_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prevention of excess base acres for peanuts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8752_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in base acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduction in base acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8752_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of farms with limited base acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of farms with limited base acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>