<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8783" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8783/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8783/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8783"><akn:num>8783</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of quality incentive payments for covered oilseed producers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8783. Availability of quality incentive payments for covered oilseed producers(a) Incentive payments requiredSubject to subsection (b) and the availability of appropriations under subsection (h), the Secretary shall use funds made available under subsection (h) to provide quality incentive payments for the production of oilseeds with specialized traits that enhance human health, as determined by the Secretary.


(b) Covered oilseedsThe Secretary shall make payments under this section only for the production of an oilseed variety that has, as determined by the Secretary—(1) been demonstrated to improve the health profile of the oilseed for use in human consumption by—(A) reducing or eliminating the need to partially hydrogenate the oil derived from the oilseed for use in human consumption; or

(B) adopting new technology traits; and


(2) 1 or more impediments to commercialization.


(c) Request for proposals(1) IssuanceIf funds are made available to carry out this section for a crop year, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals for payments under this section.


(2) Multiyear proposalsA proponent may submit a multiyear proposal for payments under this section.


(3) Content of proposalsA proposal for payments under this section shall include a description of—(A) how use of the oilseed enhances human health;

(B) the impediments to commercial use of the oilseed;

(C) each oilseed variety described in subsection (b) and the value of the oilseed variety as a matter of public policy;

(D) a range for the base price and premiums per bushel or hundredweight to be paid to producers;

(E) a per bushel or hundredweight amount of incentive payments requested for each year under this section that does not exceed ⅓ of the total premium offered for any year;

(F) the period of time, not to exceed 4 years, during which incentive payments are to be provided to producers; and

(G) the targeted total quantity of production and estimated acres needed to produce the target</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentive payments required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Incentive payments required Subject to subsection (b) and the availability of appropriations under subsection (h), the Secretary shall use funds made available under subsection (h) to provide quality incentive payments for the production of oilseeds with specialized traits that enhance human health, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered oilseeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Covered oilseeds The Secretary shall make payments under this section only for the production of an oilseed variety that has, as determined by the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Request for proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contracts for production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proprietary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Proprietary information The Secretary shall protect proprietary information provided to the Secretary for the purpose of administering this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program compliance and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program compliance and penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8783_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>