<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8792" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8792/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8792/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8792"><akn:num>8792</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8792. Geographically disadvantaged farmers and ranchers(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Agricultural commodityThe term “agricultural commodity” has the meaning given the term in section 5602 of this title.


(2) Geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancherThe term “geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher” has the meaning given the term in section 10906(a) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (7 U.S.C. 2204 note; Public Law 107–171).



(b) AuthorizationSubject to the availability of funds under subsection (d), the Secretary may provide geographically disadvantaged farmers or ranchers direct reimbursement payments for activities described in subsection (c).


(c) Transportation(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary may provide direct reimbursement payments to a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher to transport an agricultural commodity, or inputs used to produce an agricultural commodity, during a fiscal year.


(2) Proof of eligibilityTo be eligible to receive assistance under paragraph (1), a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher shall demonstrate to the Secretary that transportation of the agricultural commodity or inputs occurred over a distance of more than 30 miles, as determined by the Secretary.


(3) Amount(A) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the amount of direct reimbursement payments made to a geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher under this section for a fiscal year shall equal the product obtained by multiplying—(i) the amount of costs incurred by the geographically disadvantaged farmer or rancher for transportation of the agricultural commodity or inputs during the fiscal year; and

(ii)(I) the percentage of the allowance for that fiscal year under section 5941 of title 5 for Federal employees stationed in Alaska and Hawaii; or

(II) in the case of an insular area (as defined in section 3103 of this title), a comparable percentage of the allowance for the fiscal year, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8792_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8792_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization Subject to the availability of funds under subsection (d), the Secretary may provide geographically disadvantaged farmers or ranchers direct reimbursement payments for activities described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8792_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transportation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8792_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for fiscal year 2009 and each succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>