<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/87f–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/87f–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/87f–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_87f_2"><akn:num>87f–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 87f–2. Reporting requirements(a) General requirements; annual report to Congressional committeesOn December 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate regarding the effectiveness of the official inspection and weighing system under this chapter for the prior fiscal year, with recommendations for any legislative changes necessary to accomplish the objectives stated in section 74 of this title.


(b) Notification of Congressional committees of complaints regarding faulty grain deliveries and cancellation of export contractsThe Secretary shall notify the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate (1) of any complaint regarding faulty grain delivery made to the Department of Agriculture by a foreign purchaser of United States grain, within thirty days after a determination by the Secretary that there is reasonable cause to believe that the grain delivery was in fact faulty, and (2) notwithstanding the provisions of section 612c–3 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, within thirty days after receipt by the Secretary or the Secretary 22 So in original. The words “or the Secretary” probably should not appear. of notice of the cancellation of any contract for the export of more than one hundred thousand metric tons of grain.


(c) Submission to Congressional committees of annual summary of complaints from foreign purchasers and prospective purchasers of grainOn December 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a summary of all other complaints received by the Department of Agriculture during the prior fiscal year from foreign purchasers and prospective purchasers of United States grain and othe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements; annual report to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirements; annual report to Congressional committees On December 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate regarding the effectiveness of the official inspection and weighing system under this chapter for the prior fiscal year, with recommendations for any legislative changes necessary to accomplish the objectives stated in section 74 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Congressional committees of complaints regarding faulty grain deliveries and cancellation of export contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of Congressional committees of complaints regarding faulty grain deliveries and cancellation of export contracts The Secretary shall notify the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate (1) of any complaint regarding faulty grain delivery made to the Department of Agriculture by a foreign purchaser of United States grain, within thirty days after a determination by the Secretary that there is reasonable cause to believe that the grain delivery was in fact faulty, and (2) notwithstanding the provisions of section 612c–3 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, within thirty days after receipt by the Secretary or the Secretary 22 So in original. The words “or the Secretary” probably should not appear. of notice of the cancellation of any contract for the export of more than one hundred thousand metric tons of grain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congressional committees of annual summary of complaints from foreign purchasers and prospective purchasers of grain</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission to Congressional committees of annual summary of complaints from foreign purchasers and prospective purchasers of grain On December 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a summary of all other complaints received by the Department of Agriculture during the prior fiscal year from foreign purchasers and prospective purchasers of United States grain and other foreign purchasers interested in the trade of grain, and the resolution thereof: Provided, That the summary shall not include a complaint unless reasonable cause exists to believe that the complaint is valid, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancement of current reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enhancement of current reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reporting; consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional reporting; consultation The Secretary may, to the extent determined appropriate by the Secretary, in consultation with State agencies delegated authority under sections 79 and 79a of this title, official agencies, and the grain industries described in the second sentence of section 87j(a) of this title, publish—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_87f_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of confidential business information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protection of confidential business information Any trade secrets or information described in section 552(b)(4) of title 5 that is provided to or collected by the Secretary in carrying out subsection (d) or (e) shall not be included in a report under subsection (d) or (e) or otherwise publicly disclosed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>