<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/8901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8901"><akn:num>8901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8901. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AgentThe term “agent” means a nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological substance that causes agricultural disease or the adulteration of products regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture under any provision of law.


(2) Agricultural biosecurityThe term “agricultural biosecurity” means protection from an agent that poses a threat to—(A) plant or animal health;

(B) public health as it relates to the adulteration of products regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture under any provision of law that is caused by exposure to an agent; or

(C) the environment as it relates to agriculture facilities, farmland, and air and water within the immediate vicinity of an area associated with an agricultural disease or outbreak.


(3) Agricultural countermeasureThe term “agricultural countermeasure”—(A) means a product, practice, or technology that is intended to enhance or maintain the agricultural biosecurity of the United States; and

(B) does not include a product, practice, or technology used solely in response to a human medical incident or public health emergency not related to agriculture.


(4) Agricultural diseaseThe term “agricultural disease” has the meaning given the term by the Secretary.


(5) Agricultural disease emergencyThe term “agricultural disease emergency” means an incident of agricultural disease that requires prompt action to prevent significant damage to people, plants, or animals.


(6) Agroterrorist actThe term “agroterrorist act” means an act that—(A) causes or attempts to cause—(i) damage to agriculture; or

(ii) injury to a person associated with agriculture; and


(B) is committed or appears to be committed with the intent to—(i) intimidate or coerce a civilian population; or

(ii) disrupt the agricultural industry in order to influence the policy of a government by intimidation or coercion.



(7) AnimalThe term “animal” has the meaning given the term in section 8302 of this title.


(8) DepartmentThe </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Agent The term “agent” means a nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological substance that causes agricultural disease or the adulteration of products regulated by the Secretary of Agriculture under any provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural biosecurity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Agricultural biosecurity The term “agricultural biosecurity” means protection from an agent that poses a threat to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural countermeasure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Agricultural countermeasure The term “agricultural countermeasure”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural disease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Agricultural disease The term “agricultural disease” has the meaning given the term by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural disease emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Agricultural disease emergency The term “agricultural disease emergency” means an incident of agricultural disease that requires prompt action to prevent significant damage to people, plants, or animals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agroterrorist act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Agroterrorist act The term “agroterrorist act” means an act that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Animal The term “animal” has the meaning given the term in section 8302 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Development The term “development” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8901_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Plant The term “plant” has the meaning given the term in section 7702 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>