<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9"><akn:num>9</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition regarding manipulation and false information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9. Prohibition regarding manipulation and false information(1) Prohibition against manipulationIt shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, to use or employ, or attempt to use or employ, in connection with any swap, or a contract of sale of any commodity in interstate commerce, or for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any registered entity, any manipulative or deceptive device or contrivance, in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission shall promulgate by not later than 1 year after July 21, 2010, provided no rule or regulation promulgated by the Commission shall require any person to disclose to another person nonpublic information that may be material to the market price, rate, or level of the commodity transaction, except as necessary to make any statement made to the other person in or in connection with the transaction not misleading in any material respect.(A) Special provision for manipulation by false reportingUnlawful manipulation for purposes of this paragraph shall include, but not be limited to, delivering, or causing to be delivered for transmission through the mails or interstate commerce, by any means of communication whatsoever, a false or misleading or inaccurate report concerning crop or market information or conditions that affect or tend to affect the price of any commodity in interstate commerce, knowing, or acting in reckless disregard of the fact that such report is false, misleading or inaccurate.


(B) Effect on other lawNothing in this paragraph shall affect, or be construed to affect, the applicability of section 13(a)(2) of this title.


(C) Good faith mistakesMistakenly transmitting, in good faith, false or misleading or inaccurate information to a price reporting service would not be sufficient to violate paragraph (1)(A).



(2) Prohibition regarding false informationIt shall be unlawful for any person to make any false or misleading statement of a material fact to the Commission, incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against manipulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Prohibition against manipulation It shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, to use or employ, or attempt to use or employ, in connection with any swap, or a contract of sale of any commodity in interstate commerce, or for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any registered entity, any manipulative or deceptive device or contrivance, in contravention of such rules and regulations as the Commission shall promulgate by not later than 1 year after July 21, 2010, provided no rule or regulation promulgated by the Commission shall require any person to disclose to another person nonpublic information that may be material to the market price, rate, or level of the commodity transaction, except as necessary to make any statement made to the other person in or in connection with the transaction not misleading in any material respect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition regarding false information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Prohibition regarding false information It shall be unlawful for any person to make any false or misleading statement of a material fact to the Commission, including in any registration application or any report filed with the Commission under this chapter, or any other information relating to a swap, or a contract of sale of a commodity, in interstate commerce, or for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any registered entity, or to omit to state in any such statement any material fact that is necessary to make any statement of a material fact made not misleading in any material respect, if the person knew, or reasonably should have known, the statement to be false or misleading.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other manipulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Other manipulation In addition to the prohibition in paragraph (1), it shall be unlawful for any person, directly or indirectly, to manipulate or attempt to manipulate the price of any swap, or of any commodity in interstate commerce, or for future delivery on or subject to the rules of any registered entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Subpoena For the purpose of securing effective enforcement of the provisions of this chapter, for the purpose of any investigation or proceeding under this chapter, and for the purpose of any action taken under section 16(f) of this title, any member of the Commission or any Administrative Law Judge or other officer designated by the Commission (except as provided in paragraph (7)) may administer oaths and affirmations, subpoena witnesses, compel their attendance, take evidence, and require the production of any books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, or other records that the Commission deems relevant or material to the inquiry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Witnesses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Witnesses The attendance of witnesses and the production of any such records may be required from any place in the United States, any State, or any foreign country or jurisdiction at any designated place of hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Service A subpoena issued under this section 11 See References in Text note below. may be served upon any person who is not to be found within the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States in such manner as the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure prescribe for service of process in a foreign country, except that a subpoena to be served on a person who is not to be found within the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States may be issued only on the prior approval of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal to obey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Refusal to obey In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Commission may invoke the aid of any court of the United States within the jurisdiction in which the investigation or proceeding is conducted, or where such person resides or transacts business, in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of books, papers, correspondence, memoranda, and other records. Such court may issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Commission or member or Administrative Law Judge or other officer designated by the Commission, there to produce records, if so ordered, or to give testimony touching the matter under investigation or in question.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to obey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Failure to obey Any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by the court as a contempt thereof. All process in any such case may be served in the judicial district wherein such person is an inhabitant or transacts business or wherever such person may be found.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Evidence On the receipt of evidence under paragraph (4)(C)(iii), the Commission may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>