<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9014" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9014/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9014/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9014"><akn:num>9014</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9014. Payment acres(a) Determination of payment acres(1) General ruleFor the purpose of price loss coverage and agriculture risk coverage when county coverage has been selected under section 9015(b)(1) of this title, but subject to subsection (e), the payment acres for each covered commodity on a farm shall be equal to 85 percent of the base acres for the covered commodity on the farm.


(2) Effect of individual coverageIn the case of agriculture risk coverage when individual coverage has been selected under section 9015(b)(2) of this title, but subject to subsection (e), the payment acres for a farm shall be equal to 65 percent of the base acres for all of the covered commodities on the farm.



(b) Treatment of generic base acres(1) In generalIn the case of generic base acres, price loss coverage payments and agriculture risk coverage payments are made only with respect to generic base acres planted to a covered commodity for the crop year.


(2) AttributionWith respect to a farm containing generic base acres, for the purpose of applying paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), generic base acres on the farm are attributed to a covered commodity in the following manner:(A) If a single covered commodity is planted and the total acreage planted exceeds the generic base acres on the farm, the generic base acres are attributed to that covered commodity in an amount equal to the total number of generic base acres.

(B) If multiple covered commodities are planted and the total number of acres planted to all covered commodities on the farm exceeds the generic base acres on the farm, the generic base acres are attributed to each of the covered commodities on the farm on a pro rata basis to reflect the ratio of—(i) the acreage planted to a covered commodity on the farm; to

(ii) the total acreage planted to all covered commodities on the farm.


(C) If the total number of acres planted to all covered commodities on the farm does not exceed the generic base acres on the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of payment acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination of payment acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of generic base acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Treatment of generic base acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion The quantity of payment acres determined under subsection (a) may not include any crop subsequently planted during the same crop year on the same land for which the first crop is eligible for price loss coverage payments or agriculture risk coverage payments, unless the crop was approved for double cropping in the county, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of minimal payment acres</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of minimal payment acres</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of planting fruits and vegetables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of planting fruits and vegetables</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9014_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unassigned crop base</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unassigned crop base The Secretary shall maintain information on generic base acres on a farm allocated as unassigned crop base under subsection (b)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>