<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9071a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9071a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/9071a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9071a"><akn:num>9071a</akn:num><akn:heading>Dairy donation program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9071a. Dairy donation program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible dairy organizationThe term “eligible dairy organization” has the meaning given the term in section 9071(a) of this title.


(2) Eligible dairy productThe term “eligible dairy product” means a product primarily made from milk, including fluid milk, that is produced and processed in the United States.


(3) Eligible distributorThe term “eligible distributor” means a public or private nonprofit organization that distributes donated eligible dairy products to recipient individuals and families.


(4) Eligible partnershipThe term “eligible partnership” means a partnership between an eligible dairy organization and an eligible distributor.



(b) Establishment and purposesNot later than 60 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall establish and administer a dairy donation program for the purposes of—(1) facilitating the timely donation of eligible dairy products; and

(2) preventing and minimizing food waste.


(c) Donation and distribution plans(1) In generalTo be eligible to receive reimbursement under subsection (d), an eligible partnership shall submit to the Secretary a donation and distribution plan that describes the process that the eligible partnership will use for the donation, processing, transportation, temporary storage, and distribution of eligible dairy products.


(2) Review and approval(A) In generalNot later than 15 business days after receiving a plan described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—(i) review that plan; and

(ii) issue an approval or disapproval of that plan.


(B) Emergency and disaster-related prioritization(i) In generalIn receiving and reviewing a donation and distribution plan submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine whether an emergency or disaster was a substantial factor in the submission, including—(I) a declared or renewed public health emergency under section 247d of title 42; and

(II) a disaster designated by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment and purposes Not later than 60 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall establish and administer a dairy donation program for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donation and distribution plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Donation and distribution plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on resale of products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on resale of products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reviews The Secretary shall conduct appropriate reviews or audits to ensure the integrity of the program established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of donation activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Publication of donation activity The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, shall publish on the publicly accessible website of the Agricultural Marketing Service periodic reports describing donation activity under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental reimbursements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Supplemental reimbursements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9071a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding Out of any amounts of the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $400,000,000, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>