<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/913" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/913/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/913/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_913"><akn:num>913</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 913. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) FarmThe term “farm” means a farm, as defined by the Bureau of the Census.


(2) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.


(3) Rural areaExcept as provided otherwise in this chapter, the term “rural area” means the farm and nonfarm population of—(A) any area described in section 1991(a)(13)(C) of this title; and

(B) any area within a service area of a borrower for which a borrower has an outstanding loan made under subchapters I through V as of the date of enactment of this paragraph.


(4) TerritoryThe term “territory” includes any insular possession of the United States.


(5) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.


(May 20, 1936, ch. 432, title I, § 13, 49 Stat. 1367; Oct. 28, 1949, ch. 776, § 2, 63 Stat. 948; Pub. L. 103–129, § 2(c)(3), Nov. 1, 1993, 107 Stat. 1363; Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 235(a)(6), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3221; Pub. L. 110–234, title VI, § 6104, May 22, 2008, 122 Stat. 1195; Pub. L. 110–246, § 4(a), title VI, § 6104, June 18, 2008, 122 Stat. 1664, 1957.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date of enactment of this paragraph, referred to in par. (3)(B), is the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–246, which was approved June 18, 2008.

Codification
Pub. L. 110–234 and Pub. L. 110–246 made identical amendments to this section. The amendments by Pub. L. 110–234 were repealed by section 4(a) of Pub. L. 110–246.

Amendments2008—Pub. L. 110–246, § 6104, amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “As used in this chapter the term ‘rural area’, except as provided in section 924(b) of this title, shall be deemed to mean any area of the United States not included within the boundaries of any urban area, as defined by the Bureau of the Census, and such term shall be deemed to include both the farm and nonfarm population thereof; the term ‘farm’ shall be deemed to mean a farm as defined in the publicat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_913_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Farm The term “farm” means a farm, as defined by the Bureau of the Census.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_913_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 5304 of title 25.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_913_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Rural area Except as provided otherwise in this chapter, the term “rural area” means the farm and nonfarm population of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_913_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Territory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Territory The term “territory” includes any insular possession of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_913_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>