<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_936a"><akn:num>936a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prepayment of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 936a. Prepayment of loans(a) Conditions for prepaymentExcept as provided in subsection (c), a borrower of a loan made by the Federal Financing Bank and guaranteed under section 936 of this title may prepay such loan (or any loan advance thereunder) by paying the outstanding principal balance due on the loan (or advance), if—(1) the loan is outstanding on July 2, 1986;

(2) private capital, with the existing loan guarantee, is used to replace the loan; and

(3) the borrower certifies that any savings from such prepayment will be passed on to its customers or used to improve the financial strength of the borrower in cases of financial hardship.


(b) Charges on prepayment prohibitedNo sums in addition to the payment of the outstanding principal balance due on the loan may be charged as the result of such prepayment against the borrower, the fund, or the Secretary.


(c) Disqualification for prepayment on finding of adverse affect on Federal Financing Bank(1) A borrower will not qualify for prepayment under this section if, in the opinion of the Secretary of the Treasury, to prepay in such borrower’s case would adversely affect the operation of the Federal Financing Bank.

(2) Paragraph (1) shall be effective in fiscal year 1987 only for any loan the prepayment of the principal amount of which will cause the cumulative amount of net proceeds from all such prepayments made during such year to exceed $2,017,500,000.


(d) Amount of permissible prepayments; establishment of eligibility criteria(1) The Secretary shall permit, subject to subsection (a), prepayments of principal on loans in fiscal year 1987 under this section or Public Law 99–349 in such amounts as to realize net proceeds from all such prepayments in fiscal year 1987 in an amount not less than $2,017,500,000.

(2) The Secretary shall establish—(A) eligibility criteria to ensure that any loan prepayment activity required to be carried out under this subsection will be directed to those cooperative borrowers</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for prepayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions for prepayment Except as provided in subsection (c), a borrower of a loan made by the Federal Financing Bank and guaranteed under section 936 of this title may prepay such loan (or any loan advance thereunder) by paying the outstanding principal balance due on the loan (or advance), if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charges on prepayment prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Charges on prepayment prohibited No sums in addition to the payment of the outstanding principal balance due on the loan may be charged as the result of such prepayment against the borrower, the fund, or the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disqualification for prepayment on finding of adverse affect on Federal Financing Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disqualification for prepayment on finding of adverse affect on Federal Financing Bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of permissible prepayments; establishment of eligibility criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of permissible prepayments; establishment of eligibility criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignability and transferability of guarantees of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assignability and transferability of guarantees of loans Any guarantee of a loan prepaid under this section shall be fully assignable under the provisions of section 936 of this title and transferable. However, the Secretary may require that any such guarantee, if transfered 11 So in original. Probably should be “transferred”. or assigned, be transferred or assigned to a loan or security that, if sold, will be grouped with nonguaranteed loans or securities and sold in a manner to ensure that such sale will not unreasonably compete with the marketing of obligations of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>