<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_936b"><akn:num>936b</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale or prepayment of direct or insured loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 936b. Sale or prepayment of direct or insured loans(a) Discounted prepayment by borrowers of electric loans(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), a direct or insured loan made under this chapter shall not be sold or prepaid at a value that is less than the outstanding principal balance on the loan.


(2) ExceptionOn request of the borrower, an electric loan made under this chapter, or a portion of such a loan, that was advanced before May 1, 1992, or has been advanced for not less than 2 years, shall be sold to or prepaid by the borrower at the lesser of—(A) the outstanding principal balance on the loan; or

(B) the present value of the loan discounted from the face value at maturity at the rate established by the Secretary.


(3) Discount rateThe discount rate applicable to the prepayment under this subsection of a loan or loan advance shall be the then current cost of funds to the Department of the Treasury for obligations of comparable maturity to the remaining term of the loan.


(4) Tax exempt financingIf a borrower prepays a loan under this subsection using tax exempt financing, the discount shall be adjusted to ensure that the borrower receives a benefit that is equal to the benefit the borrower would receive if the borrower used fully taxable financing. The borrower shall certify in writing whether the financing will be tax exempt and shall comply with such other terms and conditions as the Secretary may establish that are reasonable and necessary to carry out this subsection.


(5) Eligibility(A) In generalA borrower that has prepaid an insured or direct loan shall remain eligible for assistance under this chapter in the same manner as other borrowers, except that—(i) a borrower that has prepaid a loan, either before or after October 21, 1992, at a discount rate as provided by paragraph (3), shall not be eligible, except at the discretion of the Secretary, to apply for or receive direct or insured loans under this chapter during the 120-month </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discounted prepayment by borrowers of electric loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Discounted prepayment by borrowers of electric loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mergers of electric borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mergers of electric borrowers Notwithstanding subsection (a), a direct or insured loan may be prepaid by an electric borrower at the lesser of the outstanding principal balance due thereon or the present value thereof discounted from the face value at maturity at the rate set by the Secretary if the borrower is an electrical organization which resulted from a merger or consolidation between a borrower and an organization which, prior to October 1, 1987, prepaid its direct or insured loans pursuant to this section. Prepayments by a borrower hereunder shall be made not later than one year after the effective date of the merger, consolidation, or other transaction. The discount rate to be set by the Secretary for direct or insured loans prepayments hereunder shall be based on the current cost of funds to the Department of the Treasury for obligations of comparable maturity to those being prepaid. If a borrower prepays using tax exempt financing, the discount shall be adjusted to make </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>