<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/936e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_936e"><akn:num>936e</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative prohibitions applicable to certain electric borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 936e. Administrative prohibitions applicable to certain electric borrowers(a) In generalFor the purpose of relieving borrowers of unnecessary and burdensome requirements, the Secretary, guided by the practices of private lenders with respect to similar credit risks, shall issue regulations, applicable to any electric borrower under this chapter whose net worth exceeds 110 percent of the outstanding principal balance on all loans made or guaranteed to the borrower by the Secretary, to minimize those approval rights, requirements, restrictions, and prohibitions that the Secretary otherwise may establish with respect to the operations of such a borrower.


(b) Subordination or sharing of liensAt the request of a private lender providing financing to such a borrower for a capital investment, the Secretary shall, expeditiously, either offer to share the government’s lien on the borrower’s system or offer to subordinate the government’s lien on that property financed by the private lender.


(c) Issuance of regulationsIn issuing regulations implementing this section, the Secretary may establish requirements, guided by the practices of private lenders, to ensure that the security for any loan made or guaranteed under this chapter is reasonably adequate.


(d) Authority of SecretaryNothing in this section limits the authority of the Secretary to establish terms and conditions with respect to the use by borrowers of the proceeds of loans made or guaranteed under this chapter or to take any other action specifically authorized by law.


(May 20, 1936, ch. 432, title III, § 306E, as added Pub. L. 103–129, § 2(c)(7), Nov. 1, 1993, 107 Stat. 1365; amended Pub. L. 103–201, § 1, Dec. 17, 1993, 107 Stat. 2342; Pub. L. 103–354, title II, § 235(a)(8), (13), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3221.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–354 substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator” in heading of subsec. (d) and wherever appearing in text.
1993—Pub. L. 103–201 inserted “certain” before</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the purpose of relieving borrowers of unnecessary and burdensome requirements, the Secretary, guided by the practices of private lenders with respect to similar credit risks, shall issue regulations, applicable to any electric borrower under this chapter whose net worth exceeds 110 percent of the outstanding principal balance on all loans made or guaranteed to the borrower by the Secretary, to minimize those approval rights, requirements, restrictions, and prohibitions that the Secretary otherwise may establish with respect to the operations of such a borrower.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subordination or sharing of liens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subordination or sharing of liens At the request of a private lender providing financing to such a borrower for a capital investment, the Secretary shall, expeditiously, either offer to share the government’s lien on the borrower’s system or offer to subordinate the government’s lien on that property financed by the private lender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of regulations In issuing regulations implementing this section, the Secretary may establish requirements, guided by the practices of private lenders, to ensure that the security for any loan made or guaranteed under this chapter is reasonably adequate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority of Secretary Nothing in this section limits the authority of the Secretary to establish terms and conditions with respect to the use by borrowers of the proceeds of loans made or guaranteed under this chapter or to take any other action specifically authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>