<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/940c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/940c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/940c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_940c"><akn:num>940c</akn:num><akn:heading>Cushion of credit payments program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 940c. Cushion of credit payments program(a) Establishment(1) In general(A) Development and promotion of programThe Secretary shall develop and promote a program to encourage borrowers to voluntarily make deposits into cushion of credit accounts established within the Rural Electrification and Telephone Revolving Fund.


(B) TerminationEffective on December 20, 2018, no deposits may be made under subparagraph (A).



(2) Interest(A) In generalAmounts in each cushion of credit account shall accrue interest to the borrower at a rate of 5 percent per annum.


(B) ReductionNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), amounts in each cushion of credit account shall accrue interest to the borrower at a rate equal to—(i) 4 percent per annum in fiscal year 2021; and

(ii) the then applicable 1-year Treasury rate thereafter.



(3) Balance(A) In generalA borrower may reduce the balance of its cushion of credit account only if the amount obtained from the reduction is used to make scheduled payments on loans made or guaranteed under this chapter.


(B) PrepaymentNotwithstanding subparagraph (A) and subject to subparagraph (C), beginning on December 20, 2018, and ending with September 30, 2020, a borrower may, at the sole discretion of the borrower, reduce the balance of its cushion of credit account if the amount obtained from the reduction is used to prepay loans made or guaranteed under this chapter.


(C) No prepayment premiumNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, no prepayment premium shall be imposed or collected with respect to that portion of a loan that is prepaid by a borrower in accordance with subparagraph (B).


(D) Mandatory fundingNotwithstanding section 661c of title 2, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall make available such sums as necessary to cover any loan modification costs as defined in section 661a of title 2.




(b) Uses of cushion of credit payments(1) In general(A) Cash balanceCushion o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_940c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_940c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of cushion of credit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses of cushion of credit payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>