<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/950bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/950bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/7/950bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_950bb"><akn:num>950bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to broadband telecommunications services in rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 950bb. Access to broadband telecommunications services in rural areas(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide grants, provide loans, and provide loan guarantees to provide funds for the costs of the construction, improvement, and acquisition of facilities and equipment for broadband service in rural areas.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Broadband serviceThe term “broadband service” means any technology identified by the Secretary as having the capacity to transmit data to enable a subscriber to the service to originate and receive high-quality voice, data, graphics, and video.


(2) Incumbent service providerThe term “incumbent service provider”, with respect to an application submitted under this section, means an entity that, as of the date of submission of the application, is providing broadband service to not less than 5 percent of the households in the service territory proposed in the application.


(3) Rural area(A) In generalThe term “rural area” means any area other than—(i) an area described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 1991(a)(13)(A) of this title; and

(ii) in the case of a grant or direct loan, a city, town, or incorporated area that has a population of greater than 20,000 inhabitants.


(B) Urban area growthThe Secretary may, by regulation only, consider an area described in section 1991(a)(13)(F)(i)(I) of this title to not be a rural area for purposes of this section.


(C) Exclusion of certain populationsSuch term does not include any population described in subparagraph (H) or (I) of section 1991(a)(13) of this title.




(c) Grants, loans, and loan guarantees(1) In generalThe Secretary shall make grants, shall make loans, and shall guarantee loans to eligible entities described in subsection (d) to provide funds for the construction, improvement, or acquisition of facilities and equipment for the provision of broadband service in rural areas.


(2) Priority(A) In generalIn making grants, making loans, and guaranteeing loans </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide grants, provide loans, and provide loan guarantees to provide funds for the costs of the construction, improvement, and acquisition of facilities and equipment for broadband service in rural areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants, loans, and loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants, loans, and loan guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadband service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Broadband service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technological neutrality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technological neutrality For purposes of determining whether to provide assistance for a project under this section, the Secretary shall use criteria that are technologically neutral.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions for loans and loan guarantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Terms and conditions for loans and loan guarantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adequacy of security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Adequacy of security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment assistance for certain loan and grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Payment assistance for certain loan and grant recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950bb_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>