<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1162" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1162/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1162/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1162"><akn:num>1162</akn:num><akn:heading>Clothing allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1162. Clothing allowance(a) Eligibility Requirements.—The Secretary, under regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, shall pay a clothing allowance of $716 11 See Special Benefit Allowance Rates note below. per year to each veteran who—(1) because of a service-connected disability, wears or uses a prosthetic or orthopedic appliance (including a wheelchair) which the Secretary determines tends to wear out or tear the clothing of the veteran; or

(2) uses medication which—(A) a physician has prescribed for a skin condition which is due to a service-connected disability; and

(B) the Secretary determines causes irreparable damage to the veteran’s outergarments.



(b) Continuous Nature of Payments.—Payments made to a veteran under subsection (a) shall continue on an automatically recurring annual basis until the earlier of the following:(1) The date on which the veteran elects to no longer receive such payments.

(2) The date on which the Secretary determines the veteran is no longer eligible pursuant to subsection (c).


(c) Reviews of Claims.—(1) The Secretary shall, in accordance with this subsection, conduct reviews of a claim on which a clothing allowance for a veteran under subsection (a) is based to determine the continued eligibility of the veteran for such allowance.

(2) The Secretary shall prescribe standards for determining whether a claim for a clothing allowance is based on a veteran’s wearing or use of a prosthetic, orthopedic appliance (including a wheelchair), or medication whose wear or tear or irreparable damage on a veteran’s outergarments or clothing is as likely as not subject to no change for the duration of such wearing or use.

(3)(A) If the Secretary determines, pursuant to standards prescribed under paragraph (2), that a claim for a clothing allowance is based on wear or tear or irreparable damage that is as likely as not subject to no change, the veteran shall continue to be deemed eligible for receipt of a clothing allowance under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary, under regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, shall pay a clothing allowance of $716 11 See Special Benefit Allowance Rates note below. per year to each veteran who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuous Nature of Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments made to a veteran under subsection (a) shall continue on an automatically recurring annual basis until the earlier of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews of Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1162_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination Regarding Continued Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If the Secretary determines, as the result of a review of a claim conducted under subsection (c), that the veteran who submitted such claim no longer meets the requirements specified in subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>