<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/118" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/118/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/118/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_118"><akn:num>118</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of reports to Congress in electronic form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 118. Submission of reports to Congress in electronic form(a) In General.—Whenever the Secretary or any other official of the Department is required by law to submit to Congress (or any committee of either chamber of Congress) a report, the Secretary or other official shall submit to Congress (or such committee) a copy of the report in an electronic format.

(b) Treatment.—The submission of a copy of a report in accordance with this section shall be treated as meeting any requirement of law to submit such report to Congress (or any committee of either chamber of Congress).

(c) Report Defined.—For purposes of this section, the term “report” includes any certification, notification, or other communication in writing.

(Added Pub. L. 111–163, title X, § 1003(a), May 5, 2010, 124 Stat. 1182.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whenever the Secretary or any other official of the Department is required by law to submit to Congress (or any committee of either chamber of Congress) a report, the Secretary or other official shall submit to Congress (or such committee) a copy of the report in an electronic format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The submission of a copy of a report in accordance with this section shall be treated as meeting any requirement of law to submit such report to Congress (or any committee of either chamber of Congress).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, the term “report” includes any certification, notification, or other communication in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>