<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1315"><akn:num>1315</akn:num><akn:heading>Dependency and indemnity compensation to parents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1315. Dependency and indemnity compensation to parents(a)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), dependency and indemnity compensation shall be paid monthly to parents of a deceased veteran in the amounts prescribed by this section.

(2) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, benefits under this section may be paid less frequently than monthly if the amount of the annual benefit is less than 4 percent of the maximum annual rate payable under this section.


(b)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (4) of this subsection, if there is only one parent, the monthly rate of dependency and indemnity compensation paid to such parent shall be $569, as increased from time to time under section 5312(b)(1) of this title and reduced by an amount, based upon the amount of such parent’s annual income, determined in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe under section 5312(b)(2) of this title.

(2) In no case may the amount of dependency and indemnity compensation payable to any parent under this subsection be less than $5 monthly.

(3) In no case may dependency and indemnity compensation be paid under paragraph (1) of this subsection to any parent if the annual income of such parent exceeds $13,456, as increased from time to time under section 5312 of this title.

(4) If there is only one parent and such parent has remarried and is living with such parent’s spouse, dependency and indemnity compensation shall be paid to such parent under either paragraph (1) of this subsection or under subsection (d) of this section, whichever will result in the greater amount of such compensation being paid to such parent. In such a case of remarriage the total combined annual income of the parent and such parent’s spouse shall be counted in determining the monthly rate of dependency and indemnity compensation under the appropriate formula.


(c)(1) Except as provided in subsection (d) of this section, if there are two parents, but they are not living together, t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may require as a condition of granting or continuing dependency and indemnity compensation to a parent that such parent, other than one who has attained seventy-two years of age and has been paid dependency and indemnity compensation during two consecutive calendar years, file for a calendar year with the Secretary (on the form prescribed by the Secretary) a report showing the total income which such parent expects to receive in that year and the total income which such parent received in the preceding year. The parent or parents shall notify the Secretary whenever there is a material change in annual income.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The monthly rate of dependency and indemnity compensation payable to a parent shall be increased by $308, as increased from time to time under section 5312 of this title, if such parent is (1) a patient in a nursing home or (2) blind, or so nearly blind or significantly disabled as to need or require the regular aid and attendance of another person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>