<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1703A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1703A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1703A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1703A"><akn:num>1703A</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with eligible entities or providers; certification processes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1703A. Agreements with eligible entities or providers; certification processes(a) Agreements Authorized.—(1)(A) When hospital care, a medical service, or an extended care service required by a covered individual who is entitled to such care or service under this chapter is not feasibly available to the covered individual from a facility of the Department or through a contract or sharing agreement entered into pursuant to another provision of law, the Secretary may furnish such care or service to such covered individual through an agreement under this section with an eligible entity or provider to provide such hospital care, medical service, or extended care service.

(B) An agreement entered into under this section to provide hospital care, a medical service, or an extended care service shall be known as a “Veterans Care Agreement”.

(C) For purposes of subparagraph (A), hospital care, a medical service, or an extended care service may be considered not feasibly available to a covered individual from a facility of the Department or through a contract or sharing agreement described in such subparagraph when the Secretary determines the covered individual’s medical condition, the travel involved, the nature of the care or services required, or a combination of these factors make the use of a facility of the Department or a contract or sharing agreement described in such subparagraph impracticable or inadvisable.

(D) A Veterans Care Agreement may be entered into by the Secretary or any Department official authorized by the Secretary.


(2)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall review each Veterans Care Agreement of material size, as determined by the Secretary or set forth in paragraph (3), for hospital care, a medical service, or an extended care service to determine whether it is feasible and advisable to provide such care or service within a facility of the Department or by contract or sharing agreement entered into pursuant to another provision of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities and Providers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this section, an eligible entity or provider is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entity or Provider Certification Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall establish by regulation a process for the certification of eligible entities or providers or recertification of eligible entities or providers under this section. Such a process shall, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To the extent practicable, the rates paid by the Secretary for hospital care, medical services, and extended care services provided under a Veterans Care Agreement shall be in accordance with the rates paid by the United States under section 1703(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of Veterans Care Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discontinuation or Nonrenewal of a Veterans Care Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality of Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall establish a system or systems for monitoring the quality of care provided to covered individuals through Veterans Care Agreements and for assessing the quality of hospital care, medical services, and extended care services furnished by eligible entities and providers before the renewal of Veterans Care Agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disputes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Other Provisions of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1703A_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parity of Treatment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Eligibility for hospital care, medical services, and extended care services furnished to any covered individual pursuant to a Veterans Care Agreement shall be subject to the same terms as though provided in a facility of the Department, and provisions of this chapter applicable to covered individuals receiving such care and services in a facility of the Department shall apply to covered individuals treated under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>