<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1704A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1704A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1704A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1704A"><akn:num>1704A</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent assessments of health care delivery systems and management processes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1704A. Independent assessments of health care delivery systems and management processes(a) Independent Assessments.—(1) Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary shall enter into one or more contracts with a private sector entity or entities described in subsection (d) to conduct an independent assessment of the hospital care, medical services, and other health care furnished by the Department.

(2) Each assessment required under paragraph (1) shall address each of the following:(A) Current and projected demographics and unique health care needs of the patient population served by the Department.

(B) The accuracy of models and forecasting methods used by the Department to project health care demand, including with respect to veteran demographics, rates of use of health care furnished by the Department, the inflation of health care costs, and such other factors as may be determined relevant by the Secretary.

(C) The reliability and accuracy of models and forecasting methods used by the Department to project the budgetary needs of the Veterans Health Administration and how such models and forecasting methods inform budgetary trends.

(D) The authorities and mechanisms under which the Secretary may furnish hospital care, medical services, and other health care at facilities of the Department and non-Department facilities, including through Federal and private sector partners and at joint medical facilities, and the effect of such authorities and mechanisms on eligibility and access to care.

(E) The organization, workflow processes, and tools used by the Department to support clinical staffing, access to care, effective length-of-stay management and care transitions, positive patient experience, accurate documentation, and subsequent coding of inpatient services.

(F) The efforts of the Department to recruit and retain staff at levels necessary to carry out the functions of the Veterans Health Administration and the process used by the Department </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The private sector entity or entities carrying out an assessment pursuant to subsection (a) shall complete such assessment not later than 18 months after entering into the contract described in such paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leveraging of Existing Data and Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To the extent practicable, the private sector entity or entities carrying out an assessment pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private Sector Entities Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A private sector entity described in this subsection is a private entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Integrator.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1704A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The requirement to enter into contracts under subsection (a) shall terminate on December 31, 2055.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>