<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1709" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1709/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1709/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1709"><akn:num>1709</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive policy on reporting and tracking sexual assault incidents and other safety incidents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1709. Comprehensive policy on reporting and tracking sexual assault incidents and other safety incidents(a) Policy Required.—(1) Not later than September 30, 2012, the Secretary shall develop and implement a centralized and comprehensive policy on the reporting and tracking of sexual assault incidents and other safety incidents that occur at each medical facility of the Department, including—(A) suspected, alleged, attempted, or confirmed cases of sexual assault, regardless of whether such assaults lead to prosecution or conviction;

(B) criminal and purposefully unsafe acts;

(C) alcohol or substance abuse related acts (including by employees of the Department); and

(D) any kind of event involving alleged or suspected abuse of a patient.


(2) In developing and implementing a policy under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the effects of such policy on—(A) the use by veterans of mental health care and substance abuse treatments; and

(B) the ability of the Department to refer veterans to such care or treatment.



(b) Scope.—The policy required by subsection (a) shall cover each of the following:(1) For purposes of reporting and tracking sexual assault incidents and other safety incidents, definitions of the terms—(A) “safety incident”;

(B) “sexual assault”; and

(C) “sexual assault incident”.


(2)(A) The development and use of specific risk-assessment tools to examine any risks related to sexual assault that a veteran may pose while being treated at a medical facility of the Department, including clear and consistent guidance on the collection of information related to—(i) the legal history of the veteran; and

(ii) the medical record of the veteran.


(B) In developing and using tools under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider the effects of using such tools on the use by veterans of health care furnished by the Department.


(3) The mandatory training of employees of the Department on security issues, including awareness, preparedness, pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The policy required by subsection (a) shall cover each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates to Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall review and revise the policy required by subsection (a) on a periodic basis as the Secretary considers appropriate and in accordance with best practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1709_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>