<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1712C" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1712C/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1712C/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1712C"><akn:num>1712C</akn:num><akn:heading>Dental insurance plan for veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1712C. Dental insurance plan for veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans(a) In General.—The Secretary shall establish and administer a dental insurance plan for veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans described in subsection (b).

(b) Covered Veterans and Survivors and Dependents.—The veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans described in this subsection are as follows:(1) Any veteran who is enrolled in the system of annual patient enrollment under section 1705 of this title.

(2) Any survivor or dependent of a veteran who is eligible for medical care under section 1781 of this title.


(c) Administration.—The Secretary shall contract with a dental insurer to administer the dental insurance plan under this section.

(d) Benefits.—The dental insurance plan under this section shall provide such benefits for dental care and treatment as the Secretary considers appropriate for the dental insurance plan, including diagnostic services, preventative services, endodontics and other restorative services, surgical services, and emergency services.

(e) Enrollment.—(1) Enrollment in the dental insurance plan under this section shall be voluntary.

(2) Enrollment in the dental insurance plan shall be for such minimum period as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of this section.


(f) Premiums.—(1) Premiums for coverage under the dental insurance plan under this section shall be in such amount or amounts as the Secretary shall prescribe to cover all costs associated with carrying out this section.

(2) The Secretary shall adjust the premiums payable under this section for coverage under the dental insurance plan on an annual basis. Each individual covered by the dental insurance plan at the time of such an adjustment shall be notified of the amount and effective date of such adjustment.

(3) Each individual covered by the dental insurance plan shall pay the entire premium for coverage under the dental insurance plan, in addition to the full </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish and administer a dental insurance plan for veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Veterans and Survivors and Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The veterans and survivors and dependents of veterans described in this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall contract with a dental insurer to administer the dental insurance plan under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The dental insurance plan under this section shall provide such benefits for dental care and treatment as the Secretary considers appropriate for the dental insurance plan, including diagnostic services, preventative services, endodontics and other restorative services, surgical services, and emergency services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary Disenrollment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Dental Care Provided by Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nothing in this section shall affect the responsibility of the Secretary to provide dental care under section 1712 of this title, and the participation of an individual in the dental insurance plan under this section shall not affect the entitlement of the individual to outpatient dental services and treatment, and related dental appliances, under such section 1712.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712C_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The dental insurance plan under this section shall be administered under such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>