<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1715" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1715/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1715/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1715"><akn:num>1715</akn:num><akn:heading>Tobacco for hospitalized veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1715. Tobacco for hospitalized veterans
The Secretary may furnish tobacco to veterans receiving hospital or domiciliary care.
(Pub. L. 85–857, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1143, § 615; renumbered § 1715 and amended Pub. L. 102–83, §§ 4(b)(1), (2)(E), 5(a), Aug. 6, 1991, 105 Stat. 404–406.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1991—Pub. L. 102–83, § 5(a), renumbered section 615 of this title as this section.
Pub. L. 102–83, § 4(b)(1), (2)(E), substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Use of Tobacco Products in Department of Veterans Affairs FacilitiesPub. L. 102–585, title V, § 526, Nov. 4, 1992, 106 Stat. 4961, provided that:
“(a) In General.—The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall take appropriate actions to ensure that, consistent with medical requirements and limitations, each facility of the Department described in subsection (b)—“(1) establishes and maintains—“(A) a suitable indoor area in which patients or residents may smoke and which is ventilated in a manner that, to the maximum extent feasible, prevents smoke from entering other areas of the facility; or

“(B) an area in a building that—“(i) is detached from the facility;

“(ii) is accessible to patients or residents of the facility; and

“(iii) has appropriate heating and air conditioning; and



“(2) provides access to an area established and maintained under paragraph (1), consistent with medical requirements and limitations, for patients or residents of the facility who are receiving care or services and who desire to smoke tobacco products.


“(b) Covered Facilities.—A Department facility referred to in subsection (a) is any Department of Veterans Affairs medical center, nursing home, or domiciliary care facility.

“(c) Reports.—(1) Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 4, 1992], the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the feasibility of the est</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>