<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720L" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720L/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720L/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1720L"><akn:num>1720L</akn:num><akn:heading>Home- and community-based services: programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1720L. Home- and community-based services: programs(a) In General.—In furnishing noninstitutional alternatives to nursing home care pursuant to the authority of section 1720C of this title (or any other authority under this chapter or other provision of law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs), the Secretary shall carry out each of the programs specified in this section in accordance with such relevant authorities except as otherwise provided in this section.

(b) Veteran-Directed Care Program.—(1) The Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in collaboration with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall carry out a program to be known as the “Veteran-Directed Care program”. Under such program, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may enter into agreements with the providers described in paragraph (2) to provide to eligible veterans funds, to the extent practicable, to obtain such in-home care services and related items that support clinical need and improve quality of life, as may be determined appropriate by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and selected by the veteran, including through the veteran hiring individuals to provide such services and items or directly purchasing such services and items.

(2) The providers described in this paragraph are the following:(A) An Aging and Disability Resource Center, an area agency on aging, or a State agency.

(B) A center for independent living.

(C) An Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving assistance under title VI of the Older Americans Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 3057 et seq.).

(D) Any other entity that the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, determines appropriate.


(3) In carrying out the Veteran-Directed Care program, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—(A) administer such program through each medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs;

(B) seek to ensure the availability of such program in American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In furnishing noninstitutional alternatives to nursing home care pursuant to the authority of section 1720C of this title (or any other authority under this chapter or other provision of law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs), the Secretary shall carry out each of the programs specified in this section in accordance with such relevant authorities except as otherwise provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veteran-Directed Care Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homemaker and Home Health Aide Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Home-Based Primary Care Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall carry out a program to be known as the “Home-Based Primary Care program” under which the Secretary may furnish to eligible veterans in-home health care, the provision of which is overseen by a provider of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchased Skilled Home Care Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall carry out a program to be known as the “Purchased Skilled Home Care program” under which the Secretary may furnish to eligible veterans such in-home care services as may be determined appropriate and selected by the Secretary for the veteran.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Caregiver Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary to carry out programs providing home- and community-based services under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720L_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>