<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1720A"><akn:num>1720A</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment and rehabilitative services for persons with drug or alcohol dependency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1720A. Treatment and rehabilitative services for persons with drug or alcohol dependency(a) The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, may take appropriate steps to (1) urge all Federal agencies and appropriate private and public firms, organizations, agencies, and persons to provide appropriate employment and training opportunities for veterans who have been provided treatment and rehabilitative services under this title for alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disabilities and have been determined by competent medical authority to be sufficiently rehabilitated to be employable, and (2) provide all possible assistance to the Secretary of Labor in placing such veterans in such opportunities.

(b) Upon receipt of an application for treatment and rehabilitative services under this title for an alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disability from any individual who has been discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service but who is not eligible for such treatment and services, the Secretary shall—(1) provide referral services to assist such individual, to the maximum extent practicable, in obtaining treatment and rehabilitative services from sources outside the Department; and

(2) if pertinent, advise such individual of such individual’s rights to apply to the appropriate military, naval, air, or space service and the Department for review of such individual’s discharge or release from such service.


(c)(1) Any person serving in the active military, naval, air, or space service who is determined by the Secretary concerned to have an alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disability may be transferred to any facility in order for the Secretary to furnish care or treatment and rehabilitative services for such disability. Care and services provided to a member so transferred shall be provided as if such member were a veteran. Any transfer of any such member for such care and s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management, may take appropriate steps to (1) urge all Federal agencies and appropriate private and public firms, organizations, agencies, and persons to provide appropriate employment and training opportunities for veterans who have been provided treatment and rehabilitative services under this title for alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disabilities and have been determined by competent medical authority to be sufficiently rehabilitated to be employable, and (2) provide all possible assistance to the Secretary of Labor in placing such veterans in such opportunities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Upon receipt of an application for treatment and rehabilitative services under this title for an alcohol or drug dependence or abuse disability from any individual who has been discharged or released from active military, naval, air, or space service but who is not eligible for such treatment and services, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>