<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720J" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720J/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720J/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1720J"><akn:num>1720J</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergent suicide care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1720J. Emergent suicide care(a) Emergent Suicide Care.—Pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall—(1) furnish emergent suicide care to an eligible individual at a medical facility of the Department;

(2) pay for emergent suicide care provided to an eligible individual at a non-Department facility; and

(3) reimburse an eligible individual for emergent suicide care provided to the eligible individual at a non-Department facility.


(b) Eligibility.—An individual is eligible for emergent suicide care under subsection (a) if the individual is in an acute suicidal crisis and is either of the following:(1) A veteran (as defined in section 101).

(2) An individual described in section 1720I(b) of this title.


(c) Period of Care.—(1) Emergent suicide care provided under subsection (a) shall be furnished to an eligible individual—(A) through inpatient or crisis residential care, for a period not to exceed 30 days; or

(B) if care under subparagraph (A) is unavailable, or if such care is not clinically appropriate, as outpatient care for a period not to exceed 90 days.


(2) If, upon the expiration of a period under paragraph (1), the Secretary determines that the eligible individual remains in an acute suicidal crisis, the Secretary may extend such period as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(d) Notification.—An eligible individual who receives emergent suicide care under subsection (a) at a non-Department facility (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) shall notify the Secretary of such care within seven days of admission to such facility.

(e) Outreach.—During any period when an eligible individual is receiving emergent suicide care under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—(1) ensure that—(A) in the case of an eligible individual whom the Veterans Crisis Line recommends to seek emergent suicide care at a medical facility of the Department, the Veterans Crisis Line notifies the Suicide Prevention Coordinator of such medical facility;

(B) in the case</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergent Suicide Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual is eligible for emergent suicide care under subsection (a) if the individual is in an acute suicidal crisis and is either of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An eligible individual who receives emergent suicide care under subsection (a) at a non-Department facility (or a person acting on behalf of the individual) shall notify the Secretary of such care within seven days of admission to such facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) During any period when an eligible individual is receiving emergent suicide care under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Charge.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not less than once each year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on emergent suicide care provided under subsection (a). Each such report shall include, for the year covered by the report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720J_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>