<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720K" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720K/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720K/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1720K"><akn:num>1720K</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants or contracts to provide mental health support to family caregivers of veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1720K. Grants or contracts to provide mental health support to family caregivers of veterans(a) Authority.—The Secretary may award grants or contracts to carry out, coordinate, improve, or otherwise enhance mental health counseling, treatment, or support to the family caregivers of veterans participating in the family caregiver program.

(b) Application.—(1) To be eligible for a grant or contract under this section, an entity shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.

(2) Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) A detailed plan for the use of the grant or contract.

(B) A description of the programs or efforts through which the entity will meet the outcome measures developed by the Secretary under subsection (f).

(C) A description of how the entity will distribute grant or contract amounts equitably among areas with varying levels of urbanization.

(D) A plan for how the grant or contract will be used to meet the unique needs of veterans residing in rural areas, Native American, Native Hawaiian, or Alaska Native veterans, elderly veterans, women veterans, and veterans from other underserved communities.



(c) Distribution.—The Secretary shall seek to ensure that grants and contracts awarded under this section are equitably distributed among entities located in States with varying levels of urbanization.

(d) Priority.—The Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants or contracts under this section that will serve the following areas:(1) Areas with high rates of veterans enrolled in the family caregiver program.

(2) Areas with high rates of—(A) suicide among veterans; or

(B) referrals to the Veterans Crisis Line.



(e) Required Activities.—Any grant or contract awarded under this section shall be used—(1) to expand existing programs, activities, and services;

(2) to establish new or additional programs, activities, and se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may award grants or contracts to carry out, coordinate, improve, or otherwise enhance mental health counseling, treatment, or support to the family caregivers of veterans participating in the family caregiver program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall seek to ensure that grants and contracts awarded under this section are equitably distributed among entities located in States with varying levels of urbanization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants or contracts under this section that will serve the following areas:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any grant or contract awarded under this section shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outcome Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tracking Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remediation Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720K_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The amount of a grant or contract awarded under this section may not exceed 10 percent of amounts made available for grants or contracts under this section for the fiscal year in which the grant or contract is awarded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>