<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720F" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720F/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1720F/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1720F"><akn:num>1720F</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive program for suicide prevention among veterans and members of the reserve components of</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1720F. Comprehensive program for suicide prevention among veterans and members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces(a) Establishment.—The Secretary shall develop and carry out a comprehensive program designed to reduce the incidence of suicide among covered individuals incorporating the components described in this section.

(b) Staff Education.—In carrying out the comprehensive program under this section, the Secretary shall provide for mandatory training for appropriate staff and contractors (including all medical personnel) of the Department who interact with covered individuals. This training shall cover information appropriate to the duties being performed by such staff and contractors. The training shall include information on—(1) recognizing risk factors for suicide;

(2) proper protocols for responding to crisis situations involving covered individuals who may be at high risk for suicide; and

(3) best practices for suicide prevention.


(c) Health Assessments.—In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall direct that medical staff offer mental health in their overall health assessment when covered individuals seek medical care at a Department medical facility (including a center established under section 1712A of this title) and make referrals, at the request of the individual concerned, to appropriate counseling and treatment programs for covered individuals who show signs or symptoms of mental health problems.

(d) Designation of Suicide Prevention Counselors.—In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall designate a suicide prevention counselor at each Department medical facility other than centers established under section 1712A of this title. Each counselor shall work with local emergency rooms, police departments, mental health organizations, and veterans service organizations to engage in outreach to covered individuals and improve the coordination of mental health care to covered individuals.

(e) Best Pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall develop and carry out a comprehensive program designed to reduce the incidence of suicide among covered individuals incorporating the components described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff Education.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out the comprehensive program under this section, the Secretary shall provide for mandatory training for appropriate staff and contractors (including all medical personnel) of the Department who interact with covered individuals. This training shall cover information appropriate to the duties being performed by such staff and contractors. The training shall include information on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall direct that medical staff offer mental health in their overall health assessment when covered individuals seek medical care at a Department medical facility (including a center established under section 1712A of this title) and make referrals, at the request of the individual concerned, to appropriate counseling and treatment programs for covered individuals who show signs or symptoms of mental health problems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Suicide Prevention Counselors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall designate a suicide prevention counselor at each Department medical facility other than centers established under section 1712A of this title. Each counselor shall work with local emergency rooms, police departments, mental health organizations, and veterans service organizations to engage in outreach to covered individuals and improve the coordination of mental health care to covered individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best Practices Research.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall provide for research on best practices for suicide prevention among covered individuals. Research shall be conducted under this subsection in consultation with the heads of the following entities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual Trauma Research.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall provide for research on mental health care for covered individuals who have experienced sexual trauma while in military service. The research design shall include consideration of veterans or members of a reserve component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>24-Hour Mental Health Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) 24- In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall provide for mental health care availability to covered individuals on a 24-hour basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hotline.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary may provide for a toll-free hotline for covered individuals to be staffed by appropriately trained mental health personnel and available at all times.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach and Education.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In carrying out the comprehensive program, the Secretary shall provide for outreach to and education for covered individuals and the families of covered individuals, with special emphasis on providing information to veterans of Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom and the families of such veterans. Education to promote mental health shall include information designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1720F_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer Support Counseling Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>