<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1725A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1725A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1725A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1725A"><akn:num>1725A</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to walk-in care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1725A. Access to walk-in care(a) Procedures To Ensure Access to Walk-In Care.—The Secretary shall develop procedures to ensure that eligible veterans are able to access walk-in care from qualifying non-Department entities or providers.

(b) Eligible Veterans.—For purposes of this section, an eligible veteran is any individual who—(1) is enrolled in the health care system established under section 1705(a) of this title; and

(2) has received care under this chapter within the 24-month period preceding the furnishing of walk-in care under this section.


(c) Qualifying Non-Department Entities or Providers.—For purposes of this section, a qualifying non-Department entity or provider is a non-Department entity or provider that has entered into a contract, agreement, or other arrangement with the Secretary to furnish services under this section.

(d) Federally-Qualified Health Centers.—Whenever practicable, the Secretary may use a Federally-qualified health center (as defined in section 1905(l)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396d(l)(2)(B))) to carry out this section.

(e) Continuity of Care.—The Secretary shall ensure continuity of care for those eligible veterans who receive walk-in care services under this section, including through the establishment of a mechanism to receive medical records from walk-in care providers and provide pertinent patient medical records to providers of walk-in care.

(f) Copayments.—(1)(A) The Secretary may require an eligible veteran to pay the United States a copayment for each episode of hospital care or medical services provided under this section if the eligible veteran would be required to pay a copayment under this title.

(B) An eligible veteran not required to pay a copayment under this title may access walk-in care without a copayment for the first two visits in a calendar year. For any additional visits, a copayment at an amount determined by the Secretary may be required.

(C) An eligible veteran required to pay a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures To Ensure Access to Walk-In Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall develop procedures to ensure that eligible veterans are able to access walk-in care from qualifying non-Department entities or providers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Veterans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this section, an eligible veteran is any individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying Non-Department Entities or Providers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, a qualifying non-Department entity or provider is a non-Department entity or provider that has entered into a contract, agreement, or other arrangement with the Secretary to furnish services under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally-Qualified Health Centers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Whenever practicable, the Secretary may use a Federally-qualified health center (as defined in section 1905(l)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396d(l)(2)(B))) to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuity of Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall ensure continuity of care for those eligible veterans who receive walk-in care services under this section, including through the establishment of a mechanism to receive medical records from walk-in care providers and provide pertinent patient medical records to providers of walk-in care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copayments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the Caring for Our Veterans Act of 2018, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1725A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Walk-In Care Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “walk-in care” means non-emergent care provided by a qualifying non-Department entity or provider that furnishes episodic care and not longitudinal management of conditions and is otherwise defined through regulations the Secretary shall promulgate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>