<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1729B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1729B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1729B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1729B"><akn:num>1729B</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated patient accounting centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1729B. Consolidated patient accounting centers(a) In General.—Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish not more than seven consolidated patient accounting centers for conducting industry-modeled regionalized billing and collection activities of the Department.

(b) Functions.—The centers shall carry out the following functions:(1) Reengineer and integrate all business processes of the revenue cycle of the Department.

(2) Standardize and coordinate all activities of the Department related to the revenue cycle for all health care services furnished to veterans for non-service-connected medical conditions.

(3) Apply commercial industry standards for measures of access, timeliness, and performance metrics with respect to revenue enhancement of the Department.

(4) Apply other requirements with respect to such revenue cycle improvement as the Secretary may specify.


(Added Pub. L. 110–387, title IV, § 406(a), Oct. 10, 2008, 122 Stat. 4129.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date of the enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (a), is the date of enactment of Pub. L. 110–387, which was approved Oct. 10, 2008.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1729B, added Pub. L. 106–117, title II, § 202(a), Nov. 30, 1999, 113 Stat. 1561; amended Pub. L. 107–103, title V, § 509(c), Dec. 27, 2001, 115 Stat. 997; Pub. L. 107–330, title III, § 308(g)(7), Dec. 6, 2002, 116 Stat. 2829, related to the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Services Improvement Fund, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 108–7, div. K, title I, § 113(a)(1), Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 482.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Transfer of BalancePub. L. 108–7, div. K, title I, § 113(a)(1), Feb. 20, 2003, 117 Stat. 482, repealed former section 1729B of this title and provided that any balance as of Feb. 20, 2003, in the Department of Veterans Affairs Health Services Improvement Fund established under former section 1729B w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1729B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish not more than seven consolidated patient accounting centers for conducting industry-modeled regionalized billing and collection activities of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1729B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The centers shall carry out the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>