<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1786" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1786/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1786/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1786"><akn:num>1786</akn:num><akn:heading>Care for newborn children of women veterans receiving maternity care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1786. Care for newborn children of women veterans receiving maternity care(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary may furnish health care services described in subsection (b) and transportation necessary to receive such services to a newborn child of a woman veteran who is receiving maternity care furnished by the Department for not more than seven days after the birth of the child if the veteran delivered the child in—(1) a facility of the Department;

(2) another facility pursuant to a Department contract for services relating to such delivery; or

(3) another location, including a health care facility, if the veteran delivers the child before arriving at a facility described in paragraph (1) or (2).


(b) Covered Health Care Services.—Health care services described in this subsection are all post-delivery care services, including routine care services, that a newborn child requires, including necessary health care services provided by a facility other than the facility where the newborn child was delivered (including a specialty pediatric hospital) that accepts transfer of the newborn child and responsibility for treatment of the newborn child.

(c) Exception Based on Medical Necessity.—Pursuant to such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe to carry out this section, the Secretary may furnish more than seven days of health care services described in subsection (b), and may furnish transportation necessary to receive such services, to a newborn child based on medical necessity if the child is in need of additional care, including if the child has been discharged or released from a hospital and requires readmittance to ensure the health and welfare of the child.

(d) Transportation.—(1) Transportation furnished under subsection (a) to, from, or between care settings to meet the needs of a newborn child includes costs for either or both the newborn child and parents.

(2) Transportation furnished under subsection (a) includes tra</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (c), the Secretary may furnish health care services described in subsection (b) and transportation necessary to receive such services to a newborn child of a woman veteran who is receiving maternity care furnished by the Department for not more than seven days after the birth of the child if the veteran delivered the child in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Health Care Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health care services described in this subsection are all post-delivery care services, including routine care services, that a newborn child requires, including necessary health care services provided by a facility other than the facility where the newborn child was delivered (including a specialty pediatric hospital) that accepts transfer of the newborn child and responsibility for treatment of the newborn child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception Based on Medical Necessity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pursuant to such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe to carry out this section, the Secretary may furnish more than seven days of health care services described in subsection (b), and may furnish transportation necessary to receive such services, to a newborn child based on medical necessity if the child is in need of additional care, including if the child has been discharged or released from a hospital and requires readmittance to ensure the health and welfare of the child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement or Payment for Health Care Services or Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>