<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1833" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1833/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1833/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1833"><akn:num>1833</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of receipt of monetary allowance and other benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1833. Treatment of receipt of monetary allowance and other benefits(a) Coordination With Other Benefits Paid to the Recipient.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, receipt by an individual of a monetary allowance under this chapter shall not impair, infringe, or otherwise affect the right of the individual to receive any other benefit to which the individual is otherwise entitled under any law administered by the Secretary.

(b) Coordination With Benefits Based on Relationship of Recipients.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, receipt by an individual of a monetary allowance under this chapter shall not impair, infringe, or otherwise affect the right of any other individual to receive any benefit to which such other individual is entitled under any law administered by the Secretary based on the relationship of such other individual to the individual who receives such monetary allowance.

(c) Monetary Allowance Not To Be Considered as Income or Resources for Certain Purposes.—Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a monetary allowance paid an individual under this chapter shall not be considered as income or resources in determining eligibility for, or the amount of benefits under, any Federal or federally assisted program.

(Added Pub. L. 106–419, title IV, § 401(b), Nov. 1, 2000, 114 Stat. 1860, § 1823; renumbered § 1833, Pub. L. 108–183, title I, § 102(a)(1), Dec. 16, 2003, 117 Stat. 2653.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1833 was renumbered section 3733 of this title.

Amendments2003—Pub. L. 108–183 renumbered section 1823 of this title as this section.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1833_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Other Benefits Paid to the Recipient.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, receipt by an individual of a monetary allowance under this chapter shall not impair, infringe, or otherwise affect the right of the individual to receive any other benefit to which the individual is otherwise entitled under any law administered by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1833_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Benefits Based on Relationship of Recipients.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, receipt by an individual of a monetary allowance under this chapter shall not impair, infringe, or otherwise affect the right of any other individual to receive any benefit to which such other individual is entitled under any law administered by the Secretary based on the relationship of such other individual to the individual who receives such monetary allowance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1833_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monetary Allowance Not To Be Considered as Income or Resources for Certain Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a monetary allowance paid an individual under this chapter shall not be considered as income or resources in determining eligibility for, or the amount of benefits under, any Federal or federally assisted program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>