<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1834" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1834/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1834/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1834"><akn:num>1834</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonduplication of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1834. Nonduplication of benefits(a) Monetary Allowance.—In the case of an eligible child under subchapter II of this chapter whose only covered birth defect is spina bifida, a monetary allowance shall be paid under subchapter I of this chapter. In the case of an eligible child under subchapter II of this chapter who has spina bifida and one or more additional covered birth defects, a monetary allowance shall be paid under subchapter II of this chapter. In the case of a child eligible for benefits under subchapter I or II of this chapter who is also eligible for benefits under subchapter III of this chapter, a monetary allowance shall be paid under the subchapter of this chapter elected by the child.

(b) Vocational Rehabilitation.—An individual may only be provided one program of vocational training under this chapter.

(Added Pub. L. 106–419, title IV, § 401(b), Nov. 1, 2000, 114 Stat. 1860, § 1824; renumbered § 1834 and amended, Pub. L. 108–183, title I, § 102(a)(1), (c), Dec. 16, 2003, 117 Stat. 2653, 2654.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1834 was renumbered section 3734 of this title.

Amendments2003—Pub. L. 108–183, § 102(a)(1), renumbered section 1824 of this title as this section.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–183, § 102(c), inserted at end: “In the case of a child eligible for benefits under subchapter I or II of this chapter who is also eligible for benefits under subchapter III of this chapter, a monetary allowance shall be paid under the subchapter of this chapter elected by the child.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monetary Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In the case of an eligible child under subchapter II of this chapter whose only covered birth defect is spina bifida, a monetary allowance shall be paid under subchapter I of this chapter. In the case of an eligible child under subchapter II of this chapter who has spina bifida and one or more additional covered birth defects, a monetary allowance shall be paid under subchapter II of this chapter. In the case of a child eligible for benefits under subchapter I or II of this chapter who is also eligible for benefits under subchapter III of this chapter, a monetary allowance shall be paid under the subchapter of this chapter elected by the child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1834_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vocational Rehabilitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual may only be provided one program of vocational training under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>