<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1920" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1920/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1920/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1920"><akn:num>1920</akn:num><akn:heading>National Service Life Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1920. National Service Life Insurance Fund(a) The National Service Life Insurance Fund heretofore created in the Treasury is continued as a permanent trust fund. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, all premiums paid on account of National Service Life Insurance shall be deposited and covered into the Treasury to the credit of such fund, which, together with interest earned thereon, shall be available for the payment of liabilities under such insurance, including payment of dividends and refunds of unearned premiums, and for the reimbursement of administrative costs under subsection (c). Payments from this fund shall be made upon and in accordance with awards by the Secretary.

(b) The Secretary is authorized to set aside out of such fund such reserve amounts as may be required under accepted actuarial principles to meet all liabilities under such insurance; and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to invest and reinvest such fund, or any part thereof, in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States, and to sell such obligations for the purposes of such fund.

(c)(1) For each fiscal year for which this subsection is in effect, the Secretary shall, from the National Service Life Insurance Fund, reimburse the “General operating expenses” account of the Department for the amount of administrative costs determined under paragraph (2) for that fiscal year. Such reimbursement shall be made from any surplus earnings for that fiscal year that are available for dividends on such insurance after claims have been paid and actuarially determined reserves have been set aside. However, if the amount of such administrative costs exceeds the amount of such surplus earnings, such reimbursement shall be made only to the extent of such surplus earnings.

(2) The Secretary shall determine the administrative costs to the Department for a fiscal year for which this subsection is in effec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1920_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The National Service Life Insurance Fund heretofore created in the Treasury is continued as a permanent trust fund. Except as otherwise provided in this chapter, all premiums paid on account of National Service Life Insurance shall be deposited and covered into the Treasury to the credit of such fund, which, together with interest earned thereon, shall be available for the payment of liabilities under such insurance, including payment of dividends and refunds of unearned premiums, and for the reimbursement of administrative costs under subsection (c). Payments from this fund shall be made upon and in accordance with awards by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1920_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary is authorized to set aside out of such fund such reserve amounts as may be required under accepted actuarial principles to meet all liabilities under such insurance; and the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to invest and reinvest such fund, or any part thereof, in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States, and to sell such obligations for the purposes of such fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1920_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>