<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1965" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1965/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1965/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1965"><akn:num>1965</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1965. Definitions
For the purpose of this subchapter—(1) The term “active duty” means—(A) full-time duty in the Armed Forces, other than active duty for training;

(B) full-time duty (other than for training purposes) as a commissioned officer of the Regular or Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Public Health Service;

(C) full-time duty as a commissioned officer of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and

(D) full-time duty as a cadet or midshipman at the United States Military Academy, United States Naval Academy, United States Air Force Academy, or the United States Coast Guard Academy.


(2) The term “active duty for training” means—(A) full-time duty in the Armed Forces performed by Reserves, or by members of the Space Force in a space force active status (as defined in section 101(e)(1) of title 10) but not on sustained duty under section 20105 of title 10, for training purposes;

(B) full-time duty for training purposes performed as a commissioned officer of the Reserve Corps 1 of the Public Health Service;

(C) full-time duty as a member, cadet, or midshipman of the Reserve Officers Training Corps while attending field training or practice cruises; and

(D) in the case of members of the National Guard or Air National Guard of any State, full-time duty under sections 316, 502, 503, 504, or 505 of title 32, United States Code.


(3) The term “inactive duty training” means—(A) duty (other than full-time duty) prescribed or authorized for Reserves (including commissioned officers of the Reserve Corps 1 of the Public Health Service), or for members of the Space Force in a space force active status (as defined in section 101(e)(1) of title 10), which duty is scheduled in advance by competent authority to begin at a specific time and place; and

(B) in the case of a member of the National Guard or Air National Guard of any State, such term means duty (other than full-time duty) which is scheduled in advance by competent author</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “active duty” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “active duty for training” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “inactive duty training” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The terms “active duty for training” and “inactive duty training” do not include duty performed as a temporary member of the Coast Guard Reserve, and the term “inactive duty training” does not include (A) work or study performed in connection with correspondence courses, or (B) attendance at an educational institution in an inactive status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “member” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “uniformed services” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Coast Guard, the commissioned corps of the Public Health Service, and the commissioned corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The terms “widow” or “widower” means a person who is the lawful spouse of the insured member at the time of his death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “child” means a legitimate child, a legally adopted child, an illegitimate child as to the mother, or an illegitimate child as to the alleged father, only if (A) he acknowledged the child in writing signed by him; or (B) he has been judicially ordered to contribute to the child’s support; or (C) he has been, before his death, judicially decreed to be the father of such child; or (D) proof of paternity is established by a certified copy of the public record of birth or church record of baptism showing that the insured was the informant and was named as father of the child; or (E) proof of paternity is established from service department or other public records, such as school or welfare agencies, which show that with his knowledge the insured was named as the father of the child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “parent” means a father of a legitimate child, mother of a legitimate child, father through adoption, mother through adoption, mother of an illegitimate child, and father of an illegitimate child but only if (A) he acknowledged paternity of the child in writing signed by him before the child’s death; or (B) he has been judicially ordered to contribute to the child’s support; or (C) he has been judicially decreed to be the father of such child; or (D) proof of paternity is established by a certified copy of the public record of birth or church record of baptism showing that the claimant was the informant and was named as father of the child; or (E) proof of paternity is established from service department or other public records, such as school or welfare agencies, which show that with his knowledge the claimant was named as father of the child. No person who abandoned or willfully failed to support a child during the child’s minority, or consented to the child’s adoption m</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1965_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “insurable dependent”, with respect to a member, means the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>