<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1969" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1969/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/1969/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1969"><akn:num>1969</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions; payment; investment; expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1969. Deductions; payment; investment; expenses(a)(1) During any period in which a member, on active duty or active duty for training under a call or order to such duty that does not specify a period of less than thirty-one days, is insured under Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance, there shall be deducted each month from the member’s basic or other pay until separation or release from such duty an amount determined by the Secretary (which shall be the same for all such members) as the share of the cost attributable to insuring such member under such policy, less any costs traceable to the extra hazard of such duty in the uniformed service.

(2)(A) During any month in which a member is assigned to the Ready Reserve of a uniformed service under conditions which meet the qualifications of (subparagraph (B) or (C) of section 1965(5) of this title, and is insured under a policy of insurance purchased by the Secretary, under section 1966 of this title, there shall be contributed from the appropriation made for active duty pay of the uniformed service concerned an amount determined by the Secretary (which shall be the same for all such members) as the share of the cost attributable to insuring such member under this policy, less any costs traceable to the extra hazards of such duty in the uniformed services. Any amounts so contributed on behalf of any individual shall be collected by the Secretary concerned from such individual (by deduction from pay or otherwise) and shall be credited to the appropriation from which such contribution was made.

(B) If an individual who is required pursuant to subparagraph (A) to make a direct remittance of costs to the Secretary concerned fails to make the required remittance within 60 days of the date on which such remittance is due, such individual’s insurance with respect to which such remittance is required shall be terminated by the Secretary concerned. Such termination shall be made by written notice to the individual’s official</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For each month for which any member is so insured, there shall be contributed from the appropriation made for active duty pay of the uniformed service concerned an amount determined by the Secretary and certified to the Secretary concerned to be the cost of Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance which is traceable to the extra hazard of duty in the uniformed services. Effective January 1, 1970, such cost shall be determined by the Secretary on the basis of the excess mortality incurred by members and former members of the uniformed services insured under Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance above what their mortality would have been under peacetime conditions as such mortality is determined by the Secretary using such methods and data as the Secretary shall determine to be reasonable and practicable. The Secretary is authorized to make such adjustments regarding contributions from pay appropriations as may be indicated from actual experience.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An amount equal to the first amount due on Servicemembers’ Group Life Insurance may be advanced from current appropriations for active-service pay to any such member, which amount shall constitute a lien upon any service or other pay accruing to the person from whom such advance was made and shall be collected therefrom if not otherwise paid. No disbursing or certifying officer shall be responsible for any loss incurred by reason of such advance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of the functions of the Secretaries of the military departments under this section. Such regulations shall prescribe such procedures as the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary, may consider necessary to ensure that such functions are carried out in a timely and complete manner and in accordance with the provisions of this section, including specifically the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of this section relating to contributions from appropriations made for active duty pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1969_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Any overpayment of a premium for insurance coverage for an insurable dependent of a member that is terminated under section 1968(a)(5) of this title shall be refunded to the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>