<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2001"><akn:num>2001</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2001. Purpose
The purpose of this chapter is to provide for the special needs of homeless veterans.
(Added Pub. L. 107–95, § 5(a)(1), Dec. 21, 2001, 115 Stat. 905.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2001 was renumbered section 4101 of this title.
Another prior section 2001, Pub. L. 85–857, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1217, related to compensation for veterans under agreements with States, prior to repeal by section 1(a) of Pub. L. 87–675.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Authorization for Secretary of Veterans Affairs To Use Certain Funds for Improved Flexibility in Assistance to Homeless VeteransPub. L. 118–210, title IV, § 403, Jan. 2, 2025, 138 Stat. 2796, provided that:
“(a) Use of Funds.—During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [Jan. 2, 2025] and ending on the termination date specified in subsection (d), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide to a covered veteran, as the Secretary determines necessary—“(1) food, shelter, clothing, blankets, and hygiene items required for the safety and survival of the veteran;

“(2) transportation required to support the stability and health of the veteran for appointments with service providers, the conduct of housing and employment searches, and the obtainment of food and supplies; and

“(3) tablets, smartphones, disposable phones and other technology, and related service plans required to support the stability and health of the veteran through the maintenance of contact with service providers, prospective landlords, and family members.


“(b) Homeless Veterans on Department of Veterans Affairs Land.—“(1) In general.—The Secretary may collaborate, to the extent practicable, with one or more organizations to manage the use of land of the Department of Veterans Affairs for homeless veterans for living and sleeping.

“(2) Forms of collaboration.—Collaboration under paragraph (1) may include the provision by either the Secretary or the head of the organization concerned of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>