<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2012" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2012/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2012/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2012"><akn:num>2012</akn:num><akn:heading>Per diem payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2012. Per diem payments(a) Per Diem Payments for Furnishing Services to Homeless Veterans.—(1) Subject to the availability of appropriations provided for such purpose, the Secretary, pursuant to such criteria as the Secretary shall prescribe, shall provide to a recipient of a grant under section 2011 of this title (or an entity eligible to receive a grant under that section which after November 10, 1992, establishes a program that the Secretary determines carries out the purposes described in that section) per diem payments for services furnished to any homeless veteran—(A) whom the Secretary has referred to the grant recipient (or entity eligible for such a grant); or

(B) for whom the Secretary has authorized the provision of services.


(2)(A)(i) Except as otherwise provided in subparagraph (B), the rate for such per diem payments shall be the daily cost of care estimated by the grant recipient or eligible entity adjusted by the Secretary under clause (ii).

(ii)(I) The Secretary shall adjust the rate estimated by the grant recipient or eligible entity under clause (i) to exclude other sources of income described in subclause (III) that the grant recipient or eligible entity certifies to be correct.

(II) Each grant recipient or eligible entity shall provide to the Secretary such information with respect to other sources of income as the Secretary may require to make the adjustment under subclause (I).

(III) The other sources of income referred to in subclauses (I) and (II) are payments to the grant recipient or eligible entity for furnishing services to homeless veterans under programs other than under this subchapter, including payments and grants from other departments and agencies of the United States, from departments or agencies of State or local government, and from private entities or organizations.


(iii) For purposes of calculating the rate for per diem payments under clause (i), in the case of a homeless veteran who has care of a minor dependent wh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per Diem Payments for Furnishing Services to Homeless Veterans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may inspect any facility of a grant recipient or entity eligible for payments under subsection (a) at such times as the Secretary considers necessary. No per diem payment may be provided to a grant recipient or eligible entity under this section unless the facilities of the grant recipient or eligible entity meet such standards as the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Life Safety Code.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per Diem Payments to Nonconforming Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Entities for Certain Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may reimburse a recipient of a grant under section 2011, 2013, or 2061 of this title or a recipient of per diem payments under this section for fees charged to that grant or per diem payment recipient for the use of the homeless management information system described in section 402(f) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 11360a(f))—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the HOME Act of 2024, and not less frequently than twice each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the rate for per diem payments under this section that includes, for each Veterans Integrated Service Network of the Department, the following data:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>