<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2022" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2022/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2022/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2022"><akn:num>2022</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of outreach services for veterans at risk of homelessness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2022. Coordination of outreach services for veterans at risk of homelessness(a) Outreach Plan.—The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Health, shall provide for appropriate officials of the Mental Health Service and the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration to develop a coordinated plan for joint outreach by the two Services to veterans at risk of homelessness, including particularly veterans who are being discharged or released from institutions after inpatient psychiatric care, substance abuse treatment, or imprisonment.

(b) Matters To Be Included.—The outreach plan under subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) Strategies to identify and collaborate with non-Department entities used by veterans who have not traditionally used Department services to further outreach efforts.

(2) Strategies to ensure that mentoring programs, recovery support groups, and other appropriate support networks are optimally available to veterans.

(3) Appropriate programs or referrals to family support programs.

(4) Means to increase access to case management services.

(5) Plans for making additional employment services accessible to veterans.

(6) Appropriate referral sources for mental health and substance abuse services.


(c) Cooperative Relationships.—The outreach plan under subsection (a) shall identify strategies for the Department to enter into formal cooperative relationships with entities outside the Department to facilitate making services and resources optimally available to veterans.

(d) Review of Plan.—The Secretary shall submit the outreach plan under subsection (a) to the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans for its review and consultation.

(e) Outreach Program.—(1) The Secretary shall carry out an outreach program to provide information to homeless veterans and veterans at risk of homelessness. The program shall include at a minimum—(A) provision of information about benefits available to eligible veterans fr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Health, shall provide for appropriate officials of the Mental Health Service and the Readjustment Counseling Service of the Veterans Health Administration to develop a coordinated plan for joint outreach by the two Services to veterans at risk of homelessness, including particularly veterans who are being discharged or released from institutions after inpatient psychiatric care, substance abuse treatment, or imprisonment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters To Be Included.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The outreach plan under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Relationships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The outreach plan under subsection (a) shall identify strategies for the Department to enter into formal cooperative relationships with entities outside the Department to facilitate making services and resources optimally available to veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall submit the outreach plan under subsection (a) to the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans for its review and consultation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2022_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>