<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2044" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2044/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2044/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2044"><akn:num>2044</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2044. Financial assistance for supportive services for very low-income veteran families in permanent housing(a) Distribution of Financial Assistance.—(1) The Secretary shall provide financial assistance to eligible entities approved under this section to provide and coordinate the provision of supportive services described in subsection (b) for very low-income veteran families occupying permanent housing.

(2) Financial assistance under this section shall consist of grants for each such family for which an approved eligible entity is providing or coordinating the provision of supportive services.

(3)(A) The Secretary shall provide such grants to each eligible entity that is providing or coordinating the provision of supportive services.

(B) The Secretary is authorized to establish intervals of payment for the administration of such grants and establish a maximum amount to be awarded, in accordance with the services being provided and their duration.


(4) In providing financial assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to entities providing or coordinating the provision of supportive services for very low-income veteran families who are transitioning from homelessness to permanent housing.

(5) The Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, financial assistance under this subsection is equitably distributed across geographic regions, including rural communities and tribal lands.

(6) Each entity receiving financial assistance under this section to provide supportive services to a very low-income veteran family shall notify that family that such services are being paid for, in whole or in part, by the Department.

(7) The Secretary may require entities receiving financial assistance under this section to submit a report to the Secretary that describes the projects carried out with such financial assistance.


(b) Supportive Services.—The supportive services referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) Services provide</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of Financial Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supportive Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The supportive services referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for Financial Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) From amounts appropriated to the Department for Medical Services, there shall be available to carry out subsections (a), (b), and (c) amounts as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2044_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>