<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2066" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2066/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2066/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2066"><akn:num>2066</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2066. Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans(a) Establishment.—(1) There is established in the Department the Advisory Committee on Homeless Veterans (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Committee”).

(2) The Committee shall consist of not more than 15 members appointed by the Secretary from among the following:(A) Veterans service organizations.

(B) Advocates of homeless veterans and other homeless individuals.

(C) Community-based providers of services to homeless individuals.

(D) Previously homeless veterans.

(E) State veterans affairs officials.

(F) Experts in the treatment of individuals with mental illness.

(G) Experts in the treatment of substance use disorders.

(H) Experts in the development of permanent housing alternatives for lower income populations.

(I) Experts in vocational rehabilitation.

(J) Such other organizations or groups as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(3) The Committee shall include, as ex officio members, the following:(A) The Secretary of Labor (or a representative of the Secretary selected after consultation with the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment).

(B) The Secretary of Defense (or a representative of the Secretary).

(C) The Secretary of Health and Human Services (or a representative of the Secretary).

(D) The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (or a representative of the Secretary).

(E) The Executive Director of the Interagency Council on Homelessness (or a representative of the Executive Director).

(F) The Under Secretary for Health (or a representative of the Under Secretary after consultation with the Director of the Office of Homeless Veterans Programs).

(G) The Under Secretary for Benefits (or a representative of the Under Secretary after consultation with the Director of the Office of Homeless Veterans Programs).


(4)(A) The Secretary shall determine the terms of service and allowances of the members of the Committee, except that a term of service may not exceed th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2066_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2066_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2066_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2066_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Committee shall cease to exist September 30, 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>