<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2068" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2068/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2068/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2068"><akn:num>2068</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2068. Mental health consultations(a) In General.—Not later than two weeks after the date on which a veteran described in subsection (b) enters into a program administered by the Homeless Programs Office of the Department, the Secretary shall offer the veteran a mental health consultation to assess the health needs of, and care options for, the veteran.

(b) Veteran Described.—A veteran described in this subsection is a veteran to whom a mental health consultation is not offered or provided through the case management services of the program of the Homeless Programs Office into which the veteran enters.

(Added Pub. L. 117–328, div. V, title IV, § 404(b)(1), Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5513.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2068_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than two weeks after the date on which a veteran described in subsection (b) enters into a program administered by the Homeless Programs Office of the Department, the Secretary shall offer the veteran a mental health consultation to assess the health needs of, and care options for, the veteran.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2068_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veteran Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A veteran described in this subsection is a veteran to whom a mental health consultation is not offered or provided through the case management services of the program of the Homeless Programs Office into which the veteran enters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>