<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/2109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2109"><akn:num>2109</akn:num><akn:heading>Specially adapted housing destroyed or damaged by natural disasters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2109. Specially adapted housing destroyed or damaged by natural disasters(a) In General.—Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 2102 and 2102A of this title, the Secretary may provide assistance to a veteran whose home was previously adapted with assistance of a grant under this chapter in the event the adapted home which was being used and occupied by the veteran was destroyed or substantially damaged in a natural or other disaster, as determined by the Secretary.

(b) Use of Funds.—Subject to subsection (c), assistance provided under subsection (a) shall—(1) be available to acquire a suitable housing unit with special fixtures or moveable facilities made necessary by the veteran’s disability, and necessary land therefor;

(2) be available to a veteran to the same extent as if the veteran had not previously received assistance under this chapter; and

(3) not be deducted from the maximum uses or from the maximum amount of assistance available under this chapter.


(c) Limitations.—The amount of the assistance provided under subsection (a) may not exceed the lesser of—(1) the reasonable cost, as determined by the Secretary, of repairing or replacing the damaged or destroyed home in excess of the available insurance coverage on such home; or

(2) the maximum amount of assistance to which the veteran would have been entitled under sections 2101(a), 2101(b), and 2102A of this title had the veteran not obtained previous assistance under this chapter.


(Added Pub. L. 112–154, title VII, § 701(a)(1), Aug. 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 1202; amended Pub. L. 114–58, title VI, § 601(12), Sept. 30, 2015, 129 Stat. 538.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 114–58 substituted “provisions of sections” for “provisions of section”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 112–154, title VII, § 701(g), Aug. 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 1205, provided that: “The amendments made by this section [enacting this section and amending sections 3108, 3120, 3703, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 2102 and 2102A of this title, the Secretary may provide assistance to a veteran whose home was previously adapted with assistance of a grant under this chapter in the event the adapted home which was being used and occupied by the veteran was destroyed or substantially damaged in a natural or other disaster, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to subsection (c), assistance provided under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The amount of the assistance provided under subsection (a) may not exceed the lesser of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>