<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3018C" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3018C/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3018C/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3018C"><akn:num>3018C</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for certain VEAP participants to enroll</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3018C. Opportunity for certain VEAP participants to enroll(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual who—(1) is a participant on October 9, 1996, in the educational benefits program provided by chapter 32 of this title;

(2) is serving on active duty (excluding the periods referred to in section 3202(1)(C) of this title) on such date;

(3) before applying for benefits under this section, has completed the requirements of a secondary school diploma (or equivalency certificate) or has successfully completed (or otherwise received academic credit for) the equivalent of 12 semester hours in a program of education leading to a standard college degree;

(4) if discharged or released from active duty after the date on which the individual makes the election described in paragraph (5), is discharged or released therefrom with an honorable discharge; and

(5) during the one-year period beginning on October 9, 1996, makes an irrevocable election to receive benefits under this section in lieu of benefits under chapter 32 of this title, pursuant to procedures which the Secretary of each military department shall provide in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the purpose of carrying out this section or which the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide for such purpose with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy;


may elect to become entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter.

(b) With respect to an individual who makes an election under subsection (a) to become entitled to basic education assistance under this chapter—(1) the basic pay of the individual shall be reduced (in a manner determined by the Secretary of Defense) until the total amount by which such basic pay is reduced is $1,200; or

(2) to the extent that basic pay is not so reduced before the individual’s discharge or release from active duty as specified in subsection (a)(4), the Secretary shall coll</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018C_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual who— may elect to become entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018C_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) With respect to an individual who makes an election under subsection (a) to become entitled to basic education assistance under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018C_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018C_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The procedures provided in regulations referred to in subsection (a) shall provide for notice of the requirements of subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of section 3011(a)(3) and of subparagraph (A) of section 3012(a)(3) of this title. Receipt of such notice shall be acknowledged in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018C_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>