<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3020" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3020/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3020/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3020"><akn:num>3020</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members for career service members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3020. Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members for career service members(a) In General.—Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary concerned, to promote recruitment and retention of members of the Armed Forces, to permit an individual described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this subchapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) the unused portion of entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).

(b) Eligible Individuals.—An individual referred to in subsection (a) is any member of the Armed Forces—(1) who, while serving on active duty or as a member of the Selected Reserve at the time of the approval by the Secretary concerned of the member’s request to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section, has completed six years of service in the Armed Forces and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years as a member of the Armed Forces; or

(2) as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (k).


(c) Eligible Dependents.—An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the individual’s entitlement as follows:(1) To the individual’s spouse.

(2) To one or more of the individual’s children.

(3) To a combination of the individuals referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).


(d) Limitation on Months of Transfer.—(1) An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer any unused entitlement to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c).

(2) The total number of months of entitlement transferred by an individual under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary concerned, to promote recruitment and retention of members of the Armed Forces, to permit an individual described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this subchapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) the unused portion of entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual referred to in subsection (a) is any member of the Armed Forces—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the individual’s entitlement as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Months of Transfer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Transferee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An individual transferring an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Transfer; Revocation and Modification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A dependent to whom entitlement to basic educational assistance is transferred under this section may not commence the use of the transferred entitlement until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Administrative Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overpayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3020_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approvals of Transfer Subject to Availability of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary concerned may approve transfers of entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section in a fiscal year only to the extent that appropriations for military personnel are available in that fiscal year for purposes of making deposits in the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund under section 2006 of title 10 in that fiscal year to cover the present value of future benefits payable from the Fund for the Department of Defense portion of payments of basic educational assistance attributable to increased usage of benefits as a result of such transfers of entitlement in that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>