<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_303"><akn:num>303</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Veterans Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 303. Secretary of Veterans Affairs
There is a Secretary of Veterans Affairs, who is the head of the Department and is appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Secretary is responsible for the proper execution and administration of all laws administered by the Department and for the control, direction, and management of the Department.
(Added Pub. L. 102–83, § 2(a), Aug. 6, 1991, 105 Stat. 379.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 210(a), (b)(1) of this title and in second and third sentences of section 2 of Pub. L. 100–527, known as the Department of Veterans Affairs Act, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 102–83, §§ 2(a), 3(1).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Plan for Reduction of Backlog of Freedom of Information Act RequestsPub. L. 117–328, div. U, title IV, § 406, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5493, provided that:
“(a) Plan.—“(1) In general.—The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish and carry out a plan for the Secretary to meet, by not later than five years after the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 29, 2022], the requirements of section 552 of title 5, United States Code, (commonly known as the ‘Freedom of Information Act’ or ‘FOIA’) with respect to providing documents and information under such section within the timeframes required by such section.

“(2) Elements.—The plan required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:“(A) Improving and acquiring technology, including with respect to searching email and other electronic information, and the timelines for such improvement, to ensure that the information technology of the Department of Veterans Affairs is capable of carrying out the plan.

“(B) Identification of efficient procedures, policies, and systems of the Department that could be developed to allow employees of the Department responsible for replying to requests under such section 552 to search and review documents rather tha</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>