<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3108"><akn:num>3108</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3108. Allowances(a)(1) Except in the case of a veteran who makes an election under subsection (f) of this section and subject to the provisions of paragraph (3) of this subsection, each veteran shall be paid a subsistence allowance in accordance with this section during a period determined by the Secretary to be a period of such veteran’s participation under this chapter in a rehabilitation program.

(2)(A) In any case in which the Secretary determines, at the conclusion of such veteran’s pursuit of a vocational rehabilitation program under this chapter, that such veteran has been rehabilitated to the point of employability, such veteran shall be paid a subsistence allowance, as prescribed in this section for full-time training for the type of program that the veteran was pursuing, for two months while satisfactorily following a program of employment services provided under section 3104(a)(5) of this title.

(B) In any case in which the Secretary determines that a veteran described in subparagraph (A) has been displaced as the result of a natural or other disaster while being paid a subsistence allowance under that subparagraph, as determined by the Secretary, the Secretary may extend the payment of a subsistence allowance under such subparagraph for up to an additional two months while the veteran is satisfactorily following a program of employment services described in such subparagraph.


(3) A subsistence allowance may not be paid under this chapter to a veteran for any period during which such veteran is being provided with an initial evaluation under section 3106(a) of this title or during which such veteran is being provided only with counseling or with placement or postplacement services under section 3105(b) of this title.


(b)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary shall determine the subsistence allowance to be paid to a veteran under this chapter in accordance with the following table, which shall be the monthly amount shown in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In any case in which a veteran is pursuing a rehabilitation program on a residential basis in a specialized rehabilitation facility, the Secretary may (1) pay to such facility the cost of such veteran’s room and board in lieu of payment to such veteran of the subsistence allowance (not including any portion payable for any dependents) payable under subsection (b) of this section, and (2) pay to such veteran that portion of the allowance for dependents payable, as determined by such veteran’s dependency status, under subsection (b) of this section for a full-time institutional program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding any other provision of this title, the amount of subsistence allowance, or other allowance under subsection (f) of this section, that may be paid to a veteran pursuing a rehabilitation program for any month for which such veteran receives compensation at the rate prescribed in section 1114(j) of this title as the result of hospital treatment (not including post-hospital convalescence) or observation at the expense of the Department of Veterans Affairs may not exceed, when added to any compensation to which such veteran is entitled for such month, an amount equal to the greater of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3108_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Payment of a subsistence allowance may be made in advance in accordance with the provisions of section 3680(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>