<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3115"><akn:num>3115</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3115. Rehabilitation resources(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the purpose of providing services under this chapter, the Secretary may—(1) use the facilities of any Federal agency (including the Department of Veterans Affairs), of any State or local government agency receiving Federal financial assistance, or of any federally recognized Indian tribe, to provide training or work experience as part or all of a veteran’s vocational rehabilitation program without pay or for nominal pay in any case in which the Secretary determines that such training or work experience is necessary to accomplish such veteran’s rehabilitation;

(2) use the facilities, staff, and other resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs;

(3) employ such additional personnel and experts as the Secretary considers necessary; and

(4) use the facilities and services of any Federal, State, or other public agency, any agency maintained by joint Federal and State contributions, any federally recognized Indian tribe, any public or private institution or establishment, and any private individual.


(b)(1) While pursuing on-job training or work experience under subsection (a)(1) of this section at a Federal agency, a veteran shall be considered to be an employee of the United States for the purposes of the benefits of chapter 81 of title 5, but not for the purposes of laws administered by the Office of Personnel Management.

(2) Except as provided in chapter 17 of this title, hospital care and medical services provided under this chapter shall be furnished in facilities over which the Secretary has direct jurisdiction.

(3) Use of the facilities of a State or local government agency under subsection (a)(1) of this section or use of facilities and services under subsection (a)(4) of this section, shall be procured through contract, agreement, or other cooperative arrangement.

(4) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations providing for the monitoring of training and work experience</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the purpose of providing services under this chapter, the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3115_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, the term “federally recognized Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>