<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3241" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3241/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3241/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3241"><akn:num>3241</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3241. Requirements(a)(1) The provisions of sections 3470, 3471, 3474, 3476, 3483, 3485, and 3491(a)(1) of this title and the provisions of chapter 36 of this title (with the exception of section 3687) shall be applicable with respect to individuals who are pursuing programs of education while serving on active duty.

(2) The Secretary may, without regard to the application to this chapter of so much of the provisions of section 3471 of this title as prohibit the enrollment of an eligible veteran in a program of education in which the veteran is “already qualified”, and pursuant to such regulations as the Secretary shall prescribe, approve the enrollment of such individual in refresher courses (including courses which will permit such individual to update knowledge and skills or be instructed in the technological advances which have occurred in the individual’s field of employment during and since the period of such veteran’s active military service), deficiency courses, or other preparatory or special education or training courses necessary to enable the individual to pursue an approved program of education.


(b) The Secretary may approve the pursuit of flight training (in addition to a course of flight training that may be approved under section 3680A(b) of this title) by an individual entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter if—(1) such training is generally accepted as necessary for the attainment of a recognized vocational objective in the field of aviation;

(2) the individual possesses a valid pilot certificate and meets, on the day the individual begins a course of flight training, the medical requirements necessary for a commercial pilot certificate; and

(3) the flight school courses meet Federal Aviation Administration standards for such courses and are approved by the Federal Aviation Administration and the State approving agency.


(c) The provisions of sections 3470, 3471, 3474, 3476, 3483, and 3491(a) (other than clause (1)) of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may approve the pursuit of flight training (in addition to a course of flight training that may be approved under section 3680A(b) of this title) by an individual entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3241_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The provisions of sections 3470, 3471, 3474, 3476, 3483, and 3491(a) (other than clause (1)) of this title and the provisions of chapter 36 of this title (with the exception of section 3687) shall be applicable with respect to individuals who are pursuing programs of education following discharge or release from active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>