<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_325"><akn:num>325</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans experience office 11 So in original. Probably should be “Veterans Experience Office”.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 325. Veterans experience office 11 So in original. Probably should be “Veterans Experience Office”.(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Department within the Office of the Secretary an office to be known as the “Veterans Experience Office” (in this section referred to as the “Office”).

(b) Head of Office.—(1) The head of the Office shall be the Chief Veterans Experience Officer.

(2) The Chief Veterans Experience Officer shall—(A) be appointed by the Secretary from among individuals the Secretary considers qualified to perform the duties of the position;

(B) report directly to the Secretary; and

(C) be responsible for carrying out the functions of the Office set forth under subsection (c).



(c) Function.—The functions of the Office are as follows:(1) Carrying out the key customer experience initiatives of the Department relating to veterans’ and other beneficiaries’ satisfaction with and usage of benefits and services furnished under laws administered by the Secretary for which they are eligible, including setting the strategy, framework, policy, and other guidance for the Department relating to customer experience, including ensuring the activities of the Office and those of other organizations and offices within the Department are coordinated and not duplicative.

(2) Requiring the heads of other organizations and offices within the Department to report regularly on customer experience metrics, action plans, and other customer experience improvement efforts to the Chief Veterans Experience Officer.

(3) Collecting veteran-derived data—(A) to determine veteran and beneficiary satisfaction with and usage of the benefits and services furnished under laws administered by the Secretary for which they are eligible; and

(B) to be considered during policymaking.


(4) Providing strategic guidance and strategies to Department entities for engaging with veterans and beneficiaries regarding benefits and services furnished under laws administered by the Secr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Department within the Office of the Secretary an office to be known as the “Veterans Experience Office” (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Head of Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Function.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The functions of the Office are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff and Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Chief Veterans Experience Officer to disclose any record in contravention of section 552a of title 5 (commonly referred to as the “Privacy Act of 1974”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_325_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The requirements and authorities of this section shall terminate on September 30, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>