<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3313" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3313/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3313/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3313"><akn:num>3313</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational assistance: amount; payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3313. Educational assistance: amount; payment(a) Payment.—The Secretary shall pay to each individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is pursuing an approved program of education (other than a program covered by subsections (e) and (f)) the amounts specified in subsection (c) to meet the expenses of such individual’s subsistence, tuition, fees, and other educational costs for pursuit of such program of education.

(b) Approved Programs of Education.—A program of education is an approved program of education for purposes of this chapter if the program of education is approved for purposes of chapter 30 (including approval by the State approving agency concerned).

(c) Programs of Education Leading to a Degree Pursued at Institutions of Higher Learning on More Than Half-time Basis.—The amounts payable under this subsection for pursuit of an approved program of education leading to a degree at an institution of higher learning (as that term is defined in section 3452(f)) are amounts as follows:(1) In the case of an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter by reason of paragraph (1), (2), (8), (9), (10), or (11) of section 3311(b), amounts as follows:(A) An amount equal to the following:(i) In the case of a program of education pursued at a public institution of higher learning, the actual net cost for in-State tuition and fees assessed by the institution for the program of education after the application of—(I) any waiver of, or reduction in, tuition and fees; and

(II) any scholarship, or other Federal, State, institutional, or employer-based aid or assistance (other than loans and any funds provided under section 401(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1070a(b))) that is provided directly to the institution and specifically designated for the sole purpose of defraying tuition and fees.


(ii) In the case of a program of education pursued at a non-public or foreign institution of higher learning, the les</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall pay to each individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is pursuing an approved program of education (other than a program covered by subsections (e) and (f)) the amounts specified in subsection (c) to meet the expenses of such individual’s subsistence, tuition, fees, and other educational costs for pursuit of such program of education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved Programs of Education.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A program of education is an approved program of education for purposes of this chapter if the program of education is approved for purposes of chapter 30 (including approval by the State approving agency concerned).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of Education Leading to a Degree Pursued at Institutions of Higher Learning on More Than Half-time Basis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The amounts payable under this subsection for pursuit of an approved program of education leading to a degree at an institution of higher learning (as that term is defined in section 3452(f)) are amounts as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Frequency of Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of Education Leading to a Degree Pursued on Active Duty for a Period of More Than 30 Days on More Than Half-time Basis.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of Education Pursued on Half-Time Basis or Less.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of Education Other Than Programs of Education Leading to a Degree.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Established Charges to Educational Institutions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amounts payable under subsections (c)(1)(A) (and of similar amounts payable under paragraphs (2) through (6) of subsection (c)), (e)(2), and (f)(2)(A), and under subparagraphs (A)(i), (C), and (D) of subsection (g)(3), shall be paid directly to the educational institution concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Housing Stipend Payments for Academic Years.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Any monthly housing stipend payable under this section during the academic year beginning on August 1 of a calendar year shall be determined utilizing rates for basic allowances for housing payable under section 403 of title 37 in effect as of January 1 of such calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3313_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Monthly Housing Stipends During Active Duty Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) For any month during which an individual who is entitled to a monthly housing stipend under this section is performing active duty service, the Secretary shall determine the amount of such stipend payable to such individual for such month on a pro rata basis for the period of such month during which the individual is not performing active duty service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>