<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3319" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3319/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3319/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3319"><akn:num>3319</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3319. Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members(a) In General.—(1) Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary concerned may permit an individual described in subsection (b) who is entitled to educational assistance under this chapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) a portion of such individual’s entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).

(2) The purpose of the authority in paragraph (1) is to promote recruitment and retention in the uniformed services. The Secretary concerned may exercise the authority for that purpose when authorized by the Secretary of Defense in the national security interests of the United States.


(b) Eligible Individuals.—An individual referred to in subsection (a) is any member of the uniformed services who, at the time of the approval of the individual’s request to transfer entitlement to educational assistance under this section, has completed at least—(1) six years of service in the Armed Forces and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years as a member of the uniformed services; or

(2) the years of service as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (j).


(c) Eligible Dependents.—(1) Transfer.—An individual approved to transfer an entitlement to educational assistance under this section may transfer the individual’s entitlement to an eligible dependent or a combination of eligible dependents.

(2) Definition of eligible dependent.—For purposes of this subsection, the term “eligible dependent” has the meaning given the term “dependent” under subparagraphs (A), (I), and (D) of section 1072(2) of title 10.


(d) Limitation on Months of Transfer.—The total number of months of entitlement transferred by a individual under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this sect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An individual referred to in subsection (a) is any member of the uniformed services who, at the time of the approval of the individual’s request to transfer entitlement to educational assistance under this section, has completed at least—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Months of Transfer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The total number of months of entitlement transferred by a individual under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no less than 18 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Transferee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An individual transferring an entitlement to educational assistance under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Transfer; Revocation and Modification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A dependent to whom entitlement to educational assistance is transferred under this section may not commence the use of the transferred entitlement until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Administrative Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overpayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3319_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>