<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3321"><akn:num>3321</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limitation for use of and eligibility for entitlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3321. Time limitation for use of and eligibility for entitlement(a) In General.—Except as provided in this section, the period during which an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter may use such individual’s entitlement—(1) in the case of an individual whose last discharge or release from active duty is before January 1, 2013, expires at the end of the 15-year period beginning on the date of such discharge or release; or

(2) in the case of an individual whose last discharge or release from active duty is on or after January 1, 2013, shall not expire.


(b) Exceptions.—(1) Applicability of section 3031 to running of period.—(A) Subsections (b), (c), (d), and (i) of section 3031 shall apply with respect to the running of the 15-year period described in subsection (a) of this section in the same manner as such subsections apply under section 3031 with respect to the running of the 10-year period described in section 3031(a).

(B) Subsection (i) of section 3031 shall apply with respect to the running of the 15-year period described in paragraphs (4)(A) and (5)(A) of this subsection in the same manner as such subsection applies under section 3031 of this title with respect to the running of the 10-year period described in section 3031(a) of this title.


(2) Applicability of section 3031 to termination.—Section 3031(f) shall apply with respect to the termination of an individual’s entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter in the same manner as such section applies to the termination of an individual’s entitlement to educational assistance under chapter 30, except that, in the administration of such section for purposes of this chapter, the reference to section 3013 shall be deemed to be a reference to section 3312 of this title.

(3) Determination of last discharge or release.—For purposes of subsection (a), an individual’s last discharge or release from active duty shall not include any discharge or release from a period of ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in this section, the period during which an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter may use such individual’s entitlement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>