<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3322"><akn:num>3322</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar to duplication of educational assistance benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3322. Bar to duplication of educational assistance benefits(a) In General.—An individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is also eligible for educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, or 35 of this title, chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 or section 510 of title 10, or the provisions of the Hostage Relief Act of 1980 (Public Law 96–449; 5 U.S.C. 5561 note) may not receive assistance under two or more such programs concurrently, but shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which chapter or provisions to receive educational assistance.

(b) Inapplicability of Service Treated Under Educational Loan Repayment Programs.—A period of service counted for purposes of repayment of an education loan under chapter 109 of title 10 may not be counted as a period of service for entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter.

(c) Service in Selected Reserve.—An individual who serves in the Selected Reserve may receive credit for such service under only one of this chapter, chapter 30 of this title, and chapters 1606 and 1607 of title 10, and shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which chapter such service is to be credited.

(d) Additional Coordination Matters.—In the case of an individual entitled to educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, or 35 of this title, chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10, or the provisions of the Hostage Relief Act of 1980, or making contributions toward entitlement to educational assistance under chapter 30 of this title, as of August 1, 2009, coordination of entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter, on the one hand, and such chapters or provisions, on the other, shall be governed by the provisions of section 5003(c) of the Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 2008.

(e) Bar To Concurrent Receipt of Transferred Education Benefits and Marine Gunnery Sergeant John David Fry Scholarship Assistance.—An individua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter who is also eligible for educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, or 35 of this title, chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 or section 510 of title 10, or the provisions of the Hostage Relief Act of 1980 (Public Law 96–449; 5 U.S.C. 5561 note) may not receive assistance under two or more such programs concurrently, but shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which chapter or provisions to receive educational assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of Service Treated Under Educational Loan Repayment Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A period of service counted for purposes of repayment of an education loan under chapter 109 of title 10 may not be counted as a period of service for entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service in Selected Reserve.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An individual who serves in the Selected Reserve may receive credit for such service under only one of this chapter, chapter 30 of this title, and chapters 1606 and 1607 of title 10, and shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which chapter such service is to be credited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Coordination Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In the case of an individual entitled to educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, or 35 of this title, chapter 107, 1606, or 1607 of title 10, or the provisions of the Hostage Relief Act of 1980, or making contributions toward entitlement to educational assistance under chapter 30 of this title, as of August 1, 2009, coordination of entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter, on the one hand, and such chapters or provisions, on the other, shall be governed by the provisions of section 5003(c) of the Post-9/11 Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar To Concurrent Receipt of Transferred Education Benefits and Marine Gunnery Sergeant John David Fry Scholarship Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An individual entitled to educational assistance under both section 3319 and paragraph (8), (9), or (10) of section 3311 of this title may not receive assistance under both provisions concurrently, but shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which provision to receive educational assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar To Receipt of Compensation and Pension and Marine Gunnery Sergeant John David Fry Scholarship Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The commencement of a program of education under paragraph (8), (9), or (10) of section 3311 of this title shall be a bar to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar To Concurrent Receipt of Transferred Education Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A spouse or child who is entitled to educational assistance under this chapter based on a transfer of entitlement from more than one individual under section 3319 may not receive assistance based on transfers from more than one such individual concurrently, but shall elect (in such form and manner as the Secretary may prescribe) under which source to utilize such assistance at any one time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3322_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar To Duplication of Eligibility Based on a Single Event or Period of Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>