<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3326" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3326/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3326/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3326"><akn:num>3326</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on student progress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3326. Report on student progress(a) Submittal of Information by Educational Institutions.—As a condition of approval under chapter 36 of this title of a course offered by an educational institution (as defined in section 3452 of this title), each year, each educational institution (as so defined) that received a payment in that year on behalf of an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter shall submit to the Secretary such information regarding the academic progress of the individual as the Secretary may require.

(b) Reports to Congress.—Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes a summary of the information provided by educational institutions under subsection (a) for the calendar year preceding the year during which such report is submitted.

(Added Pub. L. 114–315, title IV, § 404(a)(2), Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1554; amended Pub. L. 115–48, title I, § 114, Aug. 16, 2017, 131 Stat. 985.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2017—Pub. L. 115–48 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, and added subsec. (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective 1 year after Dec. 16, 2016, see section 404(c) of Pub. L. 114–315, set out as an Effective Date of 2016 Amendment note under section 3325 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3326_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal of Information by Educational Institutions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As a condition of approval under chapter 36 of this title of a course offered by an educational institution (as defined in section 3452 of this title), each year, each educational institution (as so defined) that received a payment in that year on behalf of an individual entitled to educational assistance under this chapter shall submit to the Secretary such information regarding the academic progress of the individual as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3326_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that includes a summary of the information provided by educational institutions under subsection (a) for the calendar year preceding the year during which such report is submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>