<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3482" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3482/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3482/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3482"><akn:num>3482</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of educational assistance allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3482. Computation of educational assistance allowances(a)(1) Except as provided in subsection (b), (c), or (g) of this section, or section 3687 of this title, while pursuing a program of education under this chapter of half-time or more, each eligible veteran shall be paid the monthly educational assistance allowance set forth in column II, III, IV, or V (whichever is applicable as determined by the veteran’s dependency status) opposite the applicable type of program as shown in column I:









Column IColumnIIColumnIIIColumnIVColumn V

Type ofprogramNodependentsOnedependentTwodependentsMore thantwodependents


    The amount in column IV, plus the following for each dependent in excess of two:
Institutional training:
Full-time$376$448$510     $32
Three-quarter time283336383      24
Half-time188224255      17
Cooperative304355404      23




(2) A “cooperative” program, other than a “farm cooperative” program, means a full-time program of education which consists of institutional courses and alternate phases of training in a business or industrial establishment with the training in the business or industrial establishment being strictly supplemental to the institutional portion.


(b) The educational assistance allowance of an individual pursuing a program of education—(1) while on active duty, or

(2) on less than a half-time basis,


shall be computed at the rate of (A) the established charges for tuition and fees which the institution requires similarly circumstanced nonveterans enrolled in the same program to pay, or (B) $376 per month for a full-time course, whichever is the lesser. An individual’s entitlement shall be charged for institutional courses on the basis of the applicable monthly training time rate as determined under section 3688 of this title.

(c)(1) An eligible veteran who is enrolled in an educational institution for a “farm cooperative” program consisting of institutional agricultural courses prescheduled to fall within 44 weeks of any per</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The educational assistance allowance of an individual pursuing a program of education— shall be computed at the rate of (A) the established charges for tuition and fees which the institution requires similarly circumstanced nonveterans enrolled in the same program to pay, or (B) $376 per month for a full-time course, whichever is the lesser. An individual’s entitlement shall be charged for institutional courses on the basis of the applicable monthly training time rate as determined under section 3688 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The educational assistance allowance of an eligible veteran pursuing an independent study program which leads to a standard college degree shall be computed at the rate provided in subsection (b) of this section. If the entire training is to be pursued by independent study, the amount of such veteran’s entitlement to educational assistance under this chapter shall be charged in accordance with the rate at which the veteran is pursuing the independent study program but at not more than the rate at which such entitlement is charged for pursuit of such program on less than a half-time basis. In any case in which independent study is combined with resident training, the educational assistance allowance shall be paid at the applicable institutional rate based on the total training time determined by adding the number of semester hours (or the equivalent thereof) of resident training to the number of semester hours (or the equivalent thereof) of independent study that do not exceed the n</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The educational assistance allowance of an eligible veteran pursuing a course by open circuit television shall be computed in the same manner that such allowance is computed under subsection (e) of this section for an independent study program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3482_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>