<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3485" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3485/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3485/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3485"><akn:num>3485</akn:num><akn:heading>Work-study allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3485. Work-study allowance(a)(1) In accordance with paragraph (4), individuals utilized under the authority of subsection (b) shall be paid an additional educational assistance allowance (hereinafter in this section referred to as “work-study allowance”). Such allowance shall be paid in return for an individual’s entering into an agreement described in paragraph (3).

(2) Such work-study allowance shall be paid in an amount equal to the product of—(A) the applicable hourly minimum wage; and

(B) the number of hours worked during the applicable period.


(3) An agreement described in this paragraph is an agreement of an individual to perform services, during or between periods of enrollment, aggregating not more than a number of hours equal to 25 times the number of weeks in the semester or other applicable enrollment period, required in connection with a qualifying work-study activity.

(4)(A) With respect to covered work-study activities, the Secretary shall carry out this section by providing to participating educational institutions an annual amount for the institution to use in paying work-study allowance under paragraph (1) to individuals enrolled at the institution.

(B) With respect to a participating educational institution that participated in the work-study program under this section during the academic year beginning August 1, 2018, the Secretary shall determine the annual amount to provide to the educational institution under subparagraph (A) as follows:(i) For the academic year beginning August 1, 2020, the amount shall be the total amount, determined in consultation with the educational institution, that the Secretary paid under this section for covered work-study activities to individuals enrolled at such educational institution during the academic year beginning August 1, 2018.

(ii) Except as provided by clauses (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (D), for each academic year beginning on or after August 1, 2021, the amount shall be the total amount the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall, subject to the provisions of subsection (e) of this section, utilize, in connection with the activities specified in subsection (a)(1) of this section, the service of individuals who are pursuing programs of rehabilitation, education, or training under chapter 30, 31, 32, 33, or 34 of this title or chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10, at a rate equal to at least three-quarters of that required of a full-time student. In carrying out this section, the Secretary, wherever feasible, shall give priority to veterans with disabilities rated at 30 percent or more for purposes of chapter 11 of this title. In the event an individual ceases to be at least a three-quarter-time student before completing such agreement, the individual may, with the approval of the Secretary, be permitted to complete such agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall determine the number of individuals whose services the Department of Veterans Affairs can effectively utilize and the types of services that such individuals may be required to perform, on the basis of a survey, which the Secretary shall conduct annually, of each Department of Veterans Affairs regional office in order to determine the numbers of individuals whose services can effectively be utilized during an enrollment period in each geographical area where Department of Veterans Affairs activities are conducted, and shall determine which individuals shall be offered agreements under this section in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, including as criteria (1) the need of the individual to augment the veteran’s educational assistance or subsistence allowance; (2) the availability to the individual of transportation to the place where the individual’s services are to be performed; (3) the motivation of the individual; and (4) in the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) While performing the services authorized by this section, individuals shall be deemed employees of the United States for the purposes of the benefits of chapter 81 of title 5 but not for the purposes of laws administrated by the Office of Personnel Management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3485_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>