<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3501"><akn:num>3501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3501. Definitions(a) For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title—(1) The term “eligible person” means any of the following:(A) A child of a person who, as a result of qualifying service—(i) died of a service-connected disability; or

(ii) has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability, or who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.


(B) The surviving spouse of any person who died of a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service.

(C) The spouse or child of any member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who, at the time of application for benefits under this chapter is listed, pursuant to section 556 of title 37 and regulations issued thereunder, by the Secretary concerned in one or more of the following categories and has been so listed for a total of more than ninety days: (i) missing in action, (ii) captured in line of duty by a hostile force, or (iii) forcibly detained or interned in line of duty by a foreign government or power.

(D)(i) The spouse of any person who has a total disability permanent in nature resulting from a service-connected disability sustained during a period of qualifying service, or (ii) the surviving spouse of a veteran who died while a disability so evaluated was in existence.


(E) The spouse or child of a person who—(i) at the time of the Secretary’s determination under clause (ii), is a member of the Armed Forces who is hospitalized or receiving outpatient medical care, services, or treatment;

(ii) the Secretary determines has a total disability permanent in nature incurred or aggravated in the line of duty in the active military, naval, air, or space service; and

(iii) is likely to be discharged or released from such service for such disability.



(2) The term “child” includes individuals who are married and individuals who are above the age of twenty-three years.

(3) The term “duty with the Armed Forces” as used in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of this chapter and chapter 36 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If an eligible person has attained the person’s majority and is under no known legal disability, all references in this chapter to “parent or guardian” shall refer to the eligible person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any provision of this chapter which requires any action to be taken by or with respect to the parent or guardian of an eligible person who has not attained such person’s majority, or who, having attained such person’s majority, is under a legal disability, shall not apply when the Secretary determines that its application would not be in the best interest of the eligible person, would result in undue delay, or would not be administratively feasible. In such a case the Secretary, where necessary to protect the interest of the eligible person, may designate some other person (who may be the eligible person) as the person by or with respect to whom the action so required should be taken.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No eligible person may be afforded educational assistance under this chapter unless such person was discharged or released after each period such person was on duty with the Armed Forces under conditions other than dishonorable, or while such person is on duty with the Armed Forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>