<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3684" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3684/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3684/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3684"><akn:num>3684</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by veterans, eligible persons, and institutions; reporting fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3684. Reports by veterans, eligible persons, and institutions; reporting fee(a)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, the veteran or eligible person and the educational institution offering a course in which such veteran or eligible person is enrolled under chapter 31, 32, 33, 34, 35, or 36 of this title shall, without delay, report to the Secretary, in the form prescribed by the Secretary, such enrollment and any interruption or termination of the education of each such veteran or eligible person. The date of such interruption or termination will be the last date of pursuit, or, in the case of correspondence training, the last date a lesson was serviced by a school.

(2)(A) In the case of a program of independent study pursued on less than a half-time basis in an educational institution, the Secretary may approve a delay by the educational institution in reporting the enrollment or reenrollment of an eligible veteran or eligible person until the end of the term, quarter, or semester if the educational institution requests the delay and the Secretary determines that it is not feasible for the educational institution to monitor interruption or termination of the veteran’s or eligible person’s pursuit of such program.

(B) An educational institution which, pursuant to subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, is delaying the reporting of the enrollment or reenrollment of a veteran shall provide the veteran with notice of the delay at the time that the veteran enrolls or reenrolls.


(3)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, an educational institution offering courses on a term, quarter, or semester basis may certify the enrollment of a veteran who is not on active duty, or of an eligible person, in such courses for more than one term, quarter, or semester at a time, but not for a period extending beyond the end of a school year (including the summer enrollment period).

(B) Subparagraph (A) of this paragraph shall not apply with respect to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3684_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3684_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary, prior to making payment of a reporting fee to an educational institution, as provided for in subsection (c) of this section, shall require such institution to certify that it has exercised reasonable diligence in determining whether such institution or any course offered by such institution approved for the enrollment of veterans or eligible persons meets all of the applicable requirements of chapters 31, 34, 35, and 36 of this title and that it will, without delay, report any failure to meet any such requirement to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3684_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3684_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall ensure that the Department provides personnel of educational institutions who are charged with submitting reports or certifications to the Secretary under this section with assistance in preparing and submitting such reports or certifications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>