<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3697A"><akn:num>3697A</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational and vocational counseling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3697A. Educational and vocational counseling(a) The Secretary shall make available to an individual described in subsection (b) of this section, upon such individual’s request, counseling services, including such educational and vocational counseling and guidance, testing, and other assistance as the Secretary determines necessary to aid the individual in selecting—(1) an educational or training objective and an educational institution or training establishment appropriate for the attainment of such objective; or

(2) an employment objective that would be likely to provide such individual with satisfactory employment opportunities in the light of the individual’s personal circumstances.


(b) For the purposes of this section, the term “individual” means an individual who—(1) is eligible for educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, or 33 of this title or chapter 106 or 107 of title 10;

(2) was discharged or released from active duty under conditions other than dishonorable if not more than one year has elapsed since the date of such last discharge or release from active duty; or

(3) is serving on active duty in any State with the Armed Forces and is within 180 days of the estimated date of such individual’s discharge or release from active duty under conditions other than dishonorable, including those who are making a determination of whether to continue as members of the Armed Forces.


(c) In any case in which the Secretary has rated the individual as being incompetent, the counseling services described in subsection (a) of this section shall be required to be provided to the individual before the selection of a program of education or training.

(d) At such intervals as the Secretary determines necessary, the Secretary shall make available information concerning the need for general education and for trained personnel in the various crafts, trades, and professions. Facilities of other Federal agencies collecting such information shall be utilized to th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall make available to an individual described in subsection (b) of this section, upon such individual’s request, counseling services, including such educational and vocational counseling and guidance, testing, and other assistance as the Secretary determines necessary to aid the individual in selecting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For the purposes of this section, the term “individual” means an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In any case in which the Secretary has rated the individual as being incompetent, the counseling services described in subsection (a) of this section shall be required to be provided to the individual before the selection of a program of education or training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) At such intervals as the Secretary determines necessary, the Secretary shall make available information concerning the need for general education and for trained personnel in the various crafts, trades, and professions. Facilities of other Federal agencies collecting such information shall be utilized to the extent the Secretary determines practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall take appropriate steps (including individual notification where feasible) to acquaint all individuals described in subsection (b) of this section with the availability and advantages of counseling services under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>