<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697B" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697B/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3697B/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3697B"><akn:num>3697B</akn:num><akn:heading>On-campus educational and vocational counseling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3697B. On-campus educational and vocational counseling(a) In General.—The Secretary shall provide educational and vocational counseling services for individuals described in section 3697A(b) of this title at locations on the campuses of institutions of higher learning selected by the Secretary. Such counseling services shall be provided by employees of the Department who provide such services under section 3697A of this title.

(b) Selection of Locations.—(1) To be selected by the Secretary under this section, an institution of higher learning shall provide an appropriate space on the campus of the institution where counseling services can be provided under this section.

(2) In selecting locations for the provision of counseling services under this section, the Secretary shall seek to select locations where the maximum number of veterans would have access to such services.


(c) Annual Report.—Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the counseling services provided under this section. Such report shall include, for the year covered by the report—(1) the average ratio of counselors providing such services to individuals who received such services at each location where such services were provided;

(2) a description of such services provided;

(3) the recommendations of the Secretary for improving the provision of such services; and

(4) any other matters the Secretary determines appropriate.


(Added Pub. L. 115–48, title III, § 307(a), Aug. 16, 2017, 131 Stat. 993.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date of the enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (c), is the date of enactment of Pub. L. 115–48, which was approved Aug. 16, 2017.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Native VetSuccess at Tribal Colleges and Universities Pilot ProgramPub. L. 117–328, div. U, title II, § 211, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5451, provided that:
“(a) Short Ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697B_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall provide educational and vocational counseling services for individuals described in section 3697A(b) of this title at locations on the campuses of institutions of higher learning selected by the Secretary. Such counseling services shall be provided by employees of the Department who provide such services under section 3697A of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697B_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of Locations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3697B_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the counseling services provided under this section. Such report shall include, for the year covered by the report—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>