<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3702"><akn:num>3702</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic entitlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3702. Basic entitlement(a)(1) The veterans described in paragraph (2) of this subsection are eligible for the housing loan benefits of this chapter. In the case of any veteran who served on active duty during two or more of the periods specified in paragraph (2) for which eligibility for the housing loan benefits under this chapter may be granted, entitlement derived from service during the most recent such period (A) shall cancel any unused entitlement derived from service during any earlier such period, and (B) shall be reduced by the amount by which entitlement from service during any earlier such period has been used to obtain a direct, guaranteed, or insured housing loan—(i) on real property which the veteran owns at the time of application; or

(ii) as to which the Secretary has incurred actual liability or loss, unless in the event of loss or the incurrence and payment of such liability by the Secretary the resulting indebtedness of the veteran to the United States has been paid in full.


(2) The veterans referred to in the first sentence of paragraph (1) of this subsection are the following:(A) Each veteran who served on active duty at any time during World War II, the Korean conflict, or the Vietnam era and whose total service was for 90 days or more.

(B) Each veteran who after September 15, 1940, was discharged or released from a period of active duty for a service-connected disability.

(C) Each veteran, other than a veteran described in clause (A) or (B) of this paragraph, who—(i) served after July 25, 1947, for a period of more than 180 days and was discharged or released therefrom under conditions other than dishonorable; or

(ii) has served more than 180 days in active duty status and continues on active duty without a break therein.


(D) Each veteran who served on active duty for 90 days or more at any time during the Persian Gulf War, other than a veteran ineligible for benefits under this title by reason of section 5303A(b) of this title.

(E)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In computing the aggregate amount of guaranty or insurance housing loan entitlement available to a veteran under this chapter, the Secretary may exclude the amount of guaranty or insurance housing loan entitlement used for any guaranteed, insured, or direct loan under the following circumstances: The Secretary may, in any case involving circumstances the Secretary deems appropriate, waive one or more of the conditions prescribed in paragraph (1). The authority of the Secretary under this subsection to exclude an amount of guaranty or insurance housing loan entitlement previously used by a veteran may be exercised only once for that veteran under the authority of paragraph (4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An honorable discharge shall be deemed to be a certificate of eligibility to apply for a guaranteed loan. Any veteran who does not have a discharge certificate, or who received a discharge other than honorable, may apply to the Secretary for a certificate of eligibility. Upon making a loan guaranteed or insured under this chapter, the lender shall forthwith transmit to the Secretary a report thereon in such detail as the Secretary may, from time to time, prescribe. Where the loan is guaranteed, the Secretary shall provide the lender with a loan guaranty certificate or other evidence of the guaranty. The Secretary shall also endorse on the veteran’s discharge, or eligibility certificate, the amount and type of guaranty used, and the amount, if any, remaining. Nothing in this chapter shall preclude the assignment of any guaranteed loan or the security therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Housing loans will be automatically guaranteed under this chapter only if made (1) by any Federal land bank, national bank, State bank, private bank, building and loan association, insurance company, credit union, or mortgage and loan company, that is subject to examination and supervision by an agency of the United States or of any State, or (2) by any State, or (3) by any lender approved by the Secretary pursuant to standards established by the Secretary. Any housing loan proposed to be made to a veteran pursuant to this chapter by any lender not of a class specified in the preceding sentence may be guaranteed by the Secretary if the Secretary finds that it is in accord otherwise with the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may at any time upon thirty days’ notice require housing loans to be made by any lender or class of lenders to be submitted to the Secretary for prior approval. No guaranty or insurance liability shall exist with respect to any such loan unless evidence of guaranty or insurance is issued by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3702_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Any housing loan at least 20 percent of which is guaranteed under this chapter may be made by any national bank or Federal savings and loan association, or by any bank, trust company, building and loan association, or insurance company, organized or authorized to do business in the District of Columbia. Any such loan may be so made without regard to the limitations and restrictions of any other law relating to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>