<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3710"><akn:num>3710</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase or construction of homes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3710. Purchase or construction of homes(a) Except as provided in section 3704(c)(2) of this title, any loan to a veteran, if made pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, is automatically guaranteed if such loan is for one or more of the following purposes:(1) To purchase or construct a dwelling to be owned and occupied by the veteran as a home.

(2) To purchase a farm on which there is a farm residence to be owned and occupied by the veteran as the veteran’s home.

(3) To construct on land owned by the veteran a farm residence to be occupied by the veteran as the veteran’s home.

(4) To repair, alter, or improve a farm residence or other dwelling owned by the veteran and occupied by the veteran as the veteran’s home.

(5) To refinance existing mortgage loans or other liens which are secured of record on a dwelling or farm residence owned and occupied by the veteran as the veteran’s home.

(6) To purchase a one-family residential unit in a condominium housing development or project, if such development or project is approved by the Secretary under criteria which the Secretary shall prescribe in regulations.

(7) To improve a dwelling or farm residence owned by the veteran and occupied by the veteran as the veteran’s home through energy efficiency improvements, as provided in subsection (d).

(8) To refinance in accordance with subsection (e) of this section an existing loan guaranteed, insured, or made under this chapter.

(9)(A)(i) To purchase a manufactured home to be permanently affixed to a lot that is owned by the veteran.

(ii) To purchase a manufactured home and a lot to which the home will be permanently affixed.


(B)(i) To refinance, in accordance with the terms and conditions applicable under the provisions of subsection (e) of this section (other than paragraph (1)(E) of such subsection) to the guaranty of a loan for the purpose specified in clause (8) of this subsection, an existing loan guaranteed, insured, or made under this chapter that is secur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in section 3704(c)(2) of this title, any loan to a veteran, if made pursuant to the provisions of this chapter, is automatically guaranteed if such loan is for one or more of the following purposes: If there is an indebtedness which is secured by a lien against land owned by the veteran, the proceeds of a loan guaranteed under this section or made under section 3711 of this title for construction of a dwelling or farm residence on such land may be used also to liquidate such lien, but only if the reasonable value of the land is equal to or greater than the amount of the lien.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No loan may be guaranteed under this section or made under section 3711 of this title unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 100–198, § 3(a)(2), Dec. 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 1315.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3710_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>