<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3732" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3732/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3732/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3732"><akn:num>3732</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure on default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3732. Procedure on default(a)(1) In the event of default in the payment of any loan guaranteed under this chapter, the holder of the loan shall notify the Secretary of such default. Upon receipt of such notice, the Secretary may, subject to subsection (c) of this section, pay to such holder the guaranty not in excess of the pro rata portion of the amount originally guaranteed. Except as provided in section 3703(e) of this title, if the Secretary makes such a payment, the Secretary shall be subrogated to the rights of the holder of the loan to the extent of the amount paid on the guaranty.

(2)(A) The Secretary may, under terms and conditions determined by the Secretary—(i) pay the holder of a loan guaranteed under this chapter an amount necessary to avoid the foreclosure of such loan;

(ii) require the holder of the loan and the veteran obligated on the loan to execute all documents necessary to ensure the Secretary obtains a secured interest in the property covered by the loan; and

(iii) require the holder of the loan to take any actions necessary to carry out this paragraph, including preparing, executing, transmitting, receiving, and recording documents, and requiring the holder of the loan to place the loan in forbearance.


(B) In the event that a housing loan guaranteed under this chapter is modified under the authority provided under section 1322(b) of title 11, the Secretary may pay the holder of the housing loan the unpaid principal balance of the housing loan due, plus accrued interest, as of the date of the filing of the petition under title 11, but only upon the assignment, transfer, and delivery to the Secretary (in a form and manner satisfactory to the Secretary) of all rights, interest, claims, evidence, and records with respect to the housing loan.

(C)(i) Any decision by the Secretary under this paragraph is final and is not subject to judicial review.

(ii) For purposes of section 511 of this title, any decision under this paragraph shall not be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3732_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3732_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) With respect to any loan made under section 3711 which has not been sold as provided in subsection (g) of such section, if the Secretary finds, after there has been a default in the payment of any installment of principal or interest owing on such loan, that the default was due to the fact that the veteran who is obligated under the loan has become unemployed as the result of the closing (in whole or in part) of a Federal installation, the Secretary shall (1) extend the time for curing the default to such time as the Secretary determines is necessary and desirable to enable such veteran to complete payments on such loan, including an extension of time beyond the stated maturity thereof, or (2) modify the terms of such loan for the purpose of changing the amortization provisions thereof by recasting, over the remaining term of the loan, or over such longer period as the Secretary may determine, the total unpaid amount then due with the modification to become effective currently or u</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3732_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3732_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prescribe loss mitigation procedures, including a mandatory sequence in which the holder of a loan guaranteed under this chapter shall offer loss mitigation options (including an option to enter into a partial claim agreement under the VA Home Loan Program Reform Act) to a veteran, to help prevent the foreclosure of such loan. The Secretary may not purchase an entire such loan until the veteran has completed such sequence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>