<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3737" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3737/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3737/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3737"><akn:num>3737</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial Claim Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3737. Partial Claim Program(a) Establishment.—The Secretary shall carry out a program, to be known as the “Partial Claim Program”, under which the Secretary may make a partial claim, described in subsection (b), with respect to a loan—(1) guaranteed under this chapter;

(2) regarding the primary residence of the borrower; and

(3) that the Secretary determines is in default or at imminent risk of default.


(b) Partial Claim Described.—A partial claim described in this subsection, with respect to a loan described in subsection (a), is the purchase by the Secretary of a portion of indebtedness under the loan, through a transaction under which the Secretary—(1) pays to the holder of the loan the amount of indebtedness, subject to subsection (c), that the Secretary determines necessary to help prevent or resolve a default; and

(2) receives a secured interest in the property that serves as collateral for the guaranteed loan, which is subordinate to the amount of indebtedness under the guaranteed loan that the Secretary does not purchase.


(c) Administration of Partial Claim.—(1)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the amount of a partial claim under this section with respect to a loan guaranteed described in subsection (a) may not exceed 25 percent of the unpaid principal balance of the loan on the date on which the partial claim is made.

(B) In the case of an individual who failed to make a payment on a loan guaranteed under this chapter during the period beginning on March 1, 2020 and ending on May 1, 2025, the amount of a partial claim under this section may not exceed 30 percent of the unpaid principal balance of the guaranteed loan as of the date that the initial partial claim is made.


(2)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may make only one partial claim per loan.

(B) The Secretary may make an additional partial claim on a loan guaranteed under this chapter in the case of an individual who failed to make a payment on such loan during—(i) a major dis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall carry out a program, to be known as the “Partial Claim Program”, under which the Secretary may make a partial claim, described in subsection (b), with respect to a loan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial Claim Described.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A partial claim described in this subsection, with respect to a loan described in subsection (a), is the purchase by the Secretary of a portion of indebtedness under the loan, through a transaction under which the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Partial Claim.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of Loan Holder.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Default and Foreclosure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Decisions by the Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance in Advance of Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may, before prescribing regulations, issue administrative guidance with respect to the Partial Claim Program under this section and the loss mitigation options prescribed under section 3732(d) of this title, including any additional terms, conditions, and requirements the Secretary determines necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary under subsections (a) and (d) of section 3732 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3737_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary may not make a partial claim under this section after the date that is five years after the date of the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>