<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3765" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3765/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/3765/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3765"><akn:num>3765</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3765. Definitions
For the purposes of this subchapter—(1) The term “trust land” means any land that—(A) is held in trust by the United States for Native Americans;

(B) is subject to restrictions on alienation imposed by the United States on Indian lands (including native Hawaiian homelands);

(C) is located in the State of Alaska within a region established under section 7(a) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1606(a));

(D) is on any island in the Pacific Ocean if such land is, by cultural tradition, communally-owned land, as determined by the Secretary;

(E) is defined by the Secretary of the Interior and recognized by the United States as land over which an Indian Tribe has governmental dominion; or

(F) is on any land that the Secretary determines is provided to Native American veterans because of their status as Native Americans.


(2) The term “Native American veteran” means any veteran who is a Native American.

(3) The term “Native American” means—(A) an Indian, as defined in section 4(d) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450b(d)); 11 See References in Text note below.

(B) a native Hawaiian, as that term is defined in section 201(a)(7) of the Hawaiian Homes Commission Act, 1920 (Public Law 67–34; 42 Stat. 108);

(C) an Alaska Native, within the meaning provided for the term “Native” in section 3(b) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1602(b)); and

(D) a Pacific Islander, within the meaning of the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (42 U.S.C. 2991 et seq.).


(4) The term “tribal organization” shall have the meaning given such term in section 4(l) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450b(l)) 1 and shall include the Department of Hawaiian Homelands, in the case of native Hawaiians, and such other organizations as the Secretary may prescribe.

(5) The term “qualified non-Native American veteran” means a veteran who—(A) is the spouse of a Nativ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “trust land” means any land that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “Native American veteran” means any veteran who is a Native American.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “Native American” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “tribal organization” shall have the meaning given such term in section 4(l) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (25 U.S.C. 450b(l)) 1 and shall include the Department of Hawaiian Homelands, in the case of native Hawaiians, and such other organizations as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “qualified non-Native American veteran” means a veteran who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “community development financial institution” has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Community Development Banking and Financial Institutions Act of 1994 (12 U.S.C. 4702).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “Indian Tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation as defined in or established pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “Native community development financial institution” means any entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “net tangible benefit” shall have such meaning as the Secretary determines appropriate, but shall include the refinance of an interim construction loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3765_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “other technical assistance” means services to assist a Native American veteran to navigate the steps necessary for securing a mortgage loan on trust land, including pre-development activities related to utilities, identifying appropriate residential construction services, and obtaining lease clearances and title status reports from the applicable tribal organization or the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>