<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4102A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4102A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4102A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4102A"><akn:num>4102A</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training; program functions; Regional Admi</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4102A. Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training; program functions; Regional Administrators(a) Establishment of Position of Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training.—(1) There is established within the Department of Labor an Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training, appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, who shall formulate and implement all departmental policies and procedures to carry out (A) the purposes of this chapter, chapter 42, and chapter 43 of this title, and (B) all other Department of Labor employment, unemployment, and training programs to the extent they affect veterans.

(2) The employees of the Department of Labor administering chapter 43 of this title shall be administratively and functionally responsible to the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training.

(3)(A) There shall be within the Department of Labor a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training. The Deputy Assistant Secretary shall perform such functions as the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training prescribes.

(B) No individual may be appointed as a Deputy Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training unless the individual has at least five years of service in a management position as an employee of the Federal civil service or comparable service in a management position in the Armed Forces. For purposes of determining such service of an individual, there shall be excluded any service described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 308(d)(2) of this title.



(b) Program Functions.—The Secretary shall carry out the following functions:(1) Except as expressly provided otherwise, carry out all provisions of this chapter and chapter 43 of this title through the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training and administer through such Assistant Se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Position of Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall carry out the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for Receipt of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in Other Federally Funded Job Training Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Assistant Secretary of Labor for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall promote and monitor participation of qualified veterans and eligible persons in employment and training opportunities under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act and other federally funded employment and training programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Administrators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Performance Standards and Outcomes Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Provide Technical Assistance to States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may provide such technical assistance as the Secretary determines appropriate to any State that the Secretary determines has, or may have, an entered-employment rate in the State that is deficient, as determined under subsection (c)(3) with respect to a program year, including assistance in the development of a corrective action plan under that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4102A_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of Disabled Veterans’ Outreach Program Specialists and Veterans’ Employment Representatives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may allow the Governor of a State receiving funds under subsection (b)(5) to support specialists and representatives as described in such subsection to consolidate the functions of such specialists and representatives if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>