<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4103"><akn:num>4103</akn:num><akn:heading>Directors and Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training; additional Federal personne</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4103. Directors and Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training; additional Federal personnel(a) Directors and Assistant Directors.—(1) The Secretary shall assign to each State a representative of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service to serve as the Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training, and shall assign full-time Federal clerical or other support personnel to each such Director.

(2)(A) Each Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for a State shall, at the time of appointment, have been a bona fide resident of the State for at least two years.

(B) The Secretary may waive the requirement in subparagraph (A) with respect to a Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training if the Secretary determines that the waiver is in the public interest. Any such waiver shall be made on a case-by-case basis.


(3) Full-time Federal clerical or other support personnel assigned to Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall be appointed in accordance with the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5.


(b) Additional Federal Personnel.—The Secretary may also assign as supervisory personnel such representatives of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the employment, training, and placement services required under this chapter, including Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training.

(c) Coordination With State Departments of Labor and Veterans Affairs.—Each Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for a State shall coordinate the Director’s activities under this chapter with the State department of labor and the State department of veterans affairs.

(Pub. L. 85–857, Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1218, § 2012; renumbered § 2003, Pub. L. 87–675, § 1(a), Sept. 19, 1962, 76 Stat. 558; amended Pub. L. 89–358, § 6(c)(1), Mar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directors and Assistant Directors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Federal Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may also assign as supervisory personnel such representatives of the Veterans’ Employment and Training Service as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the employment, training, and placement services required under this chapter, including Assistant Directors for Veterans’ Employment and Training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With State Departments of Labor and Veterans Affairs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each Director for Veterans’ Employment and Training for a State shall coordinate the Director’s activities under this chapter with the State department of labor and the State department of veterans affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>