<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4114"><akn:num>4114</akn:num><akn:heading>Credentialing and licensure of veterans: demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4114. Credentialing and licensure of veterans: demonstration project(a) Demonstration Project Authorized.—The Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall carry out a demonstration project on credentialing in accordance with this section for the purpose of facilitating the seamless transition of members of the Armed Forces from service on active duty to civilian employment.

(b) Identification of Military Occupational Specialties and Associated Credentials and Licenses.—(1) The Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training, select not more than five military occupational specialties for purposes of the demonstration project. Each specialty so selected by the Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall require a skill or set of skills that is required for civilian employment in an industry with high growth or high worker demand.

(2) The Assistant Secretary shall enter into a contract with an appropriate entity representing a coalition of State governors to consult with appropriate Federal, State, and industry officials and identify requirements for credentials, certifications, and licenses that require a skill or set of skills required by a military occupational specialty selected under paragraph (1).

(3) The Assistant Secretary shall analyze the requirements identified under paragraph (2) to determine which requirements may be satisfied by the skills, training, or experience acquired by members of the Armed Forces with the military occupational specialties selected under paragraph (1).


(c) Elimination of Barriers to Credentialing and Licensure.—The Assistant Secretary shall cooperate with appropriate Federal, State, and industry officials to reduce or eliminate any barriers to providing a credential, certification, or license to a veteran who acquired any skill, training, or experience while serving as a member of the Armed Forces </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration Project Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Assistant Secretary for Veterans’ Employment and Training shall carry out a demonstration project on credentialing in accordance with this section for the purpose of facilitating the seamless transition of members of the Armed Forces from service on active duty to civilian employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of Military Occupational Specialties and Associated Credentials and Licenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elimination of Barriers to Credentialing and Licensure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Assistant Secretary shall cooperate with appropriate Federal, State, and industry officials to reduce or eliminate any barriers to providing a credential, certification, or license to a veteran who acquired any skill, training, or experience while serving as a member of the Armed Forces with a military occupational specialty selected under subsection (b)(1) that satisfies the Federal and State requirements for the credential, certification, or license.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4114_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of Project.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The period during which the Assistant Secretary shall carry out the demonstration project under this section shall be the two-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the VOW to Hire Heroes Act of 2011.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>