<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4115"><akn:num>4115</akn:num><akn:heading>Longitudinal study of job counseling, training, and placement service for veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4115. Longitudinal study of job counseling, training, and placement service for veterans(a) Study Required.—(1) The Secretary shall enter into a contract with a non-government entity to conduct a longitudinal study of a statistically valid sample of each of the groups of individuals described in paragraph (2). The contract shall provide for the study of each such group over a period of at least 5 years.

(2) The groups of individuals described in this paragraph are the following:(A) Veterans who have received intensive services.

(B) Veterans who did not receive intensive services but who otherwise received services under this chapter.

(C) Veterans who did not seek or receive services under this chapter.


(3) The study required by this subsection shall include the collection of the following information for each individual who participates in the study:(A) The average number of months such individual served on active duty.

(B) The disability ratings of such individual.

(C) Any unemployment benefits received by such individual.

(D) The average number of months such individual was employed during the year covered by the report.

(E) The average annual starting and ending salaries of any such individual who was employed during the year covered by the report.

(F) The average annual income of such individual.

(G) The average total household income of such individual for the year covered by the report.

(H) The percentage of such individuals who own their principal residences.

(I) The employment status of such individual.

(J) In the case of such an individual who received services under this chapter, whether the individual believes that any service provided by a disabled veterans’ outreach program specialist or local veterans’ employment representative helped the individual to become employed.

(K) In the case of such an individual who believes such a service helped the individual to become employed, whether—(i) the individual retained the position of employmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>