<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/4323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4323"><akn:num>4323</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of rights with respect to a State or private employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4323. Enforcement of rights with respect to a State or private employer(a) Action for Relief.—(1) A person who receives from the Secretary a notification pursuant to section 4322(e) of this title of an unsuccessful effort to resolve a complaint relating to a State (as an employer) or a private employer may request that the Secretary refer the complaint to the Attorney General. Not later than 60 days after the Secretary receives such a request with respect to a complaint, the Secretary shall refer the complaint to the Attorney General. If the Attorney General is reasonably satisfied that the person on whose behalf the complaint is referred is entitled to the rights or benefits sought, the Attorney General may appear on behalf of, and act as attorney for, the person on whose behalf the complaint is submitted and commence an action for relief under this chapter for such person. In the case of such an action against a State (as an employer), the action shall be brought in the name of the United States as the plaintiff in the action.

(2) Not later than 60 days after the date the Attorney General receives a referral under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall—(A) make a decision whether to appear on behalf of, and act as attorney for, the person on whose behalf the complaint is submitted; and

(B) notify such person in writing of such decision.


(3) A person may commence an action for relief with respect to a complaint against a State (as an employer) or a private employer if the person—(A) has chosen not to apply to the Secretary for assistance under section 4322(a) of this title;

(B) has chosen not to request that the Secretary refer the complaint to the Attorney General under paragraph (1); or

(C) has been refused representation by the Attorney General with respect to the complaint under such paragraph.



(b) Jurisdiction.—(1) In the case of an action against a State (as an employer) or a private employer commenced by the United States, the district courts o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for Relief.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equity Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An action under this chapter may be initiated only by a person claiming rights or benefits under this chapter under subsection (a) or by the United States under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Respondent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In any action under this chapter, only an employer or a potential employer, as the case may be, shall be a necessary party respondent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees, Court Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4323_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the term “private employer” includes a political subdivision of a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>