<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/5314" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/5314/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/5314/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5314"><akn:num>5314</akn:num><akn:heading>Indebtedness offsets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5314. Indebtedness offsets(a)(1) Subject to subsections (b) and (d) of this section and section 3485(e) of this title, the Secretary shall (unless the Secretary waives recovery under section 5302 of this title) deduct the amount of the indebtedness of any person who has been determined to be indebted to the United States by virtue of such person’s participation in a benefits program administered by the Secretary from future payments made to such person under any law administered by the Secretary.

(2) The Secretary may not make a deduction under paragraph (1) while the existence or amount of such indebtedness is disputed under section 5314A of this title.


(b) Deductions may not be made under subsection (a) of this section with respect to the indebtedness of a person described in such subsection unless the Secretary—(1) has made reasonable efforts to notify such person of such person’s right to dispute through prescribed administrative processes the existence or amount of such indebtedness and of such person’s right to request a waiver of such indebtedness under section 5302 of this title;

(2) has made a determination with respect to any such dispute or request or has determined that the time required to make such a determination before making deductions would jeopardize the Secretary’s ability to recover the full amount of such indebtedness through deductions from such payments; and

(3) has made reasonable efforts to notify such person about the proposed deductions from such payments.


(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or of any other law, the authority of the Secretary to make deductions under this section or to take other administrative action authorized by law for the purpose of collecting an indebtedness described in subsection (a) of this section, or for the purpose of determining the creditworthiness of a person who owes such an indebtedness, shall not be subject to any limitation with respect to the time for bringing civil actions o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5314_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5314_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deductions may not be made under subsection (a) of this section with respect to the indebtedness of a person described in such subsection unless the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5314_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding any other provision of this title or of any other law, the authority of the Secretary to make deductions under this section or to take other administrative action authorized by law for the purpose of collecting an indebtedness described in subsection (a) of this section, or for the purpose of determining the creditworthiness of a person who owes such an indebtedness, shall not be subject to any limitation with respect to the time for bringing civil actions or for commencing administrative proceedings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5314_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>