<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/548" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/548/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/548/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_548"><akn:num>548</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee on United States Outlying Areas and Freely Associated States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 548. Advisory Committee on United States Outlying Areas and Freely Associated States(a) Establishment.—The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the “Advisory Committee on United States Outlying Areas and Freely Associated States”, to provide advice and guidance to the Secretary on matters relating to covered veterans.

(b) Duties.—The duties of the Committee shall be the following:(1) To advise the Secretary on matters relating to covered veterans, including how the Secretary may improve the programs and services of the Department to better serve such veterans.

(2) To identify for the Secretary evolving issues of relevance to covered veterans.

(3) To propose clarifications, recommendations, and solutions to address issues raised by covered veterans.

(4) To provide a forum for covered veterans, veterans service organizations serving covered veterans, and the Department to discuss issues and proposals for changes to regulations, policies, and procedures of the Department.

(5) To identify priorities for and provide advice to the Secretary on appropriate strategies for consultation with veterans service organizations serving covered veterans.

(6) To encourage the Secretary to work with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, and Congress, to ensure covered veterans are provided the full benefits of their status as covered veterans.

(7) To highlight contributions of covered veterans in the Armed Forces.

(8) To conduct other duties as determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(c) Membership.—(1) The Committee shall be comprised of 15 voting members appointed by the Secretary.

(2) In appointing members pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure the following:(A) At least one member is appointed to represent covered veterans in each of the following areas:(i) American Samoa.

(ii) Guam.

(iii) Puerto Rico.

(iv) The Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.

(v) The Virgin Islands of the United States.

(vi) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the “Advisory Committee on United States Outlying Areas and Freely Associated States”, to provide advice and guidance to the Secretary on matters relating to covered veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The duties of the Committee shall be the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms; Vacancies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meeting Format and Frequency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Representation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee Personnel Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A member of the Committee shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for an employee of an agency under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from the home or regular place of business of the member in the performance of the duties of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_548_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with veterans service organizations serving covered veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>