<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6106"><akn:num>6106</akn:num><akn:heading>Misuse of benefits by fiduciaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6106. Misuse of benefits by fiduciaries(a) Fee Forfeiture in Case of Benefit Misuse by Fiduciaries.—A fiduciary may not collect a fee from a beneficiary for any month with respect to which the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction has determined that the fiduciary misused all or part of the individual’s benefit, and any amount so collected by the fiduciary as a fee for such month shall be treated as a misused part of the individual’s benefit.

(b) Misuse of Benefits Defined.—For purposes of this chapter, misuse of benefits by a fiduciary occurs in any case in which the fiduciary receives payment, under any of laws administered by the Secretary, for the use and benefit of a beneficiary and uses such payment, or any part thereof, for a use other than for the use and benefit of such beneficiary or that beneficiary’s dependents. Retention by a fiduciary of an amount of a benefit payment as a fiduciary fee or commission, or as attorney’s fees (including expenses) and court costs, if authorized by the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction, shall be considered to be for the use or benefit of such beneficiary.

(c) Regulations.—The Secretary may prescribe by regulation the meaning of the term “use and benefit” for purposes of this section.

(Added Pub. L. 108–454, title V, § 503(a)(1), Dec. 10, 2004, 118 Stat. 3619.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable with respect to any determinations by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs made after Dec. 10, 2004, of misuse of funds by a fiduciary, see section 507(b)(2) of Pub. L. 108–454, set out as an Effective Date of 2004 Amendment note under section 5312 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee Forfeiture in Case of Benefit Misuse by Fiduciaries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A fiduciary may not collect a fee from a beneficiary for any month with respect to which the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction has determined that the fiduciary misused all or part of the individual’s benefit, and any amount so collected by the fiduciary as a fee for such month shall be treated as a misused part of the individual’s benefit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Misuse of Benefits Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this chapter, misuse of benefits by a fiduciary occurs in any case in which the fiduciary receives payment, under any of laws administered by the Secretary, for the use and benefit of a beneficiary and uses such payment, or any part thereof, for a use other than for the use and benefit of such beneficiary or that beneficiary’s dependents. Retention by a fiduciary of an amount of a benefit payment as a fiduciary fee or commission, or as attorney’s fees (including expenses) and court costs, if authorized by the Secretary or a court of competent jurisdiction, shall be considered to be for the use or benefit of such beneficiary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may prescribe by regulation the meaning of the term “use and benefit” for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>