<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/6307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6307"><akn:num>6307</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to States and Indian Tribes to improve outreach to veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6307. Grants to States and Indian Tribes to improve outreach to veterans(a) Purpose.—It is the purpose of this section to provide for assistance by the Secretary to States and Indian Tribes to carry out programs that improve covered outreach and assistance to veterans and the spouses, children, and parents of veterans, to ensure that such individuals are fully informed about, and assisted in applying for, any veterans and veterans-related benefits and programs (including veterans programs of a State or Indian Tribe) for which they may be eligible and facilitate opportunities for such individuals to receive competent, qualified services in the preparation, presentation and prosecution of veterans benefits claims.

(b) Authority.—The Secretary may award grants to States and Indian Tribes—(1) to carry out, coordinate, improve, or otherwise enhance—(A) covered outreach activities; or

(B) activities to assist in the development and submittal of claims for veterans and veterans-related benefits; or


(2) to increase the number of county or Tribal veterans service officers serving in the State by hiring new, additional such officers.


(c) Application.—(1) To be eligible for a grant under this section, a State or Indian Tribe shall submit to the Secretary an application therefor at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.

(2) Each application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) A detailed plan for the use of the grant.

(B) A description of the programs through which the State or Indian Tribe will meet the outcome measures developed by the Secretary under subsection (j).

(C) A description of how the State or Indian Tribe will distribute grant amounts equitably among counties or Tribal lands with varying levels of urbanization.

(D) A plan for how the grant will be used to meet the unique needs of American Indian veterans, Alaska Native veterans, or Native Hawaiian veterans, elderly veterans, and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) It is the purpose of this section to provide for assistance by the Secretary to States and Indian Tribes to carry out programs that improve covered outreach and assistance to veterans and the spouses, children, and parents of veterans, to ensure that such individuals are fully informed about, and assisted in applying for, any veterans and veterans-related benefits and programs (including veterans programs of a State or Indian Tribe) for which they may be eligible and facilitate opportunities for such individuals to receive competent, qualified services in the preparation, presentation and prosecution of veterans benefits claims.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may award grants to States and Indian Tribes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall seek to ensure that grants awarded under this section are equitably distributed among States and Indian Tribes with varying levels of urbanization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set-aside.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for grants under this section for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall ensure that not less than five percent is used to make grants to Indian Tribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants under this section that will serve the following areas:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of County or Tribal Veterans Service Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A State or Indian Tribe that receives a grant under this section to carry out an activity described in subsection (b)(1) shall carry out the activity through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Any grant awarded under this section shall be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A grant under this section may be used to provide education and training, including on-the-job training, for State, county, local, and Tribal government employees who provide (or when trained will provide) covered outreach services in order for those employees to obtain accreditation in accordance with procedures approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6307_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outcome Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>