<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7107" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7107/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7107/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7107"><akn:num>7107</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals: dockets; hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7107. Appeals: dockets; hearings(a) Dockets.—(1) Subject to paragraph (2), the Board shall maintain at least two separate dockets.

(2) The Board may not maintain more than two separate dockets unless the Board notifies the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives of any additional docket, including a justification for maintaining such additional docket.

(3)(A) The Board may assign to each docket maintained under paragraph (1) such cases as the Board considers appropriate, except that cases described in clause (i) of subparagraph (B) may not be assigned to any docket to which cases described in clause (ii) of such paragraph are assigned.

(B) Cases described in this paragraph are the following:(i) Cases in which no Board hearing is requested.

(ii) Cases in which a Board hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement.



(4) Except as provided in subsection (b), each case before the Board will be decided in regular order according to its respective place on the docket to which it is assigned by the Board.


(b) Advancement on the Docket.—(1) A case on one of the dockets of the Board maintained under subsection (a) may, for cause shown, be advanced on motion for earlier consideration and determination.

(2) Any such motion shall set forth succinctly the grounds upon which the motion is based.

(3) Such a motion may be granted only—(A) if the case involves interpretation of law of general application affecting other claims;

(B) if the appellant is seriously ill or is under severe financial hardship; or

(C) for other sufficient cause shown.



(c) Manner and Scheduling of Hearings for Cases on a Docket That May Include a Hearing.—(1) For cases on a docket maintained by the Board under subsection (a) that may include a hearing, in which a hearing is requested in the notice of disagreement, the Board shall notify the appellant whether a Board hearing will be held—(A) at its principal loca</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7107_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dockets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7107_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advancement on the Docket.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7107_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner and Scheduling of Hearings for Cases on a Docket That May Include a Hearing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7107_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Screening of Cases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the screening of cases for purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7107_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy on Changing Dockets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall develop and implement a policy allowing an appellant to move the appellant’s case from one docket to another docket.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>