<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7253"><akn:num>7253</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7253. Composition(a) Composition.—The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is composed of at least three and not more than seven judges, one of whom shall serve as chief judge in accordance with subsection (d).

(b) Appointment.—The judges of the Court shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, solely on the grounds of fitness to perform the duties of the office. A person may not be appointed to the Court who is not a member in good standing of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State. Not more than the number equal to the next whole number greater than one-half of the number of judges of the Court may be members of the same political party.

(c) Term of Office.—The term of office of the judges of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be 15 years. A judge who is nominated by the President for appointment to an additional term on the Court without a break in service and whose term of office expires while that nomination is pending before the Senate may continue in office for up to 1 year while that nomination is pending.

(d) Chief Judge.—(1) The chief judge of the Court is the head of the Court. The chief judge of the Court shall be the judge of the Court in regular active service who is senior in commission among the judges of the Court who—(A) have served for one or more years as judges of the Court;

(B) have at least 3 years remaining in term of office; and

(C) have not previously served as chief judge.


(2)(A) In any case in which there is no judge of the Court in regular active service who meets the requirements under paragraph (1), the judge of the Court in regular active service who is senior in commission and meets subparagraph (A) or (B) and subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) shall act as the chief judge.

(B) In any case under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph in which there is no judge of the Court in regular active service who meets subparagraph (A) or (B) and subparagraph (C)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims is composed of at least three and not more than seven judges, one of whom shall serve as chief judge in accordance with subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The judges of the Court shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, solely on the grounds of fitness to perform the duties of the office. A person may not be appointed to the Court who is not a member in good standing of the bar of a Federal court or of the highest court of a State. Not more than the number equal to the next whole number greater than one-half of the number of judges of the Court may be members of the same political party.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term of office of the judges of the Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims shall be 15 years. A judge who is nominated by the President for appointment to an additional term on the Court without a break in service and whose term of office expires while that nomination is pending before the Senate may continue in office for up to 1 year while that nomination is pending.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Judge.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each judge of the Court shall receive a salary at the same rate as is received by judges of the United States district courts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary Expansion of Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7253_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Temporary Expansion of Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>