<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7306"><akn:num>7306</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of the Under Secretary for Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7306. Office of the Under Secretary for Health(a) The Office of the Under Secretary for Health shall consist of the following:(1) The Deputy Under Secretary for Health, who shall be the principal assistant of the Under Secretary for Health and who shall be a qualified doctor of medicine.

(2) The Associate Deputy Under Secretary for Health, who shall be an assistant to the Under Secretary for Health and the Deputy Under Secretary for Health and who shall be a qualified doctor of medicine.

(3) Not to exceed eight Assistant Under Secretaries for Health.

(4) Such Medical Directors as may be appointed to suit the needs of the Department, who shall be either a qualified doctor of medicine or a qualified doctor of dental surgery or dental medicine.

(5) A Director of Nursing Service, who shall be a qualified registered nurse and who shall be responsible to, and report directly to, the Under Secretary for Health for the operation of the Nursing Service.

(6) A Director of Pharmacy Service, a Director of Dietetic Service, and a Director of Optometric Service, who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Health for the operation of their respective Services.

(7) Such directors of such other professional or auxiliary services as may be appointed to suit the needs of the Department, who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Health for the operation of their respective services.

(8) The Director of the National Center for Preventive Health, who shall be responsible to the Under Secretary for Health for the operation of the Center.

(9) The Director of Physician Assistant Services, who shall—(A) serve in a full-time capacity at the Central Office of the Department;

(B) be a qualified physician assistant; and

(C) be responsible and report directly to the Chief Patient Care Services Officer of the Veterans Health Administration on all matters relating to the education and training, employment, appropriate use, and optimal participation of physician assista</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Office of the Under Secretary for Health shall consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointments under subsection (a) shall be made by the Secretary. In the case of appointments under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (8), and (10) of that subsection, such appointments shall be made upon the recommendation of the Under Secretary for Health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as provided in subsection (d)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In organizing the Office and appointing persons to positions in the Office, the Under Secretary shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) For purposes of applying any provision of chapter 74 of this title, including sections 7404, 7410, and 7421, or any other provision of law, the Secretary may treat any appointment for a position under this chapter to be an appointment under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>