<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7310"><akn:num>7310</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Women’s Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7310. Office of Women’s Health(a) Establishment.—(1) The Under Secretary for Health shall establish and operate in the Veterans Health Administration the Office of Women’s Health (in this section referred to as the “Office”).

(2) The Office shall be located at the Central Office of the Department of Veterans Affairs.

(3)(A) The head of the Office is the Chief Officer of Women’s Health (in this section referred to as the “Chief Officer”).

(B) The Chief Officer shall report to the Under Secretary for Health.


(4) The Under Secretary for Health shall provide the Office with such staff and other support as may be necessary for the Office to carry out effectively the functions of the Office under this section.

(5) The Under Secretary for Health may reorganize existing offices within the Veterans Health Administration as of the date of the enactment of this section in order to avoid duplication with the functions of the Office.


(b) Functions.—The functions of the Office include the following:(1) To provide a central office for monitoring and encouraging the activities of the Veterans Health Administration with respect to the provision, evaluation, and improvement of health care services provided to women veterans by the Department.

(2) To develop and implement standards of care for the provision of health care for women veterans by the Department.

(3) To monitor and identify deficiencies in standards of care for the provision of health care for women veterans by the Department, to provide technical assistance to medical facilities of the Department to address and remedy deficiencies, and to perform oversight of implementation of such standards of care.

(4) To monitor and identify deficiencies in standards of care for the provision of health care for women veterans provided through the community pursuant to this title and to provide recommendations to the appropriate office to address and remedy any deficiencies.

(5) To oversee distribution of resources and in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The functions of the Office include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For purposes of carrying out the functions of the Office under this section, the standards of care for the provision of health care for women veterans from the Department shall include, at a minimum, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Chief Officer shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>