<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7310A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7310A"><akn:num>7310A</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports on Women’s Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7310A. Annual reports on Women’s Health(a) Annual Reports.—Not later than December 1 of each year, the Chief Officer of Women’s Health shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the matters under subsections (b) through (g).

(b) Office of Women’s Health.—Each report under subsection (a) shall include a description of—(1) actions taken by the Office of Women’s Health established under section 7310 of this title in the preceding fiscal year to improve the provision of health care by the Department to women veterans;

(2) any identified deficiencies related to the provision of health care by the Department to women veterans and the standards of care established in such section and the plan of the Department to address such deficiencies;

(3) the funding and personnel provided to the Office and whether additional funding or personnel are needed to meet the requirements of such section; and

(4) other information that would be of interest to the appropriate congressional committees with respect to oversight of the provision of health care by the Department to women veterans.


(c) Access to Gender-specific Services.—(1) Each report under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of the access of women veterans to gender-specific services under contracts, agreements, or other arrangements with non-Department medical providers entered into by the Secretary for the provision of hospital care or medical services to veterans.

(2) The analysis under paragraph (1) shall include data and performance measures for the availability of gender-specific services described in such paragraph, including—(A) the average wait time between the preferred appointment date of the veteran and the date on which the appointment is completed;

(B) the average driving time required for veterans to attend appointments; and

(C) reasons why appointments could not be scheduled with non-Department medical providers.



(d) Models of Care.—(1) Each report under subse</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than December 1 of each year, the Chief Officer of Women’s Health shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report containing the matters under subsections (b) through (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Women’s Health.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each report under subsection (a) shall include a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Gender-specific Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Models of Care.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staffing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each report under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of the staffing of the Department relating to the treatment of women, including the following, disaggregated by Veterans Integrated Service Network and State (except with respect to paragraph (4)):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessibility and Treatment Options.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Each report under subsection (a) shall include an analysis of the accessibility and treatment options for women veterans, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7310A_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>