<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7327" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7327/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7327/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7327"><akn:num>7327</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers for research, education, and clinical activities on complex multi-trauma associated with com</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7327. Centers for research, education, and clinical activities on complex multi-trauma associated with combat injuries(a) Purpose.—The purpose of this section is to provide for the improvement of the provision of health care services and related rehabilitation and education services to eligible veterans suffering from complex multi-trauma associated with combat injuries through—(1) the development of improved models and systems for the furnishing by the Department of health care, rehabilitation, and education services to veterans;

(2) the conduct of research to support the provision of such services in accordance with the most current evidence on multi-trauma injuries; and

(3) the education and training of health care personnel of the Department with respect to the provision of such services.


(b) Designation of Centers.—(1) The Secretary shall designate an appropriate number of cooperative centers for clinical care, consultation, research, and education activities on combat injuries.

(2) Each center designated under paragraph (1) shall function as a center for—(A) research on the long-term effects of injuries sustained as a result of combat in order to support the provision of services for such injuries in accordance with the most current evidence on complex multi-trauma;

(B) the development of rehabilitation methodologies for treating individuals with complex multi-trauma; and

(C) the continuous and consistent coordination of care from the point of referral throughout the rehabilitation process and ongoing follow-up after return to home and community.


(3) The Secretary shall designate one of the centers designated under paragraph (1) as the lead center for activities referred to in that paragraph. As the lead center for such activities, such center shall—(A) develop and provide periodic review of research priorities, and implement protocols, to ensure that projects contribute to the activities of the centers designated under paragraph (1);

(B) oversee t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The purpose of this section is to provide for the improvement of the provision of health care services and related rehabilitation and education services to eligible veterans suffering from complex multi-trauma associated with combat injuries through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Centers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Centers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To be designated as a center under this section, a facility shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall provide each center designated under this section such resources as the Secretary determines to be required by such center to achieve adequate capability of managing individuals with complex multi-trauma, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation With Department of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Centers designated under this section may compete for the award of funding from amounts appropriated for the Department for medical and prosthetics research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Oversight.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Under Secretary for Health shall designate an appropriate officer to oversee the operation of the centers designated under this section and provide for periodic evaluation of the centers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7327_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>