<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7402"><akn:num>7402</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications of appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7402. Qualifications of appointees(a) To be eligible for appointment to the positions in the Administration covered by subsection (b), a person must have the applicable qualifications set forth in that subsection.

(b)(1) Physician.—To be eligible to be appointed to a physician position, a person must—(A) hold the degree of doctor of medicine or of doctor of osteopathy from a college or university approved by the Secretary,

(B) have completed an internship satisfactory to the Secretary, and

(C) be licensed to practice medicine, surgery, or osteopathy in a State.


(2) Dentist.—To be eligible to be appointed to a dentist position, a person must—(A) hold the degree of doctor of dental surgery or dental medicine from a college or university approved by the Secretary, and

(B) be licensed to practice dentistry in a State.


(3) Nurse.—To be eligible to be appointed to a nurse position, a person must—(A) have successfully completed a full course of nursing in a recognized school of nursing, approved by the Secretary, and

(B) be registered as a graduate nurse in a State.


(4) Director of a Hospital, Domiciliary, Center, or Outpatient Clinic.—To be eligible to be appointed to a director position, a person must have such business and administrative experience and qualifications as the Secretary shall prescribe.

(5) Podiatrist.—To be eligible to be appointed to a podiatrist position, a person must—(A) hold the degree of doctor of podiatric medicine, or its equivalent, from a school of podiatric medicine approved by the Secretary, and

(B) be licensed to practice podiatry in a State.


(6) Optometrist.—To be eligible to be appointed to an optometrist position, a person must—(A) hold the degree of doctor of optometry, or its equivalent, from a school of optometry approved by the Secretary, and

(B) be licensed to practice optometry in a State.


(7) Pharmacist.—To be eligible to be appointed to a pharmacist position, a person must—(A) hold the degree of bachelor of scie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To be eligible for appointment to the positions in the Administration covered by subsection (b), a person must have the applicable qualifications set forth in that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as provided in section 7407(a) of this title, a person may not be appointed in the Administration to a position listed in section 7401(1) of this title unless the person is a citizen of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A person may not be appointed under section 7401(1) of this title to serve in the Administration in any direct patient-care capacity unless the Under Secretary for Health determines that the person possesses such basic proficiency in spoken and written English as will permit such degree of communication with patients and other health-care personnel as will enable the person to carry out the person’s health-care responsibilities satisfactorily. Any determination by the Under Secretary for Health under this subsection shall be in accordance with regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A person may not serve as Chief of Staff of a Department health-care facility if the person is not serving on a full-time basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A person may not be employed in a position under subsection (b) (other than under paragraph (4) of that subsection) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may enter into contracts with not-for-profit entities to provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>