<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7802"><akn:num>7802</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary with respect to Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7802. Duties of Secretary with respect to Service(a) Locations for Canteens.—The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate canteens where deemed necessary and practicable at hospitals and homes of the Department and at other Department establishments where similar essential facilities are not reasonably available from outside commercial sources.

(b) Warehouses and Storage Depots.—The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate such warehouses and storage depots as may be necessary in operating the canteens.

(c) Space, Buildings, and Structures.—The Secretary shall furnish the Service for its use in connection with the establishment, maintenance, and operation thereof, such space, buildings, and structures under control of the Department as the Secretary may consider necessary, including normal maintenance and repair service thereon. Reasonable charges, to be determined by the Secretary, shall be paid annually by the Service for the space, buildings, and structures so furnished, except that the Secretary may reduce or waive such charges whenever payment of such charges would impair the working capital required by the Service.

(d) Equipment, Services, and Utilities.—The Secretary shall transfer to the Service without charge, rental, or reimbursement such necessary equipment as may not be needed for other purposes, and furnish the Service such services and utilities, including light, water, and heat, as may be available and necessary for its use. Reasonable charges, to be determined by the Secretary, shall be paid annually by the Service for the utilities so furnished.

(e) Personnel.—The Secretary shall employ such persons as are necessary for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of the Service, and pay the salaries, wages, and expenses of all such employees from the funds of the Service. Personnel necessary for the transaction of the business of the Service at canteens, warehouses, and storage depots shall be appointed, compensated from fund</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Locations for Canteens.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate canteens where deemed necessary and practicable at hospitals and homes of the Department and at other Department establishments where similar essential facilities are not reasonably available from outside commercial sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warehouses and Storage Depots.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate such warehouses and storage depots as may be necessary in operating the canteens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Space, Buildings, and Structures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall furnish the Service for its use in connection with the establishment, maintenance, and operation thereof, such space, buildings, and structures under control of the Department as the Secretary may consider necessary, including normal maintenance and repair service thereon. Reasonable charges, to be determined by the Secretary, shall be paid annually by the Service for the space, buildings, and structures so furnished, except that the Secretary may reduce or waive such charges whenever payment of such charges would impair the working capital required by the Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment, Services, and Utilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall transfer to the Service without charge, rental, or reimbursement such necessary equipment as may not be needed for other purposes, and furnish the Service such services and utilities, including light, water, and heat, as may be available and necessary for its use. Reasonable charges, to be determined by the Secretary, shall be paid annually by the Service for the utilities so furnished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall employ such persons as are necessary for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of the Service, and pay the salaries, wages, and expenses of all such employees from the funds of the Service. Personnel necessary for the transaction of the business of the Service at canteens, warehouses, and storage depots shall be appointed, compensated from funds of the Service, and removed by the Secretary without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service and chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5. Those employees are subject to the provisions of title 5 relating to a preference eligible described in section 2108(3) of title 5, subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5, and subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5. An employee appointed under this section may be considered for appointment to a Department position in the competitive service in the same manner that a Department employee in the competitive service is co</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts and Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall make all necessary contracts or agreements to purchase or sell merchandise, fixtures, equipment, supplies, and services, without regard to section 6101(b) to (d) of title 41 and to do all things necessary to carry out such contracts or agreements, including the making of necessary adjustments and compromising of claims in connection therewith.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall fix the prices of merchandise and services in canteens so as to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts and Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary may accept gifts and donations of merchandise, fixtures, equipment, and supplies for the use and benefit of the Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary shall make such rules and regulations, not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, as the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate to effectuate its purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7802_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary may delegate such duties and powers to employees as the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate, whose official acts performed within the scope of the delegated authority shall have the same force and effect as though performed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>