<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/7902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7902"><akn:num>7902</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7902. Scholarship program(a) Authority.—(1) Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary may establish a scholarship program under which the Secretary shall, subject to subsection (d), provide financial assistance in accordance with this section to a qualified person—(A) who is pursuing a doctoral degree in computer science or electrical or computer engineering at an accredited institution of higher education; and

(B) who enters into an agreement with the Secretary as described in subsection (b).


(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may provide financial assistance under this section to an individual for up to five years.

(B) The Secretary may waive the limitation under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary determines that such a waiver is appropriate.



(b) Service Agreement for Scholarship Recipients.—(1) To receive financial assistance under this section an individual shall enter into an agreement to accept and continue employment in the Department for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2).

(2) For the purposes of this subsection, the period of obligated service for a recipient of financial assistance under this section shall be the period determined by the Secretary as being appropriate to obtain adequate service in exchange for the financial assistance and otherwise to achieve the goals set forth in section 7901(a) of this title. In no event may the period of service required of a recipient be less than the period equal to the total period of pursuit of a degree for which the Secretary agrees to provide the recipient with financial assistance under this section. The period of obligated service is in addition to any other period for which the recipient is obligated to serve on active duty or in the civil service, as the case may be.

(3) An agreement entered into under this section by a person pursuing a doctoral degree shall include terms that provide the following:(A) That the period of oblig</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service Agreement for Scholarship Recipients.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment for Period of Unserved Obligated Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver or Suspension of Compliance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations providing for the waiver or suspension of any obligation of an individual for service or payment under this section (or an agreement under this section) whenever noncompliance by the individual is due to circumstances beyond the control of the individual or whenever the Secretary determines that the waiver or suspension of compliance is in the best interest of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility of Individuals Receiving Montgomery GI Bill Education Assistance Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An individual who receives a payment of educational assistance under chapter 30, 31, 32, 34, or 35 of this title or chapter 1606 or 1607 of title 10 for a month in which the individual is enrolled in a course of education leading to a doctoral degree in information security is not eligible to receive financial assistance under this section for that month.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>