<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8103"><akn:num>8103</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to construct and alter, and to acquire sites for, medical facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8103. Authority to construct and alter, and to acquire sites for, medical facilities(a) Subject to section 8104 of this title, the Secretary—(1) may construct or alter any medical facility and may acquire, by purchase, lease, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, such land or interests in land as the Secretary considers necessary for use as the site for such construction or alteration;

(2) may acquire, by purchase, lease, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, any facility (including the site of such facility) that the Secretary considers necessary for use as a medical facility; and

(3) in order to assure compliance with section 8110(a)(2) of this title, in the case of any outpatient medical facility for which it is proposed to lease space and for which a qualified lessor and an appropriate leasing arrangement are available, shall execute a lease for such facility within 12 months after funds are made available for such purpose.


(b) Whenever the Secretary considers it to be in the interest of the United States to construct a new medical facility to replace an existing medical facility, the Secretary (1) may demolish the existing facility and use the site on which it is located for the site of the new medical facility, or (2) if in the judgment of the Secretary it is more advantageous to construct such medical facility on a different site in the same locality, may exchange such existing facility and the site of such existing facility for the different site.

(c) Whenever the Secretary determines that any site acquired for the construction of a medical facility is not suitable for that purpose, the Secretary may exchange such site for another site to be used for that purpose or may sell such site.

(d)(1) The Secretary may provide for the acquisition of not more than three facilities for the provision of outpatient services or nursing home care through lease-purchase arrangements on real property under the jurisdiction of the Department of Vet</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to section 8104 of this title, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Whenever the Secretary considers it to be in the interest of the United States to construct a new medical facility to replace an existing medical facility, the Secretary (1) may demolish the existing facility and use the site on which it is located for the site of the new medical facility, or (2) if in the judgment of the Secretary it is more advantageous to construct such medical facility on a different site in the same locality, may exchange such existing facility and the site of such existing facility for the different site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever the Secretary determines that any site acquired for the construction of a medical facility is not suitable for that purpose, the Secretary may exchange such site for another site to be used for that purpose or may sell such site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall use industry standards, standard designs, and best practices in carrying out the construction of medical facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>