<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8109" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8109/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8109/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8109"><akn:num>8109</akn:num><akn:heading>Parking facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8109. Parking facilities(a) For the purpose of this section—(1) The term “garage” means a structure (or part of a structure) in which vehicles may be parked.

(2) The term “parking facility” includes—(A) a surface parking lot; and

(B) a garage.


(3) The term “eligible person” means an individual to whom the Secretary is authorized to furnish medical examination or treatment.


(b) In order to accommodate the vehicles of employees of medical facilities, vehicles used to transport veterans and eligible persons to or from such facilities for the purpose of examination or treatment, and the vehicles of visitors and other individuals having business at such facilities, the Secretary—(1) may construct or alter parking facilities, and may acquire, by purchase, lease, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, such land or interests in land as the Secretary considers necessary for use as the site for any such construction or alteration;

(2) may acquire, by purchase, lease, condemnation, donation, exchange, or otherwise, any facility that the Secretary considers necessary for use as a parking facility;

(3) may operate and maintain parking facilities; and

(4) notwithstanding subsection (a) of section 1344 of title 31, may use a passenger carrier (as such term is defined in subsection (h)(1) of such section) to transport such an employee between a parking facility and the medical facility of the Department at which the employee works.


(c)(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, each employee, visitor, and other individual having business at a medical facility for which parking fees have been established under subsection (d) or (e) of this section shall be charged the applicable parking fee for the use of a parking facility at such medical facility.

(2) A parking fee shall not be charged under this subsection for the accommodation of any vehicle used to transport to or from a medical facility—(A) a veteran or eligible person in connection with </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In order to accommodate the vehicles of employees of medical facilities, vehicles used to transport veterans and eligible persons to or from such facilities for the purpose of examination or treatment, and the vehicles of visitors and other individuals having business at such facilities, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary may prescribe a schedule of parking fees for the parking facilities at any medical facility not referred to in subsection (d) of this section. Any such schedule shall be designed to establish fees which the Secretary determines to be reasonable under the circumstances and shall cover all parking facilities used in connection with such medical facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary may contract (by lease or otherwise) for the operation of parking facilities at medical facilities under such terms and conditions as the Secretary prescribes and may do so without regard to laws requiring full and open competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subject to subsections (h) and (i) of this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such amounts as are necessary to finance (in whole or in part) the construction, alteration, and acquisition (including site acquisition) of parking facilities at medical facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8109_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Funds in a construction account or capital account that are available for a construction project or a nonrecurring maintenance project may be used for the construction or relocation of a surface parking lot incidental to that project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>