<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111A" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111A/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111A/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8111A"><akn:num>8111A</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing of health-care services to members of the Armed Forces during a war or national emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8111A. Furnishing of health-care services to members of the Armed Forces during a war or national emergency(a)(1) During and immediately following a period of war, or a period of national emergency declared by the President or the Congress that involves the use of the Armed Forces in armed conflict, the Secretary may furnish hospital care, nursing home care, and medical services to members of the Armed Forces on active duty.

(2)(A) During and immediately following a disaster or emergency referred to in subparagraph (B), the Secretary may furnish hospital care and medical services to members of the Armed Forces on active duty responding to or involved in that disaster or emergency.

(B) A disaster or emergency referred to in this subparagraph is any disaster or emergency as follows:(i) A major disaster or emergency declared by the President under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.).

(ii) A disaster or emergency in which the National Disaster Medical System established pursuant to section 2812 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 300hh) 11 See References in Text note below. is activated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under that section or as otherwise authorized by law.



(3) The Secretary may give a higher priority to the furnishing of care and services under this section than to the furnishing of care and services to any other group of persons eligible for care and services in medical facilities of the Department with the exception of veterans with service-connected disabilities.

(4) For the purposes of this section, the terms “hospital care”, “nursing home care”, and “medical services” have the meanings given such terms by sections 1701(5), 101(28), and 1701(6) of this title, respectively, and the term “medical services” includes services under sections 1782 and 1783 of this title.


(b)(1) During a period in which the Secretary is authorized to furnish care and services to members</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111A_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111A_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111A_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111A_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111A_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to govern any exercise of the authority of the Secretary under subsections (a) and (b) of this section and of the Under Secretary for Health under subsection (b)(2)(A) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>