<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8111/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8111"><akn:num>8111</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense health care resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8111. Sharing of Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense health care resources(a) Required Coordination and Sharing of Health Care Resources.—The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall enter into agreements and contracts for the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of use of the health care resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense with the goal of improving the access to, and quality and cost effectiveness of, the health care provided by the Veterans Health Administration and the Military Health System to the beneficiaries of both Departments.

(b) Joint Requirements for Secretaries of Veterans Affairs and Defense.—To facilitate the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of use of the health care resources of the two Departments, the two Secretaries shall carry out the following functions:(1) Develop and publish a joint strategic vision statement and a joint strategic plan to shape, focus, and prioritize the coordination and sharing efforts among appropriate elements of the two Departments and incorporate the goals and requirements of the joint sharing plan into the strategic plan of each Department under section 306 of title 5 and the performance plan of each Department under section 1115 of title 31.

(2) Jointly fund the Department of Veterans Affairs-Department of Defense Joint Executive Committee under section 320 of this title.

(3) Continue to facilitate and improve sharing between individual Department of Veterans Affairs and Department of Defense health care facilities, but giving priority of effort to initiatives (A) that improve sharing and coordination of health resources at the intraregional and nationwide levels, and (B) that improve the ability of both Departments to provide coordinated health care.

(4) Establish a joint incentive program under subsection (d).


[(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 583(b)(1), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Coordination and Sharing of Health Care Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense shall enter into agreements and contracts for the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of use of the health care resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense with the goal of improving the access to, and quality and cost effectiveness of, the health care provided by the Veterans Health Administration and the Military Health System to the beneficiaries of both Departments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Requirements for Secretaries of Veterans Affairs and Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To facilitate the mutually beneficial coordination, use, or exchange of use of the health care resources of the two Departments, the two Secretaries shall carry out the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 583(b)(1), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1491.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Incentives Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines and Policies for Implementation of Coordination and Sharing Recommendations, Contracts, and Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Joint Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8111_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For the purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>