<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8116"><akn:num>8116</akn:num><akn:heading>Nursing home revolving fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8116. Nursing home revolving fund(a)(1) Amounts realized from a transfer pursuant to section 8122(a)(2)(C) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall be administered as a revolving fund and shall be available without fiscal year limitation.

(2) The revolving fund shall be deposited in a checking account with the Treasurer of the United States.


(b)(1) The expenditure of funds from the revolving fund may be made only for the construction, alteration, and acquisition (including site acquisition) of nursing home facilities and may be made only as provided for in appropriation Acts.

(2) For the purpose of section 8104(a)(2) of this title, a bill, resolution, or amendment which provides that funds in the revolving fund may be expended for a project involving a total expenditure of more than $2,000,000 for the construction, alteration, or acquisition (including site acquisition) of a nursing home facility shall be considered to be a bill, resolution, or amendment making an appropriation which may be expended for a major medical facility project.


(Added Pub. L. 100–322, title II, § 205(a), May 20, 1988, 102 Stat. 512, § 5016; renumbered § 8116 and amended Pub. L. 102–40, title IV, § 402(b)(1), (d)(1), May 7, 1991, 105 Stat. 238, 239.)

Repeal of SectionPub. L. 108–422, title IV, § 411(c)(1),(f), Nov. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2389, 2390, provided that this section is repealed effective at the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs certifies to Congress that the Secretary is in compliance with section 1710B(b) of this title.

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 8122(a)(2) of this title, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was amended generally by Pub. L. 108–422, title IV, § 411(e)(1), Nov. 30, 2004, 118 Stat. 2389, and, as so amended, no longer contains a subpar. (C).

Amendments1991—Pub. L. 102–40, § 402(b)(1), renumbered section 5016 of this title as this section.
Pub. L. 102–40, § 402(d)(1), substitute</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>