<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8135"><akn:num>8135</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications with respect to projects; payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8135. Applications with respect to projects; payments(a) Any State desiring to receive assistance for a project for construction of State home facilities (or acquisition of a facility to be used as a State home facility) must submit to the Secretary an application. Such application shall set forth the following:(1) The amount of the grant requested with respect to such project which may not exceed 65 percent of the estimated cost of construction (or of the estimated cost of facility acquisition and construction) of such project.

(2) A description of the site for such project.

(3) Plans and specifications for such project in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to section 8134(a)(2) of this title.

(4) Reasonable assurance that upon completion of such project the facilities will be used principally to furnish to veterans the level of care for which such application is made and that not more than 25 percent of the bed occupancy at any one time will consist of patients who are not receiving such level of care as veterans.

(5) Reasonable assurance that title to such site is or will be vested solely in the applicant, a State home, or another agency or instrumentality of the State.

(6) Reasonable assurance that adequate financial support will be available for the construction of the project (or for facility acquisition and construction of the project) by July 1 of the fiscal year for which the application is approved and for its maintenance and operation when complete.

(7) Reasonable assurance that the State will make such reports in such form and containing such information as the Secretary may from time to time reasonably require, and give the Secretary, upon demand, access to the records upon which such information is based.

(8) Reasonable assurance that the rates of pay for laborers and mechanics engaged in construction of the project will be not less than the prevailing local wage rates for similar work as determined in accordance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any State desiring to receive assistance for a project for construction of State home facilities (or acquisition of a facility to be used as a State home facility) must submit to the Secretary an application. Such application shall set forth the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No application submitted to the Secretary under this section shall be disapproved until the Secretary has afforded the applicant notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The amount of a grant under this subchapter shall be paid to the applicant or, if designated by the applicant, the State home for which such project is being carried out or any other agency or instrumentality of the applicant. Such amount shall be paid, in advance or by way of reimbursement, and in such installments consistent with the progress of the project as the Secretary may determine and certify for payment to the Secretary of the Treasury. Funds paid under this section for an approved project shall be used solely for carrying out such project as so approved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Any amendment of any application, whether or not approved, shall be subject to approval in the same manner as an original application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>