<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8162" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8162/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8162/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8162"><akn:num>8162</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced-use leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8162. Enhanced-use leases(a)(1) The Secretary may in accordance with this subchapter enter into leases with respect to real property that is under the jurisdiction or control of the Secretary. Any such lease under this subchapter may be referred to as an “enhanced-use lease”. The Secretary may dispose of any such property that is leased to another party under this subchapter in accordance with section 8164 of this title. The Secretary may exercise the authority provided by this subchapter notwithstanding section 8122 of this title, subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 40, sections 541–555 and 1302 of title 40, or any other provision of law (other than Federal laws relating to environmental and historic preservation) inconsistent with this section. The applicability of this subchapter to section 421(b) of the Veterans’ Benefits and Services Act of 1988 (Public Law 100–322; 102 Stat. 553) is covered by subsection (c).

(2)(A) The Secretary may enter into an enhanced-use lease on or after the date of the enactment of this paragraph only if the Secretary determines—(i) that the lease will not be inconsistent with, and will not adversely affect—(I) the mission of the Department; or

(II) the operation of facilities, programs, and services of the Department in the area of the leased property; and


(ii) that—(I) the lease will enhance the use of the leased property by directly or indirectly benefitting veterans; or

(II) the leased property will provide supportive housing.



(B) The Secretary shall give priority to enhanced-use leases that, on the leased property—(i) provide supportive housing for veterans;

(ii) provide direct services or benefits targeted to veterans; or

(iii) provide services or benefits that indirectly support veterans.



(3) The provisions of sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40 shall not, by reason of this section, become inapplicable to property that is leased to another party under an enhanced-use lease.

(4) A property that is lease</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8162_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8162_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8162_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The entering into an enhanced-use lease covering any land or improvement described in section 421(b)(2) of the Veterans’ Benefits and Services Act of 1988 (Public Law 100–322; 102 Stat. 553) or section 224(a) of the Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008, other than an enhanced-use lease under the Los Angeles Homeless Veterans Leasing Act of 2016, shall be considered to be prohibited by such sections unless specifically authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8162_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>