<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8168" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8168/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/8168/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8168"><akn:num>8168</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8168. Annual reports(a) Report on Administration of Leases.—(1) Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of the Honoring America’s Veterans and Caring for Camp Lejeune Families Act of 2012 and not less frequently than once each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional veterans’ affairs committees, the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on enhanced-use leases.

(2) Each report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) Identification of the actions taken by the Secretary to implement and administer enhanced-use leases.

(B) For the most recent fiscal year covered by the report, the amounts deposited into the Medical Care Collection Fund account that were derived from enhanced-use leases.

(C) Identification of the actions taken by the Secretary using the amounts described in subparagraph (B).

(D) Documents of the Department supporting the contents of the report described in subparagraphs (A) through (C).



(b) Report on Lease Consideration.—(1) Each year, as part of the annual budget submission of the President to the congressional veterans’ affairs committees, the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate under section 1105(a) of title 31, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional veterans’ affairs committees, the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and the Committees on the Budget of the House of Representatives and the Senate a detailed report of the consideration received by the Secretary for each enhanced-use lease under this subchapter.

(2) Each report under paragraph (1) shall include the following with respect to each enhanced-use lease covered by the report:(A) An overview of how the Secretary is using consideration re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8168_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on Administration of Leases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8168_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on Lease Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>