<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/38/902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_902"><akn:num>902</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement and arrest authority of Department police officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 902. Enforcement and arrest authority of Department police officers(a)(1) Employees of the Department who are Department police officers shall, with respect to acts occurring on Department property—(A) enforce Federal laws;

(B) enforce the rules prescribed under section 901 of this title;

(C) enforce traffic and motor vehicle laws of a State or local government (by issuance of a citation for violation of such laws) within the jurisdiction of which such Department property is located as authorized by an express grant of authority under applicable State or local law;

(D) carry the appropriate Department-issued weapons, including firearms, while off Department property in an official capacity or while in an official travel status;

(E) conduct investigations, on and off Department property, of offenses that may have been committed on property under the original jurisdiction of Department, consistent with agreements or other consultation with affected Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies; and

(F) carry out, as needed and appropriate, the duties described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) when engaged in duties authorized by other Federal statutes.


(2) Subject to regulations prescribed under subsection (b), a Department police officer may make arrests on Department property for a violation of a Federal law or any rule prescribed under section 901(a) of this title, and on any arrest warrant issued by competent judicial authority.

(3) Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of the Joseph Maxwell Cleland and Robert Joseph Dole Memorial Veterans Benefits and Health Care Improvement Act of 2022, the Secretary shall require Department police officers to use cameras worn on the individual police officer’s person that record and store audio and video (commonly known as “body worn cameras”).


(b) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations with respect to Department police officers. Such regulations shall include—(1) policies with res</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations with respect to Department police officers. Such regulations shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The powers granted to Department police officers designated under this section shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines approved by the Secretary and the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rates of basic pay for Department police officers may be increased by the Secretary under section 7455 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Police Incidents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>