<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/100" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/100/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/100/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_100"><akn:num>100</akn:num><akn:heading>Maryland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 100. Maryland
Maryland constitutes one judicial district comprising two divisions.(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Allegany, Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Caroline, Carroll, Cecil, Dorchester, Frederick, Garrett, Harford, Howard, Kent, Queen Anne’s, Somerset, Talbot, Washington, Wicomico, and Worcester, and the City of Baltimore.Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Baltimore, Cumberland, and Denton.


(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Calvert, Charles, Montgomery, Prince George’s, and St. Mary’s.Court for the Southern Division shall be held at a suitable site in Montgomery or Prince George’s County not more than five miles from the boundary of Montgomery and Prince George’s Counties.


(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 882; Pub. L. 91–546, § 4, Dec. 14, 1970, 84 Stat. 1412; Pub. L. 100–487, § 1, Oct. 14, 1988, 102 Stat. 2431.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 166 (Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 86, 36 Stat. 1114; Mar. 3, 1925, ch. 422, 43 Stat. 1106).
Provisions relating to appointment of a deputy clerk and a deputy marshal and the maintenance of offices by such deputies were omitted as covered by sections 541 [see 561], 542 [see 561], and 751 of this title.
The provisions respecting court accommodations at Denton were omitted as covered by section 142 of this title.
Changes in arrangement and phraseology were made.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Pub. L. 100–702 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section provided that Maryland constituted one judicial district and that court be held at Baltimore, Cumberland, Denton, and at a suitable site in Prince Georges County not more than five miles from the boundary of Montgomery and Prince Georges Counties.
1970—Pub. L. 91–546 added a suitable site in Prince Georges County not more than five miles from the boundary of Montgomery and Prince Georges Counties to the list of enumerated places for holding court in Maryland.

Statutory Notes an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_100_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Allegany, Anne Arundel, Baltimore, Caroline, Carroll, Cecil, Dorchester, Frederick, Garrett, Harford, Howard, Kent, Queen Anne’s, Somerset, Talbot, Washington, Wicomico, and Worcester, and the City of Baltimore.Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Baltimore, Cumberland, and Denton.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_100_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Calvert, Charles, Montgomery, Prince George’s, and St. Mary’s.Court for the Southern Division shall be held at a suitable site in Montgomery or Prince George’s County not more than five miles from the boundary of Montgomery and Prince George’s Counties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>