<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/129" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/129/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/129/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_129"><akn:num>129</akn:num><akn:heading>West Virginia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 129. West Virginia
West Virginia is divided into two judicial districts to be known as the Northern and Southern Districts of West Virginia.
Northern District
(a) The Northern District comprises the counties of Barbour, Berkeley, Braxton, Brooke, Calhoun, Doddridge, Gilmer, Grant, Hampshire, Hancock, Hardy, Harrison, Jefferson, Lewis, Marion, Marshall, Mineral, Monongalia, Morgan, Ohio, Pendleton, Pleasants, Pocahontas, Preston, Randolph, Ritchie, Taylor, Tucker, Tyler, Upshur, Webster, and Wetzel.
Court for the Northern District shall be held at Clarksburg, Elkins, Fairmont, Martinsburg, and Wheeling.
Southern District
(b) The Southern District comprises the counties of Boone, Cabell, Clay, Fayette, Greenbrier, Jackson, Kanawha, Lincoln, Logan, McDowell, Mason, Mercer, Mingo, Monroe, Nicholas, Putnam, Raleigh, Roane, Summers, Wayne, Wirt, Wood, and Wyoming.
Court for the Southern District shall be held at Beckley, Bluefield, Charleston, Huntington, Lewisburg, and Parkersburg.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 894; Pub. L. 97–471, § 1, Jan. 14, 1983, 96 Stat. 2601.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 194 (Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 113, 36 Stat. 1129; Mar. 23, 1912, ch. 63, 37 Stat. 76; Aug. 22, 1914, ch. 265, 38 Stat. 702; Feb. 27, 1922, ch. 83, 42 Stat. 398; June 22, 1936, ch. 695, 49 Stat. 1805; Aug. 23, 1937, ch. 737, 50 Stat. 744; June 29, 1938, ch. 817, 52 Stat. 1245).
Words “with the waters thereof,” after the list of counties in each district, were omitted as unnecessary, and in view of the absence of such words in similar sections relating to other States.
Provisions relating to special terms of court were omitted as covered by section 141 of this title.
A provision that the term at Fairmont be held “when suitable rooms and accommodations for holding terms of the court shall be furnished at Fairmont free of cost to the United States or until, subject to the recommendation of the Attorney General of the United States with re</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>