<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1390" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1390/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1390/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1390"><akn:num>1390</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1390. Scope(a) Venue Defined.—As used in this chapter, the term “venue” refers to the geographic specification of the proper court or courts for the litigation of a civil action that is within the subject-matter jurisdiction of the district courts in general, and does not refer to any grant or restriction of subject-matter jurisdiction providing for a civil action to be adjudicated only by the district court for a particular district or districts.

(b) Exclusion of Certain Cases.—Except as otherwise provided by law, this chapter shall not govern the venue of a civil action in which the district court exercises the jurisdiction conferred by section 1333, except that such civil actions may be transferred between district courts as provided in this chapter.

(c) Clarification Regarding Cases Removed From State Courts.—This chapter shall not determine the district court to which a civil action pending in a State court may be removed, but shall govern the transfer of an action so removed as between districts and divisions of the United States district courts.

(Added Pub. L. 112–63, title II, § 201(a), Dec. 7, 2011, 125 Stat. 762.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 112–63, title II, § 205, Dec. 7, 2011, 125 Stat. 764, provided that: 
“The amendments made by this title [enacting this section, amending sections 1391 and 1404 of this title, and repealing section 1392 of this title]—
“(1) shall take effect upon the expiration of the 30-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 7, 2011]; and

“(2) shall apply to—“(A) any action that is commenced in a United States district court on or after such effective date; and

“(B) any action that is removed from a State court to a United States district court and that had been commenced, within the meaning of State law, on or after such effective date.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1390_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) As used in this chapter, the term “venue” refers to the geographic specification of the proper court or courts for the litigation of a civil action that is within the subject-matter jurisdiction of the district courts in general, and does not refer to any grant or restriction of subject-matter jurisdiction providing for a civil action to be adjudicated only by the district court for a particular district or districts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1390_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of Certain Cases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as otherwise provided by law, this chapter shall not govern the venue of a civil action in which the district court exercises the jurisdiction conferred by section 1333, except that such civil actions may be transferred between district courts as provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1390_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification Regarding Cases Removed From State Courts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) This chapter shall not determine the district court to which a civil action pending in a State court may be removed, but shall govern the transfer of an action so removed as between districts and divisions of the United States district courts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>