<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1398" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1398/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1398/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1398"><akn:num>1398</akn:num><akn:heading>Interstate Commerce Commission’s orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1398. Interstate Commerce Commission’s orders(a) Except as otherwise provided by law, a civil action brought under section 1336(a) of this title shall be brought only in a judicial district in which any of the parties bringing the action resides or has its principal office.

(b) A civil action to enforce, enjoin, set aside, annul, or suspend, in whole or in part, an order of the Interstate Commerce Commission made pursuant to the referral of a question or issue by a district court or by the United States Court of Federal Claims, shall be brought only in the court which referred the question or issue.

(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 936; Pub. L. 88–513, § 2, Aug. 30, 1964, 78 Stat. 695; Pub. L. 93–584, § 2, Jan. 2, 1975, 88 Stat. 1917; Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 130, Apr. 2, 1982, 96 Stat. 39; Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1), Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4516.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 43 (Oct. 22, 1913, ch. 32, 38 Stat. 219).
This section is completely rewritten to give effect to changes recommended by the Judicial Conference of the United States.
Section 43 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., is as follows:
“§ 43. Venue of suits relating to orders of Interstate Commerce Commission.
“The venue of any suit brought to enforce, suspend, or set aside, in whole or in part, any order of the Interstate Commerce Commission shall be in the judicial district wherein is the residence of the party or any of the parties upon whose petition the order was made, except that where the order does not relate to transportation or is not made upon the petition of any party the venue shall be in the district where the matter complained of in the petition before the commission arises, and except that where the order does not relate either to transportation or to a matter so complained of before the commission the matter covered by the order shall be deemed to arise in the district where one of the petitioners in court has either its principal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as otherwise provided by law, a civil action brought under section 1336(a) of this title shall be brought only in a judicial district in which any of the parties bringing the action resides or has its principal office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1398_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A civil action to enforce, enjoin, set aside, annul, or suspend, in whole or in part, an order of the Interstate Commerce Commission made pursuant to the referral of a question or issue by a district court or by the United States Court of Federal Claims, shall be brought only in the court which referred the question or issue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>