<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_152"><akn:num>152</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of bankruptcy judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 152. Appointment of bankruptcy judges(a)(1) Each bankruptcy judge to be appointed for a judicial district, as provided in paragraph (2), shall be appointed by the court of appeals of the United States for the circuit in which such district is located. Such appointments shall be made after considering the recommendations of the Judicial Conference submitted pursuant to subsection (b). Each bankruptcy judge shall be appointed for a term of fourteen years, subject to the provisions of subsection (e). However, upon the expiration of the term, a bankruptcy judge may, with the approval of the judicial council of the circuit, continue to perform the duties of the office until the earlier of the date which is 180 days after the expiration of the term or the date of the appointment of a successor. Bankruptcy judges shall serve as judicial officers of the United States district court established under Article III of the Constitution.

(2) The bankruptcy judges appointed pursuant to this section shall be appointed for the several judicial districts as follows:






DistrictsJudges


Alabama:
Northern5
Middle2
Southern2
Alaska2
Arizona7
Arkansas:
Eastern and Western3
California:
Northern9
Eastern6
Central21
Southern4
Colorado5
Connecticut3
Delaware1
District of Columbia1
Florida:
Northern1
Middle8
Southern5
Georgia:
Northern8
Middle3
Southern2
Hawaii1
Idaho2
Illinois:
Northern10
Central3
Southern1
Indiana:
Northern3
Southern4
Iowa:
Northern2
Southern2
Kansas4
Kentucky:
Eastern2
Western3
Louisiana:
Eastern2
Middle1
Western3
Maine2
Maryland4
Massachusetts5
Michigan:
Eastern4
Western3
Minnesota4
Mississippi:
Northern1
Southern2
Missouri:
Eastern3
Western3
Montana1
Nebraska2
Nevada3
New Hampshire1
New Jersey8
New Mexico2
New York:
Northern2
Southern9
Eastern6
Western3
North Carolina:
Eastern2
Middle2
Western2
North Dakota1
Ohio:
Northern8
Southern7
Oklahoma:
Northern2
Eastern1
Western3
Oregon5
Pennsylvania:
Eastern5
Middle2
Western4
Puerto Rico2
Rhode Island1
South Carolina2
Sou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_152_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_152_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_152_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_152_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) With the approval of the Judicial Conference and of each of the judicial councils involved, a bankruptcy judge may be designated to serve in any district adjacent to or near the district for which such bankruptcy judge was appointed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_152_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A bankruptcy judge may be removed during the term for which such bankruptcy judge is appointed, only for incompetence, misconduct, neglect of duty, or physical or mental disability and only by the judicial council of the circuit in which the judge’s official duty station is located. Removal may not occur unless a majority of all of the judges of such council concur in the order of removal. Before any order of removal may be entered, a full specification of charges shall be furnished to such bankruptcy judge who shall be accorded an opportunity to be heard on such charges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>