<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1605"><akn:num>1605</akn:num><akn:heading>General exceptions to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1605. General exceptions to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state(a) A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of courts of the United States or of the States in any case—(1) in which the foreign state has waived its immunity either explicitly or by implication, notwithstanding any withdrawal of the waiver which the foreign state may purport to effect except in accordance with the terms of the waiver;

(2) in which the action is based upon a commercial activity carried on in the United States by the foreign state; or upon an act performed in the United States in connection with a commercial activity of the foreign state elsewhere; or upon an act outside the territory of the United States in connection with a commercial activity of the foreign state elsewhere and that act causes a direct effect in the United States;

(3) in which rights in property taken in violation of international law are in issue and that property or any property exchanged for such property is present in the United States in connection with a commercial activity carried on in the United States by the foreign state; or that property or any property exchanged for such property is owned or operated by an agency or instrumentality of the foreign state and that agency or instrumentality is engaged in a commercial activity in the United States;

(4) in which rights in property in the United States acquired by succession or gift or rights in immovable property situated in the United States are in issue;

(5) not otherwise encompassed in paragraph (2) above, in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for personal injury or death, or damage to or loss of property, occurring in the United States and caused by the tortious act or omission of that foreign state or of any official or employee of that foreign state while acting within the scope of his office or employment; except this paragraph shall not apply to—(A) any claim based upon the exercise or performance or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of courts of the United States or of the States in any case—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any case in which a suit in admiralty is brought to enforce a maritime lien against a vessel or cargo of the foreign state, which maritime lien is based upon a commercial activity of the foreign state: Provided, That—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever notice is delivered under subsection (b)(1), the suit to enforce a maritime lien shall thereafter proceed and shall be heard and determined according to the principles of law and rules of practice of suits in rem whenever it appears that, had the vessel been privately owned and possessed, a suit in rem might have been maintained. A decree against the foreign state may include costs of the suit and, if the decree is for a money judgment, interest as ordered by the court, except that the court may not award judgment against the foreign state in an amount greater than the value of the vessel or cargo upon which the maritime lien arose. Such value shall be determined as of the time notice is served under subsection (b)(1). Decrees shall be subject to appeal and revision as provided in other cases of admiralty and maritime jurisdiction. Nothing shall preclude the plaintiff in any proper case from seeking relief in personam in the same action brought to enforce a maritime lien a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any action brought to foreclose a preferred mortgage, as defined in section 31301 of title 46. Such action shall be brought, heard, and determined in accordance with the provisions of chapter 313 of title 46 and in accordance with the principles of law and rules of practice of suits in rem, whenever it appears that had the vessel been privately owned and possessed a suit in rem might have been maintained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) , (f) Repealed. Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1083(b)(1)(B), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 341.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Discovery.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1605_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdictional Immunity for Certain Art Exhibition Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>