<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1913" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1913/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/1913/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1913"><akn:num>1913</akn:num><akn:heading>Courts of appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1913. Courts of appeals
The fees and costs to be charged and collected in each court of appeals shall be prescribed from time to time by the Judicial Conference of the United States. Such fees and costs shall be reasonable and uniform in all the circuits.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 954.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 543 (Mar. 3, 1891, ch. 517, § 2, 26 Stat. 826; Feb. 19, 1897, ch. 263, 29 Stat. 536; Sept. 27, 1944, ch. 413, 58 Stat. 743).
Words “and in the United States Circuit Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia” were omitted as covered by “each court of appeals.”
Judicial Conference of Senior Circuit Judges was changed to Judicial Conference “of the United States” in conformity with section 331 of this title.
Changes were made in phraseology.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Appeals Filed in Courts of AppealsPub. L. 109–171, title X, § 10001(b), Feb. 8, 2006, 120 Stat. 183, provided that: “The $250 fee for docketing a case on appeal or review, or docketing any other proceeding, in a court of appeals, as prescribed by the Judicial Conference, effective as of January 1, 2005, under section 1913 of title 28, United States Code, shall be increased to $450.”


Court Fees for Electronic Access to InformationPub. L. 102–140, title III, § 303, Oct. 28, 1991, 105 Stat. 810, as amended by Pub. L. 104–317, title IV, § 403(b), Oct. 19, 1996, 110 Stat. 3854; Pub. L. 107–347, title II, § 205(e), Dec. 17, 2002, 116 Stat. 2915, provided that:
“(a) The Judicial Conference may, only to the extent necessary, prescribe reasonable fees, pursuant to sections 1913, 1914, 1926, 1930, and 1932 of title 28, United States Code, for collection by the courts under those sections for access to information available through automatic data processing equipment. These fees may distinguish between classes of persons, and shall provide for exempting persons or classes of persons from the fees, in order to avoid unreasonable burdens</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>