<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2323"><akn:num>2323</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Attorney General; intervenors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2323. Duties of Attorney General; intervenors
The Attorney General shall represent the Government in the actions specified in section 2321 of this title and in enforcement actions and actions to collect civil penalties under subtitle IV of title 49.
The Surface Transportation Board and any party or parties in interest to the proceeding before the Board, in which an order or requirement is made, may appear as parties of their own motion and as of right, and be represented by their counsel, in any action involving the validity of such order or requirement or any part thereof, and the interest of such party.
Communities, associations, corporations, firms, and individuals interested in the controversy or question before the Board, or in any action commenced under the aforesaid sections may intervene in said action at any time after commencement thereof.
The Attorney General shall not dispose of or discontinue said action or proceeding over the objection of such party or intervenor, who may prosecute, defend, or continue said action or proceeding unaffected by the action or nonaction of the Attorney General therein.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 970; May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 116, 63 Stat. 105; Pub. L. 93–584, § 6, Jan. 2, 1975, 88 Stat. 1917; Pub. L. 95–473, § 2(a)(3)(C), Oct. 17, 1978, 92 Stat. 1465; Pub. L. 104–88, title III, § 305(c)(1)(C), (D), Dec. 29, 1995, 109 Stat. 945.)

Historical and Revision Notes
1948 ActBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 45a (Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, §§ 212, 213, 36 Stat. 1150, 1151; Oct. 22, 1913, ch. 32, 38 Stat. 220).
The provision in the second sentence of section 45a of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., authorizing the Attorney General to employ and compensate special attorneys was omitted as covered by sections 503 and 508 [now 543 and 548] of this title. The provision in the same sentence authorizing the court to make rules for the conduct and procedure of actions under this section were omitted as covered by the Federal Rules of C</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>