<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2642" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2642/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/2642/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2642"><akn:num>2642</akn:num><akn:heading>Analysis of imported merchandise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2642. Analysis of imported merchandise
The Court of International Trade may order an analysis of imported merchandise and reports thereon by laboratories or agencies of the United States or laboratories accredited by the Customs Service under section 499(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930.
(Added Pub. L. 96–417, title III, § 301, Oct. 10, 1980, 94 Stat. 1737; amended Pub. L. 103–182, title VI, § 684(a)(5), Dec. 8, 1993, 107 Stat. 2219.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 499(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930, referred to in text, is classified to section 1499(b) of Title 19, Customs Duties.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2642, act May 24, 1949, ch. 139, § 123, 63 Stat. 106, authorized the Customs Court under its rules and in its discretion to permit the amendment of protests, appeals and pleadings, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 91–271, title I, § 121, June 2, 1970, 84 Stat. 281. See section 2633(b) of this title.

Amendments1993—Pub. L. 103–182 inserted before period at end “or laboratories accredited by the Customs Service under section 499(b) of the Tariff Act of 1930”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Application of 1993 AmendmentFor purposes of applying amendment by Pub. L. 103–182, any decision or order of Customs Service denying, suspending, or revoking accreditation of a private laboratory on or after Dec. 8, 1993, and before regulations to implement 19 U.S.C. 1499(b) are issued to be treated as having been denied, suspended, or revoked under such section 1499(b), see section 684(b) of Pub. L. 103–182, formerly set out as a note under section 1581 of this title.


Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the United States Customs Service of the Department of the Treasury, including functions of the Secretary of the Treasury relating thereto, to the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for treatment of related references, see sections 203(1), 551(d), 552(d), and 557 of Title 6, Domestic Security, and the Dep</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>