<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3001"><akn:num>3001</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3001. Applicability of chapter(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsection (b), the 11 So in original. Probably should be “this”. chapter provides the exclusive civil procedures for the United States—(1) to recover a judgment on a debt; or

(2) to obtain, before judgment on a claim for a debt, a remedy in connection with such claim.


(b) Limitation.—To the extent that another Federal law specifies procedures for recovering on a claim or a judgment for a debt arising under such law, those procedures shall apply to such claim or judgment to the extent those procedures are inconsistent with this chapter.

(c) Amounts Owing Other Than Debts.—This chapter shall not apply with respect to an amount owing that is not a debt or to a claim for an amount owing that is not a debt.

(Added Pub. L. 101–647, title XXXVI, § 3611, Nov. 29, 1990, 104 Stat. 4933.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 101–647, title XXXVI, § 3631, Nov. 29, 1990, 104 Stat. 4966, provided that:
“(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), this Act [probably should be “title”, meaning title XXXVI of Pub. L. 101–647, which enacted this chapter and section 2044 of this title, amended sections 550, 1962, 1963, and 2410 of this title, section 523 of Title 11, Bankruptcy, and sections 3142 and 3552 of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and enacted provisions set out as a note under section 1 of this title] and the amendments made by this Act [title] shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 29, 1990].

“(b)(1) The amendments made by title I of this Act [probably should be “subtitle A of this title”, meaning subtitle A (§§ 3611, 3302 [3612]) of title XXXVI of Pub. L. 101–647, which enacted this chapter] shall apply with respect to actions pending on the effective date of this Act [probably should be title XXXVI of Pub. L. 101–647] in any court on—“(A) a claim for a debt; or

“(B) a judgment for a debt.


“(2) All notices, writs, orders, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), the 11 So in original. Probably should be “this”. chapter provides the exclusive civil procedures for the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To the extent that another Federal law specifies procedures for recovering on a claim or a judgment for a debt arising under such law, those procedures shall apply to such claim or judgment to the extent those procedures are inconsistent with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3001_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts Owing Other Than Debts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) This chapter shall not apply with respect to an amount owing that is not a debt or to a claim for an amount owing that is not a debt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>