<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3002" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3002/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3002/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3002"><akn:num>3002</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3002. Definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) “Counsel for the United States” means—(A) a United States attorney, an assistant United States attorney designated to act on behalf of the United States attorney, or an attorney with the United States Department of Justice or with a Federal agency who has litigation authority; and

(B) any private attorney authorized by contract made in accordance with section 3718 of title 31 to conduct litigation for collection of debts on behalf of the United States.


(2) “Court” means any court created by the Congress of the United States, excluding the United States Tax Court.

(3) “Debt” means—(A) an amount that is owing to the United States on account of a direct loan, or loan insured or guaranteed, by the United States; or

(B) an amount that is owing to the United States on account of a fee, duty, lease, rent, service, sale of real or personal property, overpayment, fine, assessment, penalty, restitution, damages, interest, tax, bail bond forfeiture, reimbursement, recovery of a cost incurred by the United States, or other source of indebtedness to the United States, but that is not owing under the terms of a contract originally entered into by only persons other than the United States;


and includes any amount owing to the United States for the benefit of an Indian tribe or individual Indian, but excludes any amount to which the United States is entitled under section 3011(a).

(4) “Debtor” means a person who is liable for a debt or against whom there is a claim for a debt.

(5) “Disposable earnings” means that part of earnings remaining after all deductions required by law have been withheld.

(6) “Earnings” means compensation paid or payable for personal services, whether denominated as wages, salary, commission, bonus, or otherwise, and includes periodic payments pursuant to a pension or retirement program.

(7) “Garnishee” means a person (other than the debtor) who has, or is reasonably thought to have, possession, cust</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) “Counsel for the United States” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) “Court” means any court created by the Congress of the United States, excluding the United States Tax Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) “Debt” means— and includes any amount owing to the United States for the benefit of an Indian tribe or individual Indian, but excludes any amount to which the United States is entitled under section 3011(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) “Debtor” means a person who is liable for a debt or against whom there is a claim for a debt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) “Disposable earnings” means that part of earnings remaining after all deductions required by law have been withheld.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) “Earnings” means compensation paid or payable for personal services, whether denominated as wages, salary, commission, bonus, or otherwise, and includes periodic payments pursuant to a pension or retirement program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) “Garnishee” means a person (other than the debtor) who has, or is reasonably thought to have, possession, custody, or control of any property in which the debtor has a substantial nonexempt interest, including any obligation due the debtor or to become due the debtor, and against whom a garnishment under section 3104 or 3205 is issued by a court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) “Judgment” means a judgment, order, or decree entered in favor of the United States in a court and arising from a civil or criminal proceeding regarding a debt.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) “Nonexempt disposable earnings” means 25 percent of disposable earnings, subject to section 303 of the Consumer Credit Protection Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3002_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) “Person” includes a natural person (including an individual Indian), a corporation, a partnership, an unincorporated association, a trust, or an estate, or any other public or private entity, including a State or local government or an Indian tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>