<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/3102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3102"><akn:num>3102</akn:num><akn:heading>Attachment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3102. Attachment(a) Property Subject to Attachment.—(1) Any property in the possession, custody, or control of the debtor and in which the debtor has a substantial nonexempt interest, except earnings, may be attached pursuant to a writ of attachment in an action or proceeding against a debtor on a claim for a debt and may be held as security to satisfy such judgment, and interest and costs, as the United States may recover on such claim.

(2) The value of property attached shall not exceed the amount by which the sum of the amount of the debt claimed by the United States and the amount of interest and costs reasonably likely to be assessed against the debtor by the court exceeds the aggregate value of the nonexempt interest of the debtor in any—(A) property securing the debt; and

(B) property garnished or in receivership, or income sequestered, under this subchapter.



(b) Availability of Attachment.—If the requirements of section 3101 are satisfied, a court shall issue a writ authorizing the United States to attach property in which the debtor has a substantial nonexempt interest, as security for such judgment (and interest and costs) as the United States may recover on a claim for a debt—(1) in an action on a contract, express or implied, against the debtor for payment of money, only if the United States shows reasonable cause to believe that—(A) the contract is not fully secured by real or personal property; or

(B) the value of the original security is substantially diminished, without any act of the United States or the person to whom the security was given, below the amount of the debt;


(2) in an action against the debtor for damages in tort;

(3) if the debtor resides outside the jurisdiction of the United States; or

(4) in an action to recover a fine, penalty, or tax.


(c) Issuance of Writ; Contents.—(1) Subject to subsections (a) and (b), a writ of attachment shall be issued by the court directing the United States marshal of the district where prop</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Property Subject to Attachment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Attachment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If the requirements of section 3101 are satisfied, a court shall issue a writ authorizing the United States to attach property in which the debtor has a substantial nonexempt interest, as security for such judgment (and interest and costs) as the United States may recover on a claim for a debt—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of Writ; Contents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levy of Attachment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of Writ; Duties of Marshal; Further Return.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levy of Attachment as Lien on Property; Satisfaction of Lien.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction or Dissolution of Attachment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Replevin of Attached Property by Debtor; Bond.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) If attached property is not sold before judgment, the debtor may replevy such property or any part thereof by giving a bond approved by counsel for the United States or the court and payable to the United States in double the reasonable value of the property to be replevied or double the value of the claim, whichever is less.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preservation of Personal Property Under Attachment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) If personal property in custody of the United States marshal under a writ of attachment is not replevied, claimed, or sold, the court may make such order for its preservation or use as appears to be in the interest of the parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3102_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgment and Disposition of Attached Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>