<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_534"><akn:num>534</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition, preservation, and exchange of identification records and information; appointment of of</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 534. Acquisition, preservation, and exchange of identification records and information; appointment of officials(a) The Attorney General shall—(1) acquire, collect, classify, and preserve identification, criminal identification, crime, and other records;

(2) acquire, collect, classify, and preserve any information which would assist in the identification of any deceased individual who has not been identified after the discovery of such deceased individual;

(3) acquire, collect, classify, and preserve any information which would assist in the location of any missing person (including an unemancipated person as defined by the laws of the place of residence of such person) and provide confirmation as to any entry for such a person to the parent, legal guardian, or next of kin of that person (and the Attorney General may acquire, collect, classify, and preserve such information from such parent, guardian, or next of kin);

(4) exchange such records and information with, and for the official use of, authorized officials of the Federal Government, including the United States Sentencing Commission, the States, including State sentencing commissions, Indian tribes, cities, and penal and other institutions; and

(5) provide a person licensed as an importer, manufacturer, or dealer of firearms under chapter 44 of title 18 with information necessary to verify whether firearms offered for sale to such licensees have been stolen.


(b) The exchange of records and information authorized by subsection (a)(4) of this section is subject to cancellation if dissemination is made outside the receiving departments or related agencies, except for dissemination authorized under subsection (a)(5) of this section.

(c) The Attorney General may appoint officials to perform the functions authorized by this section.

(d) Indian Law Enforcement Agencies.—(1) In general.—The Attorney General shall permit tribal and Bureau of Indian Affairs law enforcement agencies—(A) to access and enter inf</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Attorney General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The exchange of records and information authorized by subsection (a)(4) of this section is subject to cancellation if dissemination is made outside the receiving departments or related agencies, except for dissemination authorized under subsection (a)(5) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Attorney General may appoint officials to perform the functions authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Law Enforcement Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) For purposes of this section, the term “other institutions” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>