<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/540D" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/540D/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/540D/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_540D"><akn:num>540D</akn:num><akn:heading>Multidisciplinary teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 540D. Multidisciplinary teams(a) Definitions.—In this section—(1) the term “child sexual abuse material” means a visual depiction described in section 2256(8)(A) of title 18;

(2) the term “covered investigation” means any investigation of child sexual exploitation or abuse, the production of child sexual abuse material, or child trafficking conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation;

(3) the term “Director” means the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;

(4) the term “multidisciplinary team” means a multidisciplinary team established or used under subsection (b)(2);

(5) the term “relevant children’s advocacy center personnel” means children’s advocacy center staff that regularly participate in multidisciplinary child support settings, including the director of the children’s advocacy center, the coordinator of a multidisciplinary team, forensic interviewers, victim advocates, forensic medical evaluators, physicians, sexual assault nurse examiners, and mental health clinicians; and

(6) the term “victim advocate” means a person, whether paid or serving as a volunteer, who provides services to victims under the auspices or supervision of a victim services program.


(b) FBI Victim Support Requirements.—(1) In general.—To carry out the functions described in subsection (c) in connection with each covered investigation conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director shall, unless unavailable or otherwise inconsistent with applicable Federal law—(A) use a multidisciplinary team; and

(B) in accordance with paragraph (3), use—(i) a trained Federal Bureau of Investigation child adolescent forensic interviewer; or

(ii) in the absence of a trained Federal Bureau of Investigation child adolescent forensic interviewer, a trained forensic interviewer at a children’s advocacy center.



(2) Use and coordination.—The Director shall use and coordinate with children’s advocacy center-based multidisciplinary teams as necessary to carry out para</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>FBI Victim Support Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The functions described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Teams.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Multidisciplinary teams used under this section shall be made available to victims reporting child sexual abuse or child trafficking in covered investigations, regardless of the age of the victim making the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Case Review by Multidisciplinary Team.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Throughout a covered investigation, a multidisciplinary team supporting an investigation under this section shall, at regularly scheduled times, convene to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Advocates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Director shall make advocates available to each victim who reports child sexual abuse or child trafficking in connection with an investigation by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_540D_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>