<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_605"><akn:num>605</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 605. Budget estimates
The Director, under the supervision of the Judicial Conference of the United States, shall submit to the Office of Management and Budget annual estimates of the expenditures and appropriations necessary for the maintenance and operation of the courts and the Administrative Office and the operation of the judicial survivors annuity fund, and such supplemental and deficiency estimates as may be required from time to time for the same purposes, according to law. The Director shall cause periodic examinations of the judicial survivors annuity fund to be made by an actuary, who may be an actuary employed by another department of the Government temporarily assigned for the purpose, and whose findings and recommendations shall be transmitted by the Director to the Judicial Conference.
Such estimates shall be approved, before presentation to the Office of Management and Budget, by the Judicial Conference of the United States, except that the estimate with respect to the Court of International Trade shall be approved by such court and the estimate with respect to the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit shall be approved by such court.
(June 25, 1948, ch. 646, 62 Stat. 915; July 9, 1956, ch. 517, § 1(e), 70 Stat. 497; Aug. 3, 1956, ch. 944, § 4, 70 Stat. 1026; Pub. L. 87–253, § 3, Sept. 19, 1961, 75 Stat. 521; Pub. L. 96–417, title V, § 501(14), Oct. 10, 1980, 94 Stat. 1742; Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 119(a), Apr. 2, 1982, 96 Stat. 33; Pub. L. 97–258, § 5(b), Sept. 13, 1982, 96 Stat. 1068, 1085.)

Historical and Revision NotesBased on title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., § 447 (Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 231, § 305, as added Aug. 7, 1939, ch. 501, § 1, 53 Stat. 1223).
This section contains provisions of section 447 of title 28, U.S.C., 1940 ed., relating to budget estimates. The remainder of said section 447 is incorporated in section 604 of this title.
The designation “senior circuit judges” was changed to “chief judges of the circuits” in conformity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>