<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_612"><akn:num>612</akn:num><akn:heading>Judiciary Information Technology Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 612. Judiciary Information Technology Fund(a) Establishment and Availability of Fund.—There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a special fund to be known as the “Judiciary Information Technology Fund” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”). Moneys in the Fund shall be available to the Director without fiscal year limitation for the procurement (by lease, purchase, exchange, transfer, or otherwise) of information technology resources for program activities included in the courts of appeals, district courts, and other judicial services account of the judicial branch of the United States. The Fund shall also be available for expenses, including personal services, support personnel in the courts and in the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, and other costs, for the effective management, coordination, operation, and use of information technology resources purchased by the Fund. In addition, all agencies of the judiciary may make deposits into the Fund to meet their information technology needs in accordance with subsections (b) and (c)(2).

(b) Plan for Meeting Information Technology Needs.—(1) Development of plan.—The Director shall develop and annually revise, with the approval of the Judicial Conference of the United States, a long range plan for meeting the information technology resources needs of the activities funded under subsection (a) and shall include an annual estimate of any fees that may be collected under section 404 of the Judiciary Appropriations Act, 1991 (Public Law 101–515; 104 Stat. 2133). Such plan and revisions shall be submitted to Congress.

(2) Expenditures consistent with plan.—The Director may use amounts in the Fund to procure information technology resources for the activities funded under subsection (a) only in accordance with the plan developed under paragraph (1).


(c) Deposits Into Fund.—(1) Deposits.—There shall be deposited in the Fund—(A) all proceeds resulting from activities </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and Availability of Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States a special fund to be known as the “Judiciary Information Technology Fund” (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Fund”). Moneys in the Fund shall be available to the Director without fiscal year limitation for the procurement (by lease, purchase, exchange, transfer, or otherwise) of information technology resources for program activities included in the courts of appeals, district courts, and other judicial services account of the judicial branch of the United States. The Fund shall also be available for expenses, including personal services, support personnel in the courts and in the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, and other costs, for the effective management, coordination, operation, and use of information technology resources purchased by the Fund. In addition, all agencies of the judiciary may make deposits into the Fund to meet their information technology needs in accordance with subs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for Meeting Information Technology Needs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits Into Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund for any fiscal year such sums as are required to supplement amounts deposited under subsection (c) in order to conduct activities under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Administrator of General Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Administrator of General Services under sections 501–505 of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reprogramming.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, under the supervision of the Judicial Conference of the United States, may transfer amounts up to $1,000,000 from the Fund into the account to which the funds were originally appropriated. Any amounts transferred from the Fund in excess of $1,000,000 in any fiscal year may only be transferred by following reprogramming procedures in compliance with section 606 of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1989 (Public Law 100–459; 102 Stat. 2227).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations Into the Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) If the budget request of the judiciary is appropriated in full, the amount deposited into the Fund during any fiscal year under the authority of subsection (c)(1)(B) will be the same as the amount of funds requested by the judiciary for activities described in subsection (a). If an amount to be deposited is not specified in statute by Congress and if the full request is not appropriated, the amount to be deposited under subsection (c)(1)(B) will be set by the spending priorities established by the Judicial Conference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_612_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Long Range Management and Business Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Court shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>