<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/658" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/658/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/658/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_658"><akn:num>658</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of arbitrators and neutrals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 658. Compensation of arbitrators and neutrals(a) Compensation.—The district court shall, subject to regulations approved by the Judicial Conference of the United States, establish the amount of compensation, if any, that each arbitrator or neutral shall receive for services rendered in each case under this chapter.

(b) Transportation Allowances.—Under regulations prescribed by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, a district court may reimburse arbitrators and other neutrals for actual transportation expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of duties under this chapter.

(Added Pub. L. 100–702, title IX, § 901(a), Nov. 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 4662; amended Pub. L. 105–315, § 10, Oct. 30, 1998, 112 Stat. 2997.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–315 amended section generally, substituting provisions relating to compensation of arbitrators and neutrals for provisions relating to district courts that may authorize arbitration.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The district court shall, subject to regulations approved by the Judicial Conference of the United States, establish the amount of compensation, if any, that each arbitrator or neutral shall receive for services rendered in each case under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_658_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, a district court may reimburse arbitrators and other neutrals for actual transportation expenses necessarily incurred in the performance of duties under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>