<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/81" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/81/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/28/81/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_81"><akn:num>81</akn:num><akn:heading>Alabama</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 81. Alabama
Alabama is divided into three judicial districts to be known as the Northern, Middle, and Southern Districts of Alabama.
Northern District
(a) The Northern District comprises five divisions.
(1) The Northwestern Division comprises the counties of Colbert, Franklin, Lauderdale, and Lawrence.
Court for the Northwestern Division shall be held at Florence.
(2) The Northeastern Division comprises the counties of Cullman, Jackson, Limestone, Madison, Marshall, and Morgan.
Court for the Northeastern Division shall be held at Huntsville.
(3) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Blount, Jefferson, and Shelby.
Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Birmingham.
(4) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Calhoun, Cherokee, Clay, Cleburne, DeKalb, Etowah, Saint Clair, and Talladega.
Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Anniston.
(5) The Western Division comprises the counties of Bibb, Fayette, Greene, Lamar, Marion, Pickens, Sumter, Tuscaloosa, Walker, and Winston.
Court for the Western Division shall be held at Tuscaloosa.
Middle District
(b) The Middle District comprises three divisions.
(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Autauga, Barbour, Bullock, Butler, Chilton, Coosa, Covington, Crenshaw, Elmore, Lowndes, Montgomery, and Pike.
Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Montgomery.
(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Coffee, Dale, Geneva, Henry, and Houston.
Court for the Southern Division shall be held at Dothan.
(3) The Eastern Division comprises the counties of Chambers, Lee, Macon, Randolph, Russell, and Tallapoosa.
Court for the Eastern Division shall be held at Opelika.
Southern District
(c) The Southern District comprises two divisions.
(1) The Northern Division comprises the counties of Dallas, Hale, Marengo, Perry, and Wilcox.
Court for the Northern Division shall be held at Selma.
(2) The Southern Division comprises the counties of Baldwin, Choctaw, Clarke, Conecuh, Escamb</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>