<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2401"><akn:num>2401</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2401. Appropriations(a) There are appropriated to the Postal Service all revenues received by the Postal Service.

(b)(1) As reimbursement to the Postal Service for public service costs incurred by it in providing a maximum degree of effective and regular postal service nationwide, in communities where post offices may not be deemed self-sustaining, as elsewhere, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Postal Service the following amounts:(A) for each of the fiscal years 1972 through 1979, an amount equal to 10 percent of the sum appropriated to the former Post Office Department by Act of Congress for its use in fiscal year 1971;

(B) for fiscal year 1980, an amount equal to 9 percent of such sum for fiscal year 1971;

(C) for fiscal year 1981, $486,000,000;

(D) for fiscal year 1982, $250,000,000;

(E) for fiscal year 1983, $100,000,000;

(F) for fiscal year 1984, no funds are authorized to be appropriated; and

(G) except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, for each fiscal year thereafter an amount equal to 5 percent of such sum for fiscal year 1971.


(2) After fiscal year 1984, the Postal Service may reduce the percentage figure in paragraph (1)(G) of this subsection, including a reduction to 0, if the Postal Service finds that the amounts determined under such paragraph are no longer required to operate the Postal Service in accordance with the policies of this title.


(c) There are authorized to be appropriated to the Postal Service each year a sum determined by the Postal Service to be equal to the difference between the revenues the Postal Service would have received if sections 3217 and 3403 through 3406 had not been enacted and the estimated revenues to be received on mail carried under such sections. In requesting an appropriation under this subsection for a fiscal year, the Postal Service shall include an amount to reconcile sums authorized to be appropriated for prior fiscal years on the basis of estimated mail volume.

(d) As rei</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There are appropriated to the Postal Service all revenues received by the Postal Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) There are authorized to be appropriated to the Postal Service each year a sum determined by the Postal Service to be equal to the difference between the revenues the Postal Service would have received if sections 3217 and 3403 through 3406 had not been enacted and the estimated revenues to be received on mail carried under such sections. In requesting an appropriation under this subsection for a fiscal year, the Postal Service shall include an amount to reconcile sums authorized to be appropriated for prior fiscal years on the basis of estimated mail volume.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) As reimbursement to the Postal Service for losses which it incurred as a result of insufficient amounts appropriated under section 2401(c) for fiscal years 1991 through 1993, and to compensate for the additional revenues it is estimated the Postal Service would have received under the provisions of section 3626(a) (as last in effect before enactment of the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act), for the period beginning on October 1, 1993, and ending on September 30, 1998, if the fraction specified in subclause (VI) of section 3626(a)(3)(B)(ii) (as last in effect before enactment of the Postal Accountability and Enhancement Act) were applied with respect to such period (instead of the respective fractions specified in subclauses (I) through (V) thereof), there are authorized to be appropriated to the Postal Service $29,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1994 through 2035.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Postal Service shall present to the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, at the same time it submits its annual budget under section 2009 of this title, sufficient copies of the budget of the Postal Service for the fiscal year for which funds are requested to be appropriated, and a comprehensive statement relating to the following matters: Each year, the Postal Service shall appear before the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives to submit information which any such committee considers necessary to determine the amount of funds to be appropriated for the operation of the Postal Service, and to present testimony and respond to questions with respect to such budget and statement. Each such committee shall take such action as it consider</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The failure of the President to request the appropriation of any part of the funds authorized by this section may not be deemed a failure of appropriations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2401_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The rates established under chapter 36 of this title for zone-rated parcels formerly entered under former chapter 67 of this title shall not be more than 10 percent less than the rates for such mail would be if the funds authorized under subsection (b) were not appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>