<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/2802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2802"><akn:num>2802</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2802. Strategic plans(a) No later than September 30, 1997, the Postal Service shall submit to the President and the Congress a strategic plan for its program activities. Such plan shall contain—(1) a comprehensive mission statement covering the major functions and operations of the Postal Service;

(2) general goals and objectives, including outcome-related goals and objectives, for the major functions and operations of the Postal Service;

(3) a description of how the goals and objectives are to be achieved, including a description of the operational processes, skills and technology, and the human, capital, information, and other resources required to meet those goals and objectives;

(4) a description of how the performance goals included in the plan required under section 2803 shall be related to the general goals and objectives in the strategic plan;

(5) an identification of those key factors external to the Postal Service and beyond its control that could significantly affect the achievement of the general goals and objectives; and

(6) a description of the program evaluations used in establishing or revising general goals and objectives, with a schedule for future program evaluations.


(b) The strategic plan shall cover a period of not less than five years forward from the fiscal year in which it is submitted, and shall be updated and revised at least every three years.

(c) The performance plan required under section 2803 shall be consistent with the Postal Service’s strategic plan. A performance plan may not be submitted for a fiscal year not covered by a current strategic plan under this section.

(d) When developing a strategic plan, the Postal Service shall solicit and consider the views and suggestions of those entities potentially affected by or interested in such a plan, and shall advise the Congress of the contents of the plan.

(Added Pub. L. 103–62, § 7, Aug. 3, 1993, 107 Stat. 292.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Strategic PlanningPu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) No later than September 30, 1997, the Postal Service shall submit to the President and the Congress a strategic plan for its program activities. Such plan shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The strategic plan shall cover a period of not less than five years forward from the fiscal year in which it is submitted, and shall be updated and revised at least every three years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The performance plan required under section 2803 shall be consistent with the Postal Service’s strategic plan. A performance plan may not be submitted for a fiscal year not covered by a current strategic plan under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2802_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When developing a strategic plan, the Postal Service shall solicit and consider the views and suggestions of those entities potentially affected by or interested in such a plan, and shall advise the Congress of the contents of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>