<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3016" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3016/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3016/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3016"><akn:num>3016</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative subpoenas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3016. Administrative subpoenas(a) Subpoena Authority.—(1) Investigations.—(A) In general.—In any investigation conducted under section 3005(a), the Postmaster General may require by subpoena the production of any records (including books, papers, documents, and other tangible things which constitute or contain evidence) which the Postmaster General considers relevant or material to such investigation.

(B) Condition.—No subpoena shall be issued under this paragraph except in accordance with procedures, established by the Postal Service, requiring that—(i) a specific case, with an individual or entity identified as the subject, be opened before a subpoena is requested;

(ii) appropriate supervisory and legal review of a subpoena request be performed; and

(iii) delegation of subpoena approval authority be limited to the Postal Service’s General Counsel or a Deputy General Counsel.



(2) Statutory proceedings.—In any statutory proceeding conducted under section 3005(a), the Judicial Officer may require by subpoena the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any records (including books, papers, documents, and other tangible things which constitute or contain evidence) which the Judicial Officer considers relevant or material to such proceeding.

(3) Rule of construction.—Nothing in paragraph (2) shall be considered to apply in any circumstance to which paragraph (1) applies.


(b) Service.—(1) Service within the united states.—A subpoena issued under this section may be served by a person designated under section 3061 of title 18 at any place within the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States.

(2) Foreign service.—Any such subpoena may be served upon any person who is not to be found within the territorial jurisdiction of any court of the United States, in such manner as the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure prescribe for service in a foreign country. To the extent that the courts of the United States may assert jurisdiction o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3016_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3016_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3016_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3016_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any documentary material provided pursuant to any subpoena issued under this section shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>