<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3018" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3018/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3018/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3018"><akn:num>3018</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3018. Hazardous material(a) In General.—The Postal Service shall prescribe regulations for the safe transportation of hazardous material in the mail.

(b) Prohibitions.—No person may—(1) mail or cause to be mailed hazardous material that has been declared by statute or Postal Service regulation to be nonmailable;

(2) mail or cause to be mailed hazardous material in violation of any statute or Postal Service regulation restricting the time, place, or manner in which hazardous material may be mailed; or

(3) manufacture, distribute, or sell any container, packaging kit, or similar device that—(A) is represented, marked, certified, or sold by such person for use in the mailing of hazardous material; and

(B) fails to conform with any statute or Postal Service regulation setting forth standards for a container, packaging kit, or similar device used for the mailing of hazardous material.



(c) Civil Penalty; Clean-Up Costs and Damages.—(1) In general.—A person who knowingly violates this section or a regulation prescribed under this section shall be liable for—(A) a civil penalty of at least $250, but not more than $100,000, for each violation;

(B) the costs of any clean-up associated with each violation; and

(C) damages.


(2) Knowing action.—A person acts knowingly for purposes of paragraph (1) when—(A) the person has actual knowledge of the facts giving rise to the violation; or

(B) a reasonable person acting in the circumstances and exercising reasonable care would have had that knowledge.


(3) Separate violations.—(A) Violations over time.—A separate violation under this subsection occurs for each day hazardous material, mailed or caused to be mailed in noncompliance with this section, is in the mail.

(B) Separate items.—A separate violation under this subsection occurs for each item containing hazardous material that is mailed or caused to be mailed in noncompliance with this section.



(d) Hearings.—The Postal Service may determine that a person has viol</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Postal Service shall prescribe regulations for the safe transportation of hazardous material in the mail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No person may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Penalty; Clean-Up Costs and Damages.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Postal Service may determine that a person has violated this section or a regulation prescribed under this section only after notice and an opportunity for a hearing. Proceedings under this section shall be conducted in accordance with section 3001(m).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In determining the amount of a civil penalty for a violation of this section, the Postal Service shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Actions to Collect.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Judicial Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3018_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of Amounts Collected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>