<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3626"><akn:num>3626</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3626. Reduced rates(a)(1) Except as otherwise provided in this section, rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358, 4452(b), 4452(c), 4554(b), or 4554(c) of this title shall be established in accordance with section 3622.

(2) For the purpose of this subsection, the term “regular-rate category” means any class of mail or kind of mailer, other than a class or kind referred to in section 2401(c).

(3) Rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358(a) through (c) of this title shall be established so that postage on each mailing of such mail reflects its preferred status as compared to the postage for the most closely corresponding regular-rate category mailing.

(4)(A) Except as specified in subparagraph (B), rates of postage for a class of mail or kind of mailer under former section 4358 (d) or (e) of this title shall be established so that postage on each mailing of such mail shall be as nearly as practicable 5 percent lower than the postage for a corresponding regular-rate category mailing.

(B) With respect to the postage for the advertising pound portion of any mail matter under former section 4358 (d) or (e) of this title, the 5-percent discount specified in subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the advertising portion exceeds 10 percent of the publication involved.


(5) The rates for any advertising under former section 4358(f) of this title shall be equal to 75 percent of the rates for advertising contained in the most closely corresponding regular-rate category of mail.

(6) The rates for mail matter under former sections 4452 (b) and (c) of this title shall be established as follows:(A) The estimated average revenue per piece to be received by the Postal Service from each subclass of mail under former sections 4452 (b) and (c) of this title shall be equal, as nearly as practicable, to 60 percent of the estimated average revenue per piece to be received from the most closely correspondin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the administration of this section, one conservation publication published by an agency of a State which is responsible for management and conservation of the fish or wildlife resources of such State shall be considered a publication of a qualified nonprofit organization which qualifies for rates of postage under former section 4358(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In the administration of this chapter, the rates for mail under former section 4358(g) of this title shall be established without regard to either the provisions of such former section 4358(g) or the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In the administration of this section, the number of copies of a subscription publication mailed to nonsubscribers during a calendar year at rates under subsections (a), (b), and (c) of former section 4358 of this title may not exceed 50 percent of the number of copies of such publication mailed at such rates to subscribers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(i) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–123, title VII, § 704(a)(3)(A), Oct. 28, 1993, 107 Stat. 1269.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3626_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>