<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3641" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3641/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3641/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3641"><akn:num>3641</akn:num><akn:heading>Market tests of experimental products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3641. Market tests of experimental products(a) Authority.—(1) In general.—The Postal Service may conduct market tests of experimental products in accordance with this section.

(2) Provisions waived.—A product shall not, while it is being tested under this section, be subject to the requirements of sections 3622, 3633, or 3642, or regulations promulgated under those sections.


(b) Conditions.—A product may not be tested under this section unless it satisfies each of the following:(1) Significantly different product.—The product is, from the viewpoint of the mail users, significantly different from all products offered by the Postal Service within the 2-year period preceding the start of the test.

(2) Market disruption.—The introduction or continued offering of the product will not create an unfair or otherwise inappropriate competitive advantage for the Postal Service or any mailer, particularly in regard to small business concerns (as defined under subsection (h)).

(3) Correct categorization.—The Postal Service identifies the product, for the purpose of a test under this section, as either market-dominant or competitive, consistent with the criteria under section 3642(b)(1). Costs and revenues attributable to a product identified as competitive shall be included in any determination under section 3633(3) 11 So in original. Probably should be section “3633(a)(3)”. (relating to provisions applicable to competitive products collectively). Any test that solely affects products currently classified as competitive, or which provides services ancillary to only competitive products, shall be presumed to be in the competitive product category without regard to whether a similar ancillary product exists for market-dominant products.


(c) Notice.—(1) In general.—At least 30 days before initiating a market test under this section, the Postal Service shall file with the Postal Regulatory Commission and publish in the Federal Register a notice—(A) setting out the basis for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A product may not be tested under this section unless it satisfies each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dollar-Amount Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If the Postal Regulatory Commission at any time determines that a market test under this section fails, with respect to any particular product, to meet 1 or more of the requirements of this section, it may order the cancellation of the test involved or take such other action as it considers appropriate. A determination under this subsection shall be made in accordance with such procedures as the Commission shall by regulation prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment for Inflation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of each year following the year in which occurs the deadline for the Postal Service’s first report to the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3652(a), each dollar amount contained in this section shall be adjusted by the change in the Consumer Price Index for such year (as determined under regulations of the Commission).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of a Small Business Concern.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The criteria used in defining small business concerns or otherwise categorizing business concerns as small business concerns shall, for purposes of this section, be established by the Postal Regulatory Commission in conformance with the requirements of section 3 of the Small Business Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3641_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Market tests under this subchapter may be conducted in any year beginning with the first year in which occurs the deadline for the Postal Service’s first report to the Postal Regulatory Commission under section 3652(a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>