<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/3705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3705"><akn:num>3705</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency and accountability for nonpostal services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3705. Transparency and accountability for nonpostal services(a) Annual Report to the Commission.—(1) In general.—Not later than 90 days after the last day of each year, the Postal Service shall submit to the Postal Regulatory Commission a report that analyzes costs, revenues, rates, and quality of service for each agreement or substantially similar set of agreements for the provision of property or nonpostal services under section 3703 or the program as a whole under section 3704, and any other nonpostal service authorized under this chapter, using such methodologies as the Commission may prescribe, and in sufficient detail to demonstrate compliance with the requirements of this chapter.

(2) Supporting matter.—A report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include any nonpublic annex, the working papers, and any other supporting matter of the Postal Service and the Inspector General related to the information submitted in such report.


(b) Content and Form of Report.—(1) In general.—The Postal Regulatory Commission shall, by regulation, prescribe the content and form of the report required under subsection (a). In prescribing such regulations, the Commission shall give due consideration to—(A) providing the public with timely, adequate information to assess compliance;

(B) avoiding unnecessary or unwarranted administrative effort and expense on the part of the Postal Service; and

(C) protecting the confidentiality of information that is commercially sensitive or is exempt from public disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5.


(2) Revised requirements.—The Commission may, on its own motion or on request of any interested party, initiate proceedings to improve the quality, accuracy, or completeness of Postal Service data required by the Commission if—(A) the attribution of costs or revenues to property, products, or services under this chapter has become significantly inaccurate or can be significantly improved;

(B) the quality of service data provided to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report to the Commission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content and Form of Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Inspector General shall regularly audit the data collection systems and procedures used in collecting information and preparing the report required under subsection (a). The results of any such audit shall be submitted to the Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidential Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Compliance Determination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Postal Regulatory Commission shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3705_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experimental Product Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Postal Service may conduct market tests of agreements pursuant to section 3703 and section 3704 of this chapter subject to the same terms and conditions described in section 3641 of this title. For the purposes of a market test, the cost coverage requirements in sections 3703 and 3704 of this chapter shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>