<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/5402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/5402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/39/5402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5402"><akn:num>5402</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for transportation of mail by air</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5402. Contracts for transportation of mail by air(a) In this section—(1) the term “acceptance point” means the point at which nonpriority bypass mail originates;

(2) the terms foreign air carrier,11 So in original. Probably should be set off by quotation marks and the term “foreign air carrier” probably should appear only once. “air carrier”, “interstate air transportation”, “foreign air carrier”.22 So in original. The period probably should be a comma and the term “foreign air carrier” probably should appear only once. and “foreign air transportation” have the meanings given such terms in section 40102(a) of title 49, United States Code;

(3) the term “base fare” means the fare paid to the carrier issuing the passenger ticket or carrying nonmail freight which may entail service being provided by more than 1 carrier;

(4) the term “bush carrier” means a carrier operating aircraft certificated within the payload capacity requirements of subsection (g)(1)(A)(iv)(I) on a city pair route;

(5) the term “bush passenger carrier” means a passenger carrier that meets the requirements of subsection (g)(1)(A)(iv)(I) and provides passenger service on a city pair route;

(6) the term “bush route” means an air route in which only a bush carrier is tendered nonpriority bypass mail between the origination point, being either an acceptance point or a hub, as determined by the Postal Service, and the destination city;

(7) the term “certificated air carrier” means an air carrier that holds a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued under section 41102(a) of title 49;

(8) the term “city pair” means service between an origin and destination city pair;

(9) the term “code-share relationship” means a relationship pursuant to which any certificated air carrier or foreign air carrier’s designation code is used to identify a flight operated by another air carrier or foreign air carrier;

(10) the term “composite rate”—(A) means a combination of mainline and bush linehaul </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Mail.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Good Faith Effort Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Postal Service and potential offerors shall put a good-faith effort into resolving disputes concerning the award of contracts made under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If the Postal Service determines that service by certificated air carriers or combination of air carriers between any pair or pairs of points in foreign air transportation is not adequate for its purposes, it may contract, without advertising for bids, in such manner and under such terms and conditions as it may deem appropriate, with any air taxi operator or combination thereof for such air transportation service. Contracts made under this subsection may be renewed at the existing rate by mutual agreement between the holder and the Postal Service. The Postal Service, with the consent of the air taxi operator, may adjust the compensation under such contracts for increased or decreased costs occasioned by changed conditions occurring during the contract term. The Postal Service shall cancel such a contract when the Secretary authorizes an additional certificated carrier or carriers to provide service between any pair or pairs of points covered by the contract, and such carrier or ca</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The authority of the Secretary and the Postal Service under subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section shall also apply, and the authority of the Postal Service under subsection (e) shall not apply, to the transportation of mail by aircraft between any two points both of which are within the State of Alaska and between which the air carrier is authorized by the Secretary to engage in the transportation of mail.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5402_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>