<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10216" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10216/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10216/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10216"><akn:num>10216</akn:num><akn:heading>Military technicians (dual status)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10216. Military technicians (dual status)(a) In General.—(1) For purposes of this section and any other provision of law, a military technician (dual status) is a Federal civilian employee who—(A) is employed under section 3101 of title 5 or section 709(b) of title 32;

(B) is required as a condition of that employment to maintain membership in the Selected Reserve; and

(C) is assigned to a civilian position as a technician in the organizing, administering, instructing, or training of the Selected Reserve or in the maintenance and repair of supplies or equipment issued to the Selected Reserve or the armed forces.


(2) Military technicians (dual status) shall be authorized and accounted for as a separate category of civilian employees.

(3) A military technician (dual status) who is employed under section 3101 of title 5 may perform the following additional duties to the extent that the performance of those duties does not interfere with the performance of the primary duties described in paragraph (1):(A) Supporting operations or missions assigned in whole or in part to the technician’s unit.

(B) Supporting operations or missions performed or to be performed by—(i) a unit composed of elements from more than one component of the technician’s armed force; or

(ii) a joint forces unit that includes—(I) one or more units of the technician’s component; or

(II) a member of the technician’s component whose reserve component assignment is in a position in an element of the joint forces unit.



(C) Instructing or training in the United States or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or possessions of the United States of—(i) active-duty members of the armed forces;

(ii) members of foreign military forces (under the same authorities and restrictions applicable to active-duty members providing such instruction or training);

(iii) Department of Defense contractor personnel; or

(iv) Department of Defense civilian employees.




(b) Priority for Management of Military Technici</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for Management of Military Technicians (Dual Status).—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Required To Be Submitted With Annual End Strength Authorization Request.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unit Membership Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual Status Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Deferral of Mandatory Separation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force may each implement personnel policies so as to allow, at the discretion of the Secretary concerned, a military technician (dual status) who continues to meet the requirements of this section for dual status to continue to serve beyond a mandatory removal date, and any applicable maximum years of service limitation, until the military technician (dual status) reaches age 62.11 So in original. and attains eligibility for an unreduced annuity (as defined in section 10218(c) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10216_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of Military Technicians Who Lose Dual Status Due to Combat-Related Disability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>