<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10219" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10219/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10219/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10219"><akn:num>10219</akn:num><akn:heading>Suicide prevention and resilience program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10219. Suicide prevention and resilience program(a) Program Requirement.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a program to provide members of the National Guard and Reserves and their families with training in suicide prevention, resilience, and community healing and response to suicide, including provision of such training at Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program events and activities authorized under section 582 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (10 U.S.C. 10101 note).

(b) Suicide Prevention Training.—Under the program, the Secretary shall provide members of the National Guard and Reserves with training in suicide prevention. Such training may include—(1) describing the warning signs for suicide and teaching effective strategies for prevention and intervention;

(2) examining the influence of military culture on risk and protective factors for suicide; and

(3) engaging in interactive case scenarios and role plays to practice effective intervention strategies.


(c) Community Response Training.—Under the program, the Secretary shall provide the families and communities of members of the National Guard and Reserves with training in responses to suicide that promote individual and community healing. Such training may include—(1) enhancing collaboration among community members and local service providers to create an integrated, coordinated community response to suicide;

(2) communicating best practices for preventing suicide, including safe messaging, appropriate memorial services, and media guidelines;

(3) addressing the impact of suicide on the military and the larger community, and the increased risk that can result; and

(4) managing resources to assist key community and military service providers in helping the families, friends, and fellow servicemembers of a suicide victim through the processes of grieving and healing.


(d) Community Training Assistance.—The program shall include the provision of assistance w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish and carry out a program to provide members of the National Guard and Reserves and their families with training in suicide prevention, resilience, and community healing and response to suicide, including provision of such training at Yellow Ribbon Reintegration Program events and activities authorized under section 582 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (10 U.S.C. 10101 note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suicide Prevention Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under the program, the Secretary shall provide members of the National Guard and Reserves with training in suicide prevention. Such training may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Response Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Under the program, the Secretary shall provide the families and communities of members of the National Guard and Reserves with training in responses to suicide that promote individual and community healing. Such training may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Training Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The program shall include the provision of assistance with such training to the local communities of those servicemembers and families, to be provided in coordination with local community programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall collect and analyze “lessons learned” and suggestions from State National Guard and Reserve organizations with existing or developing suicide prevention and community response programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach for Certain Members of the Reserve Components.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10219_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Triennial Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall evaluate the program every third year beginning in 2022 until the program terminates to determine whether the program effectively—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>