<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/10218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10218"><akn:num>10218</akn:num><akn:heading>Army and Air Force Reserve technicians: conditions for retention; mandatory retirement under civil s</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10218. Army and Air Force Reserve technicians: conditions for retention; mandatory retirement under civil service laws(a) Separation and Retirement of Military Technicians (Dual Status).—(1) An individual employed by the Army Reserve or the Air Force Reserve as a military technician (dual status) who after October 5, 1999, loses dual status is subject to paragraph (2) or (3), as the case may be.

(2) If a technician described in paragraph (1) is eligible at the time dual status is lost for an unreduced annuity and is age 60 or older at that time, the technician shall be separated not later than 30 days after the date on which dual status is lost.

(3)(A) If a technician described in paragraph (1) is not eligible at the time dual status is lost for an unreduced annuity or is under age 60 at that time, the technician shall be offered the opportunity to—(i) reapply for, and if qualified may be appointed to, a position as a military technician (dual status); or

(ii) apply for a civil service position that is not a technician position.


(B) If such a technician continues employment with the Army Reserve or the Air Force Reserve as a non-dual status technician, the technician—(i) shall not be permitted, after October 5, 2000, to apply for any voluntary personnel action; and

(ii) shall be separated or retired—(I) in the case of a technician first hired as a military technician (dual status) on or before February 10, 1996, not later than 30 days after becoming eligible for an unreduced annuity and becoming 60 years of age; and

(II) in the case of a technician first hired as a military technician (dual status) after February 10, 1996, not later than one year after the date on which dual status is lost.




(4) For purposes of this subsection, a military technician is considered to lose dual status upon—(A) being separated from the Selected Reserve; or

(B) ceasing to hold the military grade specified by the Secretary concerned for the position held by the technician.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation and Retirement of Military Technicians (Dual Status).—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Dual Status Technicians.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unreduced Annuity Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, a technician shall be considered to be eligible for an unreduced annuity if the technician is eligible for an annuity under section 8336, 8412, or 8414 of title 5 that is not subject to a reduction by reason of the age or years of service of the technician.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10218_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary Personnel Action Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “voluntary personnel action”, with respect to a non-dual status technician, means any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>