<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1030" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1030/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1030/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1030"><akn:num>1030</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonus to encourage Department of Defense personnel to refer persons for appointment as officers to s</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1030. Bonus to encourage Department of Defense personnel to refer persons for appointment as officers to serve in health professions(a) Authority To Pay Bonus.—(1) Authority.—The Secretary of Defense may authorize the appropriate Secretary to pay a bonus under this section to an individual referred to in paragraph (2) who refers to a military recruiter a person who has not previously served in an armed force and, after such referral, takes an oath of enlistment that leads to appointment as a commissioned officer, or accepts an appointment as a commissioned officer, in an armed force in a health profession designated by the appropriate Secretary for purposes of this section.

(2) Individuals eligible for bonus.—Subject to subsection (c), the following individuals are eligible for a referral bonus under this section:(A) A member of the armed forces in a regular component of the armed forces.

(B) A member of the armed forces in a reserve component of the armed forces.

(C) A member of the armed forces in a retired status, including a member under 60 years of age who, but for age, would be eligible for retired or retainer pay.

(D) A civilian employee of a military department or the Department of Defense.



(b) Referral.—For purposes of this section, a referral for which a bonus may be paid under subsection (a) occurs—(1) when the individual concerned contacts a military recruiter on behalf of a person interested in taking an oath of enlistment that leads to appointment as a commissioned officer, or accepting an appointment as a commissioned officer, as applicable, in an armed force in a health profession; or

(2) when a person interested in taking an oath of enlistment that leads to appointment as a commissioned officer, or accepting an appointment as a commissioned officer, as applicable, in an armed force in a health profession contacts a military recruiter and informs the recruiter of the role of the individual concerned in initially recruiting the person.


(c)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Pay Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this section, a referral for which a bonus may be paid under subsection (a) occurs—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Referrals Ineligible.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The amount of the bonus payable for a referral under subsection (a) may not exceed $2,000. The amount shall be payable as provided in subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A bonus payable for a referral of a person under subsection (a) shall be paid as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Prohibition on Bounties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The referral bonus authorized by this section is not a bounty for purposes of section 514(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Receipt of Retired Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A bonus paid under this section to a member of the armed forces in a retired status is in addition to any compensation to which the member is entitled under this title, title 37 or 38, or any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate Secretary Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “appropriate Secretary” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1030_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A bonus may not be paid under subsection (a) with respect to any referral that occurs after December 31, 2011.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>