<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1052"><akn:num>1052</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption expenses: reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1052. Adoption expenses: reimbursement(a) Authorization To Reimburse.—The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program under which a member of the armed forces may be reimbursed, as provided in this section, for qualifying adoption expenses incurred by the member in the adoption of a child under 18 years of age.

(b) Adoptions Covered.—An adoption for which expenses may be reimbursed under this section includes an adoption by a single person, an infant adoption, an intercountry adoption, and an adoption of a child with special needs (as defined in section 473(c) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 673(c))).

(c) Benefits Paid After Adoption Is Final.—Benefits paid under this section in the case of an adoption may be paid only after the adoption is final.

(d) Treatment of Other Benefits.—A benefit may not be paid under this section for any expense paid to or for a member of the armed forces under any other adoption benefits program administered by the Federal Government or under any such program administered by a State or local government.

(e) Limitations.—(1) Not more than $2,000 may be paid under this section to a member of the armed forces, or to two such members who are spouses of each other, for expenses incurred in the adoption of a child.

(2) Not more than $5,000 may be paid under this section to a member of the armed forces, or to two such members who are spouses of each other, for adoptions by such member (or members) in any calendar year.


(f) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.

(g) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “qualifying adoption expenses” means reasonable and necessary expenses that are directly related to the legal adoption of a child under 18 years of age, but only if such adoption is arranged by a qualified adoption agency or other source authorized to place children for adoption under State or local law. Such term does not include any expense incurred—(A) by an adopting </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization To Reimburse.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program under which a member of the armed forces may be reimbursed, as provided in this section, for qualifying adoption expenses incurred by the member in the adoption of a child under 18 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoptions Covered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An adoption for which expenses may be reimbursed under this section includes an adoption by a single person, an infant adoption, an intercountry adoption, and an adoption of a child with special needs (as defined in section 473(c) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 673(c))).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits Paid After Adoption Is Final.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Benefits paid under this section in the case of an adoption may be paid only after the adoption is final.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Other Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A benefit may not be paid under this section for any expense paid to or for a member of the armed forces under any other adoption benefits program administered by the Federal Government or under any such program administered by a State or local government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1052_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>