<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1060" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1060/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1060/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1060"><akn:num>1060</akn:num><akn:heading>Military service of retired members with newly democratic nations: consent of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1060. Military service of retired members with newly democratic nations: consent of Congress(a) Consent of Congress.—Subject to subsection (b), Congress consents to a retired member of the uniformed services—(1) accepting employment by, or holding an office or position in, the military forces of a newly democratic nation; and

(2) accepting compensation associated with such employment, office, or position.


(b) Approval Required.—The consent provided in subsection (a) for a retired member of the uniformed services to accept employment or hold an office or position shall apply to a retired member only if the Secretary concerned and the Secretary of State jointly approve the employment or the holding of such office or position.

(c) Determination of Newly Democratic Nations.—The Secretary concerned and the Secretary of State shall jointly determine whether a nation is a newly democratic nation for the purposes of this section.

[(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(9), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1597.]

(e) Continued Entitlement to Retired Pay and Benefits.—The eligibility of a retired member to receive retired or retainer pay and other benefits arising from the retired member’s status as a retired member of the uniformed services, and the eligibility of dependents of such retired member to receive benefits on the basis of such retired member’s status as a retired member of the uniformed services, may not be terminated by reason of employment or holding of an office or position consented to in subsection (a).

(f) Retired Member Defined.—In this section, the term “retired member” means a member or former member of the uniformed services who is entitled to receive retired or retainer pay.

(g) Civil Employment by Foreign Governments.—For a provision of law providing the consent of Congress to civil employment by foreign governments, see section 908 of title 37.

(Added Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XIV, § 1433(b)(1), Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1834</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent of Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b), Congress consents to a retired member of the uniformed services—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The consent provided in subsection (a) for a retired member of the uniformed services to accept employment or hold an office or position shall apply to a retired member only if the Secretary concerned and the Secretary of State jointly approve the employment or the holding of such office or position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Newly Democratic Nations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned and the Secretary of State shall jointly determine whether a nation is a newly democratic nation for the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(9), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1597.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued Entitlement to Retired Pay and Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The eligibility of a retired member to receive retired or retainer pay and other benefits arising from the retired member’s status as a retired member of the uniformed services, and the eligibility of dependents of such retired member to receive benefits on the basis of such retired member’s status as a retired member of the uniformed services, may not be terminated by reason of employment or holding of an office or position consented to in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retired Member Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “retired member” means a member or former member of the uniformed services who is entitled to receive retired or retainer pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1060_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Employment by Foreign Governments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For a provision of law providing the consent of Congress to civil employment by foreign governments, see section 908 of title 37.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>