<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1063" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1063/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1063/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1063"><akn:num>1063</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of commissary stores and MWR retail facilities: members of reserve components and reserve retire</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1063. Use of commissary stores and MWR retail facilities: members of reserve components and reserve retirees under age 60(a) Members of the Selected Reserve.—A member of the Selected Reserve in good standing (as determined by the Secretary concerned) shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members on active duty.

(b) Members of Ready Reserve Not in Selected Reserve.—Subject to such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, a member of the Ready Reserve (other than members of the Selected Reserve) may be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members serving on active duty.

(c) Reserve and Space Force Retirees Under Age 60.—A member or former member of a reserve component or the Space Force under 60 years of age who, but for age, would be eligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members of the armed forces entitled to retired pay under any other provision of law.

(d) Members of the Space Force.—A member of the Space Force in a space force active status who is not on sustained duty shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities under the same conditions as specified in subsection (a) for a member of the Selected Reserve.

(e) Dependents.—(1) Dependents of a member who is permitted under subsection (a), (b), or (d) to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities shall be permitted to use stores and such facilities on the same basis as dependents of members on active duty.

(2) Dependents of a member who is permitted under subsection (c) to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities shall be permitted to use stores and such facilities on the same basis as dependents of members of the armed forces entitled to retired pay under any other provision of law.


(f) MWR Retail Facility Defined.—In this section, the term “MWR retai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of the Selected Reserve.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A member of the Selected Reserve in good standing (as determined by the Secretary concerned) shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members on active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of Ready Reserve Not in Selected Reserve.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, a member of the Ready Reserve (other than members of the Selected Reserve) may be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members serving on active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve and Space Force Retirees Under Age 60.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A member or former member of a reserve component or the Space Force under 60 years of age who, but for age, would be eligible for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities on the same basis as members of the armed forces entitled to retired pay under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members of the Space Force.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A member of the Space Force in a space force active status who is not on sustained duty shall be permitted to use commissary stores and MWR retail facilities under the same conditions as specified in subsection (a) for a member of the Selected Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>MWR Retail Facility Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “MWR retail facilities” means exchange stores and other revenue-generating facilities operated by nonappropriated fund activities of the Department of Defense for the morale, welfare, and recreation of members of the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>