<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1072" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1072/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1072/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1072"><akn:num>1072</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1072. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) The term “uniformed services” means the armed forces and the Commissioned Corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and of the Public Health Service.

(2) The term “dependent”, with respect to a member or former member of a uniformed service, means—(A) the spouse;

(B) the unremarried widow;

(C) the unremarried widower;

(D) a child who—(i) has not attained the age of 21;

(ii) has not attained the age of 23, is enrolled in a full-time course of study at an institution of higher learning approved by the administering Secretary and is, or was at the time of the member’s or former member’s death, in fact dependent on the member or former member for over one-half of the child’s support; or

(iii) is incapable of self-support because of a mental or physical incapacity that occurs while a dependent of a member or former member under clause (i) or (ii) and is, or was at the time of the member’s or former member’s death, in fact dependent on the member or former member for over one-half of the child’s support;


(E) a parent or parent-in-law who is, or was at the time of the member’s or former member’s death, in fact dependent on him for over one-half of his support and residing in his household;

(F) the unremarried former spouse of a member or former member who (i) on the date of the final decree of divorce, dissolution, or annulment, had been married to the member or former member for a period of at least 20 years during which period the member or former member performed at least 20 years of service which is creditable in determining that member’s or former member’s eligibility for retired or retainer pay, or equivalent pay, and (ii) does not have medical coverage under an employer-sponsored health plan;

(G) a person who (i) is the unremarried former spouse of a member or former member who performed at least 20 years of service which is creditable in determining the member or former member’s eligibility for re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “uniformed services” means the armed forces and the Commissioned Corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and of the Public Health Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “dependent”, with respect to a member or former member of a uniformed service, means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “administering Secretaries” means the Secretaries of executive departments specified in section 1073 of this title as having responsibility for administering this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services” means the program authorized under sections 1079 and 1086 of this title and includes contracts entered into under section 1091 or 1097 of this title and demonstration projects under section 1092 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “covered beneficiary” means a beneficiary under this chapter other than a beneficiary under section 1074(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “child”, with respect to a member or former member of a uniformed service, means the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “TRICARE program” means the various programs carried out by the Secretary of Defense under this chapter and any other provision of law providing for the furnishing of medical and dental care and health benefits to members and former members of the uniformed services and their dependents, including the following health plan options:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “custodial care” means treatment or services, regardless of who recommends such treatment or services or where such treatment or services are provided, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “domiciliary care” means care provided to a patient in an institution or homelike environment because—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “health care” includes mental health care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>