<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1073a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1073a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1073a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1073a"><akn:num>1073a</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for health care: best value contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1073a. Contracts for health care: best value contracting(a) Authority.—Under regulations prescribed by the administering Secretaries, health care contracts shall be awarded in the administration of this chapter to the offeror or offerors that will provide the best value to the United States to the maximum extent consistent with furnishing high-quality health care in a manner that protects the fiscal and other interests of the United States.

(b) Factors Considered.—In the determination of best value under subsection (a)—(1) consideration shall be given to the factors specified in the regulations; and

(2) greater weight shall be accorded to technical and performance-related factors than to cost and price-related factors.


(c) Applicability.—The authority under the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall apply to any contract in excess of $5,000,000.

(Added Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VII, § 722(a), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 695.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Comptroller General Review of Defense Health Agency Oversight of Transition Between Managed Care Support Contractors for the TRICARE ProgramPub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VII, § 737, Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1821, provided that:
“(a) Briefing and Report on Current Transition.—“(1) In general.—The Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing and a report on a review by the Comptroller General of the oversight conducted by the Defense Health Agency with respect to the current transition between managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program. The briefing shall be provided by not later than July 1, 2019.

“(2) Elements.—The briefing and report under paragraph (1) shall each include the following:“(A) A description and assessment of the extent to which the Defense Health Agency provided guidance and oversight to the outgoing and incoming managed care support contractors for the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1073a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the administering Secretaries, health care contracts shall be awarded in the administration of this chapter to the offeror or offerors that will provide the best value to the United States to the maximum extent consistent with furnishing high-quality health care in a manner that protects the fiscal and other interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1073a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors Considered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In the determination of best value under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1073a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The authority under the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall apply to any contract in excess of $5,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>