<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1074m"><akn:num>1074m</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health assessments for members of the armed forces deployed in support of a contingency opera</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1074m. Mental health assessments for members of the armed forces deployed in support of a contingency operation(a) Mental Health Assessments.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall provide a person-to-person mental health assessment for each member of the armed forces who is deployed in support of a contingency operation as follows:(A) Once during the period beginning 120 days before the date of the deployment.

(B) Once during each 180-day period during which a member is deployed.

(C) Subject to paragraph (3) and subsection (d), once during the period beginning on the date of redeployment from the contingency operation and ending on the date that is 21 days after the date on which the post-deployment leave of the member terminates.

(D) Subject to subsection (d), not less than once annually—(i) beginning 21 days after the date on which the post-deployment leave of the member terminates; or

(ii) if the assessment required by subparagraph (C) is performed during the period specified in paragraph (3), beginning 180 days after the date of redeployment from the contingency operation.



(2) A mental health assessment is not required for a member of the armed forces under subparagraphs (C) and (D) of paragraph (1) (including an assessment performed pursuant to paragraph (3)) if the Secretary determines that providing such assessment to the member during the time periods under such subparagraphs would remove the member from forward deployment or put members or operational objectives at risk.

(3) A mental health assessment required under subparagraph (C) of paragraph (1) may be provided during the period beginning 90 days after the date of redeployment from the contingency operation and ending 180 days after such redeployment date if the Secretary determines that—(A) an insufficient number of personnel are available to perform the assessment during the time period under such subparagraph; or

(B) an administrative processing issue exists upon the return of the member to t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental Health Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purpose of the mental health assessments provided pursuant to this section shall be to identify post-traumatic stress disorder, suicidal tendencies, and other behavioral health conditions identified among members described in subsection (a) in order to determine which such members are in need of additional care and treatment for such health conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cessation of Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No mental health assessment is required to be provided to an individual under subparagraph (C) or (D) of subsection (a)(1) after the individual’s discharge or release from the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>