<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1074a"><akn:num>1074a</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical and dental care: members on duty other than active duty for a period of more than 30 days</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1074a. Medical and dental care: members on duty other than active duty for a period of more than 30 days(a) Under joint regulations prescribed by the administering Secretaries, the following persons are entitled to the benefits described in subsection (b):(1) Each member of a uniformed service who incurs or aggravates an injury, illness, or disease in the line of duty while performing—(A) active duty for a period of 30 days or less;

(B) inactive-duty training; or

(C) service on funeral honors duty under section 12503 of this title or section 115 of title 32.


(2) Each member of a uniformed service who incurs or aggravates an injury, illness, or disease while traveling directly to or from the place at which that member is to perform or has performed—(A) active duty for a period of 30 days or less;

(B) inactive-duty training; or

(C) service on funeral honors duty under section 12503 of this title or section 115 of title 32.


(3) Each member of the armed forces who incurs or aggravates an injury, illness, or disease in the line of duty while remaining overnight immediately before the commencement of inactive-duty training, or while remaining overnight, between successive periods of inactive-duty training, at or in the vicinity of the site of the inactive-duty training.

(4) Each member of the armed forces who incurs or aggravates an injury, illness, or disease in the line of duty while remaining overnight immediately before serving on funeral honors duty under section 12503 of this title or section 115 of title 32 at or in the vicinity of the place at which the member was to so serve, if the place is outside reasonable commuting distance from the member’s residence.


(b) A person described in subsection (a) is entitled to—(1) the medical and dental care appropriate for the treatment of the injury, illness, or disease of that person until the resulting disability cannot be materially improved by further hospitalization or treatment; and

(2) subsistence during </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under joint regulations prescribed by the administering Secretaries, the following persons are entitled to the benefits described in subsection (b):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person described in subsection (a) is entitled to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A member is not entitled to benefits under subsection (b) if the injury, illness, or disease, or aggravation of an injury, illness, or disease described in subsection (a)(2), is the result of the gross negligence or misconduct of the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Amounts available for operation and maintenance of a reserve component of the armed forces may be available for purposes of this section to ensure the medical, dental, and behavioral health readiness of members of such reserve component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>