<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1074i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1074i"><akn:num>1074i</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for certain travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1074i. Reimbursement for certain travel expenses(a) In General.—In any case in which a covered beneficiary is referred by a primary care physician to a specialty care provider who provides services more than 100 miles from the location in which the primary care provider provides services to the covered beneficiary, the Secretary of Defense shall provide travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under section 464 of title 37 for the covered beneficiary and, when accompaniment by an adult is necessary, for a parent or guardian of the covered beneficiary or another member of the covered beneficiary’s family who is at least 21 years of age.

(b) Allowable Travel and Transportation Under Exceptional Circumstances.—The Secretary of Defense may provide travel and transportation allowances as specified in the regulations referred to in subsection (a) for travel of members of the armed forces on active duty and their dependents, and accompaniment, to a specialty care provider not otherwise authorized by subsection (a) under such exceptional circumstances as the Secretary considers appropriate for purposes of this section.

(c) Outreach Program and Travel Reimbursement for Follow-on Specialty Care and Related Services.—The Secretary concerned shall ensure that an outreach program is implemented for each member of the uniformed services who incurred a combat-related disability and is entitled to retired or retainer pay, or equivalent pay, so that—(1) the progress of the member is closely monitored; and

(2) the member receives the travel reimbursement authorized by subsection (a) whenever the member requires follow-on specialty care, services, or supplies.


(d) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “specialty care provider” includes a dental specialist.

(2) The term “dental specialist” means an oral surgeon, orthodontist, prosthodontist, periodontist, endodontist, or pediatric dentist, and includes such other providers of dental care a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In any case in which a covered beneficiary is referred by a primary care physician to a specialty care provider who provides services more than 100 miles from the location in which the primary care provider provides services to the covered beneficiary, the Secretary of Defense shall provide travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under section 464 of title 37 for the covered beneficiary and, when accompaniment by an adult is necessary, for a parent or guardian of the covered beneficiary or another member of the covered beneficiary’s family who is at least 21 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable Travel and Transportation Under Exceptional Circumstances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may provide travel and transportation allowances as specified in the regulations referred to in subsection (a) for travel of members of the armed forces on active duty and their dependents, and accompaniment, to a specialty care provider not otherwise authorized by subsection (a) under such exceptional circumstances as the Secretary considers appropriate for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach Program and Travel Reimbursement for Follow-on Specialty Care and Related Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned shall ensure that an outreach program is implemented for each member of the uniformed services who incurred a combat-related disability and is entitled to retired or retainer pay, or equivalent pay, so that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1074i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>