<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1075a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1075a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1075a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1075a"><akn:num>1075a</akn:num><akn:heading>TRICARE Prime: cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1075a. TRICARE Prime: cost sharing(a) Cost-sharing Requirements.—The cost-sharing requirements under TRICARE Prime are as follows:(1) There are no cost-sharing requirements for beneficiaries who are covered by section 1074(a) of this title.

(2) With respect to beneficiaries in the active-duty family member category or the retired category (as described in section 1075(b)(1) of this title) by reason of being a member or former member of the uniformed services who originally enlists or is appointed in the uniformed services on or after January 1, 2018, or by reason of being a dependent of such a member, the cost-sharing requirements shall be calculated pursuant to subsection (b)(1).

(3)(A) With respect to beneficiaries described in subparagraph (B) in the active-duty family member category or the retired category (as described in section 1075(b)(1) of this title), the cost-sharing requirements shall be calculated in accordance with the other provisions of this chapter without regard to subsection (b).

(B) Beneficiaries described in this subparagraph are beneficiaries who are eligible to enroll in the TRICARE program by reason of being a member or former member of the uniformed services who originally enlists or is appointed in the uniformed services before January 1, 2018, or by reason of being a dependent of such a member.



(b) Cost-sharing Amounts.—(1) Beneficiaries described in subsection (a)(2) enrolled in TRICARE Prime shall be subject to cost-sharing requirements in accordance with the amounts and percentages under the following table during calendar year 2018 and as such amounts are adjusted under paragraph (2) for subsequent years:







TRICARE Prime Active-Duty Family Member  (Individual/Family)  Retired  (Individual/Family) 


Annual Enrollment$0$350 / $700
Annual deductibleNoNo
Annual catastrophic cap$1,000$3,500
Outpatient visit civilian network$0$20 primary care
..................... $30 specialty care
ER visit civilian network$0$60 network
Urgen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1075a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The cost-sharing requirements under TRICARE Prime are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1075a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1075a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule for Amounts Without Referrals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notwithstanding subsection (b)(1), the cost-sharing amount for a beneficiary enrolled in TRICARE Prime who does not obtain a referral for care under paragraph (1) of section 1095f(a) of this title (or a waiver pursuant to paragraph (2) of such section for such care) shall be an amount equal to 50 percent of the allowed point-of-service charge for such care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1075a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Cost-sharing for Certain Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>