<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1076e"><akn:num>1076e</akn:num><akn:heading>TRICARE program: TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage for certain members of the Retired Reserve who are</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1076e. TRICARE program: TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage for certain members of the Retired Reserve who are qualified for a non-regular retirement but are not yet age 60(a) Eligibility.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Retired Reserve of a reserve component of the armed forces who is qualified for a non-regular retirement at age 60 under chapter 1223 of this title, but is not age 60, is eligible for health benefits under TRICARE Retired Reserve as provided in this section.

(2) Paragraph (1) does not apply to a member who is enrolled, or is eligible to enroll, in a health benefits plan under chapter 89 of title 5.


(b) Termination of Eligibility Upon Obtaining Other TRICARE Coverage.—Eligibility for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage of a member under this section shall terminate upon the member becoming eligible for TRICARE coverage at age 60 under section 1086 of this title.

(c) Family Members.—While a member of a reserve component is covered by TRICARE Retired Reserve under this section, the members of the immediate family of such member are eligible for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage as dependents of the member. If a member of a reserve component dies while in a period of coverage under this section, the eligibility of the members of the immediate family of such member for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage under this section shall continue for the same period of time that would be provided under section 1086 of this title if the member had been eligible at the time of death for TRICARE coverage under such section (instead of under this section).

(d) Premiums.—(1) A member of a reserve component covered by TRICARE Retired Reserve under this section shall pay a premium for that coverage. Such premium shall apply instead of any enrollment fees required under section 1075 of this title.

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for the purposes of this section one premium for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage of members without depende</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Eligibility Upon Obtaining Other TRICARE Coverage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage of a member under this section shall terminate upon the member becoming eligible for TRICARE coverage at age 60 under section 1086 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) While a member of a reserve component is covered by TRICARE Retired Reserve under this section, the members of the immediate family of such member are eligible for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage as dependents of the member. If a member of a reserve component dies while in a period of coverage under this section, the eligibility of the members of the immediate family of such member for TRICARE Retired Reserve coverage under this section shall continue for the same period of time that would be provided under section 1086 of this title if the member had been eligible at the time of death for TRICARE coverage under such section (instead of under this section).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the other administering Secretaries, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>