<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1076c"><akn:num>1076c</akn:num><akn:heading>Dental insurance plan: certain retirees and their surviving spouses and other dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1076c. Dental insurance plan: certain retirees and their surviving spouses and other dependents(a) Requirement for Plan.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a dental insurance plan for retirees of the uniformed services, certain unremarried surviving spouses, and dependents in accordance with this section.

(2) The Secretary may satisfy the requirement under paragraph (1) by entering into an agreement with the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to allow persons described in subsection (b) to enroll in an insurance plan under chapter 89A of title 5 that provides benefits similar to those benefits required to be provided under subsection (d).


(b) Persons Eligible for Plan.—The following persons are eligible to enroll in the dental insurance plan established under subsection (a):(1) Members of the uniformed services who are entitled to retired pay.

(2) Members of the Retired Reserve who would be entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title but for being under 60 years of age.

(3) Eligible dependents of a member described in paragraph (1) or (2) who are covered by the enrollment of the member in the plan.

(4) Eligible dependents of a member described in paragraph (1) or (2) who is not enrolled in the plan and who—(A) is enrolled under section 1705 of title 38 to receive dental care from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;

(B) is enrolled in a dental plan that—(i) is available to the member as a result of employment by the member that is separate from the military service of the member; and

(ii) is not available to dependents of the member as a result of such separate employment by the member; or


(C) is prevented by a medical or dental condition from being able to obtain benefits under the plan.


(5) The unremarried surviving spouse and eligible child dependents of a deceased member—(A) who died while in a status described in paragraph (1) or (2);

(B) who is described in section 1448(d)(1) of this title; or

(C) who died while</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Eligible for Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The following persons are eligible to enroll in the dental insurance plan established under subsection (a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits Available Under the Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The dental insurance plan established under subsection (a) shall provide benefits for dental care and treatment which may be comparable to the benefits authorized under section 1076a of this title for plans established under that section and shall include diagnostic services, preventative services, endodontics and other basic restorative services, surgical services, and emergency services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Terminations of Enrollment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall terminate the enrollment of any enrollee, and any eligible dependents of the enrollee covered by the enrollment, in the dental insurance plan established under subsection (a) upon the occurrence of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of Dependents’ Enrollment Upon Death of Enrollee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coverage of a dependent in the dental insurance plan established under subsection (a) under an enrollment of a member or a surviving spouse who dies during the period of enrollment shall continue until the end of that period and may be renewed by (or for) the dependent, so long as the premium paid is sufficient to cover continuation of the dependent’s enrollment. The Secretary may terminate coverage of the dependent when the premiums paid are no longer sufficient to cover continuation of the enrollment. The Secretary shall prescribe in regulations under subsection (h) the parties responsible for paying the remaining premiums due on the enrollment and the manner for collection of the premiums.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The dental insurance plan established under subsection (a) shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the other administering Secretaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary Disenrollment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>