<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1076d"><akn:num>1076d</akn:num><akn:heading>TRICARE program: TRICARE Reserve Select coverage for members of the Selected Reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1076d. TRICARE program: TRICARE Reserve Select coverage for members of the Selected Reserve(a) Eligibility.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve of a reserve component of the armed forces is eligible for health benefits under TRICARE Reserve Select as provided in this section.

(2) During the period preceding January 1, 2030, paragraph (1) does not apply to a member who is enrolled, or is eligible to enroll, in a health benefits plan under chapter 89 of title 5.


(b) Termination of Eligibility Upon Termination of Service.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), eligibility for TRICARE Reserve Select coverage of a member under this section shall terminate upon the termination of the member’s service in the Selected Reserve.

(2) During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph and ending December 31, 2018, eligibility for a member under this section who is involuntarily separated from the Selected Reserve under other than adverse conditions, as characterized by the Secretary concerned, shall terminate 180 days after the date on which the member is separated.


(c) Family Members.—While a member of a reserve component is covered by TRICARE Reserve Select under the section, the members of the immediate family of such member are eligible for TRICARE Reserve Select coverage as dependents of the member. If a member of a reserve component dies while in a period of coverage under this section, the eligibility of the members of the immediate family of such member for TRICARE Reserve Select coverage shall continue for three years beyond the date of death of the member.

(d) Premiums.—(1) A member of a reserve component covered by TRICARE Reserve Select under this section shall pay a premium for that coverage. Such premium shall apply instead of any enrollment fees required under section 1075 of this title.

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for the purposes of this section one p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Eligibility Upon Termination of Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) While a member of a reserve component is covered by TRICARE Reserve Select under the section, the members of the immediate family of such member are eligible for TRICARE Reserve Select coverage as dependents of the member. If a member of a reserve component dies while in a period of coverage under this section, the eligibility of the members of the immediate family of such member for TRICARE Reserve Select coverage shall continue for three years beyond the date of death of the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the other administering Secretaries, shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>