<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1076a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1076a"><akn:num>1076a</akn:num><akn:heading>TRICARE dental program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1076a. TRICARE dental program(a) Establishment of Dental Plans.—The Secretary of Defense may establish, and in the case of the dental plan described in paragraph (1) shall establish, the following voluntary enrollment dental plans:(1) Plan for selected reserve and individual ready reserve.—A dental insurance plan for members of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve and for members of the Individual Ready Reserve described in subsection 10144(b) of this title.

(2) Plan for other reserves.—A dental insurance plan for members of the Individual Ready Reserve not eligible to enroll in the plan established under paragraph (1).

(3) Plan for active duty dependents.—Dental benefits plans for eligible dependents of members of the uniformed services who are on active duty for a period of more than 30 days.

(4) Plan for ready reserve dependents.—A dental benefits plan for eligible dependents of members of the Ready Reserve of the reserve components who are not on active duty for more than 30 days.


(b) Administration of Plans.—(1) In general.—The plans established under this section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the other administering Secretaries.

(2) Premium sharing plans.—Effective as of January 1, 2027, the regulations prescribed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to premium sharing plans referred to in subsection (d)(1), the following elements:(A) A third party administrator shall manage the administrative features of such plans, including eligibility, enrollment, plan change and premium payment processes, submission of qualifying life events changes, and address changes.

(B) Such plans shall include the following three enrollment options:(i) Self.

(ii) Self plus one.

(iii) Family.


(C) In the United States, to the extent practicable, individuals eligible to enroll in such a plan shall be offered options to enroll in plans of not fewer than two and not more than four den</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Dental Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may establish, and in the case of the dental plan described in paragraph (1) shall establish, the following voluntary enrollment dental plans:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Care Available Under Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dental plans established under subsection (a) may provide for the following dental care:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Copayments Under Premium Sharing Plans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If a member whose dependents are enrolled in the plan established under subsection (a)(3) is transferred to a duty station where dental care is provided to the member’s eligible dependents under a program other than that plan, the member may discontinue participation under the plan. If the member is later transferred to a duty station where dental care is not provided to such member’s eligible dependents except under the plan established under subsection (a)(3), the member may re-enroll the dependents in that plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Care Outside the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense may exercise the authority provided under subsection (a) to establish dental insurance plans and dental benefits plans for dental benefits provided outside the United States for the eligible members and dependents of members of the uniformed services. In the case of such an overseas dental plan, the Secretary may waive or reduce any copayments required by subsection (e) to the extent the Secretary determines appropriate for the effective and efficient operation of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Requirements for Surviving Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of Defense may waive (in whole or in part) any requirements of a dental plan established under this section as the Secretary determines necessary for the effective administration of the plan for a dependent who is an eligible dependent described in subsection (k)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority Subject to Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The authority of the Secretary of Defense to enter into a contract under this section for any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1076a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Reduction of Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) During the period preceding January 1, 2027, the Secretary of Defense may not reduce benefits provided under a plan established under this section, and on or after January 1, 2027, the Secretary may not reduce benefits provided under a standard option plan under this section, until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>