<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1077" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1077/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1077/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1077"><akn:num>1077</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical care for dependents: authorized care in facilities of uniformed services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1077. Medical care for dependents: authorized care in facilities of uniformed services(a) Only the following types of health care may be provided under section 1076 of this title:(1) Hospitalization.

(2) Outpatient care.

(3) Drugs, including, in accordance with subsection (h), medically necessary vitamins.

(4) Treatment of medical and surgical conditions.

(5) Treatment of nervous, mental, and chronic conditions.

(6) Treatment of contagious diseases.

(7) Physical examinations, including eye examinations, and immunizations.

(8) Maternity and infant care, including well-baby care that includes one screening of an infant for the level of lead in the blood of the infant.

(9) Diagnostic tests and services, including laboratory and X-ray examinations.

(10) Dental care.

(11) Ambulance service and home calls when medically necessary.

(12) Durable equipment, which may be provided on a loan basis.

(13) Primary and preventive health care services for women (as defined in section 1074d(b) of this title).

(14) Preventive health care screening for colon or prostate cancer, at the intervals and using the screening methods prescribed under section 1074d(a)(2) of this title.

(15) Prosthetic devices, as determined by the Secretary of Defense to be necessary because of significant conditions resulting from trauma, congenital anomalies, or disease.

(16) Except as provided by subsection (g), a hearing aid, but only if the dependent has a profound hearing loss, as determined under standards prescribed in regulations by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the administering Secretaries, and only for the following dependents:(A) A dependent of a member of the uniformed services on active duty.

(B) A dependent under subparagraph (D) or (I) of section 1072(2) of this title of a former member of the uniformed services who—(i) is entitled to retired or retainer pay, or equivalent pay; and

(ii) is enrolled in family coverage under TRICARE Prime.



(17) Any rehabilita</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Only the following types of health care may be provided under section 1076 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The following types of health care may not be provided under section 1076 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1077_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>