<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1079" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1079/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1079/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1079"><akn:num>1079</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for medical care for spouses and children: plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1079. Contracts for medical care for spouses and children: plans(a) To assure that medical care is available for dependents, as described in subparagraphs (A), (D), and (I) of section 1072(2) of this title, of members of the uniformed services who are on active duty for a period of more than 30 days, the Secretary of Defense, after consulting with the other administering Secretaries, shall contract, under the authority of this section, for medical care for those persons under such insurance, medical service, or health plans as he considers appropriate. The types of health care authorized under this section shall be the same as those provided under section 1076 of this title, except as follows:(1) With respect to dental care—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), only that care required as a necessary adjunct to medical or surgical treatment may be provided; and

(B) in connection with dental treatment for patients with developmental, mental, or physical disabilities or for pediatric patients age 5 or under, only institutional and anesthesia services may be provided.


(2) Consistent with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe regarding the content of health promotion and disease prevention visits, the schedule and method of cervical cancer screenings and breast cancer screenings, the schedule and method of colon and prostate cancer screenings, and the types and schedule of immunizations—(A) for dependents under six years of age, both health promotion and disease prevention visits and immunizations may be provided; and

(B) for dependents six years of age or older, health promotion and disease prevention visits may be provided in connection with immunizations or with diagnostic or preventive cervical and breast cancer screenings or colon and prostate cancer screenings.


(3) Not more than one eye examination may be provided to a patient in any calendar year.

(4) Under joint regulations to be prescribed by the administering Secretaries, the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To assure that medical care is available for dependents, as described in subparagraphs (A), (D), and (I) of section 1072(2) of this title, of members of the uniformed services who are on active duty for a period of more than 30 days, the Secretary of Defense, after consulting with the other administering Secretaries, shall contract, under the authority of this section, for medical care for those persons under such insurance, medical service, or health plans as he considers appropriate. The types of health care authorized under this section shall be the same as those provided under section 1076 of this title, except as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plans covered by subsection (a) shall include provisions for payment by the patient of the following amounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The methods for making payment under subsection (b) shall be prescribed under joint regulations issued by the administering Secretaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1079_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A plan covered by this section may include provision of liver transplants (including the cost of acquisition and transportation of the donated liver) in accordance with this subsection. Such a liver transplant may be provided if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>