<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1091a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1091a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1091a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1091a"><akn:num>1091a</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification in patient medical records of affiliation of certain non-Department of Defense health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1091a. Identification in patient medical records of affiliation of certain non-Department of Defense health care providers(a) Requirement.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that medical records of the Department of Defense include the organizational affiliation of any independent health care contractor identified in such medical records.

(b) Independent Health Care Contractor Defined.—In this section, the term “independent health care contractor” means a health care provider who meets the following criteria:(1) The health care provider is a nonpersonal services contractor, or an employee of such a contractor, pursuant to subpart 37.4 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation, or other applicable regulation.

(2) The health care provider provides health care services under this chapter in any military medical treatment facility (as defined in section 1073c(i) of this title) or other location under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense, including an operational clinic.


(Added Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title VII, § 711, Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 1947.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that medical records of the Department of Defense include the organizational affiliation of any independent health care contractor identified in such medical records.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent Health Care Contractor Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “independent health care contractor” means a health care provider who meets the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>