<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1100" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1100/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1100/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1100"><akn:num>1100</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Health Program Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1100. Defense Health Program Account(a) Establishment of Account.—(1) There is hereby established in the Department of Defense an account to be known as the “Defense Health Program Account”. All sums appropriated to carry out the functions of the Secretary of Defense with respect to medical and health care programs of the Department of Defense shall be appropriated to the account.

(2) Of the total amount appropriated for a fiscal year for programs and activities carried out under this chapter, the amount equal to three percent of such total amount shall remain available for obligation until the end of the following fiscal year.


(b) Obligation of Amounts From Account by Secretary of Defense.—The Secretary of Defense may obligate or expend funds from the account for purposes of conducting programs and activities under this chapter, including contracts entered into under section 1079, 1086, 1092, or 1097 of this title, to the extent amounts are available in the account.

(c) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.

(Added Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title VII, § 701(a)(1), Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3896; amended Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VII, § 735(a)–(d)(1), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 382.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–106, § 735(d)(1), amended section catchline generally, substituting “Defense Health Program Account” for “Military Health Care Account”.
Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 104–106, § 735(a)(1), substituted “Defense Health Program Account” for “Military Health Care Account” and “medical and health care programs of the Department of Defense” for “the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services”.
Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 104–106, § 735(b), amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “Amounts appropriated to the account shall remain available until obligated or expended under subsection (b) or (c).”
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 104–106, § 735(a)(2), substitute</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1100_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Account.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1100_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of Amounts From Account by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may obligate or expend funds from the account for purposes of conducting programs and activities under this chapter, including contracts entered into under section 1079, 1086, 1092, or 1097 of this title, to the extent amounts are available in the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1100_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>