<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1104"><akn:num>1104</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of health-care resources with the Department of Veterans Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1104. Sharing of health-care resources with the Department of Veterans Affairs(a) Sharing of Health-Care Resources.—Health-care resources of the Department of Defense shall be shared with health-care resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with section 8111 of title 38 or under section 1535 of title 31.

(b) Reimbursement From CHAMPUS Funds.—Pursuant to an agreement entered into under section 8111 of title 38 or section 1535 of title 31, the Secretary of a military department may reimburse the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from funds available for that military department for the payment of medical care provided under section 1079 or 1086 of this title.

(c) Charges.—The Secretary of Defense may prescribe by regulation a premium, deductible, copayment, or other charge for health care provided to covered beneficiaries under this chapter pursuant to an agreement entered into by the Secretary of a military department under section 8111 of title 38 or section 1535 of title 31.

(d) Provision of Services During War or National Emergency.—Members of the armed forces on active duty during and immediately following a period of war, or during and immediately following a national emergency involving the use of the armed forces in armed conflict, may be provided health-care services by the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with section 8111A of title 38.

(Added Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title VII, § 722(a), Nov. 29, 1989, 103 Stat. 1477; amended Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(14), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2499; Pub. L. 103–35, title II, § 201(c)(1), May 31, 1993, 107 Stat. 98; Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VII, § 721(b), Dec. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 2595.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2002—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 107–314 substituted “shall” for “may”.
1993—Subsecs. (a) to (c). Pub. L. 103–35, § 201(c)(1)(A), substituted “section 8111 of title 38” for “section 8011 of title 38”.
Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 103–35, § 201(c)(1)(B), substituted “sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Health-Care Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Health-care resources of the Department of Defense shall be shared with health-care resources of the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with section 8111 of title 38 or under section 1535 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement From CHAMPUS Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pursuant to an agreement entered into under section 8111 of title 38 or section 1535 of title 31, the Secretary of a military department may reimburse the Secretary of Veterans Affairs from funds available for that military department for the payment of medical care provided under section 1079 or 1086 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may prescribe by regulation a premium, deductible, copayment, or other charge for health care provided to covered beneficiaries under this chapter pursuant to an agreement entered into by the Secretary of a military department under section 8111 of title 38 or section 1535 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of Services During War or National Emergency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Members of the armed forces on active duty during and immediately following a period of war, or during and immediately following a national emergency involving the use of the armed forces in armed conflict, may be provided health-care services by the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with section 8111A of title 38.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>