<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1106"><akn:num>1106</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal of claims: standard form; time limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1106. Submittal of claims: standard form; time limits(a) Standard Form.—The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the other administering Secretaries, shall prescribe by regulation a standard form for the submission of claims for the payment of health care services provided under this chapter.

(b) Time for Submission.—A claim for payment for services provided under this chapter shall be submitted as provided in such regulations as follows:(1) In the case of services provided outside the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or the possessions of the United States, by not later than three years after the services are provided.

(2) In the case of any other services, by not later than one year after the services are provided.


(Added Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title VII, § 716(a)(1), Dec. 5, 1991, 105 Stat. 1403; amended Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VII, § 738(a), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 1815; Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title VII, § 712, Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1476.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2011—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 112–81 substituted “as follows:” for “not later than one year after the services are provided.” and added pars. (1) and (2).
1997—Pub. L. 105–85 substituted “: standard form; time limits” for “under CHAMPUS” in section catchline and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:
“(a) Submittal to Claims Processing Office.—Each provider of services under the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services shall submit claims for payment for such services directly to the claims processing office designated pursuant to regulations prescribed under subsection (b). A claim for payment for services shall be submitted in a standard form (as prescribed in the regulations) not later than one year after the services are provided.
“(b) Regulations.—The regulations required by subsection (a) shall be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense after consultation with the other administering Secretaries.
“(c) Waiver.—</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard Form.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the other administering Secretaries, shall prescribe by regulation a standard form for the submission of claims for the payment of health care services provided under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Submission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A claim for payment for services provided under this chapter shall be submitted as provided in such regulations as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>