<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1107" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1107/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1107/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1107"><akn:num>1107</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of use of an investigational new drug or a drug unapproved for its applied use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1107. Notice of use of an investigational new drug or a drug unapproved for its applied use(a) Notice Required.—(1) Whenever the Secretary of Defense requests or requires a member of the armed forces to receive an investigational new drug or a drug unapproved for its applied use, the Secretary shall provide the member with notice containing the information specified in subsection (d).

(2) The Secretary shall also ensure that health care providers who administer an investigational new drug or a drug unapproved for its applied use, or who are likely to treat members who receive such a drug, receive the information required to be provided under paragraphs (3) and (4) of subsection (d).


(b) Time of Notice.—The notice required to be provided to a member under subsection (a)(1) shall be provided before the investigational new drug or drug unapproved for its applied use is first administered to the member.

(c) Form of Notice.—The notice required under subsection (a)(1) shall be provided in writing.

(d) Content of Notice.—The notice required under subsection (a)(1) shall include the following:(1) Clear notice that the drug being administered is an investigational new drug or a drug unapproved for its applied use.

(2) The reasons why the investigational new drug or drug unapproved for its applied use is being administered.

(3) Information regarding the possible side effects of the investigational new drug or drug unapproved for its applied use, including any known side effects possible as a result of the interaction of such drug with other drugs or treatments being administered to the members receiving such drug.

(4) Such other information that, as a condition of authorizing the use of the investigational new drug or drug unapproved for its applied use, the Secretary of Health and Human Services may require to be disclosed.


(e) Records of Use.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the medical records of members accurately document—(1) the receipt by members </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The notice required to be provided to a member under subsection (a)(1) shall be provided before the investigational new drug or drug unapproved for its applied use is first administered to the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The notice required under subsection (a)(1) shall be provided in writing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The notice required under subsection (a)(1) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records of Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the medical records of members accurately document—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation and Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1107_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>