<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_113"><akn:num>113</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 113. Secretary of Defense(a)(1) There is a Secretary of Defense, who is the head of the Department of Defense, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.

(2) A person may not be appointed as Secretary of Defense—(A) within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force in a grade below O–7; or

(B) within 10 years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force in the grade of O–7 or above.



(b) The Secretary is the principal assistant to the President in all matters relating to the Department of Defense. Subject to the direction of the President and to this title and section 2 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3002) he has authority, direction, and control over the Department of Defense.

(c) The Secretary shall report annually in writing to the President and the Congress on the expenditures, work, and accomplishments of the Department of Defense during the period covered by the report, together with—(1) a report from each military department on the expenditures, work, and accomplishments of that department;

(2) a report from each military department on the status of diversity and inclusion of members and civilian employees in such department, including the status of diversity and inclusion in the military service academies, the Officer Candidate and Training Schools, and the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs of such department;

(3) itemized statements showing the savings of public funds, and the eliminations of unnecessary duplications, made under sections 125 and 191 of this title; and

(4) such recommendations as he considers appropriate.


(d) Unless specifically prohibited by law, the Secretary may, without being relieved of his responsibility, perform any of his functions or duties, or exercise any of his powers through, or with the aid of, such persons in, or o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary is the principal assistant to the President in all matters relating to the Department of Defense. Subject to the direction of the President and to this title and section 2 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3002) he has authority, direction, and control over the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall report annually in writing to the President and the Congress on the expenditures, work, and accomplishments of the Department of Defense during the period covered by the report, together with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Unless specifically prohibited by law, the Secretary may, without being relieved of his responsibility, perform any of his functions or duties, or exercise any of his powers through, or with the aid of, such persons in, or organizations of, the Department of Defense as he may designate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) When a vacancy occurs in an office within the Department of Defense and the office is to be filled by a person appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the Secretary of Defense shall inform the President of the qualifications needed by a person serving in that office to carry out effectively the duties and responsibilities of that office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of Defense shall keep the Secretaries of the military departments informed with respect to military operations and activities of the Department of Defense that directly affect their respective responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>