<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1134a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1134a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1134a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1134a"><akn:num>1134a</akn:num><akn:heading>Medal of honor: Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1134a. Medal of honor: Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll(a) Establishment.—There shall be in the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, the Department of the Air Force, and the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating a roll designated as the “Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll”.

(b) Enrollment.—The Secretary concerned shall enter and record on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll the name of each person who has served on active duty in the armed forces and who has been awarded a medal of honor pursuant to section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of this title or section 2732 of title 14.

(c) Issuance of Enrollment Certificate.—Each living person whose name is entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll shall be issued a certificate of enrollment on the roll.

(d) Entitlement to Special Pension; Notice to Secretary of Veterans Affairs.—The Secretary concerned shall deliver to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a certified copy of each certificate of enrollment issued under subsection (c). The copy of the certificate shall authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay the special pension provided by section 1562 of title 38 to the person named in the certificate.

(Added Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title V, § 563(a)(1), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 767; amended Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(a), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1840; Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(15), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 684.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2023—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 118–31 substituted “section 2732 of title 14” for “section 491 of title 14”.
2018—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 115–232 substituted “section 7271, 8291, or 9271” for “section 3741, 6241, or 8741”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 115–232 effective Feb. 1, 2019, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There shall be in the Department of the Army, the Department of the Navy, the Department of the Air Force, and the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating a roll designated as the “Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall enter and record on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll the name of each person who has served on active duty in the armed forces and who has been awarded a medal of honor pursuant to section 7271, 8291, or 9271 of this title or section 2732 of title 14.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of Enrollment Certificate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each living person whose name is entered on the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard Medal of Honor Roll shall be issued a certificate of enrollment on the roll.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to Special Pension; Notice to Secretary of Veterans Affairs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned shall deliver to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs a certified copy of each certificate of enrollment issued under subsection (c). The copy of the certificate shall authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay the special pension provided by section 1562 of title 38 to the person named in the certificate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>