<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/113a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_113a"><akn:num>113a</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission of annual defense authorization request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 113a. Transmission of annual defense authorization request(a) Time for Transmittal.—The Secretary of Defense shall transmit to Congress the annual defense authorization request for a fiscal year during the first 30 days after the date on which the President transmits to Congress the budget for that fiscal year pursuant to section 1105 of title 31.

(b) Defense Authorization Request Defined.—In this section, the term “defense authorization request”, with respect to a fiscal year, means a legislative proposal submitted to Congress for the enactment of the following:(1) Authorizations of appropriations for that fiscal year, as required by section 114 of this title.

(2) Personnel strengths for that fiscal year, as required by section 115 of this title.

(3) Authority to carry out military construction projects, as required by section 2802 of this title.

(4) Any other matter that is proposed by the Secretary of Defense to be enacted as part of the annual defense authorization bill for that fiscal year.


(Added Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title X, § 1061(a), Dec. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 2649; amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1044(a), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1612.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2003—Subsec. (b)(3), (4). Pub. L. 108–136 added par. (3) and redesignated former par. (3) as (4).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Transmittal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall transmit to Congress the annual defense authorization request for a fiscal year during the first 30 days after the date on which the President transmits to Congress the budget for that fiscal year pursuant to section 1105 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_113a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Authorization Request Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “defense authorization request”, with respect to a fiscal year, means a legislative proposal submitted to Congress for the enactment of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>