<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1153"><akn:num>1153</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to separated members to obtain employment with health care providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1153. Assistance to separated members to obtain employment with health care providers(a) Placement Program.—The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may establish a program to assist eligible members of the armed forces to obtain employment with health care providers upon their discharge or release from active duty.

(b) Eligible Members.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member shall be eligible for selection to participate in the program established under subsection (a) if the member—(A) is selected for involuntary separation, is approved for separation under section 1174a or 1175 of this title, or retires pursuant to the authority provided in section 4403 of the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992 (division D of Public Law 102–484; 10 U.S.C. 1293 note) during the six-year period beginning on October 1, 1993;

(B) has received an associate degree, baccalaureate, or advanced degree from an accredited institution of higher education or a junior or community college; and

(C) has a military occupational specialty, training, or experience related to health care, is likely to be able to obtain such training in a short period of time (as determined by the Secretary concerned), or satisfies such other criteria for selection as the Secretary concerned may prescribe.


(2) For purposes of this section, a former member of the armed forces who did not meet the minimum educational qualification criterion set forth in paragraph (1)(B) for placement assistance before discharge or release from active duty shall be considered to be a member satisfying such educational qualification criterion upon satisfying that criterion within five years after discharge or release from active duty.

(3) A member who is discharged or released from service under other than honorable conditions shall not be eligible to participate in the program.


(c) Selection of Participants.—(1) The Secretar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Placement Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard, may establish a program to assist eligible members of the armed forces to obtain employment with health care providers upon their discharge or release from active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to Facilitate Employment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements With States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1153_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, American Samoa, the Federated States of Micronesia, Guam, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Palau, and the Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>