<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/115a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/115a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/115a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_115a"><akn:num>115a</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual defense manpower profile report and related reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 115a. Annual defense manpower profile report and related reports(a) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and furnish to any Member of Congress upon request, a defense manpower profile report. The report shall contain the Secretary’s recommendations for—(1) the annual active-duty end-strength level for each component of the armed forces for the next fiscal year; and

(2) the annual civilian personnel requirements level for each component of the Department of Defense for the next fiscal year and the civilian end-strength level for the prior fiscal year.


(b)(1) The Secretary shall include in each report under subsection (a) justification for the strength levels recommended and an explanation of the relationship between the personnel strength levels recommended for that fiscal year and the national security policies of the United States in effect at the time.

(2) The justification and explanation required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) An explanation of how personnel end strength level requests address threats described in the national defense strategy under section 113(g) of this title.

(B) The rationale for recommended increases or decreases in active, reserve, and civilian personnel for each component of the Department of Defense.

(C) The actual end strength number for each armed force for the prior fiscal year, compared to authorized end strength levels.

(D) The shortfall in recruiting by each armed force as a percentage, as the Secretary determines appropriate.



(c) The Secretary shall include in each report under subsection (a) a detailed discussion of the manpower required for support and overhead functions within the armed forces and the Department of Defense.

(d) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that sets forth, with respect to each armed force under the jurisdiction </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives, and furnish to any Member of Congress upon request, a defense manpower profile report. The report shall contain the Secretary’s recommendations for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall include in each report under subsection (a) a detailed discussion of the manpower required for support and overhead functions within the armed forces and the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that sets forth, with respect to each armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of a military department, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than June 1 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that sets forth the following information with respect to personnel assigned to or supporting major Department of Defense headquarters activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the Army and Air Force military technician programs. The report shall include a presentation, shown by reserve component and shown both as of the end of the preceding fiscal year and for the next fiscal year, of the following (displayed in the aggregate and separately for military technicians (dual status) and non-dual status military technicians):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_115a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that sets forth the following with respect to personnel:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>