<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_117"><akn:num>117</akn:num><akn:heading>Readiness reporting system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 117. Readiness reporting system(a) Required Readiness Reporting System.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a comprehensive readiness reporting system for the Department of Defense. The readiness reporting system shall measure in an objective, accurate, and timely manner the capability of the armed forces to carry out—(1) the National Security Strategy prescribed by the President in the most recent annual national security strategy report under section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3043);

(2) the defense planning guidance provided by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 113(g) of this title; and

(3) the National Military Strategy prescribed by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.


(b) Readiness Reporting System Characteristics.—In establishing and maintaining the readiness reporting system, the Secretary shall ensure—(1) that the readiness reporting system and associated policies are applied uniformly throughout the Department of Defense, including between and among the joint staff and each of the armed forces;

(2) that is the single authoritative readiness reporting system for the Department, and that there shall be no military service specific systems;

(3) that readiness assessments are accomplished at an organizational level at, or below, the level at which forces are employed;

(4) that the reporting system include resources information, force posture, and mission centric capability assessments, as well as predicted changes to these attributes;

(5) that information in the readiness reporting system is continually updated, with (A) any change in the overall readiness status of a unit, or element of a unit, that is required to be reported as part of the readiness reporting system being reported within 24 hours of the event necessitating the change in readiness status, and (B) any change in the overall readiness status of an element of the training establishment or an element of defense infrastructure that is require</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Readiness Reporting System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a comprehensive readiness reporting system for the Department of Defense. The readiness reporting system shall measure in an objective, accurate, and timely manner the capability of the armed forces to carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Readiness Reporting System Characteristics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In establishing and maintaining the readiness reporting system, the Secretary shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capabilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The readiness reporting system shall measure such factors relating to readiness as the Secretary prescribes, except that the system shall include the capability to do each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_117_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. In those regulations, the Secretary shall prescribe the established information technology system for Department of Defense reporting, specifically authorize exceptions to a single-system architecture, and identify the organizations, units, and entities that are subject to reporting in the readiness reporting system, what organization resources are subject to such reporting, and the elements of the training establishment and of defense infrastructure that are subject to such reporting.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>