<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1174a"><akn:num>1174a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special separation benefits programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1174a. Special separation benefits programs(a) Requirement for Programs.—The Secretary concerned shall carry out a special separation benefits program under this section. An eligible member of the armed forces may request separation under the program. The request shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.

(b) Benefits.—Upon the approval of the request of an eligible member, the member shall—(1) be released from active duty or full-time National Guard duty or discharged, as the case may be; and

(2) be entitled to—(A) separation pay equal to 15 percent of the product of (i) the member’s years of active service, and (ii) 12 times the monthly basic pay to which the member is entitled at the time of his discharge or release from active duty; and

(B) the same benefits and services as are provided under chapter 58 of this title, sections 452 and 453(c) of title 37, and section 503(c) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (104 Stat. 1558; 37 U.S.C. 476 11 See References in Text note below. note) for members of the armed forces who are involuntarily separated within the meaning of section 1141 of this title.



(c) Eligibility.—Subject to subsections (d) and (e), a member of an armed force is eligible for voluntary separation under a program established for that armed force pursuant to this section if the member—(1) has not been approved for payment of a voluntary separation incentive under section 1175 of this title;

(2) has served on active duty or full-time National Guard duty or any combination of active duty and full-time National Guard duty for more than 6 years;

(3) has served on active duty or full-time National Guard duty or any combination of active duty and full-time National Guard duty for not more than 20 years;

(4) has served at least 5 years of continuous active duty or full-time National Guard duty or any combination of active duty and full-time National Guard duty immediately preceding the date of the member’s separat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned shall carry out a special separation benefits program under this section. An eligible member of the armed forces may request separation under the program. The request shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Upon the approval of the request of an eligible member, the member shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to subsections (d) and (e), a member of an armed force is eligible for voluntary separation under a program established for that armed force pursuant to this section if the member—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Applicability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned may provide for the program under this section to apply to any of the following members:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability Subject to Needs of the Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Conditions, Requirements, and Administrative Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subsections (e) through (h), other than subsection (e)(2)(A), of section 1174 of this title shall apply in the administration of programs established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>