<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1174/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1174"><akn:num>1174</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation pay upon involuntary discharge or release from active duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1174. Separation pay upon involuntary discharge or release from active duty(a) Regular Officers.—(1) A regular officer who is discharged under chapter 36 of this title (except under section 630(1)(A) or 643 of such chapter) or under section 580 or 8372 of this title and who has completed six or more, but less than twenty, years of active service immediately before that discharge is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d)(1).

(2) A regular commissioned officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force or Marine Corps who is discharged under section 630(1)(A), 643, or 1186 of this title, and a regular warrant officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force or Marine Corps who is separated under section 1165 or 1166 of this title, who has completed six or more, but less than twenty, years of active service immediately before that discharge or separation is entitled to separation pay computed under subsection (d)(1) or (d)(2), as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, unless the Secretary concerned determines that the conditions under which the officer is discharged or separated do not warrant payment of such pay.

(3) Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an officer discharged under any provision of chapter 36 of this title for twice failing of selection for promotion to the next higher grade is not entitled to separation pay under this section if either (or both) of those failures of selection for promotion was by the action of a selection board to which the officer submitted a request in writing not to be selected for promotion or who otherwise directly caused his nonselection through written communication to the Board under section 614(b) of this title.

(4) Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2), an officer who is subject to discharge under any provision of chapter 36 of this title or under section 580 or 8372 of this title by reason of having twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade is not entitled to separation pay</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regular Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regular Enlisted Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Separation Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The amount of separation pay which may be paid to a member under this section is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Service in Ready Reserve; Exceptions To Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counting Fractional Years of Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In determining a member’s years of active service for the purpose of computing separation pay under this section, each full month of service that is in addition to the number of full years of service creditable to the member is counted as one-twelfth of a year and any remaining fractional part of a month is disregarded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Other Separation or Severance Pay Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A period for which a member has previously received separation pay under this section or severance pay or readjustment pay under any other provision of law based on service in the armed forces may not be included in determining the years of service that may be counted in computing the separation pay of the member under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Retired or Retainer Pay and Disability Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule for Members Receiving Sole Survivorship Discharge.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1174_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; Crediting of Other Commissioned Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>