<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1175"><akn:num>1175</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary separation incentive</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1175. Voluntary separation incentive(a)(1) Consistent with this section and the availability of appropriations for this purpose, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may provide a financial incentive to members of the armed forces described in subsection (b) for voluntary appointment, enlistment, or transfer to a reserve component, requested and approved under subsection (c).

(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a financial incentive provided a member under this section shall be paid for the period equal to twice the number of years of service of the member, computed as provided in subsection (e)(5).

(B) If, before the expiration of the period otherwise applicable under subparagraph (A) to a member receiving a financial incentive under this section, the member is separated from a reserve component or is transferred to the Retired Reserve, the period for payment of a financial incentive to the member under this section shall terminate on the date of the separation or transfer unless—(i) the separation or transfer is required by reason of the age or number of years of service of the member;

(ii) the separation or transfer is required by reason of the failure of selection for promotion or the medical disqualification of the member, except in a case in which the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the basis for the separation or transfer is a result of a deliberate action taken by the member with the intent to avoid retention in the Ready Reserve or Standby Reserve; or

(iii) in the case of a separation, the member is separated from the reserve component for appointment or enlistment in or transfer to another reserve component of an armed force for service in the Ready Reserve or Standby Reserve of that armed force.




(b) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may provide the incentive to a member of the armed forces if the member—(1) has served on active duty or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may provide the incentive to a member of the armed forces if the member—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A member of the armed forces offered a voluntary separation incentive under this section shall be offered the opportunity to request separation under a program established pursuant to section 1174a of this title. If the Secretary concerned approves a request for separation under either such section, the member shall be separated under the authority of the section selected by such member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The member’s right to incentive payments shall not be transferable, except that the member may designate beneficiaries to receive the payments in the event of the member’s death.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subject to subsection (h), payments under this provision shall be paid from appropriations available to the Department of Defense and the Department of Homeland Security for the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security may issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A member of the armed forces who is provided a voluntary separation incentive under this section shall be eligible for the same benefits and services as are provided under chapter 58 of this title, sections 452 and 453(c) of title 37, and section 503(c) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1991 (104 Stat. 1558; 37 U.S.C. 476 11 See References in Text note below. note) for members of the armed forces who are involuntarily separated within the meaning of section 1141 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>