<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1175a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1175a"><akn:num>1175a</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary separation pay and benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1175a. Voluntary separation pay and benefits(a) In General.—Under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may provide voluntary separation pay and benefits in accordance with this section to eligible members of the armed forces who are voluntarily separated from active duty in the armed forces.

(b) Eligible Members.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), a member of the armed forces is eligible for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section if the member—(A) has served on active duty for more than 6 years but not more than 20 years;

(B) has served at least 5 years of continuous active duty immediately preceding the date of the member’s separation from active duty;

(C) has not been approved for payment of a voluntary separation incentive under section 1175 of this title;

(D) meets such other requirements as the Secretary concerned may prescribe, which may include requirements relating to—(i) years of service, skill, rating, military specialty, or competitive category;

(ii) grade or rank;

(iii) remaining period of obligated service; or

(iv) any combination of these factors; and


(E) requests separation from active duty.


(2) The following members are not eligible for voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section:(A) Members discharged with disability severance pay under section 1212 of this title.

(B) Members transferred to the temporary disability retired list under section 1202 or 1205 of this title.

(C) Members being evaluated for disability retirement under chapter 61 of this title.

(D) Members who have been previously discharged with voluntary separation pay.

(E) Members who are subject to pending disciplinary action or who are subject to administrative separation or mandatory discharge under any other provision of law or regulations.


(3) The Secretary concerned shall determine each year the number of members to be separated, and provided separation pay and benefits, under this section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may provide voluntary separation pay and benefits in accordance with this section to eligible members of the armed forces who are voluntarily separated from active duty in the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each eligible member of the armed forces whose request for separation from active duty under subsection (b)(1)(E) is approved shall be separated from active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Service in Ready Reserve.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Of the number of members of the armed forces to be separated from active duty in a fiscal year, as determined under subsection (b)(3), the Secretary concerned shall determine a number of such members, in such skill and grade combinations as the Secretary concerned shall designate, who shall serve in the Ready Reserve, after separation from active duty, for a period of not less than three years, as a condition of the receipt of voluntary separation pay and benefits under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation Pay and Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of Voluntary Separation Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary concerned shall specify the amount of voluntary separation pay that an individual or defined group of members of the armed forces may be paid under subsection (e)(1). No member may receive as voluntary separation pay an amount greater than four times the full amount of separation pay for a member of the same pay grade and years of service who is involuntarily separated under section 1174 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Voluntary Separation Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination With Retired or Retainer Pay and Disability Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the term “retirement” includes a transfer to the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1175a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment for Members Who Return to Active Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>