<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_118"><akn:num>118</akn:num><akn:heading>Materiel readiness metrics and objectives for major weapon systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 118. Materiel readiness metrics and objectives for major weapon systems(a) Materiel Readiness Metrics.—Each head of an element of the Department specified in paragraphs (1) through (10) of section 111(b) of this title shall establish and maintain materiel readiness metrics to enable assessment of the readiness of members of the armed forces to carry out—(1) the strategic framework required by section 113(g)(1)(B)(vii) of this title; and

(2) guidance issued by the Secretary of Defense pursuant to section 113(g)(1)(B) of this title.


(b) Required Metrics.—At a minimum, the materiel readiness metrics required by subsection (a) shall address the materiel availability, operational availability, operational capability, and materiel reliability of each major weapon system by designated mission, design series, variant, or class.

(c) Materiel Readiness Objectives.—(1) Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, each head of an element described in subsection (a) shall establish the metrics required by subsection (b) necessary to support the strategic framework and guidance referred to in paragraph (1) and (2) of subsection (a).

(2) Annually, each head of an element described in subsection (a) shall review and revise the metrics required by subsection (b) and include any such revisions in the materials submitted to Congress in support of the budget of the President under section 1105 of title 31.


(d) Budget Justification.—Not later than five days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress the materials in support of the budget of the President for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report on major weapons systems sustainment for the period covered by the future years defense program specified by section 221 of this title. Such report shall include—(1) an assessment of the materiel availability, operational availability, and materiel reliability</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Materiel Readiness Metrics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each head of an element of the Department specified in paragraphs (1) through (10) of section 111(b) of this title shall establish and maintain materiel readiness metrics to enable assessment of the readiness of members of the armed forces to carry out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Metrics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) At a minimum, the materiel readiness metrics required by subsection (a) shall address the materiel availability, operational availability, operational capability, and materiel reliability of each major weapon system by designated mission, design series, variant, or class.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Materiel Readiness Objectives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Justification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than five days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress the materials in support of the budget of the President for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report on major weapons systems sustainment for the period covered by the future years defense program specified by section 221 of this title. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding Estimates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than five days after the date on which the Secretary of Defense submits to Congress the materials in support of the budget of the President for a fiscal year, the Director of Cost Assessment and Performance Evaluation shall submit to the congressional defense committees a comprehensive estimate of the funds necessary to meet the materiel readiness objectives required by subsection (c) through the period covered by the most recent future-years defense program. At a minimum, the Director shall provide, for each major weapon system, by designated mission design series, variant, or class, a comprehensive estimate of the funds necessary to meet such objectives that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>