<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/118c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_118c"><akn:num>118c</akn:num><akn:heading>National Defense Science and Technology Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 118c. National Defense Science and Technology Strategy(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense shall develop a strategy—(1) to articulate the science and technology priorities, goals, and investments of the Department of Defense;

(2) to make recommendations on the future of the defense research and engineering enterprise and its continued success in an era of strategic competition; and

(3) to establish an integrated approach to the identification, prioritization, development, and fielding of emerging capabilities and technologies.


(b) Elements.—The strategy required under subsection (a) shall—(1) inform the development of each National Defense Strategy under section 113(g) of this title and be aligned with Government-wide strategic science and technology priorities, including the defense budget priorities of the Office of Science and Technology Policy of the President;

(2) link the priorities, goals, and investments in subsection (a)(1) with needed critical enablers to specific programs, or broader portfolios, including—(A) personnel and workforce capabilities;

(B) facilities for research and test infrastructure;

(C) relationships with academia, the acquisition community, the operational community, the defense industry, and the commercial sector; and

(D) funding, investments, personnel, facilities, and relationships with other departments and agencies of the Federal Government outside the Department of Defense without which defense capabilities would be severely degraded;


(3) support the coordination of acquisition priorities, programs, and timelines of the Department with the activities of the defense research and engineering enterprise;

(4) include recommendations for changes in authorities, regulations, policies, or any other relevant areas, that would support the achievement of the goals set forth in the strategy;

(5) identify mechanisms that may be used to identify critical capabilities and technological applications required to address operationa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall develop a strategy—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The strategy required under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall develop the strategy under subsection (a) in coordination with relevant entities within the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the military departments, the research organizations of Defense Agencies and Department of Defense Field Activities, the intelligence community, defense and technology industry partners, research and development partners, other Federal research agencies, allies and partners of the United States, and other appropriate organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In developing the strategy under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than 90 days after the date on which the strategy under subsection (a) is completed, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on the implementation plan for the strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_118c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall be known as the “National Defense Science and Technology Strategy”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>