<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1210" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1210/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1210/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1210"><akn:num>1210</akn:num><akn:heading>Members on temporary disability retired list: periodic physical examination; final determination of </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1210. Members on temporary disability retired list: periodic physical examination; final determination of status(a) A physical examination shall be given at least once every 18 months to each member of the armed forces whose name is on the temporary disability retired list to determine whether there has been a change in the disability for which he was temporarily retired. He may be required to submit to those examinations while his name is carried on that list. If a member fails to report for an examination under this subsection, after receipt of proper notification, his disability retired pay may be terminated. However, payments to him shall be resumed if there was just cause for his failure to report. If payments are so resumed, they may be made retroactive for not more than one year.

(b) The Secretary concerned shall make a final determination of the case of each member whose name is on the temporary disability retired list upon the expiration of three years after the date when the member’s name was placed on that list. If, at the time of that determination, the physical disability for which the member’s name was carried on the temporary disability retired list still exists, it shall be considered to be of a permanent nature and stable.

(c) If, as a result of a periodic examination under subsection (a), or upon a final determination under subsection (b), it is determined that the member’s physical disability is of a permanent nature and stable and is at least 30 percent under the standard schedule of rating disabilities in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs at the time of the determination, his name shall be removed from the temporary disability retired list and he shall be retired under section 1201 or 1204 of this title, whichever applies.

(d) If, as a result of a periodic examination under subsection (a), or upon a final determination under subsection (b), it is determined that the member’s physical disability is of a permanent nature and stable an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A physical examination shall be given at least once every 18 months to each member of the armed forces whose name is on the temporary disability retired list to determine whether there has been a change in the disability for which he was temporarily retired. He may be required to submit to those examinations while his name is carried on that list. If a member fails to report for an examination under this subsection, after receipt of proper notification, his disability retired pay may be terminated. However, payments to him shall be resumed if there was just cause for his failure to report. If payments are so resumed, they may be made retroactive for not more than one year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall make a final determination of the case of each member whose name is on the temporary disability retired list upon the expiration of three years after the date when the member’s name was placed on that list. If, at the time of that determination, the physical disability for which the member’s name was carried on the temporary disability retired list still exists, it shall be considered to be of a permanent nature and stable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If, as a result of a periodic examination under subsection (a), or upon a final determination under subsection (b), it is determined that the member’s physical disability is of a permanent nature and stable and is at least 30 percent under the standard schedule of rating disabilities in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs at the time of the determination, his name shall be removed from the temporary disability retired list and he shall be retired under section 1201 or 1204 of this title, whichever applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If, as a result of a periodic examination under subsection (a), or upon a final determination under subsection (b), it is determined that the member’s physical disability is of a permanent nature and stable and is less than 30 percent under the standard schedule of rating disabilities in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs at the time of the determination, and if he has at least 20 years of service computed under section 1208 of this title, his name shall be removed from the temporary disability retired list and he shall be retired under section 1201 or 1204 of this title, whichever applies, with retired pay computed under section 1401 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If, as a result of a periodic examination under subsection (a), or upon a final determination under subsection (b), it is determined that the member’s physical disability is less than 30 percent under the standard schedule of rating disabilities in use by the Department of Veterans Affairs at the time of the determination, and if he has less than 20 years of service computed under section 1208 of this title, his name shall be removed from the temporary disability retired list and he may be separated under section 1203 or 1206 of this title, whichever applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any member of the armed forces whose name is on the temporary disability retired list, and who is required to travel to submit to a physical examination under subsection (a), is entitled to the travel and transportation allowances authorized for members in his retired grade traveling in connection with temporary duty while on active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1210_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) If his name is not sooner removed, the disability retired pay of a member whose name is on the temporary disability retired list terminates upon the expiration of three years after the date when his name was placed on that list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>