<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12243"><akn:num>12243</akn:num><akn:heading>Warrant officers: suspension of laws for promotion or mandatory retirement or separation during war </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12243. Warrant officers: suspension of laws for promotion or mandatory retirement or separation during war or emergency
In time of war, or of emergency declared after May 29, 1954, by Congress or the President, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of law relating to promotion, or mandatory retirement or separation, of permanent reserve warrant officers of any armed force.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 26, § 599; renumbered § 12243, Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(d)(2), Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2991.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


59910:600p (as applicable to reserve warrant officers).34:330g (as applicable to reserve warrant officers).May 29, 1954, ch. 249, § 18 (as applicable to reserve warrant officers), 68 Stat. 165.
 34:430d (as applicable to reserve warrant officers).


The word “may” is substituted for the words “is authorized, in his discretion”. The words “any provision of law” are substituted for the words “all or any part or parts of the several provisions of law”.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–337 renumbered section 599 of this title as this section.

Executive Documents

Delegation of Functions
Functions of the President under this section delegated to the Secretary of Defense, see section 1(4) of Ex. Ord. No. 11390, Jan. 22, 1968, 33 F.R. 841, set out as a note under section 301 of Title 3, The President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>