<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12310"><akn:num>12310</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserves: for organizing, administering, etc., reserve components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12310. Reserves: for organizing, administering, etc., reserve components(a) Authority.—(1) The Secretary concerned may order a member of a reserve component under the Secretary’s jurisdiction to active duty pursuant to section 12301(d) of this title to perform Active Guard and Reserve duty organizing, administering, recruiting, instructing, or training the reserve components.

(2) A Reserve ordered to active duty under paragraph (1) shall be ordered in the Reserve’s reserve grade. While so serving, the Reserve continues to be eligible for promotion as a Reserve, if otherwise qualified.


(b) Duties.—A Reserve on active duty under subsection (a) may perform the following additional duties to the extent that the performance of those duties does not interfere with the performance of the Reserve’s primary Active Guard and Reserve duties described in subsection (a)(1):(1) Supporting operations or missions assigned in whole or in part to the reserve components.

(2) Supporting operations or missions performed or to be performed by—(A) a unit composed of elements from more than one component of the same armed force; or

(B) a joint forces unit that includes—(i) one or more reserve component units; or

(ii) a member of a reserve component whose reserve component assignment is in a position in an element of the joint forces unit.



(3) Advising the Secretary of Defense, the Secretaries of the military departments, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and the commanders of the combatant commands regarding reserve component matters.

(4) Instructing or training in the United States or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico or possessions of the United States of—(A) active-duty members of the armed forces;

(B) members of foreign military forces (under the same authorities and restrictions applicable to active-duty members providing such instruction or training);

(C) Department of Defense contractor personnel; or

(D) Department of Defense civilian employees.



(c) Operations Relating to D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A Reserve on active duty under subsection (a) may perform the following additional duties to the extent that the performance of those duties does not interfere with the performance of the Reserve’s primary Active Guard and Reserve duties described in subsection (a)(1):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations Relating to Defense Against Weapons of Mass Destruction and Terrorist Attacks.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12310_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A Reserve on active duty as described in subsection (a) may be provided training consistent with training provided to other members on active duty, as the Secretary concerned sees fit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>