<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12402"><akn:num>12402</akn:num><akn:heading>Army and Air National Guard of the United States: commissioned officers; duty in National Guard Bure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12402. Army and Air National Guard of the United States: commissioned officers; duty in National Guard Bureau(a) The President may, with their consent, order commissioned officers of the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States to active duty in the National Guard Bureau.

(b)(1) The number of officers of the Army National Guard of the United States in grades below brigadier general who are ordered to active duty in the National Guard Bureau may not be more than 40 percent of the number of officers of the Army authorized for duty in that Bureau and, to the extent practicable, shall not exceed 40 percent of the number of officers of the Army serving in that Bureau in any grade below brigadier general.

(2) The number of officers of the Air National Guard of the United States in grades below brigadier general who are ordered to active duty in the National Guard Bureau may not be more than 40 percent of the number of officers of the Air Force authorized for duty in that Bureau and, to the extent practicable, shall not exceed 40 percent of the number of officers of the Air Force serving in that Bureau in any grade below brigadier general.


(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(f)(1), Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2993; amended Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(18)(B), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 497.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 3496 and 8496 of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–337, § 1662(f)(2).

Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–106 inserted “the” in section catchline.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1996 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 104–106 effective as if included in the Reserve Officer Personnel Management Act, title XVI of Pub. L. 103–337, as enacted on Oct. 5, 1994, see section 1501(f)(3) of Pub. L. 104–106, set out as a note under section 113 of this title.

Effective DateSection effective De</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President may, with their consent, order commissioned officers of the Army National Guard of the United States and the Air National Guard of the United States to active duty in the National Guard Bureau.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>