<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/125a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/125a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/125a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_125a"><akn:num>125a</akn:num><akn:heading>Reform: improvement of efficacy and efficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 125a. Reform: improvement of efficacy and efficiency(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense shall take such action as is necessary to reform the Department of Defense to improve the efficacy and efficiency of the Department, and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.

(b) Policy.—The Secretary shall develop a policy and issue guidance to implement reform within the Department and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.

(c) Framework for Reform.—(1) In general.—Not later than February 1, 2023, the Secretary shall establish policies, guidance, and a consistent reporting framework to measure the progress of the Department toward covered elements of reform, including by establishing categories of reform, consistent metrics, and a process for prioritization of reform activities.

(2) Scope.—The framework required by paragraph (1) may address duties under the following:(A) Section 125 of this title.

(B) Section 192 of this title.

(C) Section 2222 of this title.

(D) Section 1124 of title 31.

(E) Section 11319 of title 40.


(3) Consultation.—The Secretary shall consult with the Deputy Secretary of Defense, the Performance Improvement Officer of the Department of Defense, the Chief Data Officer of the Department of Defense, the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense, the Director for Administration and Management of the Department of Defense, and the financial managers of the military departments in carrying out activities under this subsection.


(d) Covered Elements of Reform.—For purposes of this section and the policies, guidance, and reporting framework required by subsection (c), covered elements of reform may include the following:(1) Business systems modernization.

(2) Enterprise business operations process re-engineering.

(3) Expanded and modernized collection, manageme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_125a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall take such action as is necessary to reform the Department of Defense to improve the efficacy and efficiency of the Department, and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_125a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall develop a policy and issue guidance to implement reform within the Department and to improve the ability of the Department to prioritize among and assess the costs and benefits of covered elements of reform.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_125a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Framework for Reform.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_125a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Elements of Reform.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For purposes of this section and the policies, guidance, and reporting framework required by subsection (c), covered elements of reform may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_125a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) At the same time the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary shall, using the policies, guidance, and reporting framework required by subsection (c), submit to the congressional defense committees a report, including detailed narrative justifications and tradeoff analyses between options, on the actions of the Department as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>