<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12644" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12644/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/12644/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12644"><akn:num>12644</akn:num><akn:heading>Members physically not qualified for active duty: discharge or transfer to retired status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12644. Members physically not qualified for active duty: discharge or transfer to retired status
Except as otherwise provided by law, the Secretary concerned may provide for the honorable discharge or the transfer to a retired status of members of the reserve components under his jurisdiction who are found to be not physically qualified for active duty. However, no member of the Army National Guard of the United States or the Air National Guard of the United States may be transferred under this subsection without the consent of the governor or other appropriate authority of the jurisdiction concerned.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 79, § 1004; Pub. L. 86–603, § 1(1), July 7, 1960, 74 Stat. 357; Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 519, Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1651; renumbered § 12644 and amended Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, §§ 1661(a)(4), 1662(h)(2), (4)(B), Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2980, 2996, 2997.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


1004(a)1004(b)1004(c)50:949.50:950 (last sentence).50:950 (less last sentence).July 9, 1952, ch. 608, §§ 225, 226, 66 Stat. 488.


In subsection (a), the words “Each * * * who is not on active duty” are substituted for the words “when not on active duty all”. The words “examined as to his physical fitness” are substituted for the words “given physical examinations”. The words “be required to” are omitted as surplusage. The words “execute and” are inserted for clarity.
In subsection (c), the words “under his jurisdiction” are inserted for clarity.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–337, § 1662(h)(2), (4)(B), renumbered section 1004 of this title as this section and substituted “Members physically not qualified for active duty: discharge or transfer to retired status” for “Physical examination” as section catchline.
Pub. L. 103–337, § 1661(a)(4), struck out “(c)” before “Except as otherwise provided” and struck out subsecs. (a) and (b) which read</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>