<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/129a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/129a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/129a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_129a"><akn:num>129a</akn:num><akn:heading>General policy for total force management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 129a. General policy for total force management(a) Policies and Procedures.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for determining the most appropriate and cost efficient mix of military, civilian, and contractor personnel to perform the mission of the Department of Defense.

(b) Risk Mitigation Over Cost.—In establishing the policies and procedures under subsection (a), the Secretary shall clearly provide that attainment of a Department of Defense workforce sufficiently sized and comprised of the appropriate mix of personnel necessary to carry out the mission of the Department and the core mission areas of the armed forces takes precedence over cost. The Secretary may not reduce the civilian workforce programmed full-time equivalent levels unless the Secretary conducts an appropriate analysis of the impacts of such reductions on workload, military force structure, lethality, readiness, operational effectiveness, stress on the military force, and fully burdened costs.

(c) Delegation of Responsibilities.—The Secretary shall delegate responsibility for implementation of the policies and procedures established under subsection (a) as follows:(1) The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall have overall responsibility for guidance to implement such policies and procedures.

(2) The Secretaries of the military departments and the heads of the Defense Agencies shall have overall responsibility for the requirements determination, planning, programming, and budgeting for such policies and procedures. The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the requirements determination, planning, programming, and budgeting conducted under this paragraph considers all components of the total force (including active and reserve military, the civilian workforce, and contract support) in a holistic manner—(A) to avoid duplication of efforts and waste of resources attributable to a component working outside the scope of its responsibilities; a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policies and Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish policies and procedures for determining the most appropriate and cost efficient mix of military, civilian, and contractor personnel to perform the mission of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk Mitigation Over Cost.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In establishing the policies and procedures under subsection (a), the Secretary shall clearly provide that attainment of a Department of Defense workforce sufficiently sized and comprised of the appropriate mix of personnel necessary to carry out the mission of the Department and the core mission areas of the armed forces takes precedence over cost. The Secretary may not reduce the civilian workforce programmed full-time equivalent levels unless the Secretary conducts an appropriate analysis of the impacts of such reductions on workload, military force structure, lethality, readiness, operational effectiveness, stress on the military force, and fully burdened costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall delegate responsibility for implementation of the policies and procedures established under subsection (a) as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Plan, Inventory, and List.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The policies and procedures established by the Secretary under subsection (a) shall specifically require the Department of Defense to use the following when making determinations regarding the appropriate workforce mix necessary to perform its mission:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in Converting Performance of Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If conversion of functions to performance by either Department of Defense civilian personnel or contractor personnel is considered, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall ensure compliance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction With Other Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this title may be construed as authorizing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_129a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance of Civilian Functions by Military Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>