<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_132"><akn:num>132</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Secretary of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 132. Deputy Secretary of Defense(a) There is a Deputy Secretary of Defense, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Deputy Secretary shall be appointed from among persons most highly qualified for the position by reason of background and experience, including persons with appropriate management experience. A person may not be appointed as Deputy Secretary of Defense within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.

(b)(1) The Deputy Secretary shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe.

(2)(A) The Deputy Secretary shall act for, and exercise the powers of, the Secretary when the Secretary dies, resigns, or is otherwise unable to perform the functions and duties of the office.

(B) If the Secretary is unable to perform the functions and duties of the office as described in subparagraph (A), the Deputy Secretary, or any other individual performing such functions and duties in accordance with applicable law, shall, not later than 24 hours before any planned transfer of such functions and duties or 24 hours after any unplanned transfer of such functions and duties, notify the following of the transfer:(i) The Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, and the majority and minority leaders of the Senate.

(ii) The Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Appropriations, the Speaker, and the minority leader of the House of Representatives.




(c) The Deputy Secretary takes precedence in the Department of Defense immediately after the Secretary.

(d) Until September 30, 2020, the Deputy Secretary of Defense shall lead the Guam Oversight Council and shall be the Department of Defense’s principal representative for coordinating the interagency efforts in matters relating to Guam, including the following executive orders:(1) Executive Order No. 13299 of May 12, 2003 (68 Fed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is a Deputy Secretary of Defense, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Deputy Secretary shall be appointed from among persons most highly qualified for the position by reason of background and experience, including persons with appropriate management experience. A person may not be appointed as Deputy Secretary of Defense within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Deputy Secretary takes precedence in the Department of Defense immediately after the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Until September 30, 2020, the Deputy Secretary of Defense shall lead the Guam Oversight Council and shall be the Department of Defense’s principal representative for coordinating the interagency efforts in matters relating to Guam, including the following executive orders:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>