<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/133b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/133b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/133b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_133b"><akn:num>133b</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 133b. Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment(a) Under Secretary of Defense.—There is an Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Under Secretary shall be appointed from among persons who have an extensive system development, engineering, production, or management background and experience with managing complex programs. A person may not be appointed as Under Secretary within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.

(b) Duties and Powers.—Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary may prescribe, including—(1) serving as the chief acquisition and sustainment officer of the Department of Defense with the mission of delivering and sustaining timely, cost-effective capabilities for the armed forces (and the Department);

(2) establishing policies on, and supervising, all elements of the Department relating to acquisition (including system design, development, appropriate prototyping activities, and production, and procurement of goods and services) and sustainment (including logistics, maintenance, and materiel readiness);

(3) establishing policies for access to, and maintenance of, the defense industrial base and materials critical to national security, and policies on contract administration;

(4) establishing policies for, and providing oversight, guidance, and coordination with respect to, the nuclear command, control, and communications system;

(5) serving as—(A) the principal advisor to the Secretary on acquisition and sustainment in the Department;

(B) the senior procurement executive for the Department for the purposes of section 1702(c) of title 41;

(C) the Defense Acquisition Executive for purposes of regulations and procedures </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_133b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Under Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is an Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Under Secretary shall be appointed from among persons who have an extensive system development, engineering, production, or management background and experience with managing complex programs. A person may not be appointed as Under Secretary within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_133b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary may prescribe, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_133b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Precedence in Department of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>