<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1370a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1370a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1370a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1370a"><akn:num>1370a</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers entitled to retired pay for non-regular service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1370a. Officers entitled to retired pay for non-regular service(a) Retirement in Highest Grade Held Satisfactorily.—Unless entitled to a different grade, or to credit for satisfactory service in a different grade under some other provision of law, a person who is entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title shall, upon application under section 12731 of this title, be credited with satisfactory service in the highest permanent grade in which that person served satisfactorily at any time in the armed forces, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned in accordance with this section.

(b) Service-in-grade Requirement for Officers in Grades Below O–5.—In order to be credited with satisfactory service in an officer grade (other than a warrant officer grade) below the grade of lieutenant colonel or commander (in the case of the Navy), a person covered by subsection (a) must have served satisfactorily in that grade (as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned) as a reserve commissioned officer in an active status, or in a retired status on active duty, for not less than six months.

(c) Service-in-grade Requirement for Offices in Grades Above O–4.—(1) In general.—In order to be credited with satisfactory service in an officer grade above major or lieutenant commander (in the case of the Navy), a person covered by subsection (a) must have served satisfactorily in that grade (as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned) as a reserve commissioned officer in an active status, or in a retired status on active duty, for not less than three years.

(2) Satisfaction of requirement by certain officers not completing three years.—A person covered by paragraph (1) who has completed at least six months of satisfactory service in grade may be credited with satisfactory service in the grade in which serving at the time of transfer or discharge, notwithstanding failure of the person to complete three </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement in Highest Grade Held Satisfactorily.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unless entitled to a different grade, or to credit for satisfactory service in a different grade under some other provision of law, a person who is entitled to retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title shall, upon application under section 12731 of this title, be credited with satisfactory service in the highest permanent grade in which that person served satisfactorily at any time in the armed forces, as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service-in-grade Requirement for Officers in Grades Below O–5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In order to be credited with satisfactory service in an officer grade (other than a warrant officer grade) below the grade of lieutenant colonel or commander (in the case of the Navy), a person covered by subsection (a) must have served satisfactorily in that grade (as determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned) as a reserve commissioned officer in an active status, or in a retired status on active duty, for not less than six months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service-in-grade Requirement for Offices in Grades Above O–4.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers in O–9 and O–10 Grades.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditional Retirement Grade and Retirement for Officers Under Investigation for Misconduct or Pending Adverse Personnel Action.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The retirement grade, and retirement, of a person covered by this section who is under investigation for alleged misconduct or pending the disposition of an adverse personnel action at the time of retirement is as provided for by section 1370(d) of this title. In the application of such section 1370(d) for purposes of this subsection, any reference to “active duty” shall be deemed not to apply, and any reference to a provision of section 1370 of this title shall be deemed to be a reference to the analogous provision of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final Retirement Grade Following Resolution of Pending Investigation or Adverse Action.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The final retirement grade under this section of a person described in subsection (e) following resolution of the investigation or personnel action concerned is the final retirement grade provided for by section 1370(e) of this title. In the application of such section 1370(e) for purposes of this subsection, any reference to a provision of section 1370 of this title shall be deemed to be a reference to the analogous provision of this section. In the application of paragraph (3) of such section 1370(e) for purposes of this subsection, the reference to “chapter 71 of this title” shall be deemed to be a reference to “chapter 1223 of this title”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of Retired Grade Determinations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1370a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Highest Permanent Grade Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “highest permanent grade” means a grade at or below the grade of major general in the Army, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Space Force, or rear admiral in the Navy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>