<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14001" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14001/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14001/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14001"><akn:num>14001</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of this part</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14001. Applicability of this part
This chapter and chapters 1403 through 1411 of this title apply, as appropriate, to all reserve officers of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps except warrant officers.
(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2922.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1996, see section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337, set out as a note under section 10001 of this title.

Effects of Selection for Promotion and Failure of Selection for Army and Air Force OfficersSection 1682 of title XVI of div. A of Pub. L. 103–337 provided that:
“(a) Promotions To Fill Vacancies.—A reserve commissioned officer of the Army or Air Force (other than a commissioned warrant officer) who, on the day before the effective date of this title [Oct. 1, 1996, see section 1691(b)(1), (2) of Pub. L. 103–337, set out as an Effective Date note under section 10001 of this title], is recommended for promotion to fill a vacancy in the Army Reserve or the Air Force Reserve under section 3383, 3384, 8372, or 8373 of title 10, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the effective date of this title, in the next higher reserve grade shall be considered to have been recommended for promotion to that grade by a vacancy promotion board under section 14101(a)(2) of title 10, United States Code, as added by this title.

“(b) Promotions Other Than To Fill Vacancies.—A reserve officer of the Army or Air Force who, on the day before the effective date of this title, is recommended for promotion under section 3366, 3367, 3370, 3371, 8366, or 8371 of title 10, United States Code, as in effect on the day before the effective date of this title, to a reserve grade higher than the grade in which the officer is serving shall be considered to have been recommended for promotion by a mandatory promotion board convened under section 14101(a)(1) of title 10, United States Code, as added by this title.

“(c) </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>