<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1407"><akn:num>1407</akn:num><akn:heading>Retired pay base for members who first became members after September 7, 1980: high-36 month average</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1407. Retired pay base for members who first became members after September 7, 1980: high-36 month average(a) Use of Retired Pay Base in Computing Retired Pay.—The retired pay or retainer pay of any person entitled to that pay who first became a member of a uniformed service after September 7, 1980, is computed using the retired pay base or retainer pay base determined under this section.

(b) High-Three Average.—Except as provided in subsection (f), the retired pay base or retainer pay base of a person under this section is the person’s high-three average determined under subsection (c) or (d).

(c) Computation of High-Three Average for Members Entitled to Retired or Retainer Pay for Regular Service.—(1) General rule.—The high-three average of a member entitled to retired or retainer pay under any provision of law other than section 1204 or 1205 or section 12731 of this title is the amount equal to—(A) the total amount of monthly basic pay to which the member was entitled for the 36 months (whether or not consecutive) out of all the months of active service of the member for which the monthly basic pay to which the member was entitled was the highest, divided by

(B) 36.


(2) Special rule for short-term disability retirees.—In the case of a member who is entitled to retired pay under section 1201 or 1202 of this title and who has completed less than 36 months of active service, the member’s high-three average (notwithstanding paragraph (1)) is the amount equal to—(A) the total amount of basic pay to which the member was entitled during the period of the member’s active service, divided by

(B) the number of months (including any fraction thereof) of the member’s active service.


(3) Special Rule for Reserve Component Members.—In the case of a member of a reserve component who is entitled to retired pay under section 1201 or 1202 of this title, the member’s high-three average (notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2)) is computed in the same manner as prescribed i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Retired Pay Base in Computing Retired Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The retired pay or retainer pay of any person entitled to that pay who first became a member of a uniformed service after September 7, 1980, is computed using the retired pay base or retainer pay base determined under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-Three Average.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (f), the retired pay base or retainer pay base of a person under this section is the person’s high-three average determined under subsection (c) or (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of High-Three Average for Members Entitled to Retired or Retainer Pay for Regular Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of High-Three Average for Members and Former Members Entitled to Retired Pay for Nonregular Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation for Enlisted Members Retiring With Less Than 30 Years’ Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In the case of a member who is retired under section 7314 or 9314 of this title or who is transferred to the Fleet Reserve or Fleet Marine Corps Reserve under section 8330 of this title, the member’s high-36 average shall be computed using only rates of basic pay applicable to months of active duty of the member as an enlisted member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1407_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Enlisted Members Reduced in Grade and Officers Who Do Not Serve Satisfactorily in Highest Grade Held.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>