<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1408" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1408/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1408/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1408"><akn:num>1408</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of retired or retainer pay in compliance with court orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1408. Payment of retired or retainer pay in compliance with court orders(a) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “court” means—(A) any court of competent jurisdiction of any State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands;

(B) any court of the United States (as defined in section 451 of title 28) having competent jurisdiction;

(C) any court of competent jurisdiction of a foreign country with which the United States has an agreement requiring the United States to honor any court order of such country; and

(D) any administrative or judicial tribunal of a State competent to enter orders for support or maintenance (including a State agency administering a program under a State plan approved under part D of title IV of the Social Security Act), and, for purposes of this subparagraph, the term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.


(2) The term “court order” means a final decree of divorce, dissolution, annulment, or legal separation issued by a court, or a court ordered, ratified, or approved property settlement incident to such a decree (including a final decree modifying the terms of a previously issued decree of divorce, dissolution, annulment, or legal separation, or a court ordered, ratified, or approved property settlement incident to such previously issued decree), or a support order, as defined in section 453(p) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 653(p)), which—(A) is issued in accordance with the laws of the jurisdiction of that court;

(B) provides for—(i) payment of child support (as defined in section 459(i)(2) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 659(i)(2)));

(ii) payment of alimony (as defined in section 459(i)(3) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 659(i)(3))); or

(iii) division of property (including a division of commu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Service of Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Court To Treat Retired Pay as Property of the Member and Spouse.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments by Secretary Concerned to (or for Benefit of) Spouse or Former Spouse.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity of Officers and Employees of United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Member of Service of Court Order on Secretary Concerned.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A person receiving effective service of a court order under this section shall, as soon as possible, but not later than 30 days after the date on which effective service is made, send a written notice of such court order (together with a copy of such order) to the member affected by the court order at his last known address.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits for Dependents Who Are Victims of Abuse by Members Losing Right to Retired Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) It is not necessary that the date of a certification of the authenticity or completeness of a copy of a court order for child support received by the Secretary concerned for the purposes of this section be recent in relation to the date of receipt by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1408_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe uniform regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>