<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14308"><akn:num>14308</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotions: how made</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14308. Promotions: how made(a) Promotion List.—When the report of a selection board convened under section 14101(a) or 14502 of this title is approved by the President, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall place the names of all officers selected for promotion within a competitive category on a single list for that competitive category, to be known as a promotion list, in the order of seniority of those officers on the reserve active-status list or based on particular merit, as determined by the promotion board. A promotion list is considered to be established under this section as of the date of the approval of the report of the selection board under the preceding sentence.

(b) Promotion; How Made; Order.—(1) Officers on a promotion list for a competitive category shall be promoted in the manner specified in section 12203 of this title.

(2) Officers on a promotion list for a competitive category shall be promoted to the next higher grade in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned. Except as provided in section 14311, 14312, or 14502(e) of this title or in subsection (d) or (e), promotions shall be made in the order in which the names of officers appear on the promotion list and after officers previously selected for promotion in that competitive category have been promoted.

(3) Officers to be promoted to the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade) shall be promoted in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned.

(4)(A) Officers in the permanent grade of first lieutenant or, in the case of the Navy, lieutenant (junior grade) who are on an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list shall be promoted to the next higher grade in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned. Such promotions shall be in the manner specified in section 12203 of this title.

(B) An all-fully-qualified-officers list shall be cons</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion List.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When the report of a selection board convened under section 14101(a) or 14502 of this title is approved by the President, the Secretary of the military department concerned shall place the names of all officers selected for promotion within a competitive category on a single list for that competitive category, to be known as a promotion list, in the order of seniority of those officers on the reserve active-status list or based on particular merit, as determined by the promotion board. A promotion list is considered to be established under this section as of the date of the approval of the report of the selection board under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion; How Made; Order.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date of Rank.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers With Running Mates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An officer to whom a running mate system applies under section 14306 of this title and who is selected for promotion is eligible for promotion to the grade for which selected when the officer who is that officer’s running mate becomes eligible for promotion under chapter 36 of this title. The effective date of the promotion of that officer shall be the same as that of the officer’s running mate in the grade to which the running mate is promoted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Army Reserve and Air Force Reserve Promotions To Fill Vacancies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subject to this section and to section 14311(e) of this title, and under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the military department concerned—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Promotion After Federal Recognition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14308_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Army and Air Force General Officer Promotions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A reserve officer of the Army or the Air Force who is on a promotion list for promotion to the grade of brigadier general or major general as a result of selection by a vacancy promotion board may be promoted to that grade only to fill a vacancy in the Army Reserve or the Air Force Reserve, as the case may be, in that grade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>