<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14315"><akn:num>14315</akn:num><akn:heading>Position vacancy promotions: Army and Air Force officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14315. Position vacancy promotions: Army and Air Force officers(a) Officers Eligible for Consideration For Vacancy Promotions Below Brigadier General.—A reserve officer of the Army who is in the Army Reserve, or a reserve officer of the Air Force who is in the Air Force Reserve, who is on the reserve active-status list in the grade of first lieutenant, captain, major, or lieutenant colonel is eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade under this section if each of the following applies:(1) The officer is occupying or, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, has been recommended to occupy a position in the same competitive category as the officer and for which a grade higher than the one held by that officer is authorized.

(2) The officer is fully qualified to meet all requirements for the position as established by the Secretary of the military department concerned.

(3) The officer has held the officer’s present grade for the minimum period of service prescribed in section 14303 of this title for eligibility for consideration for promotion to the higher grade.


(b) Consideration for Vacancy Promotion to Brigadier General or Major General.—(1) A reserve officer of the Army who is in the Army Reserve and on the reserve active-status list in the grade of colonel or brigadier general may be considered for promotion to the next higher grade under this section if the officer (A) is assigned to the duties of a general officer of the next higher reserve grade in the Army Reserve or is recommended for such an assignment under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Army, (B) has held the officer’s present grade for the minimum period of service prescribed in section 14303 of this title for eligibility for consideration for promotion to the higher grade, and (C) meets the standards for consideration prescribed by the Secretary of the Army.

(2) A reserve officer of the Air Force who is in the Air Force Reserve and on the res</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers Eligible for Consideration For Vacancy Promotions Below Brigadier General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A reserve officer of the Army who is in the Army Reserve, or a reserve officer of the Air Force who is in the Air Force Reserve, who is on the reserve active-status list in the grade of first lieutenant, captain, major, or lieutenant colonel is eligible for consideration for promotion to the next higher grade under this section if each of the following applies:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration for Vacancy Promotion to Brigadier General or Major General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14315_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancy Promotion Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consideration for promotion under this section shall be by a vacancy promotion board convened under section 14101(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14315_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Nonselection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An officer who is considered for promotion under this section and is not selected shall not be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14315_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule for Officers Failed of Selection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A reserve officer of the Army or the Air Force who is considered as failed of selection for promotion under section 14501 of this title to a grade may be considered for promotion under this section or, if selected, promoted to that grade only if the Secretary of the military department concerned finds that the officer is the only qualified officer available to fill the vacancy. The Secretary concerned may not delegate the authority under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>