<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14311"><akn:num>14311</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay of promotion: involuntary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14311. Delay of promotion: involuntary(a) Delay During Investigations and Proceedings.—(1) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer to a higher grade may be delayed if any of the following applies before the date on which the appointment would otherwise be made:(A) Sworn charges against the officer have been received by an officer exercising general court-martial jurisdiction over the officer and the charges have not been disposed of.

(B) An investigation is being conducted to determine whether disciplinary action of any kind should be brought against the officer.

(C) A board of officers has been convened under section 14903 of this title to review the record of the officer.

(D) A criminal proceeding in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction is pending against the officer.

(E) Substantiated adverse information about the officer that is material to the decision to appoint the officer is under review by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary concerned.

(F) The Secretary of the military department concerned determines that credible information of adverse nature, including a substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in section 14107(a)(3)(A) of this title, with respect to the officer will result in the convening of a special selection review board under section 14502a of this title to review the officer and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the officer should be sustained.


(2) If disciplinary action is not taken against the officer, if the charges against the officer are withdrawn or dismissed, if the officer is not separated by the Secretary of the military department concerned as the result of having been required to show cause for retention, if the officer is acquitted of the charges, or if, after a review of substantiated adverse information about the officer regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay During Investigations and Proceedings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay for Lack of Qualifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the appointment of an officer to a higher grade may also be delayed if there is cause to believe that the officer has not met the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, or is mentally, physically, morally, or professionally unqualified to perform the duties of the grade to which selected. If it is later determined by a civilian official of the Department of Defense (not below the level of Secretary of a military department) that the officer is qualified for promotion to the higher grade and, after a review of adverse information regarding the requirement for exemplary conduct set forth in section 7233, 8167, or 9233 of this title, as applicable, the officer is determined to be among the officers best qualified for promotion to the higher grade, the officer shall be retained on the promotion list (including an approved all-fully-qualified-officers list, if appl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Officer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Length of Delay in Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The appointment of an officer to a higher grade may not be delayed under subsection (a) or (b) for more than six months after the date on which the officer would otherwise have been promoted unless the Secretary concerned specifies a further period of delay. An officer’s appointment may not be delayed more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any criminal case against the officer in a Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction or more than 90 days after final action has been taken in any court-martial case against the officer. Except for court action, a promotion may not be delayed more than 18 months after the date on which the officer would otherwise have been promoted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14311_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delay Because of Limitations on Officer Strength in Grade or Duties to Which Assigned.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>