<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1450" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1450/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1450/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1450"><akn:num>1450</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of annuity: beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1450. Payment of annuity: beneficiaries(a) In General.—Effective as of the first day after the death of a person to whom section 1448 of this title applies (or on such other day as that person may provide under subsection (j)), a monthly annuity under section 1451 of this title shall be paid to the person’s beneficiaries under the Plan, as follows:(1) Surviving spouse or former spouse.—The eligible surviving spouse or the eligible former spouse.

(2) Surviving children.—The surviving dependent children in equal shares, if the eligible surviving spouse or the eligible former spouse is dead, dies, or otherwise becomes ineligible under this section.

(3) Dependent children.—The dependent children in equal shares if the person to whom section 1448 of this title applies (with the concurrence of the person’s spouse, if required under section 1448(a)(3) of this title) elected to provide an annuity for dependent children but not for the spouse or former spouse.

(4) Special needs trusts for sole benefit of certain dependent children.—Notwithstanding subsection (i), a supplemental or special needs trust established under subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 1917(d)(4) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396p(d)(4)) for the sole benefit of a dependent child considered disabled under section 1614(a)(3) of that Act (42 U.S.C. 1382c(a)(3)) who is incapable of self-support because of mental or physical incapacity.

(5) Natural person designated under “insurable interest” coverage.—The natural person designated under section 1448(b)(1) of this title, unless the election to provide an annuity to the natural person has been changed as provided in subsection (f).


(b) Termination of Annuity for Death, Remarriage Before Age 55, Etc.—(1) General rule.—An annuity payable to the beneficiary terminates effective as of the first day of the month in which eligibility is lost.

(2) Termination of spouse annuity upon death or remarriage before age 55.—An annuity for a surviving spouse or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Effective as of the first day after the death of a person to whom section 1448 of this title applies (or on such other day as that person may provide under subsection (j)), a monthly annuity under section 1451 of this title shall be paid to the person’s beneficiaries under the Plan, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Annuity for Death, Remarriage Before Age 55, Etc.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offset for Amount of Dependency and Indemnity Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Payment of Annuities When Coverage Under Civil Service Retirement Elected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If, upon the death of a person to whom section 1448 of this title applies, that person had in effect a waiver of that person’s retired pay for the purposes of subchapter III of chapter 83 of title 5 or chapter 84 of such title, an annuity under this section shall not be payable unless, in accordance with section 8339(j) or 8416(a) of title 5, that person notified the Office of Personnel Management that he did not desire any spouse surviving him to receive an annuity under section 8341(b) or 8442(a) of that title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refund of Amounts Deducted From Retired Pay or CRSC When DIC Offset Is Applicable.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change in Election of Insurable Interest or Former Spouse Beneficiary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Changing or Revoking Elections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Annuities Under Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Except as provided in section 1451 of this title, an annuity under this section is in addition to any other payment to which a person is entitled under any other provision of law. Such annuity shall be considered as income under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities Exempt From Certain Legal Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Except as provided in subsection (a)(4) or (l)(3)(B), an annuity under this section is not assignable or subject to execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1450_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date of Reserve-Component Annuities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>