<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14506"><akn:num>14506</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of failure of selection for promotion: reserve majors of the Army, Air Force, and Marine Corp</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14506. Effect of failure of selection for promotion: reserve majors of the Army, Air Force, and Marine Corps and reserve lieutenant commanders of the Navy
Unless retained as provided in section 12646, 12686, 14701, 14701a, or 14702 of this title, each reserve officer of the Army, Navy, Air Force, or Marine Corps who holds the grade of major or lieutenant commander who has failed of selection to the next higher grade for the second time and whose name is not on a list of officers recommended for promotion to the next higher grade shall, if not earlier removed from the reserve active-status list, be removed from that list in accordance with section 14513 of this title on the later of (1) the first day of the month after the month in which the officer completes 20 years of commissioned service, or (2) the first day of the seventh month after the month in which the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public.
(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2951; amended Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XV, § 1501(b)(29), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 498; Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 514(a), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 593; Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title V, §§ 505(b)(6), 513(c)(3), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 1870, 1876.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2024—Pub. L. 118–159, § 513(c)(3), inserted “14701a,” after “14701,”.
Pub. L. 118–159, § 505(b)(6), substituted “the Secretary concerned releases the promotion results of the board which considered the officer for the second time to the public” for “the President approves the report of the board which considered the officer for the second time”.
1999—Pub. L. 106–65 inserted “the later of (1)” after “in accordance with section 14513 of this title on” and “, or (2) the first day of the seventh month after the month in which the President approves the report of the board which considered the officer for the second time” before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>