<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14503"><akn:num>14503</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of officers with less than six years of commissioned service or found not qualified for pr</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14503. Discharge of officers with less than six years of commissioned service or found not qualified for promotion to first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade)(a) Authorized Discharges.—The Secretary of the military department concerned may discharge any reserve officer who—(1) has less than six years of service in an active status as a commissioned officer; or

(2) is serving in the grade of second lieutenant or ensign and has been found not qualified for promotion to the grade of first lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade).


(b) Time for Discharge.—(1) An officer described in subsection (a)(2)—(A) may be discharged at any time after being found not qualified for promotion; and

(B) if not sooner discharged, shall be discharged at the end of the 18-month period beginning on the date on which the officer is first found not qualified for promotion.


(2) Paragraph (1) shall not apply if the officer is sooner promoted.


(c) Regulations.—Discharges under this section shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense and may be made without regard to section 12645 of this title.

(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2949; amended Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 503(c)(1), (2), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 95.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in subsecs. (a) and (b) of this section were contained in sections 3819(b) and 8819(c) of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–337, § 1629(a)(2), (c)(2).

Amendments2008—Pub. L. 110–181, § 503(c)(2), substituted “six years” for “five years” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 110–181, § 503(c)(1), substituted “six years” for “five years”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1996, see section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337, set out as a note under section 10001 of this title.

Rights for Officers With Over Three Years ServicePub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1689, Oct. 5, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Discharges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the military department concerned may discharge any reserve officer who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Discharge.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discharges under this section shall be made under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense and may be made without regard to section 12645 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>