<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1451" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1451/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1451/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1451"><akn:num>1451</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1451. Amount of annuity(a) Computation of Annuity for a Spouse, Former Spouse, or Child.—(1) Standard annuity.—In the case of a standard annuity provided to a beneficiary under section 1450(a) of this title (other than under section 1450(a)(5)), the monthly annuity payable to the beneficiary shall be determined as follows:(A) Beneficiary under 62 years of age.—If the beneficiary is under 62 years of age or is a dependent child when becoming entitled to the annuity, the monthly annuity shall be the amount equal to 55 percent of the base amount.

(B) Beneficiary 62 years of age or older.—(i) General rule.—If the beneficiary (other than a dependent child) is 62 years of age or older when becoming entitled to the annuity, the monthly annuity shall be the amount equal to the product of the base amount and the percent applicable to the month, as follows:(I) For a month before October 2005, the applicable percent is 35 percent.

(II) For months after September 2005 and before April 2006, the applicable percent is 40 percent.

(III) For months after March 2006 and before April 2007, the applicable percent is 45 percent.

(IV) For months after March 2007 and before April 2008, the applicable percent is 50 percent.

(V) For months after March 2008, the applicable percent is 55 percent.


(ii) Rule if beneficiary eligible for social security offset computation.—If the beneficiary is eligible to have the annuity computed under subsection (e) and if computation of the annuity under that subsection is more favorable to the beneficiary than computation under clause (i), the annuity shall be computed under that subsection rather than under clause (i).



(2) Reserve-component annuity.—In the case of a reserve-component annuity provided to a beneficiary under section 1450(a) of this title (other than under section 1450(a)(5)), the monthly annuity payable to the beneficiary shall be determined as follows:(A) Beneficiary under 62 years of age.—If the beneficiary is under 62 years of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of Annuity for a Spouse, Former Spouse, or Child.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurable Interest Beneficiary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities for Survivors of Certain Persons Dying During a Period of Special Eligibility for SBP.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of Annuities at Age 62.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings Provision for Certain Beneficiaries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Percentages Applicable to Computation of Reserve-Component Annuities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The percentage to be applied in determining the amount of an annuity computed under subsection (a)(2), (b)(2), or (e)(2)(B) shall be determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Such regulations shall be prescribed taking into consideration the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments to Annuities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments to Base Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1451_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recomputation of Annuity for Certain Beneficiaries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In the case of an annuity under the Plan which is computed on the basis of the retired pay of a person who would have been entitled to have that retired pay recomputed under section 1410 of this title upon attaining 62 years of age, but who dies before attaining that age, the annuity shall be recomputed, effective on the first day of the first month beginning after the date on which the member or former member would have attained 62 years of age, so as to be the amount equal to the amount of the annuity that would be in effect on that date if increases under subsection (h)(1) in the base amount applicable to that annuity to the time of the death of the member or former member, and increases in such annuity under subsection (g)(1), had been computed as provided in paragraph (2) of section 1401a(b) of this title (rather than under paragraph (3) of that section).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>