<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1455" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1455/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1455/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1455"><akn:num>1455</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1455. Regulations(a) In General.—The President shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subchapter. Those regulations shall, so far as practicable, be uniform for the uniformed services.

(b) Notice of Elections.—Regulations prescribed under this section shall provide that before the date on which a member becomes entitled to retired pay—(1) if the member is married, the member and the member’s spouse shall be informed of the elections available under section 1448(a) of this title and the effects of such elections; and

(2) if the notification referred to in section 1448(a)(3)(E) of this title is required, any former spouse of the member shall be informed of the elections available and the effects of such elections.


(c) Procedure for Depositing Certain Receipts.—Regulations prescribed under this section shall establish procedures for depositing the amounts referred to in sections 1448(g), 1450(k)(2), and 1452(d) of this title.

(d) Payments to Guardians, Fiduciaries, and Special Needs Trusts.—(1) In general.—Regulations prescribed under this section shall provide procedures for the payment of an annuity under this subchapter in the case of—(A) a person for whom a guardian or other fiduciary has been appointed;

(B) a minor, mentally incompetent, or otherwise legally disabled person for whom a guardian or other fiduciary has not been appointed; and

(C) a dependent child incapable of self-support because of mental or physical incapacity for whom a supplemental or special needs trust has been established under subparagraph (A) or (C) of section 1917(d)(4) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396p(d)(4)).


(2) Authorized procedures.—The regulations under paragraph (1) may include provisions for the following:(A) In the case of an annuitant referred to in paragraph (1)(A), payment of the annuity to the appointed guardian or other fiduciary.

(B) In the case of an annuitant referred to in paragraph (1)(B), payment of the annuity to any person who, in the judg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President shall prescribe regulations to carry out this subchapter. Those regulations shall, so far as practicable, be uniform for the uniformed services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Elections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations prescribed under this section shall provide that before the date on which a member becomes entitled to retired pay—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for Depositing Certain Receipts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations prescribed under this section shall establish procedures for depositing the amounts referred to in sections 1448(g), 1450(k)(2), and 1452(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1455_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to Guardians, Fiduciaries, and Special Needs Trusts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>