<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1465" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1465/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1465/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1465"><akn:num>1465</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of contributions to the Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1465. Determination of contributions to the Fund(a)(1) Not later than six months after the Board of Actuaries is first appointed, the Board shall determine the amount that is the present value (as of October 1, 1984) of future benefits payable from the Fund that are attributable to service in the armed forces performed before October 1, 1984. That amount is the original unfunded liability of the Fund. The Board shall determine the period of time over which the original unfunded liability should be liquidated and shall determine an amortization schedule for the liquidation of such liability over that period. Contributions to the Fund for the liquidation of the original unfunded liability in accordance with such schedule shall be made as provided in section 1466(b) of this title.

(2) Not later than October 1, 2022, the Board of Actuaries shall determine the amount that is the present value (as of September 30, 2022) of future benefits payable from the Fund that are attributable to service in the Coast Guard performed before October 1, 2022. That amount is the original Coast Guard unfunded liability of the Fund. The Board shall determine the period of time over which the original Coast Guard unfunded liability should be liquidated and shall determine an amortization schedule for the liquidation of such liability over that period. Contributions to the Fund for the liquidation of the original Coast Guard unfunded liability in accordance with such schedule shall be made as provided in section 1466(b) of this title.


(b)(1) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, shall determine each year, in sufficient time for inclusion in budget requests for the following fiscal year, the total amount of Department of Defense and Coast Guard contributions to be made to the Fund during that fiscal year under section 1466(a) of this title. That amount shall be the sum of the following:(A) The product of—(i) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) All determinations under this section shall be made using methods and assumptions approved by the Board of Actuaries (including assumptions of interest rates and inflation) and in accordance with generally accepted actuarial principles and practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense and, with regard to the Coast Guard, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall provide for the keeping of such records as are necessary for determining the actuarial status of the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>