<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14705"><akn:num>14705</akn:num><akn:heading>Selective early retirement: reserve general and flag officers of the Navy and Marine Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14705. Selective early retirement: reserve general and flag officers of the Navy and Marine Corps(a) Authority To Consider.—An officer in the Navy Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of rear admiral (lower half) or rear admiral and an officer in the Marine Corps Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of brigadier general or major general may be considered for early retirement whenever the Secretary of the Navy determines that such action is necessary.

(b) Boards.—(1) If the Secretary of the Navy determines that consideration of officers for early retirement under this section is necessary, the Secretary shall convene a selection board under section 14101(b) of this title to recommend an appropriate number of officers for early retirement.

(2) In the case of such a board convened to consider officers in the grade of rear admiral or major general, the Secretary of the Navy may appoint the board without regard to section 14102(b) of this title. In doing so, however, the Secretary shall ensure that—(A) each regular commissioned officer appointed to the board holds a grade higher than the grade of rear admiral or major general; and

(B) at least one member of the board is a reserve officer who holds the grade of rear admiral or major general.



(c) Separation Under Section 14514.—An officer selected for early retirement under this section shall be separated in accordance with section 14514 of this title.

(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2957; amended Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 515, Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2008; Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 511(b)(3), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1459; Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 515(b)(1)(VV), Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3234.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 6389(f)(3) of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–337, § 1628(4).

Amendments2006—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 109–163 substi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Consider.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An officer in the Navy Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of rear admiral (lower half) or rear admiral and an officer in the Marine Corps Reserve in an active status serving in the grade of brigadier general or major general may be considered for early retirement whenever the Secretary of the Navy determines that such action is necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation Under Section 14514.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An officer selected for early retirement under this section shall be separated in accordance with section 14514 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>