<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1482" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1482/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1482/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1482"><akn:num>1482</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses incident to death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1482. Expenses incident to death(a) Incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of the remains of any decedent covered by section 1481 of this title, the Secretary concerned may pay the necessary expenses of the following:(1) Recovery and identification of the remains.

(2) Notification to the next of kin or other appropriate person.

(3) Preparation of the remains for burial, including cremation if requested by the person designated to direct disposition of the remains.

(4) Furnishing of a uniform or other clothing.

(5) Furnishing of a casket or urn, or both, with outside box.

(6) Hearse service.

(7) Funeral director’s services.

(8)(A) Transportation of the remains, and travel and transportation allowances as specified in regulations prescribed under section 464 of title 37 for an escort of one person, to the place, subject to subparagraph (B), selected by the person designated to direct disposition of the remains or, if such a selection is not made, to a national or other cemetery which is selected by the Secretary and in which burial of the decedent is authorized.

(B) The person designated to direct disposition of the remains may select two places under subparagraph (A) if the second place is a national cemetery. If that person selects two places, the Secretary concerned may pay for transportation to the second place only by means of reimbursement under subsection (b).

(C) When transportation of the remains includes transportation by aircraft under section 562 of the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 (Public Law 109–364; 10 U.S.C. 1482 note), the Secretary concerned shall provide, to the maximum extent practicable, for delivery of the remains by air to the commercial, general aviation, or military airport nearest to the place selected by the designee.


(9) Interment or inurnment of the remains.

(10) In the case of a decedent under the jurisdiction of a Secretary of a military department at the time of death, enduri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of the remains of any decedent covered by section 1481 of this title, the Secretary concerned may pay the necessary expenses of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If an individual pays any expense payable by the United States under this section, the Secretary concerned shall reimburse him or his representative in an amount not larger than that normally incurred by the Secretary in furnishing the supply or service concerned. If reimbursement by the United States is also authorized under another provision of law or regulation, the individual may elect under which provision to be reimbursed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The following persons may be designated to direct disposition of the remains of a decedent covered by this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When the remains of a decedent covered by section 1481 of this title, whose death occurs after January 1, 1961, are determined to be nonrecoverable, the person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains if they had been recovered may be— However, the amount of the reimbursement shall be determined in the manner prescribed in subsection (b) for an interment, but may not be larger than that authorized when the United States provides the grave site. A claim for reimbursement under this subsection may be allowed only if it is presented within two years after the date of death or the date the person who would have been designated under subsection (c) to direct disposition of the remains, if they had been recovered, receives notification that the member has been reported or determined to be dead under authority of chapter 10 of title 37, whichever is later.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presentation of Flag of the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The payment of expenses incident to the recovery, care, and disposition of a decedent covered by section 1481(a)(9) of this title is limited to the payment of expenses described in paragraphs (1) through (5) of subsection (a) and air transportation of the remains from a location outside the United States to a point of entry in the United States. Such air transportation may be provided without reimbursement on a space-available basis in military or military-chartered aircraft. The Secretary concerned may pay any other expenses relating to the remains of such a decedent that are authorized to be paid under this section only on a reimbursable basis. Amounts reimbursed to the Secretary concerned under this subsection shall be credited to appropriations available, at the time of reimbursement, for the payment of such expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1482_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>