<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/149" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/149/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/149/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_149"><akn:num>149</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Strategic Capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 149. Office of Strategic Capital(a) Establishment.—There is in the Office of the Secretary of Defense an office to be known as the Office of Strategic Capital (in this section referred to as the “Office”).

(b) Director.—The Office shall be headed by a Director (in this section referred to as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the Secretary from among employees in Senior Executive Service positions (as defined in section 3132 of title 5), or from outside the civil service who have successfully held equivalent positions.

(c) Duties.—The Office shall—(1) develop, integrate, and implement capital investment strategies proven in the commercial sector to shape and scale investment in critical technologies and assets;

(2) identify and prioritize promising critical technologies and assets that require capital assistance and have the potential to benefit the Department of Defense; and

(3) make eligible investments in such technologies and assets, such as supply chain technologies not always supported through direct investment.


(d) Non-Federal Funding Requirements for Certain Investments.—In the case of an eligible investment made through a direct loan, not less than 80 percent of the total capital provided for the specific technology to be funded by the investment shall be derived from non-Federal sources as of the time of the investment.

(e) Pilot Program on Capital Assistance to Support Defense Investment in the Industrial Base.—(1) To the extent and in such amounts as specifically provided in advance in appropriations Acts for the purposes detailed in this subsection, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director, may carry out a pilot program under this subsection to provide capital assistance to eligible entities for eligible investments to develop technologies that support the duties and elements of the Office and meet the needs of the Department of Defense.

(2)(A) An eligible entity seeking capital assistance for an eligible investment under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is in the Office of the Secretary of Defense an office to be known as the Office of Strategic Capital (in this section referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Office shall be headed by a Director (in this section referred to as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the Secretary from among employees in Senior Executive Service positions (as defined in section 3132 of title 5), or from outside the civil service who have successfully held equivalent positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Office shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal Funding Requirements for Certain Investments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In the case of an eligible investment made through a direct loan, not less than 80 percent of the total capital provided for the specific technology to be funded by the investment shall be derived from non-Federal sources as of the time of the investment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot Program on Capital Assistance to Support Defense Investment in the Industrial Base.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_149_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>