<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/14901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14901"><akn:num>14901</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation of chaplains for loss of professional qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14901. Separation of chaplains for loss of professional qualifications(a) Separation.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, an officer on the reserve active-status list who is appointed or designated as a chaplain may, if the officer fails to maintain the qualifications needed to perform the professional function of a chaplain, be discharged. The authority under the preceding sentence applies without regard to the provisions of section 12645 of this title.

(b) Effect of Separation.—If an officer separated under this section is eligible for retirement, the officer may be retired. If the officer has completed the years of service required for eligibility for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title, the officer may be transferred to the Retired Reserve.

(Added Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1611, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2957.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1996, see section 1691(b)(1) of Pub. L. 103–337, set out as a note under section 10001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14901_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, an officer on the reserve active-status list who is appointed or designated as a chaplain may, if the officer fails to maintain the qualifications needed to perform the professional function of a chaplain, be discharged. The authority under the preceding sentence applies without regard to the provisions of section 12645 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14901_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Separation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If an officer separated under this section is eligible for retirement, the officer may be retired. If the officer has completed the years of service required for eligibility for retired pay under chapter 1223 of this title, the officer may be transferred to the Retired Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>