<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1491" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1491/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1491/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1491"><akn:num>1491</akn:num><akn:heading>Funeral honors functions at funerals for veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1491. Funeral honors functions at funerals for veterans(a) Availability of Funeral Honors Detail Ensured.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, upon request, a funeral honors detail is provided for the funeral of any veteran, except when military honors are prohibited under section 985(a) of this title.

(b) Composition of Funeral Honors Details.—(1) The Secretary of each military department shall ensure that a funeral honors detail for the funeral of a veteran consists of two or more persons.

(2) At least two members of the funeral honors detail for a veteran’s funeral shall be members of the armed forces (other than members in a retired status). The remainder of the detail may consist of members of the armed forces (including members in a retired status), or members of veterans organizations or other organizations approved for purposes of this section under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Each member of the armed forces in the detail shall wear the uniform of the member’s armed force while serving in the detail.

(3) The Secretary concerned shall provide full military honors (as determined by the Secretary concerned) for the funeral of a veteran who—(A) is first interred or first inurned in Arlington National Cemetery on or after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020;

(B) was awarded the medal of honor or the prisoner-of-war medal; and

(C) is not entitled to full military honors by the grade of that veteran.



(c) Ceremony.—A funeral honors detail shall, at a minimum, perform at the funeral a ceremony that includes the folding of a United States flag and presentation of the flag to the veteran’s family and the playing of Taps. Unless a bugler is a member of the detail, the funeral honors detail shall play a recorded version of Taps using audio equipment which the detail shall provide if adequate audio equipment is not otherwise available for use at the funeral.

(d) Support.—(1) To </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funeral Honors Detail Ensured.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, upon request, a funeral honors detail is provided for the funeral of any veteran, except when military honors are prohibited under section 985(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of Funeral Honors Details.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceremony.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A funeral honors detail shall, at a minimum, perform at the funeral a ceremony that includes the folding of a United States flag and presentation of the flag to the veteran’s family and the playing of Taps. Unless a bugler is a member of the detail, the funeral honors detail shall play a recorded version of Taps using audio equipment which the detail shall provide if adequate audio equipment is not otherwise available for use at the funeral.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Those regulations shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report not later than January 31 of each year beginning with 2001 and ending with 2005 on the experience of the Department of Defense under this section. Each such report shall provide data on the number of funerals supported under this section, the cost for that support, shown by manpower and other cost factors, and the number and costs of funerals supported by each participating organization. The data in the report shall be presented in a standard format, regardless of military department or other organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1491_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veteran Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “veteran” means a decedent who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>