<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1501"><akn:num>1501</akn:num><akn:heading>System for accounting for missing persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1501. System for accounting for missing persons(a) Responsibility for Missing Persons.—(1)(A) The Secretary of Defense shall designate a single organization within the Department of Defense to have responsibility for Department matters relating to missing persons from past conflicts, including accounting for missing persons and persons whose remains have not been recovered from the conflict in which they were lost.

(B) The organization designated under this paragraph shall be a Defense Agency or other entity of the Department of Defense outside the military departments and is referred to in this chapter as the “designated Defense Agency”.

(C) The head of the organization designated under this paragraph is referred to in this chapter as the “designated Agency Director”.


(2) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the responsibilities of the designated Agency Director shall include the following:(A) Policy, control, and oversight of the program established under section 1509 of this title.

(B) Responsibility for accounting for missing persons from past conflicts, including locating, recovering, and identifying missing persons from past conflicts or their remains after hostilities have ceased.

(C) Coordination for the Department of Defense with other departments and agencies of the United States on all matters concerning missing persons from past conflicts.

(D) Dissemination of appropriate information on the status of missing persons from past conflicts to authorized family members.

(E) Establishment of a means for communication between officials of the designated Defense Agency and family members of missing persons from past conflicts, veterans service organizations, concerned citizens, and the public on the Department’s efforts to account for missing persons from past conflicts, including a readily available means for communication of their views and recommendations to the designated Agency Director.


(3) In carrying o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Missing Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform DoD Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary Next of Kin.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The individual who is primary next of kin of any person described in subsection (c) may for purposes of this chapter designate another individual to act on behalf of that individual as primary next of kin. The Secretary concerned shall treat an individual so designated as if the individual designated were the primary next of kin for purposes of this chapter. A designation under this subsection may be revoked at any time by the person who made the designation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Applicability of Procedures When Missing Person Is Accounted for.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The provisions of this chapter relating to boards of inquiry and to the actions by the Secretary concerned on the reports of those boards shall cease to apply in the case of a missing person upon the person becoming accounted for or otherwise being determined to be in a status other than missing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1501_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary Concerned.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this chapter, the term “Secretary concerned” includes, in the case of a civilian officer or employee of the Department of Defense or an employee of a contractor of the Department of Defense, the Secretary of the military department or head of the element of the Department of Defense employing the officer or employee or contracting with the contractor, as the case may be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>