<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1504"><akn:num>1504</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent board of inquiry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1504. Subsequent board of inquiry(a) Additional Board.—If information that may result in a change of status of a person covered by a determination under section 1503(i) of this title becomes available within one year after the date of the transmission of a report with respect to the person under section 1502(a)(2) of this title, the Secretary concerned shall appoint a board under this section to conduct an inquiry into the information.

(b) Date of Appointment.—The Secretary concerned shall appoint a board under this section to conduct an inquiry into the whereabouts and status of a missing person on or about one year after the date of the transmission of a report concerning the person under section 1502(a)(2) of this title.

(c) Combined Inquiries.—If it appears to the Secretary concerned that the absence or status of two or more persons is factually related, the Secretary may appoint one board under this section to conduct the inquiry into the whereabouts and status of such persons.

(d) Composition.—(1) A board appointed under this section shall be composed of at least three members as follows:(A) In the case of a board that will inquire into the whereabouts and status of one or more members of the armed forces (and no civilians described in subparagraph (B)), the board shall be composed of officers having the grade of major or lieutenant commander or above.

(B) In the case of a board that will inquire into the whereabouts and status of one or more civilian employees of the Department of Defense or contractors of the Department of Defense (and no members of the armed forces), the board shall be composed of—(i) not less than three employees of the Department of Defense whose rate of annual pay is equal to or greater than the rate of annual pay payable for grade GS–13 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5; and

(ii) such members of the armed forces as the Secretary considers advisable.


(C) In the case of a board that will inquire into the where</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If information that may result in a change of status of a person covered by a determination under section 1503(i) of this title becomes available within one year after the date of the transmission of a report with respect to the person under section 1502(a)(2) of this title, the Secretary concerned shall appoint a board under this section to conduct an inquiry into the information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date of Appointment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall appoint a board under this section to conduct an inquiry into the whereabouts and status of a missing person on or about one year after the date of the transmission of a report concerning the person under section 1502(a)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combined Inquiries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If it appears to the Secretary concerned that the absence or status of two or more persons is factually related, the Secretary may appoint one board under this section to conduct the inquiry into the whereabouts and status of such persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A board appointed under this section to conduct an inquiry into the whereabouts and status of a person shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Counsel for Missing Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance of Family Members and Certain Other Interested Persons at Proceedings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Information to Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendation on Status.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1504_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A board appointed under this section shall submit to the Secretary concerned a report on the inquiry carried out by the board, together with the evidence considered by the board during the inquiry. The report may include a classified annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>