<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_155"><akn:num>155</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 155. Joint Staff(a) Appointment of Officers to Joint Staff.—(1) There is a Joint Staff under the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff. The Joint Staff assists the Chairman and, subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Chairman, the other members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in carrying out their responsibilities.

(2) Officers of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) assigned to serve on the Joint Staff shall be selected by the Chairman in approximately equal numbers from—(A) the Army;

(B) the Navy and the Marine Corps; and

(C) the Air Force and the Space Force.


(3) Selection of officers of an armed force to serve on the Joint Staff shall be made by the Chairman from a list of officers submitted by the Secretary of the military department having jurisdiction over that armed force. Each officer whose name is submitted shall be among those officers considered to be the most outstanding officers of that armed force. The Chairman may specify the number of officers to be included on any such list.


(b) Director.—The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, after consultation with the other members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, may select an officer to serve as Director of the Joint Staff.

(c) Management of Joint Staff.—The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff manages the Joint Staff and the Director of the Joint Staff. The Joint Staff shall perform such duties as the Chairman prescribes and shall perform such duties under such procedures as the Chairman prescribes.

(d) Operation of Joint Staff.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Joint Staff is independently organized and operated so that the Joint Staff supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting the congressional purpose set forth in the last clause of section 2 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3002) to provide—(1) for the unified strategic direction of the combatant forces;

(2) for their opera</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Officers to Joint Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, after consultation with the other members of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, may select an officer to serve as Director of the Joint Staff.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Joint Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff manages the Joint Staff and the Director of the Joint Staff. The Joint Staff shall perform such duties as the Chairman prescribes and shall perform such duties under such procedures as the Chairman prescribes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of Joint Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the Joint Staff is independently organized and operated so that the Joint Staff supports the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in meeting the congressional purpose set forth in the last clause of section 2 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3002) to provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of Function as Armed Forces General Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Joint Staff shall not operate or be organized as an overall Armed Forces General Staff and shall have no executive authority. The Joint Staff may be organized and may operate along conventional staff lines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tour of Duty of Joint Staff Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of Joint Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_155_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>