<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1561a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1561a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1561a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1561a"><akn:num>1561a</akn:num><akn:heading>Civilian orders of protection: force and effect on military installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1561a. Civilian orders of protection: force and effect on military installations(a) Force and Effect.—A civilian order of protection shall have the same force and effect on a military installation as such order has within the jurisdiction of the court that issued such order.

(b) Civilian Order of Protection Defined.—In this section, the term “civilian order of protection” has the meaning given the term “protection order” in section 2266(5) of title 18.

(c) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall be designed to further good order and discipline by members of the armed forces and civilians present on military installations.

(Added Pub. L. 107–311, § 2(a), Dec. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 2455.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Policies and Procedures on Registration at Military Installations of Civilian Protective Orders Applicable to Members of the Armed Forces Assigned to Such Installations and Certain Other IndividualsPub. L. 116–92, div. A, title V, § 550A, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1380, provided that:
“(a) Policies and Procedures Required.—Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act [Dec. 20, 2019], the Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, establish policies and procedures for the registration at military installations of any civilian protective orders described in subsection (b), including the duties and responsibilities of commanders of installations in the registration process.

“(b) Civilian Protective Orders.—A civilian protective order described in this subsection is any civilian protective order as follows:“(1) A civilian protective order against a member of the Armed Forces assigned to the installation concerned.

“(2) A civilian protective order against a civilian employee employed at the installation concerned.

“(3) A civilian protective order against the civilian spouse or intimate partner of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1561a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Force and Effect.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A civilian order of protection shall have the same force and effect on a military installation as such order has within the jurisdiction of the court that issued such order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1561a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civilian Order of Protection Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “civilian order of protection” has the meaning given the term “protection order” in section 2266(5) of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1561a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. The regulations shall be designed to further good order and discipline by members of the armed forces and civilians present on military installations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>