<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1566" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1566/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1566/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1566"><akn:num>1566</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting assistance: compliance assessments; assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1566. Voting assistance: compliance assessments; assistance(a) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to require that the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force ensure their compliance with any directives issued by the Secretary of Defense in implementing any voting assistance program.

(b) Voting Assistance Programs Defined.—In this section, the term “voting assistance programs” means—(1) the Federal Voting Assistance Program carried out under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (42 U.S.C. 1973ff et seq.); 11 See References in Text note below. and

(2) any similar program.


(c) Annual Effectiveness and Compliance Reviews.—(1) The Inspector General of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force shall conduct—(A) an annual review of the effectiveness of voting assistance programs; and

(B) an annual review of the compliance with voting assistance programs of that armed force.


(2) Upon the completion of each annual review under paragraph (1), each Inspector General specified in that paragraph shall submit to the Inspector General of the Department of Defense a report on the results of each such review. Such report shall be submitted in time each year to be reflected in the report of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense under paragraph (3).

(3) Not later than March 31 each year, the Inspector General of the Department of Defense shall submit to Congress a report on—(A) the effectiveness during the preceding calendar year of voting assistance programs; and

(B) the level of compliance during the preceding calendar year with voting assistance programs of each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force.



[(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 596(a), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2235.]

(e) Regular Military Department Assessments.—The Secretary of each military department shall include in the set of issues and programs to be reviewed during any </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to require that the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Space Force ensure their compliance with any directives issued by the Secretary of Defense in implementing any voting assistance program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting Assistance Programs Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “voting assistance programs” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Effectiveness and Compliance Reviews.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title V, § 596(a), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2235.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regular Military Department Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of each military department shall include in the set of issues and programs to be reviewed during any management effectiveness review or inspection at the installation level an assessment of compliance with the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (42 U.S.C. 1973ff et seq.) 1 and with Department of Defense regulations regarding the Federal Voting Assistance Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voting Assistance Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of Mail From Overseas Preceding Federal Elections.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Deadlines and Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of each military department, utilizing the voting assistance officer network established for each military installation, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, provide notice to members of the armed forces stationed at that installation of the last date before a general Federal election for which absentee ballots mailed from a postal facility located at that installation can reasonably be expected to be timely delivered to the appropriate State and local election officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1566_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration and Voting Information for Members and Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>