<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1584" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1584/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1584/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1584"><akn:num>1584</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of non-citizens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1584. Employment of non-citizens
Laws prohibiting the employment of, or payment of pay or expenses to, a person who is not a citizen of the United States do not apply to personnel of the Department of Defense.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 118; Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(20)(A), Oct. 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 1290; Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, §§ 1481(d)(1), (2), 1482(b), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1706, 1709; Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title X, § 1062(b), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 444.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


15845:235c.5:475h.5:628c.July 16, 1952, ch. 882, § 2, 66 Stat. 725.


The words “appointment or” are omitted as surplusage.

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Pub. L. 104–106 struck out subsec. (a) heading “Waiver of employment restrictions for certain personnel”, designated subsec. (a) as entire section, and struck out subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Notice to Congress of Certain Salary Increases.—The Secretary of Defense shall notify the Committees on Armed Services and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives when any salary increase granted to direct and indirect hire foreign national employees of the Department of Defense overseas, stated as a percentage, is greater than the higher of the following percentages:
“(1) The percentage pay increase authorized by law for civilian employees of the Department of Defense whose pay is computed under the provisions of section 5332 of title 5.
“(2) The percentage increase provided to national government employees of the host nation.”
1990—Pub. L. 101–510, § 1482(b), substituted “personnel of the Department of Defense” for “any expert, scientist, technician, or professional person whose employment in connection with the research and development activities of a military department is determined to be necessary by the Secretary of that department” in subsec. (a).
Pub. L. 101–510, § 1481(d)(1), (2), substitute</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>