<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1588" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1588/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1588/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1588"><akn:num>1588</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to accept certain voluntary services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1588. Authority to accept certain voluntary services(a) Authority To Accept Services.—Subject to subsection (b) and notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, the Secretary concerned may accept from any person the following services:(1) Voluntary medical services, dental services, nursing services, or other health-care related services.

(2) Voluntary services to be provided for a museum or a natural resources program.

(3) Voluntary services to be provided for programs providing services to members of the uniformed services and the families of such members, including the following programs:(A) Family support programs.

(B) Child development and youth services programs.

(C) Library and education programs.

(D) Religious programs.

(E) Housing referral programs.

(F) Programs providing employment assistance to spouses of such members.

(G) Morale, welfare, and recreation programs, to the extent not covered by another subparagraph of this paragraph.


(4) Voluntary services as a member of a funeral honors detail under section 1491 of this title.

(5) Legal services voluntarily provided as legal assistance under section 1044 of this title.

(6) Voluntary services as a proctor for administration to secondary school students of the test known as the “Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery”.

(7) Voluntary translation or interpretation services offered with respect to a foreign language by a person (A) who is registered for such foreign language on the National Foreign Language Skills Registry under section 1596b of this title, or (B) who otherwise is approved to provide voluntary translation or interpretation services for national security purposes, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.

(8) Voluntary services to support programs of a committee of the Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve as authorized by the Secretary of Defense.

(9) Voluntary services to facilitate accounting for missing persons.

(10) Voluntary legal support services provided by law st</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Accept Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b) and notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, the Secretary concerned may accept from any person the following services:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements and Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Recruit and Train Persons Providing Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned may recruit and train persons to provide voluntary services accepted under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Persons Providing Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Incidental Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary concerned may provide for reimbursement of a person for incidental expenses incurred by the person in providing voluntary services accepted under subsection (a). The Secretary shall determine which expenses are eligible for reimbursement under this subsection. Any such reimbursement may be made from appropriated or nonappropriated funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Install Equipment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1588_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary Concerned for Acceptance of Services for Programs Serving Members of NOAA Corps and Their Families.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of the acceptance of services described in subsection (a)(3), the term “Secretary concerned” in subsection (a) shall include the Secretary of Commerce with respect to members of the commissioned officer corps of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>