<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1592" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1592/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1592/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1592"><akn:num>1592</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on payment of severance pay to foreign nationals in the event of certain overseas base c</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1592. Prohibition on payment of severance pay to foreign nationals in the event of certain overseas base closures
Funds available to the Department of Defense (including funds in the Foreign National Employees Separation Pay Account, Defense, established under section 1581 of this title) may not be used to pay severance pay to a foreign national employed by the Department of Defense under a contract, a treaty, or a memorandum of understanding with a foreign nation that provides for payment of separation pay if the termination of the employment of the foreign national is the result of the closing of, or the curtailment of activities at, a United States military facility in that country at the request of the government of that country.
(Added Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 311(b)(1), Nov. 29, 1989, 103 Stat. 1411; amended Pub. L. 102–190, div. A, title X, § 1003(b), Dec. 5, 1991, 105 Stat. 1456; Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title X, § 1052(21), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2500.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Another section 1592 was renumbered section 1596 of this title.

Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–484 inserted “section” after “established under”.
1991—Pub. L. 102–190 inserted “(including funds in the Foreign National Employees Separation Pay Account, Defense, established under 1581 of this title)” and substituted “a contract, a treaty, or a memorandum of understanding with a foreign nation that provides for payment of separation pay” for “a contract performed in a foreign country”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 101–189, div. A, title III, § 311(b)(3), Nov. 29, 1989, 103 Stat. 1412, as amended by Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1352(a), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2558, provided that:
“(A) Section 1592 of title 10, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act [Nov. 29, 1989].

“[(B) Repealed. Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title XIII, § 1352(a), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2558</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>