<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1599g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1599g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1599g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1599g"><akn:num>1599g</akn:num><akn:heading>Public-private talent exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1599g. Public-private talent exchange(a) Assignment Authority.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may, with the agreement of a private-sector organization and the consent of the employee, arrange for the temporary assignment of an employee to such private-sector organization, or from such private-sector organization to a Department of Defense organization under this section.

(b) Agreements.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall provide for a written agreement among the Department of Defense, the private-sector organization, and the employee concerned regarding the terms and conditions of the employee’s assignment under this section. The agreement—(A) shall require that the employee of the Department of Defense, upon completion of the assignment, will serve in the Department of Defense, or elsewhere in the civil service if approved by the Secretary, for a period equal to twice the length of the assignment;

(B) shall provide that if the employee of the Department of Defense or of the private-sector organization (as the case may be) fails to carry out the agreement, such employee shall be liable to the United States for payment of all expenses of the assignment, unless that failure was for good and sufficient reason, as determined by the Secretary of Defense; and

(C) shall contain language ensuring that such employee of the Department does not improperly use information that such employee knows relates to a Department acquisition or procurement for the benefit or advantage of the private-sector organization.


(2) An amount for which an employee is liable under paragraph (1) shall be treated as a debt due the United States.

(3) The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, collection of a debt described in paragraph (2) based on a determination that the collection would be against equity and good conscience and not in the best interests of the United States, after taking into account any indication of fraud, misrepresentation, fa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may, with the agreement of a private-sector organization and the consent of the employee, arrange for the temporary assignment of an employee to such private-sector organization, or from such private-sector organization to a Department of Defense organization under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An assignment under this section may, at any time and for any reason, be terminated by the Department of Defense or the private-sector organization concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Federal Employees Assigned to Private-sector Organizations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and Conditions for Private-sector Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An employee of a private-sector organization who is assigned to a Department of Defense organization under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition Against Charging Certain Costs to the Federal Government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A private-sector organization may not charge the Department or any other agency of the Federal Government, as direct or indirect costs under a Federal contract, the costs of pay or benefits paid by the organization to an employee assigned to a Department organization under this section for the period of the assignment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicts of Interest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A private-sector organization that is temporarily assigned a member of the acquisition workforce under this section shall not be considered to have a conflict of interest with the Department of Defense solely because of participation in the program established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1599g_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding; Use of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Funds for the expenses for the program established under this section may be provided from amounts in the Department of Defense Acquisition Workforce Development Fund. Expenses for the program include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>