<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1602"><akn:num>1602</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1602. Basic pay(a) Authority To Fix Rates of Basic Pay.—The Secretary of Defense (subject to the provisions of this section) shall fix the rates of basic pay for positions established under section 1601 of this title in relation to the rates of pay provided for comparable positions in the Department of Defense and subject to the same limitations on maximum rates of pay established for employees of the Department of Defense by law or regulation.

(b) Prevailing Rate Systems.—The Secretary of Defense may, consistent with section 5341 of title 5, adopt such provisions of that title as provide for prevailing rate systems of basic pay and may apply those provisions to positions for civilian employees in or under which the Department of Defense may employ individuals described by section 5342(a)(2)(A) of that title.

(Added Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title XVI, § 1632(a)(3), Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2746; amended Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title XI, § 1103(a), Oct. 28, 2004, 118 Stat. 2072; Pub. L. 109–364, div. A, title X, § 1071(g)(12), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2403.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1602 was renumbered section 1621 of this title.
Provisions similar to those in this section were contained in sections 1590(b) and (c) and 1604(b)(1) and (c) of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 104–201, §§ 1632(a)(3), 1633(a).

Amendments2006—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 109–364 made technical correction to directory language of Pub. L. 108–375, § 1103(a)(1). See 2004 Amendment note below.
2004—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 108–375, § 1103(a)(1), as amended by Pub. L. 109–364, substituted “in relation to the rates of pay provided for comparable positions in the Department of Defense and subject to the same limitations on maximum rates of pay established for employees of the Department of Defense by law or regulation” for “in relation to the rates of basic pay provided in subpart D of part III of title 5 for positions subject to that subpart which have corresponding level</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Fix Rates of Basic Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense (subject to the provisions of this section) shall fix the rates of basic pay for positions established under section 1601 of this title in relation to the rates of pay provided for comparable positions in the Department of Defense and subject to the same limitations on maximum rates of pay established for employees of the Department of Defense by law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevailing Rate Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may, consistent with section 5341 of title 5, adopt such provisions of that title as provide for prevailing rate systems of basic pay and may apply those provisions to positions for civilian employees in or under which the Department of Defense may employ individuals described by section 5342(a)(2)(A) of that title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>