<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16132a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16132a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16132a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16132a"><akn:num>16132a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16132a. Authority to transfer unused education benefits to family members(a) In General.—Subject to regulation prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may permit a member described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) a portion of such member’s entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).

(b) Eligible Members.—A member referred to in subsection (a) is a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who, at the time of the approval of the member’s request to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section, has completed—(1) at least six years of service in the Selected Reserve and enters into an agreement to serve at least four more years as a member of the armed forces; or

(2) the years of service as determined in regulations pursuant to subsection (j).


(c) Eligible Dependents.—A member approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the member’s entitlement as follows:(1) To the member’s spouse.

(2) To one or more of the member’s children.

(3) To a combination of the individuals referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2).


(d) Limitation on Months of Transfer.—The total number of months of entitlement transferred by a member under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no less than 18 months.

(e) Designation of Transferee.—A member transferring an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section shall—(1) designate the dependent or dependents to whom such entitlement is being transferred;

(2) designate the number of months of such entitlement to be transferred to each such dependent; and

(3) specify the period for which the transfer shall be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to regulation prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary concerned may permit a member described in subsection (b) who is entitled to basic educational assistance under this chapter to elect to transfer to one or more of the dependents specified in subsection (c) a portion of such member’s entitlement to such assistance, subject to the limitation under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A member referred to in subsection (a) is a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who, at the time of the approval of the member’s request to transfer entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section, has completed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A member approved to transfer an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section may transfer the member’s entitlement as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Months of Transfer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The total number of months of entitlement transferred by a member under this section may not exceed 36 months. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations that would limit the months of entitlement that may be transferred under this section to no less than 18 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Transferee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A member transferring an entitlement to basic educational assistance under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Transfer; Revocation and Modification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of Use.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A dependent to whom entitlement to basic educational assistance is transferred under this section may not commence the use of the transferred entitlement until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Administrative Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overpayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, shall prescribe regulations for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall specify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>