<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16163" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16163/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16163/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16163"><akn:num>16163</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for educational assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16163. Eligibility for educational assistance(a) Eligibility.—On or after September 11, 2001, a member of a reserve component is entitled to educational assistance under this chapter if the member—(1) served on active duty in support of a contingency operation for 90 consecutive days or more; or

(2) in the case of a member of the Army National Guard of the United States or Air National Guard of the United States, performed full time National Guard duty under section 502(f) of title 32 for 90 consecutive days or more when authorized by the President or Secretary of Defense for the purpose of responding to a national emergency declared by the President and supported by Federal funds.


(b) Disabled Members.—Notwithstanding the eligibility requirements in subsection (a), a member who was ordered to active service as prescribed under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) but is released from duty before completing 90 consecutive days because of an injury, illness or disease incurred or aggravated in the line of duty shall be entitled to educational assistance under this chapter at the rate prescribed in section 16162(c)(4)(A) of this title.

(c) Written Notification.—(1) Each member who becomes entitled to educational assistance under subsection (a) shall be given a statement in writing prior to release from active service that summarizes the provisions of this chapter and stating clearly and prominently the substance of section 16165 of this title as such section may apply to the member.

(2) At the request of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary concerned shall transmit a notice of entitlement for each such member to that Secretary.


(d) Bar From Dual Eligibility.—A member who qualifies for educational assistance under this chapter may not receive credit for such service under both the program established by chapter 30 of title 38 and the program established by this chapter but shall make an irrevocable election (in such form and manner as the Secretary of Veter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16163_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) On or after September 11, 2001, a member of a reserve component is entitled to educational assistance under this chapter if the member—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16163_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disabled Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notwithstanding the eligibility requirements in subsection (a), a member who was ordered to active service as prescribed under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) but is released from duty before completing 90 consecutive days because of an injury, illness or disease incurred or aggravated in the line of duty shall be entitled to educational assistance under this chapter at the rate prescribed in section 16162(c)(4)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16163_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16163_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar From Dual Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A member who qualifies for educational assistance under this chapter may not receive credit for such service under both the program established by chapter 30 of title 38 and the program established by this chapter but shall make an irrevocable election (in such form and manner as the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may prescribe) as to the program to which such service is to be credited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16163_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bar From Duplication of Educational Assistance Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>