<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16165" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16165/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16165/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16165"><akn:num>16165</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16165. Termination of assistance(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsection (b), educational assistance may not be provided under this chapter, or if being provided under this chapter, shall be terminated—(1) if the member is receiving financial assistance under section 2107 of this title as a member of the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program; or

(2) when the member separates from the Ready Reserve as provided in section 16164(a)(1) of this title, or upon completion of the period provided for in section 16164(a)(2) of this title, as applicable.


(b) Exception.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, educational assistance may be provided under this chapter to a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who incurs a break in service in the Selected Reserve if the member continues to serve in the Ready Reserve during and after such break in service.

(Added Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title V, § 527(a), Oct. 28, 2004, 118 Stat. 1893; amended Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title V, § 540(b), Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3251; Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title V, § 530(a)(2), (b), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 110.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2008—Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 110–181, § 530(a)(2), amended par. (2) generally. Prior to amendment, par. (2) read as follows: “when the member separates from the Ready Reserve, as provided for under section 16164(a)(1) or section 16164(a)(2), as applicable, of this title.”
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 110–181, § 530(b), struck out “of not more than 90 days” after “in the Selected Reserve”.
2006—Pub. L. 109–163 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a), inserted heading, substituted “Except as provided in subsection (b), educational assistance” for “Educational assistance”, and added subsec. (b).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2008 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 110–181 effective as of Oct. 28, 2004, as if included in the enactment of Pub. L. 108–375 to which such amendment related, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16165_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), educational assistance may not be provided under this chapter, or if being provided under this chapter, shall be terminated—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16165_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, educational assistance may be provided under this chapter to a member of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve who incurs a break in service in the Selected Reserve if the member continues to serve in the Ready Reserve during and after such break in service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>