<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/16201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16201"><akn:num>16201</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance: health-care professionals in reserve components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16201. Financial assistance: health-care professionals in reserve components(a) Establishment of Program.—For the purpose of obtaining adequate numbers of commissioned officers in the reserve components who are qualified in health professions, the Secretary of each military department may establish and maintain a program to provide financial assistance under this chapter to persons engaged in training that leads to a degree in medicine or dentistry or training in a health professions specialty that is critically needed in wartime. Under such a program, the Secretary concerned may agree to pay a financial stipend to persons engaged in health care education and training in return for a commitment to subsequent service in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve.

(b) Medical and Dental School Students.—(1) Under the stipend program under this chapter, the Secretary of the military department concerned may enter into an agreement with a person who—(A) is eligible to be appointed as an officer in a reserve component;

(B) is enrolled or has been accepted for enrollment in an institution in a course of study that results in a degree in medicine or dentistry;

(C) signs an agreement that, unless sooner separated, the person will—(i) complete the educational phase of the program;

(ii) accept a reappointment or redesignation within the person’s reserve component, if tendered, based upon the person’s health profession, following satisfactory completion of the educational and intern programs; and

(iii) participate in a residency program; and


(D) if required by regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, agrees to apply for, if eligible, and accept, if offered, residency training in a health profession skill which has been designated by the Secretary of Defense as a critically needed wartime skill.


(2) Under the agreement—(A) the Secretary of the military department concerned shall agree to pay the participant a stipend, in the amount determined under subsecti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purpose of obtaining adequate numbers of commissioned officers in the reserve components who are qualified in health professions, the Secretary of each military department may establish and maintain a program to provide financial assistance under this chapter to persons engaged in training that leads to a degree in medicine or dentistry or training in a health professions specialty that is critically needed in wartime. Under such a program, the Secretary concerned may agree to pay a financial stipend to persons engaged in health care education and training in return for a commitment to subsequent service in the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical and Dental School Students.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physicians and Dentists in Critical Wartime Specialties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registered Nurses in Critical Specialties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Baccalaureate Students in Nursing or Other Health Professions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental Health Professionals in Critical Wartime Specialties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16201_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Stipend.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The amount of a stipend under an agreement under subsection (b), (c), (d), or (f) shall be the stipend rate in effect for participants in the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship Program under section 2121(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>