<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/172" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/172/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/172/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_172"><akn:num>172</akn:num><akn:heading>Explosive safety board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 172. Explosive safety board(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense, acting through a joint board that includes members selected by the Secretaries of the military departments, composed of military officers designated as the chair and voting members of the board for each military department, and other civilian officers and employees of the Department of Defense, as necessary, shall provide oversight on storage and transportation of supplies of ammunition and components thereof for use of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard, with particular regard to keeping those supplies properly dispersed and stored and to preventing hazardous conditions from arising to endanger life and property inside or outside of storage reservations. When the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint an officer of the Coast Guard to serve as a voting member of the board.

(b) Oversight by Secretaries of the Military Departments.—The Secretaries of the military departments shall provide research, development, test, evaluation, and manufacturing oversight for energetic materials supporting military requirements.

(c) Responsibilities of Chair.—Except as provided in subsection (h), the chair of the explosive safety board shall carry out the following responsibilities:(1) To act as the principal executive representative and advisor of the Secretary on explosive and chemical agent safety matters related to Department of Defense military munitions.

(2) To perform the hazard classification approval duties assigned to the chair.

(3) To preside over meetings of the explosive safety board.

(4) To direct the staff of the explosive safety board.

(5) To perform other functions relating to explosives safety management, as directed by the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Sustainment.

(6) To provide impartial and objective advice related to explosives safety management to the Secretary o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, acting through a joint board that includes members selected by the Secretaries of the military departments, composed of military officers designated as the chair and voting members of the board for each military department, and other civilian officers and employees of the Department of Defense, as necessary, shall provide oversight on storage and transportation of supplies of ammunition and components thereof for use of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, and Coast Guard, with particular regard to keeping those supplies properly dispersed and stored and to preventing hazardous conditions from arising to endanger life and property inside or outside of storage reservations. When the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint an officer of the Coast Guard to serve as a voting member of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight by Secretaries of the Military Departments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretaries of the military departments shall provide research, development, test, evaluation, and manufacturing oversight for energetic materials supporting military requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Chair.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as provided in subsection (h), the chair of the explosive safety board shall carry out the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Executive Director and Civilian Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The executive director and civilian members of the explosive safety board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The explosive safety board shall have exclusive responsibility within the Department of Defense for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Components.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the covered components of the Department are each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_172_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explosives Used by Space Launch Vehicles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>