<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1734" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1734/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1734/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1734"><akn:num>1734</akn:num><akn:heading>Career development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1734. Career development(a) Three-Year Assignment Period.—(1) Except as provided under subsection (b) and paragraph (3), the Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, shall provide that any person who is assigned to a critical acquisition position shall be assigned to the position for not fewer than three years. Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary concerned may not reassign a person from such an assignment before the end of the three-year period.

(2) A person may not be assigned to a critical acquisition position unless the person executes a written agreement to remain on active duty (in the case of a member of the armed forces) or to remain in Federal service (in the case of an employee) in that position for at least three years. The service obligation contained in such a written agreement shall remain in effect unless and until waived by the Secretary concerned under subsection (b).

(3) The assignment period requirement of the first sentence of paragraph (1) is waived for any individual serving as a deputy program manager if the individual is assigned to a critical acquisition position upon completion of the individual’s assignment as a deputy program manager.


(b) Assignment Period for Program Managers.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe in regulations—(A) a requirement that a program manager and a deputy program manager (except as provided in paragraph (3)) of a major defense acquisition program be assigned to the position at least until completion of the major milestone that occurs closest in time to the date on which the person has served in the position for four years; and

(B) a requirement that, to the maximum extent practicable, a program manager who is the replacement for a reassigned program manager arrive at the assignment location before the reassigned program manager leaves.


Except as provided in subsection (d), the Secretary concerned may not reassign </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Three-Year Assignment Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment Period for Program Managers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major Milestone Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Assignment Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rotation Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Centralized Job Referral System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations providing for the use of centralized lists to ensure that persons are selected for critical positions without regard to geographic location of applicants for such positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense shall establish, for purposes of broadening the experience of members of the acquisition workforce, a test program in which members of the acquisition workforce serving in a military department or Defense Agency are assigned or detailed to an acquisition position in another department or agency. Under the test program, the Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, at least 5 percent of the members of the acquisition workforce in critical acquisition positions shall serve in such exchange assignments each year. The test program shall operate for not less than a period of three years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1734_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Assignments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of each military department, acting through the service acquisition executive for that department, is responsible for making assignments of civilian and military personnel of that military department who are members of the acquisition workforce to critical acquisition positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>