<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1746a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1746a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1746a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1746a"><akn:num>1746a</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition workforce educational partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1746a. Acquisition workforce educational partnerships(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish a program within Defense Acquisition University to—(1) facilitate the engagement of relevant experts, including with the acquisition research activities established under section 4142 of this title, with the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University to assess and modify the curriculum of the Defense Acquisition University, as appropriate, to enhance the capabilities of the Defense Acquisition University to support educational, training, and research activities in support of acquisition missions of the Department of Defense;

(2) establish a cross-discipline, peer mentoring program for academic advising and to address critical retention concerns with respect to the acquisition workforce;

(3) partner with extramural institutions and military department functional leadership to offer training and on-the-job learning support to all members of the acquisition workforce addressing operational challenges that affect procurement decisionmaking;

(4) support the partnerships between the Department of Defense and extramural institutions with missions relating to the training and continuous development of members of the acquisition workforce;

(5) accelerate the adoption, appropriate design and customization, and use of flexible acquisition practices by the acquisition workforce by expanding the availability of training and on-the-job learning and guidance on such practices and incorporating such training into the curriculum of the Defense Acquisition University; and

(6) support and enhance the capabilities of the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University, and the currency and applicability of the knowledge possessed by such faculty, by—(A) building partnerships between the faculty of the Defense Acquisition University and the director of, and individuals involved with, the a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, shall establish a program within Defense Acquisition University to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Official.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than 180 days after the enactment of this section, the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall designate a senior official to execute activities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support From Other Department of Defense Organizations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may direct other elements of the Department of Defense to provide personnel, resources, and other support to the program established under this section, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment may use amounts available in the Defense Acquisition Workforce and Development Account (as established under section 1705 of this title) to carry out the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than September 30, 2022, and annually thereafter, the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall submit to the Secretary of Defense and the congressional defense committees a report describing the activities conducted under this section during the one-year period ending on the date on which such report is submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption to Report Termination Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Section 1080(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 (Public Law 114–92; 129 Stat. 1000; 10 U.S.C. 111 note), as amended by section 1061(j) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (Public Law 114–328; 130 Stat. 2405; 10 U.S.C. 111 note), does not apply with respect to the reports required to be submitted to Congress under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1746a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>