<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1749" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1749/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1749/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1749"><akn:num>1749</akn:num><akn:heading>Field training for acquisition and sustainment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1749. Field training for acquisition and sustainment(a) Training Program.—Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall establish a training program that supports cross-functional personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense involved in any phase of the acquisition and sustainment lifecycle in making important decisions with respect to acquisition or sustainment, including requirements validation, the development of an acquisition strategy, awarding contracts, and ongoing management of performance and governance.

(b) Elements.—The training program established under subsection (a) shall—(1) create deployable training teams to coach the cross-functional personnel and contractors described in subsection (a) and facilitate such personnel and contractors successfully completing a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort with the same training team to the maximum extent possible;

(2) to the extent practicable, ensure that the same training team under paragraph (1) provides the support described under such paragraph with respect to a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort until such phase is completed or otherwise ends;

(3) provide to the cross-functional personnel and contractors described in subsection (a) short, intermittent lessons on innovative acquisition and fielding procedures, flexible contracting frameworks, and business negotiation skills that are timed to align the topics of the lessons to relevant activities under a phase of an acquisition or sustainment effort;

(4) emphasizes— 11 So in original. Probably should be “emphasize—”.(A) the acquisition of commercial products, commercial services, and commercially available off-the-shelf items (as such terms are defined in sections 103, 103a, and 104, respectively, of title 41);

(B) technology procured “as-a-service” or as a consumption-based solution (as defined in section 834 of the William M. (Mac) Th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall establish a training program that supports cross-functional personnel and contractors of the Department of Defense involved in any phase of the acquisition and sustainment lifecycle in making important decisions with respect to acquisition or sustainment, including requirements validation, the development of an acquisition strategy, awarding contracts, and ongoing management of performance and governance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The training program established under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Team Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each training team created under the training program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall ensure that each member of the acquisition workforce who participates in the training program established under subsection (a) can meet up to 80 hours of a continuous education requirement established under section 1723 of this title by participating in the training program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) During fiscal year 2025, the Secretary of each military department shall carry out not less than one pilot program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment is authorized to use funds available for the Defense Acquisition University for civilian faculty members, contracts, and associated travel and expenses to carry out the training program established in (a) 33 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “subsection”. starting in fiscal year 2025, and for fiscal years 2027 through fiscal year 2031—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1749_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than November 1, 2026, the Under Secretary for Acquisition and Sustainment shall provide a report to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives on the training program required under subsection (a), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>