<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1784a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1784a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1784a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1784a"><akn:num>1784a</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and training opportunities for military spouses to expand employment and portable career o</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1784a. Education and training opportunities for military spouses to expand employment and portable career opportunities(a) Programs and Tuition Assistance.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may establish programs to assist the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) in achieving—(A) the education and training required for a degree or credential at an accredited college, university, or technical school in the United States that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse; or

(B) the education prerequisites and professional licensure or credential required, by a government or government sanctioned licensing body, for an occupation that expands employment and portable career opportunities for the spouse.


(2) As an alternative to, or in addition to, establishing a program under this subsection, the Secretary may provide tuition assistance to an eligible spouse who is pursuing education, training, or a license or credential to expand the spouse’s employment and portable career opportunities.


(b) Eligible Spouses.—(1) Assistance under this section is limited to a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is serving on active duty.

(2) A spouse who is eligible for a program under this section and begins a course of education or training for a degree, license, or credential described in subsection (a) may not become ineligible to complete such course of education or training solely because the member to whom the spouse is married is promoted to a higher grade.


(c) Exceptions.—Subsection (b) does not include—(1) a person who is married to, but legally separated from, a member of the armed forces under court order or statute of any State or territorial possession of the United States; and

(2) a spouse of a member of the armed forces who is also a member of the armed forces.


(d) Doula and IBCLC Certifications.—In carrying out the programs authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide assistance to the spou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs and Tuition Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Spouses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subsection (b) does not include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Doula and IBCLC Certifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out the programs authorized by subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide assistance to the spouse of a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) with obtaining certification—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portable Career Opportunities Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the term “portable career” includes an occupation identified by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, as requiring education and training that results in a credential that is recognized nationwide by industry or specific businesses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1784a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to govern the availability and use of assistance under this section. The Secretary shall ensure that programs established under this section do not result in inequitable treatment for spouses of members of the armed forces who are also members, since they are excluded from participation in the programs under subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>