<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1789" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1789/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/1789/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1789"><akn:num>1789</akn:num><akn:heading>Chaplain-led programs: authorized support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1789. Chaplain-led programs: authorized support(a) Authority.—The Secretary of a military department may provide support services described in subsection (b) to support a chaplain-led program to assist a covered individual in building and maintaining a strong family structure, or to support the resiliency, suicide prevention, or holistic wellness of such covered individual.

(b) Authorized Support Services.—The support services referred to in subsection (a) are costs of transportation, food, lodging, child care, supplies, fees, and training materials for a covered individual while participating in a program referred to in that subsection, including participation at a retreat or conference.

(c) Covered Individual Defined.—In this section, the term “covered individual” means—(1) a member of the armed forces on active duty;

(2) a member of the reserve components in an active status; or

(3) a dependent of an individual described in paragraph (1) or (2).


(Added Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 582(a)(1), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1489; amended Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title V, § 571(a), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 2600; Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(17), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 684.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2023—Subsec. (c)(3). Pub. L. 118–31 substituted “paragraph (1) or (2)” for “subparagraph (A) or (B)”.
2022—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 117–263, § 571(a)(1), substituted “a chaplain-led program to assist a covered individual” for “chaplain-led programs to assist members of the armed forces on active duty and their immediate family members, and members of reserve components in an active status and their immediate family members,” and inserted “, or to support the resiliency, suicide prevention, or holistic wellness of such covered individual” after “structure”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 117–263, § 571(a)(2), substituted “a covered individual” for “members of the armed forces and their family members”, “a program” for “programs”, and “a retreat or conferen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1789_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of a military department may provide support services described in subsection (b) to support a chaplain-led program to assist a covered individual in building and maintaining a strong family structure, or to support the resiliency, suicide prevention, or holistic wellness of such covered individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1789_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Support Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The support services referred to in subsection (a) are costs of transportation, food, lodging, child care, supplies, fees, and training materials for a covered individual while participating in a program referred to in that subsection, including participation at a retreat or conference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1789_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Individual Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section, the term “covered individual” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>