<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/181" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/181/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/181/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_181"><akn:num>181</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Requirements Oversight Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 181. Joint Requirements Oversight Council(a) In General.—There is a Joint Requirements Oversight Council in the Department of Defense.

(b) Mission.—In addition to other matters assigned to it by the President or Secretary of Defense, the Joint Requirements Oversight Council shall assist the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in—(1) assessing joint military capabilities, and identifying, approving, and prioritizing gaps in such capabilities, to meet applicable requirements in the national defense strategy under section 113(g) of this title;

(2) increasing awareness of global trends, threats, and adversary capabilities to address gaps in joint military capabilities and validate joint requirements developed by the military departments;

(3) reviewing and validating whether a capability proposed by an armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department of Defense fulfills a gap in joint military capabilities;

(4) establishing and approving joint performance requirements that—(A) ensure interoperability, where appropriate, between and among joint military capabilities; and

(B) are necessary, as designated by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, to fulfill capability gaps of more than one armed force, Defense Agency, or other entity of the Department;


(5) reviewing performance requirements for any existing or proposed capability that the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff determines should be reviewed by the Council;

(6) identifying new joint military capabilities based on advances in technology and concepts of operation; and

(7) identifying alternatives to any acquisition program that meets approved joint military capability requirements for the purposes of sections 4251(b), 4252(a)(4), and 4375(b) of this title.


(c) Composition.—(1) In general.—The Joint Requirements Oversight Council is composed of the following:(A) The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, who is the Chair of the Council and is the principal adviser to the Chai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is a Joint Requirements Oversight Council in the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In addition to other matters assigned to it by the President or Secretary of Defense, the Joint Requirements Oversight Council shall assist the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Requirements as Responsibility of Armed Forces.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Chief of Staff of an armed force is responsible for all performance requirements for that armed force and, except for performance requirements specified in subsections (b)(4) and (b)(5), such performance requirements do not need to be validated by the Joint Requirements Oversight Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analytic Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that analytical organizations within the Department of Defense, such as the Office of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, provide resources and expertise in operations research, systems analysis, and cost estimation to the Joint Requirements Oversight Council to assist the Council in performing the mission in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Oversight Information to Congressional Defense Committees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that, in the case of a recommendation by the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to the Secretary that is approved by the Secretary, oversight information with respect to such recommendation that is produced as a result of the activities of the Joint Requirements Oversight Council is made available in a timely fashion to the congressional defense committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_181_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>