<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18233a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18233a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18233a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18233a"><akn:num>18233a</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and wait requirements for certain projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18233a. Notice and wait requirements for certain projects(a) Congressional Notification.—Except as provided in subsection (b), an expenditure or contribution in excess of the amount specified in section 2805(b)(1) of this title may not be made under section 18233 of this title for any facility until—(1) the Secretary of Defense has notified the congressional defense committees of the location, nature, and estimated cost of the facility; and

(2) a period of 21 days has elapsed after the notification has been received by those committees or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed after the date on which a copy of the notification is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title.


(b) Certain Expenditures or Contributions Exempted.—Subsection (a) does not apply to expenditures or contributions for the following:(1) Facilities acquired by lease.

(2) A project for a facility that has been authorized by Congress, if the location and purpose of the facility are the same as when authorized and if, based upon bids received—(A) the scope of work of the project, as approved by Congress, is not proposed to be reduced by more than 25 percent; and

(B) the current working estimate of the cost of the project does not exceed the amount approved for the project by more than the lesser of the following:(i) 25 percent.

(ii) 200 percent of the amount specified by section 2805(a) of this title as the maximum amount for a minor military construction project.



(3) A repair project (as that term is defined in subsection (e) of section 2811 of this title) that costs less than the amount specified in subsection (d) of such section.


(Added Pub. L. 85–685, title VI, § 601(3), Aug. 20, 1958, 72 Stat. 665, § 2233a; amended Pub. L. 87–554, title VII, § 701, July 27, 1962, 76 Stat. 243; Pub. L. 93–552, title VII, § 703, Dec. 27, 1974, 88 Stat. 1770; Pub. L. 94–107, title VII, § 703, Oct. 7, 1975, 89 Stat. 569; Pub. L. 96–125, title VII, § 704, Nov. 26, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18233a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), an expenditure or contribution in excess of the amount specified in section 2805(b)(1) of this title may not be made under section 18233 of this title for any facility until—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18233a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Expenditures or Contributions Exempted.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subsection (a) does not apply to expenditures or contributions for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>