<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18240" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18240/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/18240/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18240"><akn:num>18240</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of facilities by exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18240. Acquisition of facilities by exchange(a) Exchange Authority.—In addition to the acquisition authority provided by section 18233 of this title, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of a military department to acquire a facility, or addition to an existing facility, needed to satisfy military requirements for a reserve component by carrying out an exchange of an existing facility under the control of that Secretary through an agreement with an Executive agency (as defined in section 105 of title 5), the United States Postal Service, or a State, local government, local authority, or private entity. The acquisition of a facility or an addition to an existing facility under this section may include the acquisition of utilities, equipment, and furnishings for the facility.

(b) Facilities Eligible for Exchange.—Only a facility of a reserve component that is not excess property (as defined in section 102(3) of title 40) may be exchanged using the authority provided by this section.

(c) Equal Value Exchange.—In any exchange carried out using the authority provided by this section, the value of the replacement facility, or addition to an existing facility, including any utilities, equipment, and furnishings, to be acquired by the United States shall be at least equal to the fair market value of the facility conveyed by the United States under the agreement. If the values are unequal, the values may not be equalized by any payment of cash consideration by either party to the agreement.

(d) Requirements for Replacement Facilities.—The Secretary of a military department may not accept a replacement facility, or addition to an existing facility, to be acquired by the United States in an exchange carried out using the authority provided by this section until that Secretary determines that the facility or addition—(1) is complete and usable, fully functional, and ready for occupancy;

(2) satisfies all operational requirements; and

(3) meets all applica</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In addition to the acquisition authority provided by section 18233 of this title, the Secretary of Defense may authorize the Secretary of a military department to acquire a facility, or addition to an existing facility, needed to satisfy military requirements for a reserve component by carrying out an exchange of an existing facility under the control of that Secretary through an agreement with an Executive agency (as defined in section 105 of title 5), the United States Postal Service, or a State, local government, local authority, or private entity. The acquisition of a facility or an addition to an existing facility under this section may include the acquisition of utilities, equipment, and furnishings for the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities Eligible for Exchange.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Only a facility of a reserve component that is not excess property (as defined in section 102(3) of title 40) may be exchanged using the authority provided by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal Value Exchange.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In any exchange carried out using the authority provided by this section, the value of the replacement facility, or addition to an existing facility, including any utilities, equipment, and furnishings, to be acquired by the United States shall be at least equal to the fair market value of the facility conveyed by the United States under the agreement. If the values are unequal, the values may not be equalized by any payment of cash consideration by either party to the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Replacement Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of a military department may not accept a replacement facility, or addition to an existing facility, to be acquired by the United States in an exchange carried out using the authority provided by this section until that Secretary determines that the facility or addition—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of a military department authorized to enter into an agreement under subsection (a) to convey an existing facility under the control of that Secretary by exchange shall consult with representatives of other reserve components to evaluate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance Notice of Proposed Exchange.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18240_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Other Military Construction Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The acquisition of a facility, or an addition to an existing facility, using the authority provided by this section shall not be treated as a military construction project for which an authorization is required by section 2802 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>