<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/183a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/183a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/183a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_183a"><akn:num>183a</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Clearinghouse for review of mission obstructions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 183a. Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Clearinghouse for review of mission obstructions(a) Establishment.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Military Aviation and Installation Assurance Siting Clearinghouse (in this section referred to as the “Clearinghouse”).

(2) The Clearinghouse shall be—(A) organized under the authority, direction, and control of an Assistant Secretary of Defense designated by the Secretary; and

(B) assigned such personnel and resources as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.



(b) Functions.—(1) The Clearinghouse shall coordinate Department of Defense review of applications for energy projects or antenna structure projects filed with the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to section 44718 of title 49 and received by the Department of Defense from the Secretary of Transportation. In performing such coordination, the Clearinghouse shall provide procedures to ensure affected local military installations are consulted.

(2) The Clearinghouse shall accelerate the development of planning tools necessary to determine the acceptability to the Department of Defense of proposals included in an application for an energy project or antenna structure project submitted pursuant to such section.

(3) The Clearinghouse shall perform such other functions as the Secretary of Defense assigns.


(c) Review of Proposed Actions.—(1) Not later than 75 days after receiving from the Secretary of Transportation a proper application for an energy project or antenna structure project under section 44718 of title 49 that may have an adverse impact on military operations and readiness, the Clearinghouse shall conduct a preliminary review of such application. The review shall—(A) assess the likely scope, duration, and level of risk of any adverse impact of such energy project or antenna structure project on military operations and readiness; and

(B) identify any feasible and affordable actions that could be taken by t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of Proposed Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense Finding of Unacceptable Risk.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Accept Contributions of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense is authorized to request and accept a voluntary contribution of funds from an applicant for an energy project or antenna structure project. Amounts so accepted shall remain available until expended for the purpose of offsetting the cost of measures undertaken by the Secretary of Defense to mitigate adverse impacts of such a project on military operations and readiness or to conduct studies of potential measures to mitigate such impacts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Department of Defense Hazard Assessment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An action taken pursuant to this section shall not be considered to be a substitute for any assessment or determination required of the Secretary of Transportation under section 44718 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_183a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>