<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/185" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/185/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/185/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_185"><akn:num>185</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint Safety Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 185. Joint Safety Council(a) In General.—There is established, within the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense, a Joint Safety Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).

(b) Membership; Appointment; Compensation.—(1) The Council shall be composed of voting members as follows:(A) The Director of Safety for each military department.

(B) An employee of the Department of Defense who is a career member of the Senior Executive Service and has a demonstrated record of success in the implementation of programs within the Department of Defense (as determined by the Deputy Secretary of Defense), appointed by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.

(C) One member of the armed forces or civilian employee from each military department, appointed by the Secretary concerned.

(D) During periods in which the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy, an officer of the Coast Guard, appointed by the Secretary of Homeland Security.

(E) Such additional members as may be determined by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.


(2)(A) Each member of the Council shall serve at the will of the official who appointed that member.

(B) Any vacancy on the Council shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment.


(3) Members of the Council may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Council.


(c) Chairperson and Vice Chairperson.—(1)(A) The Secretary of Defense, or the designee of the Secretary, shall select one of the members of the Council who is a member of the armed forces to serve as the Chairperson of the Council.

(B) The Chairperson shall serve for a term of two years and shall be responsible for—(i) serving as the Director of Safety for the Department of Defense;

(ii) serving as principal advisor to the Secretary of Defense regarding military safety and related regulations and policy reforms, including issues regarding maintenance, supply chains, personnel management, and training;

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established, within the Office of the Deputy Secretary of Defense, a Joint Safety Council (in this section referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; Appointment; Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson and Vice Chairperson.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Council shall carry out the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The decisions and recommendations of the Council are subject to review and approval by the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Council may enter into contracts for the acquisition of administrative supplies, equipment, and personnel services for use by the Council, to the extent that funds are available for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of Temporary and Intermittent Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Chairperson may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5 at rates for individuals which do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data Collection.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_185_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Council shall meet quarterly and at the call of the Chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>