<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2005"><akn:num>2005</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced education assistance: active duty agreement; reimbursement requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2005. Advanced education assistance: active duty agreement; reimbursement requirements(a) The Secretary concerned may require, as a condition to the Secretary providing advanced education assistance to any person, that such person enter into a written agreement with the Secretary concerned under the terms of which such person shall agree—(1) to complete the educational requirements specified in the agreement and to serve on active duty for a period specified in the agreement;

(2) that if such person fails to complete the education requirements specified in the agreement, such person will serve on active duty for a period specified in the agreement;

(3) that if such person does not complete the period of active duty specified in the agreement, or does not fulfill any term or condition prescribed pursuant to paragraph (4), such person shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37; and

(4) to such other terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned may prescribe to protect the interest of the United States.


(b) The Secretary concerned shall determine the period of active duty to be served by any person for advanced education assistance to be provided such person by an armed force, except that if the period of active duty required to be served is specified under another provision of law with respect to the advanced education assistance to be provided, the period specified in the agreement referred to in subsection (a) shall be the same as the period specified in such other provision of law.

(c) As a condition of the Secretary concerned providing financial assistance under section 2107 or 2107a of this title to any person, the Secretary concerned shall require that the person enter into the agreement described in subsection (a). In addition to the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4) of such subsection, the agreement shall specify that, if the person does not complete the education requirements specified in the agreeme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may require, as a condition to the Secretary providing advanced education assistance to any person, that such person enter into a written agreement with the Secretary concerned under the terms of which such person shall agree—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall determine the period of active duty to be served by any person for advanced education assistance to be provided such person by an armed force, except that if the period of active duty required to be served is specified under another provision of law with respect to the advanced education assistance to be provided, the period specified in the agreement referred to in subsection (a) shall be the same as the period specified in such other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) As a condition of the Secretary concerned providing financial assistance under section 2107 or 2107a of this title to any person, the Secretary concerned shall require that the person enter into the agreement described in subsection (a). In addition to the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (4) of such subsection, the agreement shall specify that, if the person does not complete the education requirements specified in the agreement or does not fulfill any term or condition prescribed pursuant to paragraph (4) of such subsection, the person shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37 without the Secretary first ordering such person to active duty as provided for under subsection (a)(2) and sections 2107(f) and 2107a(f) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>