<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2006a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2006a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2006a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2006a"><akn:num>2006a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for education and training: availability of certain assistance for use only for certain p</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2006a. Assistance for education and training: availability of certain assistance for use only for certain programs of education(a) In General.—Effective as of August 1, 2014, an individual eligible for assistance under a Department of Defense educational assistance program or authority covered by this section may, except as provided in subsection (b), only use such assistance for educational expenses incurred for a program as follows:(1) An eligible program (as defined in section 481 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1088)) that is offered by an institution of higher education that has entered into, and is complying with, a program participation agreement under section 487 of such Act (20 U.S.C. 1094).

(2) In the case of a program designed to prepare individuals for licensure or certification in any State, if the program meets the instructional curriculum licensure or certification requirements of such State.

(3) In the case of a program designed to prepare individuals for employment pursuant to standards developed by a State board or agency in an occupation that requires approval or licensure for such employment, if the program is approved or licensed by such State board or agency.


(b) Waiver.—The Secretary of Defense may, by regulation, authorize the use of educational assistance under a Department of Defense educational assistance program or authority covered by this chapter for educational expenses incurred for a program of education that is not described in subsection (a) if the program—(1) is accredited and approved by a nationally or regionally recognized accrediting agency or association recognized by the Department of Education;

(2) was not an eligible program described in subsection (a) at any time during the most recent two-year period;

(3) is a program that the Secretary determines would further the purposes of the educational assistance programs or authorities covered by this chapter, or would further the education interests of stud</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Effective as of August 1, 2014, an individual eligible for assistance under a Department of Defense educational assistance program or authority covered by this section may, except as provided in subsection (b), only use such assistance for educational expenses incurred for a program as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may, by regulation, authorize the use of educational assistance under a Department of Defense educational assistance program or authority covered by this chapter for educational expenses incurred for a program of education that is not described in subsection (a) if the program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2006a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>