<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2007"><akn:num>2007</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of tuition for off-duty training or education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2007. Payment of tuition for off-duty training or education(a) Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary concerned may pay all or a portion of the charges of an educational institution for the tuition or expenses of a member of the armed forces enrolled in such educational institution for education or training during the member’s off-duty periods.

(b)(1) In the case of a commissioned officer on active duty (other than a member of the Ready Reserve), the Secretary concerned may not pay charges under subsection (a) unless the officer agrees to remain on active duty for a period of at least two years after the completion of the training or education for which the charges are paid.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned may reduce or waive the active duty service obligation—(A) in the case of a commissioned officer who is subject to mandatory separation;

(B) in the case of a commissioned officer who has completed the period of active duty service for which the officer was ordered to active duty in support of a contingency operation; or

(C) in other exigent circumstances as determined by the Secretary concerned.



(c)(1) Subject to paragraphs (3) and (5), the Secretary concerned may pay the charges of an educational institution for the tuition or expenses described in subsection (a) of a member of the Selected Reserve.

(2) Subject to paragraphs (4) and (5), the Secretary concerned may pay the charges of an educational institution for the tuition or expenses described in subsection (a) of a member of the Individual Ready Reserve who has a military occupational specialty designated by the Secretary concerned for purposes of this subsection.

(3) The Secretary concerned may not pay charges under paragraph (1) for tuition or expenses of an officer of the Selected Reserve unless the officer enters into an agreement to remain a member of the Selected Reserve for at least 4 years after completion of the education or training for which the cha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary concerned may pay all or a portion of the charges of an educational institution for the tuition or expenses of a member of the armed forces enrolled in such educational institution for education or training during the member’s off-duty periods.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) This section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of Homeland Security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2007_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The provisions of this section pertaining to members of the Ready Reserve, the Selected Reserve, or the Individual Ready Reserve also apply to members of the Space Force in a space force active status who are not on active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>