<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20105"><akn:num>20105</akn:num><akn:heading>Sustained duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20105. Sustained duty(a) Enlisted Members.—An authority designated by the Secretary of the Air Force may order an enlisted member of the Space Force in a space force active status to sustained duty, or retain an enlisted member on sustained duty, with the consent of that member, as specified in the terms of the member’s enlistment or reenlistment agreement.

(b) Officers.—(1) An authority designated by the Secretary of the Air Force may order a Space Force officer in a space force active status to sustained duty—(A) with the consent of the officer; or

(B) to fulfill the terms of an active-duty service commitment incurred by the officer under any provision of law.


(2) An officer ordered to sustained duty under paragraph (1) may not be released from sustained duty without the officer’s consent except as provided in chapter 2009 or 2011 of this title.


(Added Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title XVII, § 1715, Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 629.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enlisted Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An authority designated by the Secretary of the Air Force may order an enlisted member of the Space Force in a space force active status to sustained duty, or retain an enlisted member on sustained duty, with the consent of that member, as specified in the terms of the member’s enlistment or reenlistment agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>