<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2012" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2012/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2012/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2012"><akn:num>2012</akn:num><akn:heading>Support and services for eligible organizations and activities outside Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2012. Support and services for eligible organizations and activities outside Department of Defense(a) Authority To Provide Services and Support.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may in accordance with this section authorize units or individual members of the armed forces under that Secretary’s jurisdiction to provide support and services to non-Department of Defense organizations and activities specified in subsection (e), but only if—(1) such assistance is authorized by a provision of law (other than this section); or

(2) the provision of such assistance is incidental to military training.


(b) Scope of Covered Activities Subject to Section.—This section does not—(1) apply to the provision by the Secretary concerned, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, of customary community relations and public affairs activities conducted in accordance with Department of Defense policy; or

(2) prohibit the Secretary concerned from encouraging members of the armed forces under the Secretary’s jurisdiction to provide volunteer support for community relations activities under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.


(c) Requirement for Specific Request.—Assistance under subsection (a) may only be provided if—(1) the assistance is requested by a responsible official of the organization to which the assistance is to be provided; and

(2) the assistance is not reasonably available from a commercial entity or (if so available) the official submitting the request for assistance certifies that the commercial entity that would otherwise provide such services has agreed to the provision of such services by the armed forces.


(d) Relationship to Military Training.—(1) Assistance under subsection (a) may only be provided if the following requirements are met:(A) The provision of such assistance—(i) in the case of assistance by a unit, will accomplish valid unit training requirements; and

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Provide Services and Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of a military department may in accordance with this section authorize units or individual members of the armed forces under that Secretary’s jurisdiction to provide support and services to non-Department of Defense organizations and activities specified in subsection (e), but only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Covered Activities Subject to Section.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section does not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Specific Request.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance under subsection (a) may only be provided if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Military Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The following organizations and activities are eligible for assistance under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the provision of assistance under this section. The regulations shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Member’s Participation in Provision of Support or Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Councils.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of Provision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2012_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight and Cost Accounting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to improve the oversight and cost accounting of training projects conducted in accordance with this section. The program shall include measures to accomplish the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>