<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20203"><akn:num>20203</akn:num><akn:heading>Original appointments: service credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20203. Original appointments: service credit(a) In General.—The provisions of section 533 of this title shall apply to the crediting of prior active commissioned service for original appointments of commissioned officers.

(b) Credit for Prior Service.—(1) For the purpose of determining the grade and rank within grade of a person receiving an original appointment in a commissioned grade in the Space Force, such person shall be credited at the time of such appointment with any commissioned service (other than service as a commissioned warrant officer) that the person performed before such appointment—(A) as a Space Force officer on active duty or in a space force active status; or

(B) as a regular officer, or as a reserve officer in an active status, in any uniformed service.


(2) The regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under section 533 of this title shall apply to the Space Force to authorize the Secretary of the Air Force to limit the amount of prior active commissioned service with which a person receiving an original appointment may be credited under paragraph (1).


(b) Credit for Education, Training, and Experience.—(1) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, the Secretary shall credit a person who is receiving an original appointment in a commissioned grade in the Space Force and who has advanced education, training, or special experience with constructive service for such education, training, or experience in a particular officer career field as designated by the Secretary of the Air Force, if such education, training, or experience is directly related to the operational needs of the Space Force.

(2)(A) The Secretary may credit a person with constructive service under this subsection for each instance of relevant advanced education or training or special experience regardless of whether two or more such instances are concurrent.

(B) The Secretary may not credit more than 20 persons with an amount of constructive c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The provisions of section 533 of this title shall apply to the crediting of prior active commissioned service for original appointments of commissioned officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for Prior Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit for Education, Training, and Experience.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Use of Constructive Credit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Constructive service credited an officer under subsection (b) shall be used only for determining the officer’s—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion for Graduates of the Service Academies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A graduate of a Service Academy (as such term is defined in section 347 of this title) is not entitled to service credit under this section for service performed, or education, training, or experience obtained, before graduation from such Service Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A reserve officer (other than a warrant officer) who receives an original appointment as an officer in the Space Force shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20203_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuity of Existing Delegation of Presidential Appointment Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Except as otherwise provided by the President by Executive order, the provisions of Executive Order 13384 (10 U.S.C. 531 note) relating to the functions of the President under section 531(a) of this title shall apply in the same manner to functions of the President under section 20201 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>