<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20215" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20215/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20215/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20215"><akn:num>20215</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations for promotion by selection boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20215. Recommendations for promotion by selection boards(a) Board to Recommend Officers Best Qualified for Promotion.—A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title shall recommend for promotion to the next higher grade those officers considered by the board whom the board, giving due consideration to the needs of the Space Force for officers with particular skills (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under section 615(b) of this title), considers best qualified for promotion within each competitive category considered by the board.

(b) Number to Be Recommended.—The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish the number of officers such a selection board may recommend for promotion from among officers being considered.

(c) Board Procedures for Recommendations; Limitations.—A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title may not recommend an officer for promotion unless—(1) the officer receives the recommendation of a majority of the members of the board;

(2) a majority of the members of the board finds that the officer is fully qualified for promotion; and

(3) a majority of the members of the board, after consideration by all members of the board of any adverse information about the officer that is provided to the board under section 615 of this title, finds that the officer is among the officers best qualified for promotion to meet the needs of the Space Force consistent with the requirement of exemplary conduct set forth in section 9233 of this title.


(d) Limitation on Promotions Under Other Authority.—Except as otherwise provided by law, a Space Force officer may not be promoted to a higher grade under this chapter unless the officer is considered and recommended for promotion to that grade by a selection board convened under this chapter or, in the case of an officer transferring into the Space Force from another armed force, chapter 36 or chapter 1403 of this title.

(e) Disclosure of Board Recommendat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board to Recommend Officers Best Qualified for Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title shall recommend for promotion to the next higher grade those officers considered by the board whom the board, giving due consideration to the needs of the Space Force for officers with particular skills (as noted in the guidelines or information furnished the board under section 615(b) of this title), considers best qualified for promotion within each competitive category considered by the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number to Be Recommended.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Air Force shall establish the number of officers such a selection board may recommend for promotion from among officers being considered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board Procedures for Recommendations; Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title may not recommend an officer for promotion unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Promotions Under Other Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Except as otherwise provided by law, a Space Force officer may not be promoted to a higher grade under this chapter unless the officer is considered and recommended for promotion to that grade by a selection board convened under this chapter or, in the case of an officer transferring into the Space Force from another armed force, chapter 36 or chapter 1403 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of Board Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The recommendations of a selection board may be disclosed only in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. Those recommendations may not be disclosed to a person not a member of the board (or a member of the administrative staff designated by the Secretary of the Air Force to assist the board) until the written report of the recommendations of the board, required by section 617 of this title, is signed by each member of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Attempting to Influence Members of a Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of the Air Force, and an officer or other official exercising authority over any member of a selection board, may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20215_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Higher Placement on Promotion List of Officer of Particular Merit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>