<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20231"><akn:num>20231</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for consideration for promotion: general rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20231. Eligibility for consideration for promotion: general rules(a) In General.—(1) Requirement to be on space force officer list.—An officer is eligible under this chapter for consideration for promotion by a selection board convened under section 14101(a) of this title only if the officer is on the Space Force officer list.

(2) Authority to preclude from consideration certain officers based on time of entry on or departure from sustained duty.—The Secretary of the Air Force—(A) may, by regulation, prescribe a period of time, not to exceed one year, from the time an officer on the Space Force officer list transfers on or off of sustained duty during which the officer shall be ineligible for consideration for promotion; and

(B) may, by regulation, provide for the exclusion from consideration for promotion by a selection board of an officer otherwise eligible to be considered by the board who has an established date for removal from the Space Force officer list that is not more than 90 days after the date on which the board is to be convened.



(b) Certain Officers Not to Be Considered.—A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title may not consider for promotion to the next higher grade any of the following officers:(1) An officer whose name is on a promotion list for that grade as a result of recommendation for promotion to that grade by an earlier selection board convened under that section or section 20151 of this title, under section 14101 or 14502 of this title, or under chapter 36 of this title.

(2) An officer who is recommended for promotion to that grade in the report of an earlier selection board convened under a provision referred to in paragraph (1), in the case of such a report that has not yet been approved by the President.

(3) An officer who has been nominated by the President for promotion to that grade under any other provision of law, if that nomination is pending before the Senate.

(4) An officer in the grade of first lieute</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Officers Not to Be Considered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A selection board convened under section 20211 of this title may not consider for promotion to the next higher grade any of the following officers:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Colonels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brigadier Generals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers on Educational Delay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) An officer on the Space Force officer list is ineligible for consideration for promotion, but shall remain on the Space Force officer list, while the officer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20231_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain Officers Not to Be Considered for Selection for Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of the Air Force may provide that an officer who is in a space force active status, but is in a duty status in which the only points the officer accrues under section 12732(a)(2) of this title are pursuant to subparagraph (C)(i) of that section, shall not be considered for selection for promotion until completion of two years of service in such duty status. Any such officer may remain on the Space Force officer list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>