<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20252" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20252/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20252/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20252"><akn:num>20252</akn:num><akn:heading>Special selection boards; correction of errors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20252. Special selection boards; correction of errors(a) Persons Not Considered by Promotion Board Because of Administrative Error.—(1) Convening of board.—In the case of an officer or former officer who the Secretary of the Air Force determines was not considered for selection for promotion by a selection board convened under section 20211 of this title because of administrative error, the Secretary shall convene a special selection board under this subsection to determine whether that officer or former officer should be recommended for promotion.

(2) Board composition; oath.—Any such board shall be convened under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense and shall be appointed and composed in accordance with section 20212 of this title and shall include the representation of competitive categories required by that section. The members of a board convened under this subsection shall be required to take an oath in the same manner as prescribed in section 14103 of this title.

(3) Record considered by board.—A special selection board convened under paragraph (1) shall consider the record of the officer or former officer as that record would have appeared to the selection board that should have considered the officer or former officer. That record shall be compared with a sampling of the records of those officers of the same grade and competitive category who were recommended for promotion, and those officers of the same grade and competitive category who were not recommended for promotion, by that board.

(4) Effect.—If a special selection board convened under paragraph (1) does not recommend for promotion an officer or former officer in a grade below the grade of colonel whose name was referred to it for consideration, the officer or former officer shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.


(b) Officers Considered but Not Selected; Material Error.—(1) Convening of board.—In the case of an officer or former officer who was eligible f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Not Considered by Promotion Board Because of Administrative Error.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers Considered but Not Selected; Material Error.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each special selection board convened under this section shall submit to the Secretary of the Air Force a written report, signed by each member of the board, containing the name of each officer or former officer it recommends for promotion and certifying that the board has carefully considered the record of each officer or former officer whose name was referred to it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The provisions of sections 20215 and 20216 of this title apply to the report and proceedings of a special selection board convened under this section in the same manner as they apply to the report and proceedings of a selection board convened under section 20211 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Officers Recommended for Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescribing of Circumstances for Consideration by Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense may prescribe by regulation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convening of Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A board convened under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of Other Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No official or court of the United States shall have power or jurisdiction—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20252_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary of the Air Force may designate a promotion board convened under section 20201(a) of this title as a special selection board convened under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>