<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2031" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2031/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2031/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2031"><akn:num>2031</akn:num><akn:heading>Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2031. Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps(a)(1) The Secretary of each military department shall establish and maintain a Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, organized into units, at public and private secondary educational institutions, including Job Corps centers as defined in section 147 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. 3197), which apply for a unit and meet the standards and criteria prescribed pursuant to this section. The Secretary of Defense shall promulgate regulations prescribing the standards and criteria to be followed by the military departments in selecting the institutions at which units are to be established and maintained.

(2) It is a purpose of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps to instill in students in United States secondary educational institutions the values of citizenship, service to the United States (including an introduction to service opportunities in military, national, and public service), and personal responsibility and a sense of accomplishment.


(b)(1) No unit may be established or maintained at an institution unless—(A) the number of physically fit students in such unit who are in a grade above the 7th grade and physically co-located with the 9th grade participating unit and are citizens or nationals of the United States, or aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence, is—(i) in the case of an educational institution with fewer than 1,000 enrolled students, the lesser of—(I) 10 percent of the number of such students who are in a grade above the 7th grade and physically co-located with the 9th grade participating unit; and

(II) 50; or


(ii) in the case of an educational institution with 1,000 or more enrolled students—(I) 50; or

(II) a number, determined by the Secretary of the military department concerned, that is higher than 50 and not more than 100;



(B) the institution has adequate facilities for classroom instruction, storage of arms and other equipmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the military department concerned shall, to support the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No unit may be established or maintained at an educational institution that is owned, operated, or controlled by a person that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2031_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>