<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/20502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20502"><akn:num>20502</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20502. Retention boards(a) Convening of Boards to Consider Officers Required to Show Cause.—The Secretary of the Air Force shall convene retention boards at such times and places as the Secretary may prescribe to receive evidence and make findings and recommendations as to whether an officer who is required under section 20501 of this title to show cause for retention in a space force active status should be retained in a space force active status. Each retention board shall be composed of not less than three officers having the qualifications prescribed by section 20506 of this title.

(b) Fair and Impartial Hearing.—A retention board shall give a fair and impartial hearing to each officer required under section 20501 of this title to show cause for retention in a space force active status.

(c) Effect of Board Determination That an Officer Has Failed to Establish That the Officer Should Be Retained.—(1) If a retention board determines that the officer has failed to establish that the officer should be retained in a space force active status, the board shall recommend to the Secretary of the Air Force one of the following:(A) That the officer be transferred to an inactive status.

(B) That the officer, if qualified under any provision of law, be retired.

(C) That the officer be discharged from the Space Force.


(2) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force, an officer as to whom a retention board makes a recommendation under paragraph (1) that the officer not be retained in a space force active status may be required to take leave pending the completion of the officer’s case under this chapter. The officer may be required to begin such leave at any time following the officer’s receipt of the report of the retention board, including the board’s recommendation for removal from a space force active status, and the expiration of any period allowed for submission by the officer of a rebuttal to that report. The leave may be continued until the d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convening of Boards to Consider Officers Required to Show Cause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Air Force shall convene retention boards at such times and places as the Secretary may prescribe to receive evidence and make findings and recommendations as to whether an officer who is required under section 20501 of this title to show cause for retention in a space force active status should be retained in a space force active status. Each retention board shall be composed of not less than three officers having the qualifications prescribed by section 20506 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fair and Impartial Hearing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A retention board shall give a fair and impartial hearing to each officer required under section 20501 of this title to show cause for retention in a space force active status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Board Determination That an Officer Has Failed to Establish That the Officer Should Be Retained.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Board Determination That an Officer Has Established That the Officer Should Be Retained.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>