<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2107a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2107a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2107a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2107a"><akn:num>2107a</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance program for specially selected members: Army Reserve and Army National Guard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2107a. Financial assistance program for specially selected members: Army Reserve and Army National Guard(a)(1) The Secretary of the Army may appoint as a cadet in the Army Reserve or Army National Guard of the United States any eligible member of the program who is enrolled in the Advanced Course of the Army Reserve Officers’ Training Corps at a military college, military junior college, or civilian institution and who will be under 31 years of age on December 31 of the calendar year in which he is eligible under this section for appointment as a second lieutenant in the Army Reserve or Army National Guard.

(2) To be considered a military college or military junior college for the purposes of this section, a school must be a civilian postsecondary educational institution essentially military in nature and meet such other requirements as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe. For purposes of this section, a military junior college does not confer a baccalaureate degree.


(b)(1) To be eligible for appointment as a cadet under this section, a member of the program must—(A) be a citizen or national of the United States;

(B) be specially selected for the financial assistance program under this section under procedures prescribed by the Secretary of the Army;

(C) enlist in a reserve component of the Army for the period prescribed by the Secretary of the Army;

(D) contract, with the consent of his parent or guardian if he is a minor, with the Secretary of the Army to serve for the period required by the program;

(E) agree in writing that he will accept an appointment, if offered, as a commissioned officer in the Army Reserve or the Army National Guard of the United States; and

(F) agree in writing that he will serve in a troop program unit of the Army Reserve or Army National Guard for not less than eight years.


(2) Performance of duty under an agreement under this subsection shall be under such terms and conditions as the Secretary of the Army may prescribe a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Upon satisfactorily completing the academic and military requirements of the program, a cadet may be appointed as a reserve officer in the Army in the grade of second lieutenant, even though he is under 21 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The date of rank of officers appointed under this section in May or June of any year is the date of graduation of cadets from the United States Military Academy in that year. The Secretary of the Army shall establish the date of rank of all other officers appointed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A cadet who does not complete the course of instruction, or who completes the course but declines to accept a commission when offered, or who does not complete a baccalaureate degree within five years after appointment as a cadet under this section, may be ordered to active duty by the Secretary of the Army to serve in his enlisted grade for such period of time as the Secretary prescribes but not for more than four years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In computing length of service for any purpose, an officer appointed under this section may not be credited with service as a cadet or with concurrent enlisted service, other than enlisted service performed after August 1, 1979, as a member of the Selected Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of the Army shall appoint each year under this section not less than 22 cadets at each military junior college at which there are not less than 22 members of the program eligible under subsection (b) for such an appointment. At any military junior college at which in any year there are fewer than 22 such members, the Secretary shall appoint each such member as a cadet under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cadets appointed under this section are in addition to the number appointed under section 2107 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2107a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Financial assistance provided under this section to a cadet appointed at a military junior college is designated as, and shall be known as, an “Ike Skelton Early Commissioning Program Scholarship”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>