<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2113"><akn:num>2113</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of University</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2113. Administration of University(a) The business of the University shall be conducted by the Secretary of Defense with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Defense.

(b) The Secretary shall appoint a President of the University (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “President”).

(c)(1) The Secretary, after considering the recommendations of the President, shall obtain the services of such military and civilian professors, instructors, and administrative and other employees as may be necessary to operate the University. Civilian members of the faculty and staff shall be employed under salary schedules and granted retirement and other related benefits prescribed by the Secretary (after due consideration by the Secretary) so as to place the employees of the University on a comparable basis with the employees of fully accredited schools of the health professions identified by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph.

(2) The Secretary may confer academic titles, as appropriate, upon military and civilian members of the faculty.

(3) The military members of the faculty shall include a professor of military, naval, or air science as the Secretary may determine.

(4) The limitations in sections 5307 and 5373 of title 5 do not apply to the authority of the Secretary under paragraph (1) to prescribe salary schedules and other related benefits. In no event may the total amount of compensation paid to an employee under paragraph (1) in any year (including salary, allowances, differentials, bonuses, awards, and other similar cash payments) exceed the total amount of annual compensation (excluding expenses) specified in section 102 of title 3.


(d) The Secretary may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources. Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Secretary may negotiate affiliati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The business of the University shall be conducted by the Secretary of Defense with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall appoint a President of the University (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “President”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources. Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Secretary may negotiate affiliation agreements with an accredited university or universities. Such agreements may include provisions for payments for educational services provided students participating in Department of Defense educational programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense may establish the following educational programs at the University:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary shall also establish programs in continuing medical education for military members of the health professions to the end that high standards of health care may be maintained within the military medical services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>