<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2155"><akn:num>2155</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint professional military education Phase II program of instruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2155. Joint professional military education Phase II program of instruction(a) Prerequisite of Completion of Joint Professional Military Education Phase I Program of Instruction.—(1) After September 30, 2009, an officer of the armed forces may not be accepted for, or assigned to, a program of instruction designated by the Secretary of Defense as joint professional military education Phase II unless the officer has successfully completed a program of instruction designated by the Secretary of Defense as joint professional military education Phase I.

(2) The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff may grant exceptions to the requirement under paragraph (1). Such an exception may be granted only on a case-by-case basis under exceptional circumstances, as determined by the Chairman. An officer selected to receive such an exception shall have knowledge of joint matters and other aspects of the Phase I curriculum that, to the satisfaction of the Chairman, qualifies the officer to meet the minimum requirements established for entry into Phase II instruction without first completing Phase I instruction. The number of officers selected to attend an offering of the principal course of instruction at the Joint Forces Staff College or a senior level service school designated by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education institution who have not completed Phase I instruction should comprise no more than 10 percent of the total number of officers selected.


(b) Phase II Requirements.—The Secretary shall require that the curriculum for Phase II joint professional military education at any school—(1) focus on developing joint operational expertise and perspectives and honing joint warfighting skills; and

(2) be structured—(A) so as to adequately prepare students to perform effectively in an assignment to a joint, multiservice organization; and

(B) so that students progress from a basic knowledge of joint matters learned in Phase I instruction to the lev</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisite of Completion of Joint Professional Military Education Phase I Program of Instruction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase II Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall require that the curriculum for Phase II joint professional military education at any school—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Curriculum Content.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In addition to the subjects specified in section 2151(a) of this title, the curriculum for Phase II joint professional military education shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2155_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student Ratio; Faculty Ratio.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than September 30, 2009, for courses of instruction in a Phase II program of instruction that is offered at senior level service school that has been designated by the Secretary of Defense as a joint professional military education institution—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>