<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2167" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2167/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2167/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2167"><akn:num>2167</akn:num><akn:heading>National Defense University: admission of private sector civilians to professional military educatio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2167. National Defense University: admission of private sector civilians to professional military education program(a) Authority for Admission.—The Secretary of Defense may permit eligible private sector employees who work in organizations relevant to national security to receive instruction at the National Defense University in accordance with this section. No more than the equivalent of 35 full-time student positions may be filled at any one time by private sector employees enrolled under this section. Upon successful completion of the course of instruction in which enrolled, any such private sector employee may be awarded an appropriate diploma or degree under section 2165 of this title.

(b) Eligible Private Sector Employees.—For purposes of this section, an eligible private sector employee is an individual employed by a private firm that is engaged in providing to the Department of Defense or other Government departments or agencies significant and substantial defense-related systems, products, or services or whose work product is relevant to national security policy or strategy. A private sector employee admitted for instruction at the National Defense University remains eligible for such instruction only so long as that person remains employed by the same firm.

(c) Annual Certification by Secretary of Defense.—Private sector employees may receive instruction at the National Defense University during any academic year only if, before the start of that academic year, the Secretary of Defense determines, and certifies to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, that providing instruction to private sector employees under this section during that year will further national security interests of the United States.

(d) Program Requirements.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—(1) the curriculum for the professional military education program in which private sector employees may be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Admission.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may permit eligible private sector employees who work in organizations relevant to national security to receive instruction at the National Defense University in accordance with this section. No more than the equivalent of 35 full-time student positions may be filled at any one time by private sector employees enrolled under this section. Upon successful completion of the course of instruction in which enrolled, any such private sector employee may be awarded an appropriate diploma or degree under section 2165 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Private Sector Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this section, an eligible private sector employee is an individual employed by a private firm that is engaged in providing to the Department of Defense or other Government departments or agencies significant and substantial defense-related systems, products, or services or whose work product is relevant to national security policy or strategy. A private sector employee admitted for instruction at the National Defense University remains eligible for such instruction only so long as that person remains employed by the same firm.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Certification by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Private sector employees may receive instruction at the National Defense University during any academic year only if, before the start of that academic year, the Secretary of Defense determines, and certifies to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, that providing instruction to private sector employees under this section during that year will further national security interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tuition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The President of the National Defense University shall charge students enrolled under this section a rate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of Conduct.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) While receiving instruction at the National Defense University, students enrolled under this section, to the extent practicable, are subject to the same regulations governing academic performance, attendance, norms of behavior, and enrollment as apply to Government civilian employees receiving instruction at the university.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2167_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Amounts received by the National Defense University for instruction of students enrolled under this section shall be retained by the university to defray the costs of such instruction. The source, and the disposition, of such funds shall be specifically identified in records of the university.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>