<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2174" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2174/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2174/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2174"><akn:num>2174</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest payment program: members on active duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2174. Interest payment program: members on active duty(a) Authority.—(1) The Secretary concerned may pay in accordance with this section the interest and any special allowances that accrue on one or more student loans of an eligible member of the armed forces.

(2) The Secretary of a military department may exercise the authority under paragraph (1) only if approved by the Secretary of Defense and subject to such requirements, conditions, and restrictions as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe.


(b) Eligible Members.—A member of the armed forces is eligible for the benefit under subsection (a) while the member—(1) is serving on active duty in fulfillment of the member’s first enlistment in the armed forces or, in the case of an officer, is serving on active duty and has not completed more than three years of service on active duty;

(2) is the debtor on one or more unpaid loans described in subsection (c); and

(3) is not in default on any such loan.


(c) Student Loans.—The authority to make payments under subsection (a) may be exercised with respect to the following loans:(1) A loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.).

(2) A loan made under part D of such title (20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.).

(3) A loan made under part E of such title (20 U.S.C. 1087aa et seq.).


(d) Maximum Benefit.—The months for which interest and any special allowance may be paid on behalf of a member of the armed forces under this section are any 36 consecutive months during which the member is eligible under subsection (b).

(e) Funds for Payments.—Appropriations available for the pay and allowances of military personnel shall be available for payments under this section.

(f) Coordination.—(1) The Secretary of Defense and, with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, the Secretary of the Department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall consult with the Secretary of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A member of the armed forces is eligible for the benefit under subsection (a) while the member—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student Loans.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The authority to make payments under subsection (a) may be exercised with respect to the following loans:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Benefit.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The months for which interest and any special allowance may be paid on behalf of a member of the armed forces under this section are any 36 consecutive months during which the member is eligible under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appropriations available for the pay and allowances of military personnel shall be available for payments under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2174_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Allowance Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “special allowance” means a special allowance that is payable under section 438 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1087–1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>