<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2193a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2193a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2193a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2193a"><akn:num>2193a</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of education in technical fields: general authority for support of elementary and second</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2193a. Improvement of education in technical fields: general authority for support of elementary and secondary education in science and mathematics
The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, may establish programs for the purpose of improving the mathematics and scientific knowledge and skills of elementary and secondary school students and faculty members.
(Added and amended Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title V, § 580(c)(1), (2), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 632, 633.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The text of section 2193(b) of this title, which was transferred to, and redesignated as text of, this section, was based on Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title II, § 247(a)(1), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1521.

Amendments1999—Pub. L. 106–65, § 580(c)(2), renumbered section 2193(b) of this title as text of this section. See Codification note above.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Pilot Program on Enhancement of Preparation of Dependents of Members of Armed Forces for Careers in Science, Technology, Engineering, and MathematicsPub. L. 113–291, div. A, title II, § 233, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3334, which required the Secretary of Defense to carry out a pilot program related to the enhancement of preparation of certain students for careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, was repealed by Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title II, § 211(c), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1255. See section 2192b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>