<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2202"><akn:num>2202</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations on production, warehousing, and supply distribution functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2202. Regulations on production, warehousing, and supply distribution functions
The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the performance within the Department of Defense of the production, warehousing, and supply distribution functions, and related functions, of the Department of Defense.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 120; Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1202, Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1153; Pub. L. 103–355, title III, § 3061(a), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3336; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1807(b)(2), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4157.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


220241:162.July 10, 1952, ch. 630, § 638, 66 Stat. 537.


The words “an officer or agency * * * may * * * only” are substituted for the words “no officer or agency * * * shall * * * except”. The word “of”, before the words “the Department”, is substituted for the words “in or under”. The words “under regulations prescribed” are substituted for the words “in accordance with regulations issued”. The words “after the effective date of this section” and 41:162(b) are omitted as executed. The words “or equipment” are omitted as covered by the definition of “supplies” in section 101(26) of this title.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283 struck out “procurement,” before “production,” in section catchline and text.
1994—Pub. L. 103–355 amended heading and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:
“(a) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an officer or agency of the Department of Defense may obligate funds for procuring, producing, warehousing, or distributing supplies, or for related functions of supply management, only under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense. The purpose of this section is to achieve the efficient, economical, and practical operation of an integrated supply system to meet the needs of the military departments without duplicate or o</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>