<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2208" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2208/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2208/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2208"><akn:num>2208</akn:num><akn:heading>Working-capital funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2208. Working-capital funds(a) To control and account more effectively for the cost of programs and work performed in the Department of Defense, the Secretary of Defense may require the establishment of working-capital funds in the Department of Defense to—(1) finance inventories of such supplies as he may designate; and

(2) provide working capital for such industrial-type activities, and such commercial-type activities that provide common services within or among departments and agencies of the Department of Defense, as he may designate.


(b) Upon the request of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish working-capital funds established under this section on the books of the Department of the Treasury.

(c) Working-capital funds shall be charged, when appropriate, with the cost of—(1) supplies that are procured or otherwise acquired, manufactured, repaired, issued, or used, including the cost of the procurement and qualification of technology-enhanced maintenance capabilities that improve either reliability, maintainability, sustainability, or supportability and have, at a minimum, been demonstrated to be functional in an actual system application or operational environment; and

(2) services or work performed;


including applicable administrative expenses, and be reimbursed from available appropriations or otherwise credited for those costs, including applicable administrative expenses and costs of using equipment.

(d) The Secretary of Defense may provide capital for working-capital funds by capitalizing inventories. In addition, such amounts may be appropriated for the purpose of providing capital for working-capital funds as have been specifically authorized by law.

(e) Subject to the authority and direction of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of each military department shall allocate responsibility for its functions, powers, and duties to accomplish the most economical and efficient organization and operation of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To control and account more effectively for the cost of programs and work performed in the Department of Defense, the Secretary of Defense may require the establishment of working-capital funds in the Department of Defense to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Upon the request of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Treasury shall establish working-capital funds established under this section on the books of the Department of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Working-capital funds shall be charged, when appropriate, with the cost of— including applicable administrative expenses, and be reimbursed from available appropriations or otherwise credited for those costs, including applicable administrative expenses and costs of using equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense may provide capital for working-capital funds by capitalizing inventories. In addition, such amounts may be appropriated for the purpose of providing capital for working-capital funds as have been specifically authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subject to the authority and direction of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of each military department shall allocate responsibility for its functions, powers, and duties to accomplish the most economical and efficient organization and operation of the activities, and the most economical and efficient use of the inventories, for which working-capital funds are authorized by this section. The accomplishment of the most economical and efficient organization and operation of working capital fund activities for the purposes of this subsection shall include actions toward the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The requisitioning agency may not incur a cost for supplies drawn from inventories, or services or work performed by industrial-type or commercial-type activities for which working-capital funds may be established under this section, that is more than the amount of appropriations or other funds available for those purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The appraised value of supplies returned to working-capital funds by a department, activity, or agency may be charged to that fund. The proceeds thereof shall be credited to current applicable appropriations and are available for expenditure for the same purposes that those appropriations are so available. Credits may not be made to appropriations under this subsection as the result of capitalization of inventories under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the operation of activities and use of inventories authorized by this section. The regulations may, if the needs of the Department of Defense require it and it is otherwise authorized by law, authorize supplies to be sold to, or services to be rendered or work performed for, persons outside the Department of Defense. However, supplies available in inventories financed by working capital funds established under this section may be sold to contractors for use in performing contracts with the Department of Defense. Working-capital funds shall be reimbursed for supplies so sold, services so rendered, or work so performed by charges to applicable appropriations or payments received in cash.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) For provisions relating to sales outside the Department of Defense of manufactured articles and services by a working-capital funded Army industrial facility (including a Department of the Army arsenal) that manufactures large caliber cannons, gun mounts, recoil mechanisms, ammunition, munitions, or components thereof, see section 7543 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2208_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>