<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_221"><akn:num>221</akn:num><akn:heading>Future-years defense program: submission to Congress; consistency in budgeting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 221. Future-years defense program: submission to Congress; consistency in budgeting(a) The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress each year, not later than five days after the date on which the President’s budget is submitted to Congress that year under section 1105(a) of title 31, a future-years defense program (including associated annexes) reflecting the estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in that budget. Any such future-years defense program shall cover the fiscal year with respect to which the budget is submitted and at least the four succeeding fiscal years.

(b)(1) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that amounts described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2) for any fiscal year are consistent with amounts described in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) for that fiscal year.

(2) Amounts referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:(A) The amounts specified in program and budget information submitted to Congress by the Secretary in support of expenditure estimates and proposed appropriations in the budget submitted to Congress by the President under section 1105(a) of title 31 for any fiscal year, as shown in the future-years defense program submitted pursuant to subsection (a).

(B) The total amounts of estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations necessary to support the programs, projects, and activities of the Department of Defense included pursuant to paragraph (5) of section 1105(a) of title 31 in the budget submitted to Congress under that section for any fiscal year.



(c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the inclusion in the future-years defense program of amounts for management contingencies, subject to the requirements of subsection (b).

(d)(1) The Secretary of Defense shall make available to Congress, the Congressional Budget Office, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the Congressional Research Service each future-years defense program under this section as follows:(A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_221_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress each year, not later than five days after the date on which the President’s budget is submitted to Congress that year under section 1105(a) of title 31, a future-years defense program (including associated annexes) reflecting the estimated expenditures and proposed appropriations included in that budget. Any such future-years defense program shall cover the fiscal year with respect to which the budget is submitted and at least the four succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_221_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_221_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the inclusion in the future-years defense program of amounts for management contingencies, subject to the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_221_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_221_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each future-years defense program under this subsection shall be accompanied by a certification by the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller), in the case of the Department of Defense, and the comptroller of each military department, in the case of such military department, that any information entered into the Standard Data Collection System of the Department of Defense, the Comptroller Information System, or any other data system, as applicable, for purposes of assembling such future-years defense program was accurate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>