<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2218a"><akn:num>2218a</akn:num><akn:heading>National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2218a. National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund”.

(b) Administration of Fund.—The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Fund consistent with the provisions of this section.

(c) Fund Purposes.—(1) Funds in the Fund shall be available for obligation and expenditure only for construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of national sea-based deterrence vessels.

(2) Funds in the Fund may not be used for a purpose or program unless the purpose or program is authorized by law.


(d) Deposits.—There shall be deposited in the Fund all funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of national sea-based deterrence vessels.

(e) Expiration of Funds After 5 Years.—No part of an appropriation that is deposited in the Fund pursuant to subsection (d) shall remain available for obligation more than five years after the end of fiscal year for which appropriated except to the extent specifically provided by law.

(f) Authority to Enter Into Economic Order Quantity Contracts.—(1) The Secretary of the Navy may use funds deposited in the Fund to enter into contracts known as “economic order quantity contracts” with private shipyards and other commercial or government entities to achieve economic efficiencies based on production economies for major components or subsystems. The authority under this subsection extends to the procurement of parts, components, and systems (including weapon systems) common with and required for other nuclear powered vessels under joint economic order quantity contracts.

(2) A contract entered into under paragraph (1) shall provide that any obligation of the United States to make a payment under the contract is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose, and that total liability t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Sea-Based Deterrence Fund”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Fund consistent with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) There shall be deposited in the Fund all funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of national sea-based deterrence vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration of Funds After 5 Years.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No part of an appropriation that is deposited in the Fund pursuant to subsection (d) shall remain available for obligation more than five years after the end of fiscal year for which appropriated except to the extent specifically provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Enter Into Economic Order Quantity Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Begin Manufacturing and Fabrication Efforts Prior to Ship Authorization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Use Incremental Funding to Enter Into Contracts for Certain Items.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Multiyear Procurement of Critical Components to Support Continuous Production.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Requests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Budget requests submitted to Congress for the Fund shall separately identify the amount requested for programs, projects, and activities for construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of national sea-based deterrence vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>