<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2218/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2218"><akn:num>2218</akn:num><akn:heading>National Defense Sealift Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2218. National Defense Sealift Fund(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Defense Sealift Fund”.

(b) Administration of Fund.—The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Fund consistent with the provisions of this section.

(c) Fund Purposes.—(1) Funds in the National Defense Sealift Fund shall be available for obligation and expenditure only for the following purposes:(A) Construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of Department of Defense sealift vessels.

(B) Operation, maintenance, and lease or charter of Department of Defense vessels for national defense purposes.

(C) Installation and maintenance of defense features for national defense purposes on privately owned and operated vessels that are constructed in the United States and documented under the laws of the United States.

(D) Expenses for maintaining the National Defense Reserve Fleet under section 11 of the Merchant Ship Sales Act of 1946 (50 U.S.C. 4405),11 See References in Text note below. and for the costs of acquisition of vessels for, and alteration and conversion of vessels in (or to be placed in), the fleet, but only for vessels built in United States shipyards.


(2) Funds in the National Defense Sealift Fund may be obligated or expended only in amounts authorized by law.

(3) Funds obligated and expended for a purpose set forth in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (1) may be derived only from funds deposited in the National Defense Sealift Fund pursuant to subsection (d)(1).


(d) Deposits.—There shall be deposited in the Fund the following:(1) All funds appropriated to the Department of Defense for—(A) construction (including design of vessels), purchase, alteration, and conversion of national defense sealift vessels;

(B) operations, maintenance, and lease or charter of national defense sealift vessels; and

(C) installation and maintenance of defense features for national defense p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund to be known as the “National Defense Sealift Fund”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Fund consistent with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) There shall be deposited in the Fund the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration of Funds After 5 Years.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No part of an appropriation that is deposited in the National Defense Sealift Fund pursuant to subsection (d)(1) shall remain available for obligation more than five years after the end of fiscal year for which appropriated except to the extent specifically provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Requests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Budget requests submitted to Congress for the National Defense Sealift Fund shall separately identify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Title or Management of Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section (other than subsection (c)(1)(D)) shall be construed to affect or modify title to, management of, or funding responsibilities for, any vessel of the National Defense Reserve Fleet, or assigned to the Ready Reserve Force component of the National Defense Reserve Fleet, as established by section 57100 of title 46.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2218_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for Incorporation of Defense Features in Commercial Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>