<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2222" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2222/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2222/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2222"><akn:num>2222</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense business systems: business process reengineering; enterprise architecture; management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2222. Defense business systems: business process reengineering; enterprise architecture; management(a) Defense Business Processes Generally.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that defense business processes are reviewed, and as appropriate revised, through business process reengineering to match best commercial practices, to the maximum extent practicable, so as to minimize customization of commercial business systems.

(b) Defense Business Systems Generally.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each covered defense business system developed, deployed, and operated by the Department of Defense—(1) supports efficient business processes that have been reviewed, and as appropriate revised, through business process reengineering;

(2) is integrated into a comprehensive defense business enterprise architecture;

(3) is managed in a manner that provides visibility into, and traceability of, expenditures for the system; and

(4) uses an acquisition and sustainment strategy that prioritizes the use of commercial software and business practices.


(c) Issuance of Guidance.—(1) Secretary of defense guidance.—The Secretary shall issue guidance to provide for the coordination of, and decision making for, the planning, programming, and control of investments in covered defense business systems.

(2) Supporting guidance.—The Secretary shall direct the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, and the Chief Information Officer of each of the military departments to issue and maintain supporting guidance, as appropriate and within their respective areas of responsibility, for the guidance of the Secretary issued under paragraph (1).


(d) Guidance Elements.—The guidance issued under subsection (c) shall include the following elements:(1) Policy to ensure that the business processes of the Department of Defense are continuously reviewed and revised—(A) to implement the most streamlined and effi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Business Processes Generally.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that defense business processes are reviewed, and as appropriate revised, through business process reengineering to match best commercial practices, to the maximum extent practicable, so as to minimize customization of commercial business systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Business Systems Generally.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each covered defense business system developed, deployed, and operated by the Department of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of Guidance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The guidance issued under subsection (c) shall include the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Business Enterprise Architecture.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Business Council.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approvals Required for Development.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility of Milestone Decision Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The milestone decision authority for a covered defense business system program shall be responsible for the acquisition of such system and shall ensure that acquisition process approvals are not considered for such system until the relevant certifications and approvals have been made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2222_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>