<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/222c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/222c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/222c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_222c"><akn:num>222c</akn:num><akn:heading>Armed forces: Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirements; Out-Year inventory numbers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 222c. Armed forces: Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirements; Out-Year inventory numbers(a) Annual Reports.—At the same time each year that the budget for the fiscal year beginning in such year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, the chief of staff of each armed force (other than the Coast Guard) shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth for such armed force each of the following for such fiscal year, broken out as specified in subsection (c):(1) The Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement.

(2) The Out-Year inventory numbers.


(b) Prohibition on Delegation of Submittal Responsibility.—The responsibility of the chief of staff of an armed force in subsection (a) to submit a report may not be delegated outside the armed force concerned.

(c) Presentation.—The Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement and Out-Year inventory numbers for an armed force for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (a) shall include specific inventory objective requirements for each variant of munitions with respect to each of the following:(1) Combat Requirement, broken out by operation plan (OPLAN).

(2) Current Operation/Forward Presence Requirement.

(3) Strategic Readiness Requirement.

(4) Homeland Defense.

(5) Training and Testing Requirement.

(6) Total Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement, calculated in accordance with the implementation guidance described in subsection (d).

(7) Out-year worldwide inventory.

(8) Requirement for Protracted Warfare Scenarios, calculated by doubling the duration of each applicable operation plan.


(d) Implementation Guidance Used.—In submitting information pursuant to subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the chief of staff of each armed force shall describe and explain the munitions requirements process implementation guidance developed by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and used by such armed force for the munit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) At the same time each year that the budget for the fiscal year beginning in such year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, the chief of staff of each armed force (other than the Coast Guard) shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth for such armed force each of the following for such fiscal year, broken out as specified in subsection (c):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Delegation of Submittal Responsibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The responsibility of the chief of staff of an armed force in subsection (a) to submit a report may not be delegated outside the armed force concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presentation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Out-Year Unconstrained Total Munitions Requirement and Out-Year inventory numbers for an armed force for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (a) shall include specific inventory objective requirements for each variant of munitions with respect to each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation Guidance Used.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In submitting information pursuant to subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the chief of staff of each armed force shall describe and explain the munitions requirements process implementation guidance developed by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and used by such armed force for the munitions requirements process for such armed force for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Each report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_222c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>