<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/223a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/223a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/223a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_223a"><akn:num>223a</akn:num><akn:heading>Ballistic missile defense programs: procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 223a. Ballistic missile defense programs: procurement(a) Budget Justification Materials.—In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31), the Secretary of Defense shall specify, for each ballistic missile defense system element for which the Missile Defense Agency is engaged in planning for production and initial fielding, the following information:(1) The production rate capabilities of the production facilities planned to be used for production of that element.

(2) The potential date of availability of that element for initial fielding.

(3) The estimated date on which the administration of the acquisition of that element is to be transferred from the Director of the Missile Defense Agency to the Secretary of a military department.


(b) Future-Years Defense Program.—The Secretary of Defense shall include in the future-years defense program submitted to Congress each year under section 221 of this title an estimate of the amount necessary for procurement for each ballistic missile defense system element, together with a discussion of the underlying factors and reasoning justifying the estimate.

(c) Performance Criteria.—The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall include in the performance criteria prescribed for planned development phases of the ballistic missile defense system and its elements a description of the intended effectiveness of each such phase against foreign adversary capabilities.

(Added Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title II, § 223(a)(1), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1420; amended Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title X, § 1060(a)(1), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3502.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 113–291 struck out subsec. (d). Text read as follows: “The Director of Operational Test and Evaluation shall make available for review by the congressional defense committees the d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_223a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Justification Materials.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In the budget justification materials submitted to Congress in support of the Department of Defense budget for any fiscal year (as submitted with the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31), the Secretary of Defense shall specify, for each ballistic missile defense system element for which the Missile Defense Agency is engaged in planning for production and initial fielding, the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_223a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Future-Years Defense Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall include in the future-years defense program submitted to Congress each year under section 221 of this title an estimate of the amount necessary for procurement for each ballistic missile defense system element, together with a discussion of the underlying factors and reasoning justifying the estimate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_223a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Director of the Missile Defense Agency shall include in the performance criteria prescribed for planned development phases of the ballistic missile defense system and its elements a description of the intended effectiveness of each such phase against foreign adversary capabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>