<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2241b"><akn:num>2241b</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on contracts providing payments for activities at sporting events to honor members of th</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2241b. Prohibition on contracts providing payments for activities at sporting events to honor members of the armed forces(a) Prohibition.—The Department of Defense may not enter into any contract or other agreement under which payments are to be made in exchange for activities by the contractor intended to honor, or giving the appearance of honoring, members of the armed forces (whether members of the regular components or the reserve components) at any form of sporting event.

(b) Construction.—Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed as prohibiting the Department of Defense from taking actions to facilitate activities intended to honor members of the armed forces at sporting events that are provided on a pro bono basis or otherwise funded with non-Federal funds if such activities are provided and received in accordance with applicable rules and regulations regarding the acceptance of gifts by the military departments, the armed forces, and members of the armed forces.

(Added Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title III, § 341(a), Nov. 25, 2015, 129 Stat. 792.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Department of Defense may not enter into any contract or other agreement under which payments are to be made in exchange for activities by the contractor intended to honor, or giving the appearance of honoring, members of the armed forces (whether members of the regular components or the reserve components) at any form of sporting event.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nothing in subsection (a) shall be construed as prohibiting the Department of Defense from taking actions to facilitate activities intended to honor members of the armed forces at sporting events that are provided on a pro bono basis or otherwise funded with non-Federal funds if such activities are provided and received in accordance with applicable rules and regulations regarding the acceptance of gifts by the military departments, the armed forces, and members of the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>