<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2241/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2241"><akn:num>2241</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations for certain purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2241. Availability of appropriations for certain purposes(a) Operation and Maintenance Appropriations.—Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance of the active forces may be used for the following purposes:(1) Morale, welfare, and recreation.

(2) Modification of personal property.

(3) Design of vessels.

(4) Industrial mobilization.

(5) Military communications facilities on merchant vessels.

(6) Acquisition of services, special clothing, supplies, and equipment.

(7) Expenses for the Reserve Officers’ Training Corps and other units at educational institutions.


(b) Necessary Expenses.—Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense may be used for all necessary expenses, at the seat of the Government or elsewhere, in connection with communication and other services and supplies that may be necessary for the national defense.

(c) Activities of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve.—Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, be used by the Secretary for official reception, representation, and advertising activities and materials of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve to further employer commitments to their employees who are members of a reserve component.

(d) Implementation of Vienna Document 2011.—Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may be used by the Secretary of Defense for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses for meetings and demonstrations hosted by the Department of Defense for the implementation of the Vienna Document 2011 on Confidence and Security-Building Measures.

(Added Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(e)(1), July 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 844; amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title V, § 518, Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1462; Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title X, § 1043, Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 389.)

Historical and Revision NotesSubsection (a) of this section and sections</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation and Maintenance Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense for operation and maintenance of the active forces may be used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amounts appropriated to the Department of Defense may be used for all necessary expenses, at the seat of the Government or elsewhere, in connection with communication and other services and supplies that may be necessary for the national defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, be used by the Secretary for official reception, representation, and advertising activities and materials of the National Committee for Employer Support of the Guard and Reserve to further employer commitments to their employees who are members of a reserve component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2241_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of Vienna Document 2011.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts appropriated for operation and maintenance may be used by the Secretary of Defense for travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses for meetings and demonstrations hosted by the Department of Defense for the implementation of the Vienna Document 2011 on Confidence and Security-Building Measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>