<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2254a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2254a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2254a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2254a"><akn:num>2254a</akn:num><akn:heading>Data files of military flight operations quality assurance systems: exemption from disclosure under </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2254a. Data files of military flight operations quality assurance systems: exemption from disclosure under Freedom of Information Act(a) Authority to Exempt Certain Data Files From Disclosure Under FOIA.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may exempt information contained in any data file of the military flight operations quality assurance system of a military department from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5, upon a written determination that—(A) the information is sensitive information concerning military aircraft, units, or aircrew; and

(B) the public interest consideration in the disclosure of such information does not outweigh preventing the disclosure of such information.


(2) In this section, the term “data file” means a file of the military flight operations quality assurance (in this section referred to as “MFOQA”) system that contains information acquired or generated by the MFOQA system, including—(A) any data base containing raw MFOQA data; and

(B) any analysis or report generated by the MFOQA system or which is derived from MFOQA data.


(3) Information that is exempt under paragraph (1) from disclosure under section 552(b)(3) of title 5 shall be exempt from such disclosure even if such information is contained in a data file that is not exempt in its entirety from such disclosure.

(4) The provisions of paragraph (1) may not be superseded except by a provision of law which is enacted after the date of the enactment of this section and which specifically cites and repeals or modifies those provisions.


(b) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. Such regulations shall ensure consistent application of the authority in subsection (a) across the military departments.

(c) Transparency.—Each determination of the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made in writing and accompanied by a statement of the basis for the determination. All such determinations and statements of basis s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2254a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Exempt Certain Data Files From Disclosure Under FOIA.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2254a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section. Such regulations shall ensure consistent application of the authority in subsection (a) across the military departments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2254a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each determination of the Secretary under subsection (a) shall be made in writing and accompanied by a statement of the basis for the determination. All such determinations and statements of basis shall be available to the public, upon request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>