<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/227" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/227/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/227/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_227"><akn:num>227</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget justification for covered military unaccompanied housing Facilities Sustainment, Restoration,</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 227. Budget justification for covered military unaccompanied housing Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects(a) In General.—Along with the budget for each fiscal year submitted by the President pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, each Secretary of a military department shall include a consolidated budget justification display for the congressional defense committees that individually identifies—(1) for the fiscal year covered by the budget, the total requested expenditure for Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects for covered military unaccompanied housing compared to the total expenditure required by such projects, disaggregated by military department; and

(2) the total expenditure for Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization projects made during the fiscal year beginning two years before the fiscal year covered by the budget, disaggregated by—(A) military installation;

(B) the type of facility repaired or restored under such repair projects;

(C) the number of such repair projects that were for sustainment or repair of a facility; and

(D) the number of such repair projects that were for restoration or modernization of a facility.



(b) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “covered military unaccompanied housing” has the meaning given in section 2856 of this title.

(2) The terms “facility” and “military installation” have the meanings given, respectively, in section 2801 of this title.

(3) The term “repair project” has the meaning given in section 2811 of this title.


(Added Pub. L. 118–159, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2821, Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2253.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 227, added Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title III, § 374(a), Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1636, directed Secretary of Defense to include recruiting costs in budget justification documents submitted to Congress each year in connection with submission of budget, prior to repeal </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Along with the budget for each fiscal year submitted by the President pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, each Secretary of a military department shall include a consolidated budget justification display for the congressional defense committees that individually identifies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_227_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>