<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2276"><akn:num>2276</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial space launch cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2276. Commercial space launch cooperation(a) Authority.—The Secretary of Defense may take such actions as the Secretary considers to be in the best interest of the Federal Government to—(1) maximize the use of the capacity of the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense by the private sector in the United States;

(2) maximize the effectiveness and efficiency of the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense;

(3) reduce the cost of services provided by the Department of Defense related to space transportation infrastructure at launch support facilities and space recovery support facilities;

(4) encourage commercial space activities by enabling investment by covered entities in the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense; and

(5) foster cooperation between the Department of Defense and covered entities.


(b) Authority for Contracts and Other Agreements Relating to Space Transportation Infrastructure.—The Secretary of Defense—(1) may enter into an agreement with a covered entity to provide the covered entity with support and services related to the space transportation infrastructure of the Department of Defense; and

(2) upon the request of such covered entity, may include such support and services in the space launch and reentry range support requirements of the Department of Defense if—(A) the Secretary determines that the inclusion of such support and services in such requirements—(i) is in the best interest of the Federal Government;

(ii) does not interfere with the requirements of the Department of Defense; and

(iii) does not compete with the commercial space activities of other covered entities, unless that competition is in the national security interests of the United States; and


(B) any commercial requirement included in the agreement has full non-Federal funding before the execution of the agreement.



(c) Contributions.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Defense may enter into </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may take such actions as the Secretary considers to be in the best interest of the Federal Government to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Contracts and Other Agreements Relating to Space Transportation Infrastructure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Cooperation Space Launch Account.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(e) Repealed. Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 813(a)(2), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1851.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>