<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2276a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2276a"><akn:num>2276a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special authority for provision of space launch support services to increase space launch capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2276a. Special authority for provision of space launch support services to increase space launch capacity(a) In General.—The Secretary of a military department may support Federal and commercial space launch capacity on any domestic real property under the control of the Secretary through the provision of space launch support services.

(b) Provision of Launch Equipment and Services to Commercial Entities.—(1) Contract or other transaction authority.—The Secretary of a military department may enter into a contract or other transaction with one or more commercial entities that intend to conduct space launch activities on a military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. Under such a contract or agreement, the Secretary may agree to provide to the commercial entity supplies, services, equipment, and construction needed for commercial space launch.

(2) Costs.—(A) Direct costs.—If the Secretary of a military department enters into a contract or other transaction with a commercial entity under paragraph (1), such contract or transaction shall include a provision that requires the commercial entity to reimburse the Department of Defense for all direct costs to the United States that are associated with any good, service, or equipment provided to the commercial entity under the contract or other transaction.

(B) Indirect costs.—If the Secretary of a military department enters into a contract or other transaction with a commercial entity under paragraph (1), such contract or transaction may include a provision that requires the commercial entity to reimburse the Department of Defense for such indirect costs as the Secretary considers to be appropriate. In such a case, such contract or other transaction may provide for the reimbursement of such indirect costs through the establishment of a rate, fixed price, or similar mechanism the Secretary concerned determines is reasonable.


(3) Retention of funds collected from commercial users.—Any amount collected </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of a military department may support Federal and commercial space launch capacity on any domestic real property under the control of the Secretary through the provision of space launch support services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of Launch Equipment and Services to Commercial Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2276a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition Limitations and Reporting Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, and 2026, the Secretary of a military department shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>