<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2281" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2281/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2281/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2281"><akn:num>2281</akn:num><akn:heading>Global Positioning System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2281. Global Positioning System(a) Sustainment and Operation for Military Purposes.—The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the sustainment of the capabilities of the Global Positioning System (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “GPS”), and the operation of basic GPS services, that are beneficial for the national security interests of the United States. In doing so, the Secretary shall—(1) develop appropriate measures for preventing hostile use of the GPS so as to make it unnecessary for the Secretary to use the selective availability feature of the system continuously while not hindering the use of the GPS by the United States and its allies for military purposes; and

(2) ensure that United States armed forces have the capability to use the GPS effectively despite hostile attempts to prevent the use of the system by such forces.


(b) Sustainment and Operation for Civilian Purposes.—The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the sustainment and operation of the GPS Standard Positioning Service for peaceful civil, commercial, and scientific uses on a continuous worldwide basis free of direct user fees. In doing so, the Secretary—(1) shall provide for the sustainment and operation of the GPS Standard Positioning Service in order to meet the performance requirements of the Federal Radionavigation Plan prepared jointly by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Transportation pursuant to subsection (c);

(2) shall coordinate with the Secretary of Transportation regarding the development and implementation by the Government of augmentations to the basic GPS that achieve or enhance uses of the system in support of transportation;

(3) shall coordinate with the Secretary of Commerce, the United States Trade Representative, and other appropriate officials to facilitate the development of new and expanded civil and commercial uses for the GPS;

(4) shall develop measures for preventing hostile use of the GPS in a particular area without hindering pea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sustainment and Operation for Military Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the sustainment of the capabilities of the Global Positioning System (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “GPS”), and the operation of basic GPS services, that are beneficial for the national security interests of the United States. In doing so, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sustainment and Operation for Civilian Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall provide for the sustainment and operation of the GPS Standard Positioning Service for peaceful civil, commercial, and scientific uses on a continuous worldwide basis free of direct user fees. In doing so, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Radionavigation Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Transportation shall jointly prepare the Federal Radionavigation Plan. The plan shall be revised and updated not less often than every two years. The plan shall be prepared in accordance with the requirements applicable to such plan as first prepared pursuant to section 507 of the International Maritime Satellite Telecommunications Act 11 See References in Text note below. (47 U.S.C. 756). The plan, and any amendment to the plan, shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2281_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>