<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231"><akn:num>231</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgeting for construction, maintenance, and modernization of naval vessels: annual plans and certif</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231. Budgeting for construction, maintenance, and modernization of naval vessels: annual plans and certifications(a) Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan and Certification.—The Secretary of the Navy shall include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year each of the following:(1) A plan for the construction of naval vessels developed in accordance with this section for each of the following classes of ships:(A) Combatant and support vessels.

(B) Auxiliary vessels.


(2) A certification by the Secretary that both the budget for that fiscal year and the future-years defense program submitted to Congress in relation to such budget under section 221 of this title provide for funding of the construction of naval vessels at a level that is sufficient for the procurement of the vessels provided for in the plan under paragraph (1) on the schedule provided in that plan, together with the views of the Chief of Naval Operations and Commandant of the Marine Corps on the budget.

(3) The unaltered assessment of the Chief of Naval Operations and the Commandant of the Marine Corps of the plan required under paragraph (1).


(b) Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan.—(1) The annual naval vessel construction plan developed for a fiscal year for purposes of subsection (a)(1) shall be designed so that the naval vessel force provided for under that plan supports the national security strategy of the United States as set forth in the most recent national security strategy report of the President under section 108 of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3043), except that, if at the time such plan is submitted with the defense budget materials for that fiscal year, a national security strategy report required under such section 108 has not been submitted to Congress as required by paragraph (2) or paragraph (3), if applicable, of subsection (a) of such section, then such annual plan shall be designed so that the naval vessel force provided for under that plan suppor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan and Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Navy shall include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment When Annual Naval Vessel Construction Plan Does Not Meet Force Structure Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If the annual naval vessel construction plan for a fiscal year under subsection (b) does not result in a force structure or capabilities that meet the requirements identified in subsection (b)(2)(B), the Secretary shall include with the defense budget materials for that fiscal year an assessment of the extent of the strategic and operational risk to national security associated with the reduced force structure of naval vessels over the period of time that the required force structure or capabilities are not achieved. Such assessment shall include an analysis of whether the risks are acceptable, and plans to mitigate such risks. Such assessment shall be coordinated in advance with the commanders of the combatant commands and the Nuclear Weapons Council under section 179 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Plan for Maintenance and Modernization of Naval Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In addition to the plan included under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of Defense shall include with the defense budget materials for a fiscal year each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>CBO Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 60 days after the date on which the congressional defense committees receive the plan under subsection (a)(1), the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall submit to such committees a report assessing the sufficiency of the estimated levels of annual funding included in such plan with respect to the budget submitted during the year in which the plan is submitted and the future-years defense program submitted under section 221 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Availability of Funds for Fiscal Years Without Plan and Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction in Battle Force Ships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If the plan and certification under subsection (a) for a fiscal year include a proposed reduction in the number of battle force ships proposed to be procured during that fiscal year or during the any of the subsequent nine fiscal years, as compared to the number of such ships proposed in the plan and certification for the preceding fiscal year for that fiscal year and the subsequent nine fiscal years, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees, by not later than 15 days after the date of the submission of the plan and certification under subsection (a), a briefing that includes each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>