<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350q"><akn:num>2350q</akn:num><akn:heading>Execution of projects under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350q. Execution of projects under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program(a) Authority To Execute Projects.—When the United States is designated as the Host Nation for purposes of executing a project under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”), the Secretary of Defense may accept such designation and carry out such project consistent with the requirements of this section.

(b) Project Funding.—The Secretary of Defense may fund authorized expenditures of projects accepted under subsection (a) with—(1) contributions under subsection (c);

(2) appropriations of the Department of Defense for the Program when directed by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization to apply amounts of such appropriations as part of the share of contributions of the United States for the Program; or

(3) any combination of amounts described in paragraphs (1) and (2).


(c) Authority To Accept Contributions.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may accept contributions from the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization for the purpose of carrying out a project under subsection (a).

(2) Contributions accepted under paragraph (1) shall be placed in an account established for the purpose of carrying out the project for which the funds were provided and shall remain available until expended.

(3)(A) If contributions are made under paragraph (1) as reimbursement for a project or portion of a project previously completed by the Department of Defense, such contributions shall be credited to—(i) the appropriations used for the project or portion thereof, if such appropriations have not yet expired; or

(ii) the appropriations for the Program, if the appropriations described in clause (i) have expired.


(B) Funding credited under subparagraph (A) shall merge with and remain available for the same purposes and duration as the appropriations to which cred</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Execute Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When the United States is designated as the Host Nation for purposes of executing a project under the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”), the Secretary of Defense may accept such designation and carry out such project consistent with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may fund authorized expenditures of projects accepted under subsection (a) with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Accept Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The construction agent of the Department of Defense designated by the Secretary of Defense to execute a project under subsection (a) may recognize the North Atlantic Treaty Organization project authorization amounts as budgetary resources to incur obligations against for the purposes of executing the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insufficient Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Expenditures Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “authorized expenditures” means project expenses for which the North Atlantic Treaty Organization has agreed to contribute funding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>