<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350d"><akn:num>2350d</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative acquisition and logistics support agreements: NATO countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350d. Cooperative acquisition and logistics support agreements: NATO countries(a) General Authority.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may enter into bilateral or multilateral agreements known as Support or Procurement Partnership Agreements with one or more governments of other member countries of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) participating in the operation of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies. Any such agreement shall be for the purpose of providing cooperative acquisition and logistics support for the armed forces of the countries which are parties to the agreement. Any such agreement—(A) shall be entered into pursuant to the terms of the charter of the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and

(B) shall provide for the common acquisition and logistics support of activities common to the participating countries.


(2) Such an agreement may provide for—(A) the transfer of logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies; and

(B) the acquisition of armaments and logistics support, supplies, and services by the United States from that Organization.



(b) Authority of Secretary.—Under the terms of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement or Arrangement, the Secretary of Defense—(1) may agree that the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies may enter into contracts for supply, services, support, and acquisition, including armaments for requirements of the United States, to the extent the Secretary determines that the procedures of such Organization governing such supply, services, support, and acquisition are appropriate; and

(2) may share the costs of set-up charges of facilities for use by the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies to provide cooperative acquisition and logistics support and in the costs of establishing a revo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under the terms of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement or Arrangement, the Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Administrative Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Each Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall provide for joint management by the participating countries and for the equitable sharing of the administrative costs and costs of claims incident to the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Chapter 137.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Except as otherwise provided in this section, the provisions of chapter 137 11 See References in Text note below. of this title apply to a contract entered into by the Secretary of Defense for the acquisition of logistics support under a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Arms Export Control Act.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any transfer of defense articles or defense services to a member country of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or to the NATO Support and Procurement Organization and its executive agencies for the purposes of a Support or Procurement Partnership Agreement shall be carried out in accordance with this chapter and the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The authority of the Secretary of Defense under this section is in addition to the authority of the Secretary under subchapter I and any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>