<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350i"><akn:num>2350i</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign contributions for cooperative projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350i. Foreign contributions for cooperative projects(a) Crediting of Contributions.—Whenever the United States participates in a cooperative project with a friendly foreign country or the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) on a cost-sharing basis, any contribution received by the United States from that foreign country or NATO to meet its share of the costs of the project may be credited to appropriations available to an appropriate military department or another appropriate organization within the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.

(b) Use of Amounts Credited.—The amount of a contribution credited pursuant to subsection (a) to an appropriation account in connection with a cooperative project referred to in that subsection shall be available only for payment of the share of the project expenses allocated to the foreign country or NATO making the contribution. Payments for which such amount is available include the following:(1) Payments to contractors and other suppliers (including the Department of Defense and other participants acting as suppliers) for necessary articles and services.

(2) Payments for any damages and costs resulting from the performance or cancellation of any contract or other obligation.

(3) Payments or reimbursements of other program expenses, including program office overhead and administrative costs.

(4) Refunds to other participants.


(c) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “cooperative project” means a jointly managed arrangement, described in a written cooperative agreement entered into by the participants, that—(A) is undertaken by the participants in order to improve the conventional defense capabilities of the participants; and

(B) provides for—(i) one or more participants (other than the United States) to share with the United States the cost of research and development, testing, evaluation, or joint production (including follow-on support) of defense articles;

(ii) the United States</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whenever the United States participates in a cooperative project with a friendly foreign country or the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) on a cost-sharing basis, any contribution received by the United States from that foreign country or NATO to meet its share of the costs of the project may be credited to appropriations available to an appropriate military department or another appropriate organization within the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Amounts Credited.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The amount of a contribution credited pursuant to subsection (a) to an appropriation account in connection with a cooperative project referred to in that subsection shall be available only for payment of the share of the project expenses allocated to the foreign country or NATO making the contribution. Payments for which such amount is available include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>