<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350a"><akn:num>2350a</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative research and development agreements: NATO organizations; allied and friendly foreign cou</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350a. Cooperative research and development agreements: NATO organizations; allied and friendly foreign countries(a) Authority To Engage in Cooperative R&amp;D Projects.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may enter into a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) with one or more countries or organizations referred to in paragraph (2) for the purpose of conducting cooperative research and development projects on defense equipment and munitions.

(2) The countries and organizations with which the Secretary may enter into a memorandum of agreement (or other formal agreement) under paragraph (1) are as follows:(A) The North Atlantic Treaty Organization.

(B) A NATO organization.

(C) A member nation of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.

(D) A major non-NATO ally.

(E) Any other friendly foreign country.

(F) The European Union, including the European Defence Agency, the European Commission, and the Council of the European Union, and their suborganizations.


(3) If such a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) is with a country referred to in subparagraph (E) of paragraph (2), such memorandum (or agreement) may go into effect only after the Secretary submits to the Committees on Armed Services and on Foreign Relations of the Senate and to the Committees on Armed Services and on International Relations of the House of Representatives a report with respect to the proposed memorandum (or agreement) and a period of 30 days has passed after the report has been submitted.


(b) Requirement That Projects Improve Conventional Defense Capabilities.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may not enter into a memorandum of understanding (or other formal agreement) to conduct a cooperative research and development project under this section unless the Secretary determines that the proposed project will improve, through the application of emerging technology, the conventional defense capabilities of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or the common conventiona</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Engage in Cooperative R&amp;D Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement That Projects Improve Conventional Defense Capabilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost Sharing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on Procurement of Equipment and Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Opportunities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(f) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(17), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1597.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Side-by-Side Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary To Encourage Similar Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of Defense shall encourage member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, major non-NATO allies, and other friendly foreign countries to establish programs similar to the one provided for in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>