<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350j"><akn:num>2350j</akn:num><akn:heading>Burden sharing contributions by designated countries and regional organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350j. Burden sharing contributions by designated countries and regional organizations(a) Authority To Accept Contributions.—The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, may accept cash contributions from any country or regional organization designated for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, for the purposes specified in subsection (c).

(b) Accounting.—Contributions accepted under subsection (a) which are not related to security assistance may be accepted, managed, and expended in dollars or in the currency of the host nation (or, in the case of a contribution from a regional organization, in the currency in which the contribution was provided). Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (c). The Secretary of Defense shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country or regional organization from which such contributions are accepted under subsection (a).

(c) Availability of Contributions.—Contributions accepted under subsection (a) shall be available only for the payment of the following costs:(1) Compensation for local national employees of the Department of Defense.

(2) Military construction projects of the Department of Defense.

(3) Supplies and services of the Department of Defense.


(d) Authorization of Military Construction.—Contributions placed in an account established under subsection (b) may be used—(1) by the Secretary of Defense to carry out a military construction project that is consistent with the purposes for which the contributions were made and is not otherwise authorized by law; or

(2) by the Secretary of a military department, with the approval of the Secretary of Defense, to carry out such a project.


(e) Notice and Wait Requirements.—(1) When a decision is made to carry out a military construction project un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Accept Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretary of State, may accept cash contributions from any country or regional organization designated for purposes of this section by the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, for the purposes specified in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contributions accepted under subsection (a) which are not related to security assistance may be accepted, managed, and expended in dollars or in the currency of the host nation (or, in the case of a contribution from a regional organization, in the currency in which the contribution was provided). Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (c). The Secretary of Defense shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country or regional organization from which such contributions are accepted under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contributions accepted under subsection (a) shall be available only for the payment of the following costs:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Military Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contributions placed in an account established under subsection (b) may be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Wait Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on Contributions Received From Designated Countries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>