<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2350k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2350k"><akn:num>2350k</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation within host nation of elements of armed forces overseas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2350k. Relocation within host nation of elements of armed forces overseas(a) Authority To Accept Contributions.—The Secretary of Defense may accept contributions from any nation because of or in support of the relocation of elements of the armed forces from or to any location within that nation. Such contributions may be accepted in dollars or in the currency of the host nation. Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (b). The Secretary shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country from which such contributions are accepted.

(b) Use of Contributions.—The Secretary may use a contribution accepted under subsection (a) only for payment of costs incurred in connection with the relocation concerning which the contribution was made. Those costs include the following:(1) Design and construction services, including development and review of statements of work, master plans and designs, acquisition of construction, and supervision and administration of contracts relating thereto.

(2) Transportation and movement services, including packing, unpacking, storage, and transportation.

(3) Communications services, including installation and deinstallation of communications equipment, transmission of messages and data, and rental of transmission capability.

(4) Supply and administration, including acquisition of expendable office supplies, rental of office space, budgeting and accounting services, auditing services, secretarial services, and translation services.

(5) Personnel costs, including salary, allowances and overhead of employees whether full-time or part-time, temporary or permanent (except for military personnel), and travel and temporary duty costs.

(6) All other clearly identifiable expenses directly related to relocation.


(c) Method of Contribution.—Contributions may be accepted in any of the following forms:(1) Irr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Accept Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may accept contributions from any nation because of or in support of the relocation of elements of the armed forces from or to any location within that nation. Such contributions may be accepted in dollars or in the currency of the host nation. Any such contribution shall be placed in an account established for such purpose and shall remain available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (b). The Secretary shall establish a separate account for such purpose for each country from which such contributions are accepted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may use a contribution accepted under subsection (a) only for payment of costs incurred in connection with the relocation concerning which the contribution was made. Those costs include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2350k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of Contribution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contributions may be accepted in any of the following forms:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>