<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2391"><akn:num>2391</akn:num><akn:heading>Military base reuse studies and community planning assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2391. Military base reuse studies and community planning assistance(a) Reuse Studies.—Whenever the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned publicly announces that a military installation is a candidate for closure or that a final decision has been made to close a military installation and the Secretary of Defense determines, because of the location, facilities, or other particular characteristics of the installation, that the installation may be suitable for some specific Federal, State, or local use potentially beneficial to the Nation, the Secretary of Defense may conduct such studies, including the preparation of an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), in connection with such installation and such potential use as may be necessary to provide information sufficient to make sound conclusions and recommendations regarding the possible use of the installation.

(b) Adjustment and Diversification Assistance.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may make grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds available under Federal programs administered by agencies other than the Department of Defense in order to assist State and local governments in planning community adjustments and economic diversification required (A) by the proposed or actual establishment, realignment, or closure of a military installation, (B) by the cancellation or termination of a Department of Defense contract or the failure to proceed with an approved major weapon system program, (C) by a publicly announced planned major reduction in Department of Defense spending that would directly and adversely affect a community, (D) by the encroachment of a civilian community on a military installation, (E) by threats to military installation resilience, or (F) by the closure or the significantly reduced operations of a defense facility as the result of the merger, acquisition, or con</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reuse Studies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Whenever the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned publicly announces that a military installation is a candidate for closure or that a final decision has been made to close a military installation and the Secretary of Defense determines, because of the location, facilities, or other particular characteristics of the installation, that the installation may be suitable for some specific Federal, State, or local use potentially beneficial to the Nation, the Secretary of Defense may conduct such studies, including the preparation of an environmental impact statement in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), in connection with such installation and such potential use as may be necessary to provide information sufficient to make sound conclusions and recommendations regarding the possible use of the installation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment and Diversification Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may make grants to, or conclude cooperative agreements or enter into contracts with, another Federal agency, a State or local government, or any private entity to conduct research and provide technical assistance in support of activities under this section or Executive Order 12788 (57 Fed. Reg. 2213), as amended by section 33 of Executive Order 13286 (68 Fed. Reg. 10625) and Executive Order 13378 (70 Fed. Reg. 28413).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Community Infrastructure Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2391_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance Subject to Appropriations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The authority of the Secretary of Defense to make grants under this section in any fiscal year is subject to the availability of appropriations for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>