<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/239d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/239d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/239d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_239d"><akn:num>239d</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgeting for depot and ammunition production facility maintenance and repair: annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 239d. Budgeting for depot and ammunition production facility maintenance and repair: annual report(a) Annual Report.—The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall include with the defense budget materials for each fiscal year a report regarding the maintenance and repair of covered facilities.

(b) Elements.—Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following (disaggregated by military department):(1) With respect to each of the three fiscal years preceding the fiscal year covered by the defense budget materials with which the report is included, revenue data for that fiscal year for the maintenance, repair, and overhaul workload funded at all the depots of the military department.

(2) With respect to the fiscal year covered by the defense budget materials with which the report is included and each of the two fiscal years prior, an identification of the following:(A) The amount of appropriations budgeted for that fiscal year for depots, further disaggregated by the type of appropriation.

(B) The amount budgeted for that fiscal year for working-capital fund investments by the Secretary of the military department for the capital budgets of the covered depots of the military department, shown in total and further disaggregated by whether the investment relates to the efficiency of depot facilities, work environment, equipment, equipment (non-capital investment program), or processes.

(C) The total amount required to be invested by the Secretary of the military department for that fiscal year for the capital budgets of covered depots pursuant to section 2476(a) of this title.

(D) A comparison of the budgeted amount identified under subparagraph (B) with the total required amount identified under subparagraph (C).

(E) For each covered depot of the military department, of the total required amount identified under subparagraph (C), the percentage of such amount allocated, or projec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall include with the defense budget materials for each fiscal year a report regarding the maintenance and repair of covered facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each report required under subsection (a) shall include, at a minimum, the following (disaggregated by military department):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>