<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2466" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2466/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2466/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2466"><akn:num>2466</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on the performance of depot-level maintenance of materiel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2466. Limitations on the performance of depot-level maintenance of materiel(a) Percentage Limitation.—Not more than 50 percent of the funds made available in a fiscal year to a military department or a Defense Agency for depot-level maintenance and repair workload may be used to contract for the performance by non-Federal Government personnel of such workload for the military department or the Defense Agency. Any such funds that are not used for such a contract shall be used for the performance of depot-level maintenance and repair workload by employees of the Department of Defense.

(b) Waiver of Limitation.—The Secretary of Defense may waive the limitation in subsection (a) for a fiscal year if—(1) the Secretary determines that the waiver is necessary for reasons of national security; and

(2) the Secretary submits to Congress a notification of the waiver together with the reasons for the waiver.


(c) Prohibition on Delegation of Waiver Authority.—The authority to grant a waiver under subsection (b) may not be delegated.

(d) Annual Report.—(1) Not later than 90 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report identifying, for each of the armed forces (other than the Coast Guard) and each Defense Agency, the percentage of the funds referred to in subsection (a) that was expended during the preceding fiscal year, and are projected to be expended during the current fiscal year and the ensuing fiscal year, for performance of depot-level maintenance and repair workloads by the public and private sectors.

(2) Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include as a separate item any expenditure covered by section 2474(f) of this title that was made during the fiscal year covered by the report and shall specify the amount and nature of each such expenditure.


(Added Pub. L. 100–456, div. A, title III, § 326(a), Sept.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2466_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not more than 50 percent of the funds made available in a fiscal year to a military department or a Defense Agency for depot-level maintenance and repair workload may be used to contract for the performance by non-Federal Government personnel of such workload for the military department or the Defense Agency. Any such funds that are not used for such a contract shall be used for the performance of depot-level maintenance and repair workload by employees of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2466_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may waive the limitation in subsection (a) for a fiscal year if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2466_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Delegation of Waiver Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The authority to grant a waiver under subsection (b) may not be delegated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2466_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>