<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2469" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2469/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2469/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2469"><akn:num>2469</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts to perform workloads previously performed by depot-level activities of the Department of D</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2469. Contracts to perform workloads previously performed by depot-level activities of the Department of Defense: requirement of competition(a) Requirement for Competition.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the performance of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload described in subsection (b) is not changed to performance by a contractor or by another depot-level activity of the Department of Defense unless the change is made using—(1) merit-based selection procedures for competitions among all depot-level activities of the Department of Defense; or

(2) competitive procedures for competitions among private and public sector entities.


(b) Scope.—Except as provided in subsection (c), subsection (a) applies to any depot-level maintenance and repair workload that has a value of not less than $3,000,000 (including the cost of labor and materials) and is being performed by a depot-level activity of the Department of Defense.

(c) Exception for Public-Private Partnerships.—The requirements of subsection (a) may be waived in the case of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload that is performed at a Center of Industrial and Technical Excellence designated under subsection (a) of section 2474 of this title by a public-private partnership entered into under subsection (b) of such section consisting of a depot-level activity and a private entity.

(d) Inapplicability of OMB Circular A–76.—Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 (or any successor administrative regulation or policy) does not apply to a performance change to which subsection (a) applies.

(Added Pub. L. 102–484, div. A, title III, § 353(a), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2378; amended Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title III, § 346, title XI, § 1182(a)(7), Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1625, 1771; Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 338, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2718; Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title III, § 311(f)(1), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 248; Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title III, §§ 355(b), 363, N</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2469_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Competition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the performance of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload described in subsection (b) is not changed to performance by a contractor or by another depot-level activity of the Department of Defense unless the change is made using—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2469_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c), subsection (a) applies to any depot-level maintenance and repair workload that has a value of not less than $3,000,000 (including the cost of labor and materials) and is being performed by a depot-level activity of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2469_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Public-Private Partnerships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The requirements of subsection (a) may be waived in the case of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload that is performed at a Center of Industrial and Technical Excellence designated under subsection (a) of section 2474 of this title by a public-private partnership entered into under subsection (b) of such section consisting of a depot-level activity and a private entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2469_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of OMB Circular A–76.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 (or any successor administrative regulation or policy) does not apply to a performance change to which subsection (a) applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>