<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2483" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2483/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2483/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2483"><akn:num>2483</akn:num><akn:heading>Commissary stores: use of appropriated funds to cover operating expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2483. Commissary stores: use of appropriated funds to cover operating expenses(a) Operation of Agency and System.—Except as otherwise provided in this title, the operation of the Defense Commissary Agency and the defense commissary system shall be funded using such amounts as are appropriated for such purpose.

(b) Operating Expenses of Commissary Stores.—Appropriated funds shall be used to cover the expenses of operating commissary stores and central product processing facilities of the defense commissary system. For purposes of this subsection, operating expenses include the following:(1) Salaries and wages of employees of the United States, host nations, and contractors supporting commissary store operations.

(2) Utilities.

(3) Communications.

(4) Operating supplies and services.

(5) Second destination transportation costs within or outside the United States.

(6) Any cost associated with above-store-level management or other indirect support of a commissary store or a central product processing facility, including equipment maintenance and information technology costs.

(7) Advertising of commissary sales on materials available within commissary stores and at other on-base locations.


(c) Supplemental Funds for Commissary Operations.—Amounts appropriated to cover the expenses of operating the Defense Commissary Agency and the defense commissary system may be supplemented with additional funds from manufacturers’ coupon redemption fees, handling fees for tobacco products, and other amounts received as reimbursement for other support activities provided by commissary activities. Such appropriated amounts may also be supplemented with additional funds derived from improved management practices implemented pursuant to sections 2481(c)(3) and 2487(c) of this title and the variable pricing program implemented pursuant to section 2484(i) of this title.

(Added Pub. L. 98–525, title XIV, § 1401(i)(1), Oct. 19, 1984, 98 Stat. 2619, § 2484; amended Pub. L. 106–398,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2483_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of Agency and System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as otherwise provided in this title, the operation of the Defense Commissary Agency and the defense commissary system shall be funded using such amounts as are appropriated for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2483_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating Expenses of Commissary Stores.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriated funds shall be used to cover the expenses of operating commissary stores and central product processing facilities of the defense commissary system. For purposes of this subsection, operating expenses include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2483_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Funds for Commissary Operations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amounts appropriated to cover the expenses of operating the Defense Commissary Agency and the defense commissary system may be supplemented with additional funds from manufacturers’ coupon redemption fees, handling fees for tobacco products, and other amounts received as reimbursement for other support activities provided by commissary activities. Such appropriated amounts may also be supplemented with additional funds derived from improved management practices implemented pursuant to sections 2481(c)(3) and 2487(c) of this title and the variable pricing program implemented pursuant to section 2484(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>