<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2487" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2487/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2487/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2487"><akn:num>2487</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship between defense commissary system and exchange stores system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2487. Relationship between defense commissary system and exchange stores system(a) Separate Operation of Systems.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the defense commissary system and the exchange stores system shall be operated as separate systems of the Department of Defense.

(2) Paragraph (1) does not apply to the following:(A) Combined exchange and commissary stores operated under the authority provided by section 2489 of this title.

(B) NEXMART stores of the Navy Exchange Service Command established before October 1, 2003.



(b) Consolidation or Other Organizational Changes of Defense Retail Systems.—(1) The operation and administration of the defense retail systems may not be consolidated or otherwise merged unless the consolidation or merger is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress.

(2) In this subsection, the term “defense retail systems” means the defense commissary system and exchange stores system and other revenue-generating facilities operated by nonappropriated fund instrumentalities of the Department of Defense for the morale, welfare, and recreation of members of the armed forces.


(c) Common Business Practices.—(1) Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary of Defense may establish common business processes, practices, and systems—(A) to exploit synergies between the defense commissary system and the exchange system; and

(B) to optimize the operations of the defense retail systems as a whole and the benefits provided by the commissaries and exchanges.


(2) The Secretary may authorize the defense commissary system and the exchange system to enter into contracts or other agreements—(A) for products and services that are shared by the defense commissary system and the exchange system; and

(B) for the acquisition of supplies, resale goods, and services on behalf of both the defense commissary system and the exchange system.


(3) For the purpose of a contract or agreement authorized under paragraph (2), the Secretary m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2487_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate Operation of Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2487_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation or Other Organizational Changes of Defense Retail Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2487_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common Business Practices.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2487_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access of Exchange Stores System to Federal Financing Bank.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To facilitate the provision of in-store credit to patrons of the exchange stores system while reducing the costs of providing such credit, the Army and Air Force Exchange Service, Navy Exchange Service Command, and Marine Corps exchanges may issue and sell their obligations to the Federal Financing Bank as provided in section 6 of the Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973 (12 U.S.C. 2285).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>