<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/252" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/252/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/252/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_252"><akn:num>252</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of militia and armed forces to enforce Federal authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 252. Use of militia and armed forces to enforce Federal authority
Whenever the President considers that unlawful obstructions, combinations, or assemblages, or rebellion against the authority of the United States, make it impracticable to enforce the laws of the United States in any State by the ordinary course of judicial proceedings, he may call into Federal service such of the militia of any State, and use such of the armed forces, as he considers necessary to enforce those laws or to suppress the rebellion.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 15, § 332; Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(2), Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3440; renumbered § 252, Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1241(a)(2), Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2497.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


33250:202.R.S. 5298.


50:202 (last 22 words) is omitted as surplusage. The words “armed forces” are substituted for the words “land and naval forces of the United States”. The words “call into Federal service such of the militia” are substituted for the words “call forth the militia of any or all the States” for clarity and uniformity. The word “may” is substituted for the words “it shall be lawful”. The words “faithful execution of the” and “in whatever State or Territory thereof the laws of the United States may be forcibly opposed” are omitted as surplusage.

DerivationAct July 29, 1861, ch. 25, § 1, 12 Stat. 281.

Editorial Notes
Codification
Another section 252 was renumbered section 240b of this title.

Amendments2016—Pub. L. 114–328 renumbered section 332 of this title as this section.
2006—Pub. L. 109–163 struck out “or Territory” after “in any State”.
Executive Documents


Ex. Ord. No. 10730. Assistance for Removal of an Obstruction of Justice Within the State of Arkansas
Ex. Ord. No. 10730, Sept. 24, 1957, 22 F.R. 7628, authorized the Secretary of Defense to order into the active military service of the United States units</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>