<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2552" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2552/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2552/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2552"><akn:num>2552</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment for instruction and practice: American National Red Cross</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2552. Equipment for instruction and practice: American National Red Cross
The Secretary of a military department, under regulations to be prescribed by him, may lend equipment under the jurisdiction of that department that is on hand, and that can be temporarily spared, to any organization formed by the American National Red Cross that needs it for instruction and practice for the purpose of aiding the Army, Navy, or Air Force in time of war. The Secretary shall by regulation require the immediate return, upon request, of equipment lent under this section. The Secretary shall require a bond, in double the value of the property issued under this section, for the care and safekeeping of that property and for its return when required.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 142, § 2542; renumbered § 2552, Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A], title X, § 1033(b)(1)], Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1654, 1654A–260.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


254210:1255.10:1256.34:549.34:550.May 8, 1914, J. Res. 15, 38 Stat. 771.


The word “may” is substituted for the words “is authorized * * * at his discretion”, in 10:1255 and 34:549. The word “lend” is substituted for the word “issue”, in 10:1255 and 34:549. The words “proper”, “to be”, “out of equipment for medical or other establishments”, and “belonging to the Government”, in 10:1255 and 34:549, are omitted as surplusage. The words “that needs it” are substituted for the words “as may appear to be required”. The words “under the jurisdiction of that department” are inserted for clarity. The words “upon request” are substituted for the words “when called for by the authority which issued them”.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2552 was renumbered section 2562 of this title and was subsequently repealed.

Amendments2000—Pub. L. 106–398 renumbered section 2542 of this title as this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>