<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2561" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2561/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2561/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2561"><akn:num>2561</akn:num><akn:heading>Humanitarian assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2561. Humanitarian assistance(a) Authorized Assistance.—(1) To the extent provided in defense authorization Acts, funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year for humanitarian assistance shall be used for the purpose of providing transportation of humanitarian relief and for other humanitarian purposes worldwide.

(2) The Secretary of Defense may use the authority provided by paragraph (1) to transport supplies intended for use to respond to, or mitigate the effects of, an event or condition, such as an oil spill, that threatens serious harm to the environment, but only if other sources to provide such transportation are not readily available. The Secretary may require reimbursement for costs incurred by the Department of Defense to transport supplies under this paragraph.


(b) Availability of Funds.—To the extent provided in appropriation Acts, funds appropriated for humanitarian assistance for the purposes of this section shall remain available until expended.

(c) Notice Before Provision of Assistance.—(1) If the Secretary of Defense uses the authority under subsection (a) to provide assistance for any program or activity in an amount in excess of $5,000,000, the Secretary shall provide to the congressional committees specified in subsection (g) notice in writing of the use of such authority in accordance with paragraph (2). Notice under this subsection shall include an identification of each of the following:(A) The amount, type, and purpose of assistance to be provided and the recipient of the assistance.

(B) The goals and objectives of the assistance.

(C) The number and role of any members of the Armed Forces involved in the provision of the assistance.

(D) Any other information the Secretary determines is relevant.


(2) Notice required under paragraph (1) shall be provided—(A) before the provision of assistance under subsection (a) using funds authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense for a fiscal </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To the extent provided in appropriation Acts, funds appropriated for humanitarian assistance for the purposes of this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice Before Provision of Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report Regarding Relief for Unauthorized Countries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In any case in which the Secretary of Defense provides for the transportation of humanitarian relief to a country to which the transportation of humanitarian relief has not been specifically authorized by law, the Secretary shall notify the congressional committees specified in subsection (g) and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives of the Secretary’s intention to provide such transportation. The notification shall be submitted not less than 15 days before the commencement of such transportation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “defense authorization Act” means an Act that authorizes appropriations for one or more fiscal years for military activities of the Department of Defense, including authorizations of appropriations for the activities described in paragraph (7) of section 114(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2561_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Committees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The congressional committees referred to in subsections (c)(1), (d)(1), and (e) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>