<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2563" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2563/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2563/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2563"><akn:num>2563</akn:num><akn:heading>Articles and services of industrial facilities: sale to persons outside the Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2563. Articles and services of industrial facilities: sale to persons outside the Department of Defense(a) Authority To Sell Outside DOD.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may sell in accordance with this section to a person outside the Department of Defense articles and services referred to in paragraph (2) that are not available from any United States commercial source.

(2)(A) Except as provided in subparagraph (B), articles and services referred to in paragraph (1) are articles and services that are manufactured or performed by any working-capital funded industrial facility of the armed forces.

(B) The authority in this section does not apply to sales of articles and services by a working-capital funded Army industrial facility (including a Department of the Army arsenal) that manufactures large caliber cannons, gun mounts, recoil mechanisms, ammunition, munitions, or components thereof, which are governed by regulations required by section 7543 of this title.



(b) Designation of Participating Industrial Facilities.—The Secretary may designate facilities referred to in subsection (a) as the facilities from which articles and services manufactured or performed by such facilities may be sold under this section.

(c) Conditions for Sales.—(1) A sale of articles or services may be made under this section only if—(A) the Secretary of Defense determines that the articles or services are not available from a commercial source in the United States;

(B) the purchaser agrees to hold harmless and indemnify the United States, except as provided in paragraph (3), from any claim for damages or injury to any person or property arising out of the articles or services;

(C) the articles or services can be substantially manufactured or performed by the industrial facility concerned with only incidental subcontracting;

(D) it is in the public interest to manufacture the articles or perform the services;

(E) the Secretary determines that the sale of the articles or services will</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Sell Outside DOD.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Participating Industrial Facilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary may designate facilities referred to in subsection (a) as the facilities from which articles and services manufactured or performed by such facilities may be sold under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for Sales.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods of Sale.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of Proceeds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Proceeds from sales of articles and services under this section shall be credited to the funds, including working capital funds and operation and maintenance funds, incurring the costs of manufacture or performance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Arms Export Control Act.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of the export controls provided for in section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2778) to items which incorporate or are produced through the use of an article sold under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2563_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>