<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2613"><akn:num>2613</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of frequent traveler miles, credits, points, and tickets: use to facilitate rest and recu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2613. Acceptance of frequent traveler miles, credits, points, and tickets: use to facilitate rest and recuperation travel of deployed members and their families(a) Authority to Accept Donation of Travel Benefits.—Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may accept from any person or government agency the donation of travel benefits for the purposes of use under subsection (d).

(b) Travel Benefit Defined.—In this section, the term “travel benefit” means—(1) frequent traveler miles, credits for tickets, or tickets for air or surface transportation issued by an air carrier or a surface carrier, respectively, that serves the public; and

(2) points or awards for free or reduced-cost accommodations issued by an inn, hotel, or other commercial establishment that provides lodging to transient guests.


(c) Condition on Authority to Accept Donation.—The Secretary may accept a donation of a travel benefit under this section only if the business entity referred to in subsection (b) that is the source of the benefit consents to such donation. Any such donation shall be under such terms and conditions as the business entity may specify, and the travel benefit so donated may be used only in accordance with the rules established by the business entity.

(d) Use of Donated Travel Benefits.—A travel benefit accepted under this section may be used only for the purpose of—(1) facilitating the travel of a member of the armed forces who—(A) is deployed on active duty outside the United States away from the permanent duty station of the member in support of a contingency operation; and

(B) is granted, during such deployment, rest and recuperative leave, emergency leave, convalescent leave, or another form of leave authorized for the member; or


(2) in the case of a member of the armed forces recuperating from an injury or illness incurred or aggravated in the line of duty during such a deployment, facilitating the travel of family members of the member in order to be reu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Accept Donation of Travel Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense may accept from any person or government agency the donation of travel benefits for the purposes of use under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel Benefit Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “travel benefit” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition on Authority to Accept Donation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may accept a donation of a travel benefit under this section only if the business entity referred to in subsection (b) that is the source of the benefit consents to such donation. Any such donation shall be under such terms and conditions as the business entity may specify, and the travel benefit so donated may be used only in accordance with the rules established by the business entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Donated Travel Benefits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A travel benefit accepted under this section may be used only for the purpose of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services of Nonprofit Organization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense may enter into an agreement with a nonprofit organization to use the services of the organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2613_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Member Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “family member” has the meaning given that term in section 451(a) of title 37.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>