<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2631a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2631a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2631a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2631a"><akn:num>2631a</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingency planning: sealift and related intermodal transportation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2631a. Contingency planning: sealift and related intermodal transportation requirements(a) Consideration of Private Capabilities.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all studies and reports of the Department of Defense, and all actions taken in the Department of Defense, concerning sealift and related intermodal transportation requirements take into consideration the full range of the transportation and distribution capabilities that are available from operators of privately owned United States flag merchant vessels.

(b) Private Capacities Presentations.—The Secretary shall afford each operator of a vessel referred to in subsection (a), not less often than annually, an opportunity to present to the Department of Defense information on its port-to-port and intermodal transportation capacities.

(Added Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title XI, § 1173(a), Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1767.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2631a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Private Capabilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all studies and reports of the Department of Defense, and all actions taken in the Department of Defense, concerning sealift and related intermodal transportation requirements take into consideration the full range of the transportation and distribution capabilities that are available from operators of privately owned United States flag merchant vessels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2631a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private Capacities Presentations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall afford each operator of a vessel referred to in subsection (a), not less often than annually, an opportunity to present to the Department of Defense information on its port-to-port and intermodal transportation capacities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>