<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2641b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2641b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2641b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2641b"><akn:num>2641b</akn:num><akn:heading>Space-available travel on Department of Defense aircraft: program authorized and eligible recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2641b. Space-available travel on Department of Defense aircraft: program authorized and eligible recipients(a) Authority to Establish Program.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may establish a program (in this section referred to as the “travel program”) to provide transportation on Department of Defense aircraft on a space-available basis to the categories of individuals eligible under subsection (c).

(2) If the Secretary makes a determination to establish the travel program, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations for the operation of the travel program not later than one year after the date on which the determination was made. The regulations shall take effect on that date or such earlier date as the Secretary shall specify in the regulations.

(3) Not later than 30 days after making the determination to establish the travel program, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees an initial implementation report describing—(A) the basis for the determination;

(B) any additional categories of individuals to be eligible for the travel program under subsection (c)(6);

(C) how the Secretary will ensure that the travel program is established and operated in compliance with the conditions specified in subsection (b); and

(D) the metrics by which the Secretary will monitor the travel program to determine the efficient and effective execution of the travel program.



(b) Conditions on Establishment and Operation.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall operate the travel program in a budget-neutral manner.

(2) No additional funds may be used, or flight hours performed, for the purpose of providing transportation under the travel program.


(c) Eligible Individuals.—Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall provide transportation under the travel program (if established) to the following categories of individuals:(1) Members of the armed forces on active duty.

(2) Members of the Selected Reserve who hold a valid Uniformed Services Iden</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Establish Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions on Establishment and Operation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Individuals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to subsection (d), the Secretary of Defense shall provide transportation under the travel program (if established) to the following categories of individuals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities and Restrictions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In operating the travel program, the Secretary of Defense shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Priority for Retired Members Residing in Commonwealths and Possessions of the United States Who Need Certain Health Care Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans With Service-connected Disabilities Rated as Total.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2641b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The authority to provide transportation under the travel program is in addition to any other authority under law to provide transportation on Department of Defense aircraft on a space-available basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>