<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2642" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2642/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2642/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2642"><akn:num>2642</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation services provided to certain non-Department of Defense agencies and entities: use of </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2642. Transportation services provided to certain non-Department of Defense agencies and entities: use of Department of Defense reimbursement rate(a) Authority.—Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may authorize the use of the Department of Defense reimbursement rate for military transportation services provided by a component of the Department of Defense as follows:(1) For military transportation services provided to the Central Intelligence Agency, if the Secretary of Defense determines that those military transportation services are provided for activities related to national security objectives.

(2) For military transportation services provided to the Department of State for the transportation of armored motor vehicles to a foreign country to meet requirements of the Department of State for armored motor vehicles associated with the overseas travel of the Secretary of State in that country.

(3) For military transportation services provided to any element of the Federal Government outside the Department of Defense in circumstances other than those specified in paragraphs (1) and (2), but only if the Secretary of Defense determines that the provision of such services will promote the improved use of transportation capacity without any negative effect on the national security objectives or the national security interests contained within the United States commercial transportation industry.

(4) For military transportation services provided in support of foreign military sales.

(5) For military transportation services provided to a State, local, or tribal agency (including any organization composed of State, local, or tribal agencies).

(6) For military transportation services provided to a Department of Defense contractor when transporting supplies that are for, or destined for, a Department of Defense entity.


(b) Termination of Authority for Certain Categories of Transportation.—The provisions of paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of subsecti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense may authorize the use of the Department of Defense reimbursement rate for military transportation services provided by a component of the Department of Defense as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority for Certain Categories of Transportation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The provisions of paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) of subsection (a) shall apply only to military transportation services provided before October 1, 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2642_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section, the term “Department of Defense reimbursement rate” means the amount charged a component of the Department of Defense by another component of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>