<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2646" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2646/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2646/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2646"><akn:num>2646</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel services: procurement for official and unofficial travel under one contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2646. Travel services: procurement for official and unofficial travel under one contract(a) Authority.—The head of an agency may enter into a contract for travel-related services that provides for the contractor to furnish services for both official travel and unofficial travel.

(b) Credits, Discounts, Commissions, Fees.—(1) A contract entered into under this section may provide for credits, discounts, or commissions or other fees to accrue to the Department of Defense. The accrual and amounts of credits, discounts, or commissions or other fees may be determined on the basis of the volume (measured in the number or total amount of transactions or otherwise) of the travel-related sales that are made by the contractor under the contract.

(2) The evaluation factors applicable to offers for a contract under this section may include a factor that relates to the estimated aggregate value of any credits, discounts, commissions, or other fees that would accrue to the Department of Defense for the travel-related sales made under the contract.

(3) Commissions or fees received by the Department of Defense as a result of travel-related sales made under a contract entered into under this section shall be distributed as follows:(A) For amounts relating to sales for official travel, credit to appropriations available for official travel for the fiscal year in which the amounts were charged.

(B) For amounts relating to sales for unofficial travel, deposit in nonappropriated fund accounts available for morale, welfare, and recreation programs.



(c) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “head of an agency” has the meaning given that term in section 3004 of this title.

(2) The term “official travel” means travel at the expense of the Federal Government.

(3) The term “unofficial travel” means personal travel or other travel that is not paid for or reimbursed by the Federal Government out of appropriated funds.


(d) Inapplicability to Coast Guard and NASA.—This section do</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The head of an agency may enter into a contract for travel-related services that provides for the contractor to furnish services for both official travel and unofficial travel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credits, Discounts, Commissions, Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2646_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to Coast Guard and NASA.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section does not apply to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, nor to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>