<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2663" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2663/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2663/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2663"><akn:num>2663</akn:num><akn:heading>Land acquisition authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2663. Land acquisition authorities(a) Acquisition of Land by Condemnation for Certain Military Purposes.—(1) Subject to subsection (f), the Secretary of a military department may have proceedings brought in the name of the United States, in a court of proper jurisdiction, to acquire by condemnation any interest in land, including temporary use, needed for—(A) the site, construction, or operation of fortifications, coast defenses, or military training camps;

(B) the construction and operation of plants for the production of nitrate and other compounds, and the manufacture of explosives or other munitions of war; or

(C) the development and transmission of power for the operation of plants under subparagraph (B).


(2) In time of war or when war is imminent, the United States may, immediately upon the filing of a petition for condemnation under paragraph (1), take and use the land to the extent of the interest sought to be acquired.


(b) Acquisition by Purchase in Lieu of Condemnation.—The Secretary of the military department concerned may contract for or buy any interest in land, including temporary use, needed for any purpose named in subsection (a), as soon as the owner fixes a price for it and the Secretary considers that price to be reasonable.

(c) Acquisition of Low-Cost Interests in Land.—(1) The Secretary of a military department may acquire any interest in land that—(A) the Secretary determines is needed in the interest of national defense; and

(B) does not cost more than $4,000,000, exclusive of administrative costs and the amounts of any deficiency judgments.


(2) The Secretary of a military department may acquire any interest in land that—(A) the Secretary determines is needed solely to correct a deficiency that is life-threatening, health-threatening, or safety-threatening; and

(B) does not cost more than $1,500,000, exclusive of administrative costs and the amounts of any deficiency judgments.


(3) This subsection does not apply to the acquisiti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of Land by Condemnation for Certain Military Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition by Purchase in Lieu of Condemnation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the military department concerned may contract for or buy any interest in land, including temporary use, needed for any purpose named in subsection (a), as soon as the owner fixes a price for it and the Secretary considers that price to be reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of Low-Cost Interests in Land.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of Interests in Land When Need Is Urgent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survey Authority; Acquisition Methods.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority provided the Secretary of a military department by law to acquire an interest in real property (including a temporary interest) includes authority—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance Notice of Use of Condemnation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception to Advance Notice Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If the Secretary of a military department determines that the use of condemnation, eminent domain, or seizure to acquire an interest in land is required under subsection (a) to satisfy a requirement vital to national security, and that any delay would be detrimental to national security or the protection of health, safety, or the environment, the Secretary may have proceedings brought in the name of the United States to acquire the land in advance of submitting the report required by subsection (f)(1)(B). However, the Secretary shall submit the report not later than seven days after commencement of the legal proceedings with respect to the land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2663_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land Acquisition Options in Advance of Military Construction Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>