<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2668" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2668/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2668/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2668"><akn:num>2668</akn:num><akn:heading>Easements for rights-of-way</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2668. Easements for rights-of-way(a) Authorized Types of Easements.—If the Secretary of a military department finds that it will not be against the public interest, the Secretary may grant, upon such terms as the Secretary considers advisable, easements for rights-of-way over, in, and upon public lands permanently withdrawn or reserved for the use of that department, and other lands under the Secretary’s control for—(1) railroad tracks;

(2) gas, water, sewer, and oil pipe lines;

(3) substations for electric power transmission lines and pumping stations for gas, water, sewer, and oil pipe lines;

(4) canals;

(5) ditches;

(6) flumes;

(7) tunnels;

(8) dams and reservoirs in connection with fish and wildlife programs, fish hatcheries, and other improvements relating to fish-culture;

(9) roads and streets;

(10) poles and lines for the transmission or distribution of electric power;

(11) poles and lines for the transmission or distribution of communications signals (including telephone and telegraph signals);

(12) structures and facilities for the transmission, reception, and relay of such signals; and

(13) any other purpose that the Secretary considers advisable.


(b) Limitation on Size of Easement.—No easement granted under this section may include more land than is necessary for the easement.

(c) Termination.—The Secretary of the military department concerned may terminate all or part of any easement granted under this section for—(1) failure to comply with the terms of the grant;

(2) nonuse for a two-year period; or

(3) abandonment.


(d) Notice to Department of the Interior.—Copies of instruments granting easements over public lands under this section shall be furnished to the Secretary of the Interior.

(e) Disposition of Consideration.—Subsections (c) and (e) of section 2667 of this title shall apply with respect to in-kind consideration and proceeds received by the Secretary of a military department in connection with an easement granted under thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2668_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Types of Easements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If the Secretary of a military department finds that it will not be against the public interest, the Secretary may grant, upon such terms as the Secretary considers advisable, easements for rights-of-way over, in, and upon public lands permanently withdrawn or reserved for the use of that department, and other lands under the Secretary’s control for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2668_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Size of Easement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No easement granted under this section may include more land than is necessary for the easement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2668_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the military department concerned may terminate all or part of any easement granted under this section for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2668_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Department of the Interior.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Copies of instruments granting easements over public lands under this section shall be furnished to the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2668_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsections (c) and (e) of section 2667 of this title shall apply with respect to in-kind consideration and proceeds received by the Secretary of a military department in connection with an easement granted under this section in the same manner as such subsections apply to in-kind consideration and money rentals received pursuant to leases entered into by that Secretary under such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>