<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2672" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2672/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2672/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2672"><akn:num>2672</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of buildings, grounds, property, and persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2672. Protection of buildings, grounds, property, and persons(a) Secretary of Defense Responsibility.—The Secretary of Defense shall protect the buildings, grounds, and property that are under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and the persons on that property.

(b) Designation of Officers and Agents.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may designate military or civilian personnel of the Department of Defense as officers and agents to perform the functions of the Secretary under subsection (a), including, with regard to civilian officers and agents, duty in areas outside the property specified in that subsection to the extent necessary to protect that property and persons on that property.

(2) A designation under paragraph (1) may be made by individual, by position, by installation, or by such other category of personnel as the Secretary determines appropriate.

(3) In making a designation under paragraph (1) with respect to any category of personnel, the Secretary shall specify each of the following:(A) The personnel or positions to be included in the category.

(B) The authorities provided for in subsection (c) that may be exercised by personnel in that category.

(C) In the case of civilian personnel in that category—(i) the authorities provided for in subsection (c), if any, that are authorized to be exercised outside the property specified in subsection (a); and

(ii) with respect to the exercise of any such authorities outside the property specified in subsection (a), the circumstances under which coordination with law enforcement officials outside of the Department of Defense should be sought in advance.



(4) The Secretary may make a designation under paragraph (1) only if the Secretary determines, with respect to the category of personnel to be covered by that designation, that—(A) the exercise of each specific authority provided for in subsection (c) to be delegated to that category of personnel is necessary for the performance</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Defense Responsibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall protect the buildings, grounds, and property that are under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and the persons on that property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Officers and Agents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to subsection (i) and to the extent specifically authorized by the Secretary of Defense, while engaged in the performance of official duties pursuant to this section, an officer or agent designated under subsection (b) may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Delegation of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The authority of the Secretary of Defense under subsections (b), (c), and (d) may be exercised only by the Secretary or the Deputy Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of Persons Arrested.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A person who is arrested pursuant to authority exercised under subsection (b) may not be held in a military confinement facility, other than in the case of a person who is subject to chapter 47 of this title (the Uniform Code of Military Justice).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities and Services of Other Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In implementing this section, when the Secretary of Defense determines it to be economical and in the public interest, the Secretary may utilize the facilities and services of Federal, State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, with the consent of those agencies, and may reimburse those agencies for the use of their facilities and services. Such services of State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement, including application of their powers of law enforcement, may be provided notwithstanding that the property is subject to the legislative jurisdiction of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority Outside Federal Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) For the protection of property under the jurisdiction, custody, or control of the Department of Defense and persons on that property, the Secretary of Defense may enter into agreements with Federal agencies and with State, Indian tribal, and local governments to obtain authority for civilian officers and agents designated under this section to enforce Federal laws and State, Indian tribal, and local laws concurrently with other Federal law enforcement officers and with State, Indian tribal, and local law enforcement officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorney General Approval.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The powers granted pursuant to subsection (c) to officers and agents designated under subsection (b) shall be exercised in accordance with guidelines approved by the Attorney General. Such guidelines may include specification of the geographical extent of property outside of the property specified in subsection (a) within which those powers may be exercised.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2672_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation With Regard to Other Federal Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for the protection of facilities (including the buildings, grounds, and properties of the General Services Administration) that are under the jurisdiction, custody, or control, in whole or in part, of a Federal agency other than the Department of Defense and that are located off of a military installation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>