<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2679" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2679/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2679/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2679"><akn:num>2679</akn:num><akn:heading>Installation-support services: intergovernmental support agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2679. Installation-support services: intergovernmental support agreements(a) In General.—(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law governing the award of Federal Government contracts for goods and services, the Secretary concerned may enter into an intergovernmental support agreement, on a sole source basis, with a State, local, or tribal government to provide, receive, or share installation-support services if the Secretary determines that the agreement will serve the best interests of the department by enhancing mission effectiveness or creating efficiencies or economies of scale, including by reducing costs.

(2) An intergovernmental support agreement under paragraph (1)—(A) may be for a term not to exceed ten years; and

(B) may use, for installation-support services provided by a State, local, or tribal government, wage grades normally paid by that State, local, or tribal government.


(3) An intergovernmental support agreement under paragraph (1) may only be used when the Secretary concerned or the State, local, or tribal government, as the case may be, providing the installation-support services already provides such services for its own use.

(4) Any contract for the provision of installation-support services awarded by the Federal Government or a State, local, or tribal government pursuant to an intergovernmental support agreement provided in subsection (a) shall be awarded on a competitive basis.


(b) Effect on First Responder Arrangements.—The authority provided by this section and limitations on the use of that authority are not intended to revoke, preclude, or otherwise interfere with existing or proposed mutual-aid agreements relating to police or fire protection services or other similar first responder agreements or arrangements.

(c) Availability of Funds.—Funds available to the Secretary concerned for operation and maintenance may be used to pay for such installation-support services. The costs of agreements under this section for any fisca</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on First Responder Arrangements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The authority provided by this section and limitations on the use of that authority are not intended to revoke, preclude, or otherwise interfere with existing or proposed mutual-aid agreements relating to police or fire protection services or other similar first responder agreements or arrangements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funds available to the Secretary concerned for operation and maintenance may be used to pay for such installation-support services. The costs of agreements under this section for any fiscal year may be paid using annual appropriations made available for that year. Funds received by the Secretary as reimbursement for providing installation-support services pursuant to such an agreement shall be credited to the appropriation or account charged with providing installation support.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on OMB Circular A-76.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned shall ensure that intergovernmental support agreements authorized by this section are not used to circumvent the requirements of Office of Management and Budget Circular A-76 regarding public-private competitions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot Program for Use of Cost Savings Realized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>