<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2680" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2680/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2680/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2680"><akn:num>2680</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum capital investment for facilities sustainment, restoration, and modernization for military d</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2680. Minimum capital investment for facilities sustainment, restoration, and modernization for military departments(a) Minimum Investment.—Beginning in fiscal year 2027, and each fiscal year thereafter, each Secretary of a military department shall—(1) calculate (in accordance with subsection (b)) the cumulative plant replacement value of the total inventory of facilities on each military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned; and

(2) invest in the budget for facilities sustainment, restoration, and modernization of that military department, a total amount equal to not less than the percentage specified in subsection (c) of the cumulative plant replacement value described in paragraph (1).


(b) Exclusion.—In making any calculation pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a), each Secretary of a military department shall exclude any facility under the jurisdiction of such Secretary that is scheduled for demolition during the two-year period beginning after the date of such calculation.

(c) Percentage Specified.—The percentage of the specified in this subsection is—(1) for fiscal year 2027, 1.75 percent;

(2) for fiscal year 2028, 2.5 percent;

(3) for fiscal year 2029, 3.25 percent; and

(4) for fiscal year 2030 and each subsequent fiscal year, 4 percent.


(d) Certification.—As part of the annual budget submission of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, each Secretary of each military department shall include—(1) a certification to the congressional defense committees that the military department is in compliance with this section; and

(2) a list of facilities under the jurisdiction of that Secretary, disaggregated by military installation and location, that are scheduled for demolition during the two-year period beginning after the date of the submission of such budget, which shall include cost and schedule estimates.


(e) Plant Replacement Value Defined.—In this section, the term “plant replacement value” means, with re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum Investment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Beginning in fiscal year 2027, and each fiscal year thereafter, each Secretary of a military department shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In making any calculation pursuant to paragraph (1) of subsection (a), each Secretary of a military department shall exclude any facility under the jurisdiction of such Secretary that is scheduled for demolition during the two-year period beginning after the date of such calculation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage Specified.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The percentage of the specified in this subsection is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) As part of the annual budget submission of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, each Secretary of each military department shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plant Replacement Value Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the term “plant replacement value” means, with respect to a facility, the cost to replace such facility using construction costs (including labor and materials) and standards (including methodologies and codes) in effect as of the date such cost is calculated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>