<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2684a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2684a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2684a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2684a"><akn:num>2684a</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements to limit encroachments and other constraints on military training, testing, and operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2684a. Agreements to limit encroachments and other constraints on military training, testing, and operations(a) Agreements Authorized.—The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may enter into an agreement with an eligible entity or entities described in subsection (b) to address the use or development of real property in the vicinity of, or ecologically related to, a military installation, as well as a State-owned National Guard installation, or military airspace for purposes of—(1) limiting any development or use of the property that would be incompatible with the mission of the installation;

(2) preserving habitat on the property in a manner that—(A) is compatible with environmental requirements; and

(B) may eliminate or relieve current or anticipated environmental restrictions that would or might otherwise restrict, impede, or otherwise interfere, whether directly or indirectly, with current or anticipated military training, testing, or operations on the installation;


(3) maintaining or improving military installation resilience; or

(4) protecting Clear Zone Areas from use or encroachment that is incompatible with the mission of the installation.


(b) Eligible Entities.—For purposes of this section, an eligible entity is any of the following:(1) A State or political subdivision of a State.

(2) A private entity that has as its stated principal organizational purpose or goal the conservation, restoration, or preservation of land and natural resources, or a similar purpose or goal, as determined by the Secretary concerned.


(c) Authority to Coordinate.—(1) In entering into an agreement under subsection (a) or undertaking a project under such agreement, the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department, as the case may be, may coordinate with any other covered official with an interest in the activities proposed to be undertaken under such agreement.

(2) In this subsection, the term “covered official” means a Secre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of a military department may enter into an agreement with an eligible entity or entities described in subsection (b) to address the use or development of real property in the vicinity of, or ecologically related to, a military installation, as well as a State-owned National Guard installation, or military airspace for purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For purposes of this section, an eligible entity is any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Coordinate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of Certain Contract Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notwithstanding chapter 63 of title 31, an agreement under this section that is a cooperative agreement or a grant may be used to acquire property or services for the direct benefit or use of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and Acceptance of Property and Interests.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of Water Rights.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The authority of the Secretary concerned to enter into an agreement under this section for the acquisition of real property (or an interest therein) includes the authority to support the purchase of water rights from any available source when necessary to support or protect the mission of a military installation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary concerned may require such additional terms and conditions in an agreement under this section as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Cooperation in Conservation and Resilience Programs to Avoid or Reduce Adverse Impacts on Military Installation Resilience and Military Readiness Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In order to facilitate interagency cooperation and enhance the effectiveness of actions that will protect the environment, military installation resilience, and military readiness, the recipient of funds provided pursuant to an agreement under this section or under the Sikes Act (16 U.S.C. 670 et seq.) may, with regard to the lands and waters within the scope of the agreement, use such funds to satisfy any matching funds or cost-sharing requirement of any conservation or resilience program of any Federal agency notwithstanding any limitation of such program on the source of matching or cost-sharing funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>