<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2687a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2687a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2687a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2687a"><akn:num>2687a</akn:num><akn:heading>Overseas base closures and realignments and status of United States overseas military locations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2687a. Overseas base closures and realignments and status of United States overseas military locations(a) Annual Report on Status of Overseas Closures and Realignments and Overseas Military Locations.—(1) At the same time that the budget is submitted under section 1105(a) of title 31 for a fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on—(A) the status of overseas base closure and realignment actions undertaken as part of a global defense posture realignment strategy; and

(B) the status of overseas military locations, whether such a location is designated as an enduring location or contingency location.


(2) To satisfy the reporting requirement specified in paragraph (1)(B), a report under paragraph (1) shall contain the following:(A) A list of overseas military locations. For any overseas military location established during the previous fiscal year, the reasons for the establishment of the overseas military location.

(B) A description of the strategic goal and operational requirements supported by each overseas military location.

(C) A list of each construction or facility improvement project carried out by the Department of Defense regardless of the funding source, and each construction or facility improvement project accepted as a payment-in-kind, at overseas military locations during the previous fiscal year if the construction or facility improvement project was not specifically authorized in a Military Construction Authorization Act or congressional notice of the construction or facility improvement project was not provided by another means. Each construction or facility improvement project on the list shall be delineated by project location, project title or description, project cost, including costs covered by the host country, and authority used to undertake the project.

(D) F</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report on Status of Overseas Closures and Realignments and Overseas Military Locations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense Overseas Military Facility Investment Recovery Account.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Amounts Corresponding to the Value of Property Purchased With Nonappropriated Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the case of a payment referred to in subsection (b)(1) for the residual value of real property or improvements at an overseas military facility, the portion of the payment that is equal to the depreciated value of the investment made with nonappropriated funds shall be deposited in the reserve account established under section 204(b)(7)(C) of the Defense Authorization Amendments and Base Closure and Realignment Act (Public Law 100–526; 10 U.S.C. 2687 note). The Secretary of Defense may use amounts in the account (in such an aggregate amount as is provided in advance by appropriation Acts) for the purpose of acquiring, constructing, or improving commissary stores and nonappropriated fund instrumentalities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>OMB Review of Proposed Overseas Basing Settlements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Oversight of Use of Payments-In-Kind for Construction or Operations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Military Construction Projects As Payments-In-Kind and In-Kind Contributions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2687a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>