<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2693" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2693/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2693/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2693"><akn:num>2693</akn:num><akn:heading>Sentinel Landscapes Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2693. Sentinel Landscapes Partnership(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the program, may establish and carry out a program to preserve and restore sentinel landscapes. The program shall be known as the “Sentinel Landscapes Partnership”.

(b) Designation of Sentinel Landscapes.—The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership may, as such Secretaries and other heads determine appropriate, collectively designate one or more sentinel landscapes.

(c) Coordination of Activities.—In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may coordinate actions between their departments and agencies and with other Federal, State, interstate, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, and private entities to more efficiently work together for the mutual benefit of conservation, resilience, working lands, and national defense, and to encourage owners and managers of land to engage in voluntary land management, resilience, and conservation activities that contribute to the sustainment of military installations, State-owned National Guard installations, and associated airspace.

(d) Priority Consideration.—In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may give to any eligible owner or manager of land within a designated sentinel landscape priority consideration for participation in any easement, grant, or assistance program administered by that Secretary or head. Participation by an eligible owner or manager of land in any such program pursuant to this section shall be voluntary.

(e) Participation by Other Agencies.—Other Federal agenci</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the program, may establish and carry out a program to preserve and restore sentinel landscapes. The program shall be known as the “Sentinel Landscapes Partnership”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Sentinel Landscapes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the heads of other Federal departments and agencies that elect to become full partners in the Sentinel Landscapes Partnership may, as such Secretaries and other heads determine appropriate, collectively designate one or more sentinel landscapes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may coordinate actions between their departments and agencies and with other Federal, State, interstate, and local agencies, Indian Tribes, and private entities to more efficiently work together for the mutual benefit of conservation, resilience, working lands, and national defense, and to encourage owners and managers of land to engage in voluntary land management, resilience, and conservation activities that contribute to the sustainment of military installations, State-owned National Guard installations, and associated airspace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In carrying out this section, the Secretaries and the other heads of Federal departments and agencies may give to any eligible owner or manager of land within a designated sentinel landscape priority consideration for participation in any easement, grant, or assistance program administered by that Secretary or head. Participation by an eligible owner or manager of land in any such program pursuant to this section shall be voluntary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by Other Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other Federal agencies with programs addressing conservation or resilience may, and are encouraged to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section may be construed to require an owner or manager of land, including a private landowner or agricultural producer, to participate in any land management, resilience, or conservation activity under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2693_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>