<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2694a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2694a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2694a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2694a"><akn:num>2694a</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of surplus real property for natural resource conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2694a. Conveyance of surplus real property for natural resource conservation(a) Authority to Convey.—The Secretary of a military department may convey to an eligible entity described in subsection (b) any surplus real property that—(1) is under the administrative control of the Secretary;

(2) is suitable and desirable for conservation purposes;

(3) has been made available for public benefit transfer for a sufficient period of time to potential claimants; and

(4) is not subject to a pending request for transfer to another Federal agency or for conveyance to any other qualified recipient for public benefit transfer under the real property disposal processes and authorities under subtitle I of title 40.


(b) Eligible Entities.—The conveyance of surplus real property under this section may be made to any of the following:(1) A State or political subdivision of a State.

(2) A nonprofit organization that exists for the primary purpose of conservation of natural resources on real property.


(c) Reversionary Interest and Other Deed Requirements.—(1) The deed of conveyance of any surplus real property conveyed under this section shall require the property to be used and maintained for the conservation of natural resources in perpetuity. If the Secretary concerned determines at any time that the property is not being used or maintained for such purpose, then, at the option of the Secretary, all or any portion of the property shall revert to the United States.

(2) The deed of conveyance may permit the recipient of the property—(A) to convey the property to another eligible entity, subject to the approval of the Secretary concerned and subject to the same covenants and terms and conditions as provided in the deed from the United States; and

(B) to conduct incidental revenue-producing activities on the property that are compatible with the use of the property for conservation purposes.


(3) The deed of conveyance may contain such additional terms, reservations, restri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Convey.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of a military department may convey to an eligible entity described in subsection (b) any surplus real property that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The conveyance of surplus real property under this section may be made to any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversionary Interest and Other Deed Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of Covenants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) With the concurrence of the Secretary of Interior, the Secretary concerned may grant a release from a covenant included in the deed of conveyance of real property conveyed under this section, subject to the condition that the recipient of the property pay the fair market value, as determined by the Secretary concerned, of the property at the time of the release of the covenant. The Secretary concerned may reduce the amount required to be paid under this subsection to account for the value of the natural resource conservation benefit that has accrued to the United States during the period the covenant was in effect, if the benefit was not taken into account in determining the original consideration for the conveyance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Wait Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary concerned may not approve of the reconveyance of real property under subsection (c) or grant the release of a covenant under subsection (d) until after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title, to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice of the proposed reconveyance or release.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The conveyance of real property under this section shall not be used as a condition of allowing any defense activity under any Federal, State, or local permitting or review process. The Secretary concerned may make the conveyance, with the restrictions specified in subsection (c), to establish a mitigation bank, but only if the establishment of the mitigation bank does not occur in order to satisfy any condition for permitting military activity under a Federal, State, or local permitting or review process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In fixing the consideration for the conveyance of real property under this section, or in determining the amount of any reduction of the amount to be paid for the release of a covenant under subsection (d), the Secretary concerned shall take into consideration any benefit that has accrued or may accrue to the United States from the use of such property for the conservation of natural resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Other Conveyance Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2694a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>