<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2703" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2703/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2703/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2703"><akn:num>2703</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental restoration accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2703. Environmental restoration accounts(a) Establishment of Accounts.—There are hereby established in the Department of Defense the following accounts:(1) An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Defense”.

(2) An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Army”.

(3) An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Navy”.

(4) An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Air Force”.

(5) An account to be known as the “Environmental Restoration Account, Formerly Used Defense Sites”.


(b) Program Elements for Ordnance Remediation.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program element for remediation of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents within each environmental restoration account established under subsection (a). In this subsection, the terms “discarded military munitions” and “munitions constituents” have the meanings given such terms in section 2710 of this title.

(c) Obligation of Authorized Amounts.—(1) Funds authorized for deposit in an account under subsection (a) may be obligated or expended from the account only to carry out the environmental restoration functions of the Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military departments under this chapter and under any other provision of law.

(2) Funds authorized for deposit in an account under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.


(d) Budget Reports.—In proposing the budget for any fiscal year pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the President shall set forth separately the amounts requested for environmental restoration programs of the Department of Defense and of each of the military departments under this chapter and under any other Act.

(e) Credit of Amounts Recovered.—The following amounts shall be credited to the appropriate environmental restoration account:(1) Amounts recovered under CERCLA for response actions.

(2) Any other amounts recover</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Accounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There are hereby established in the Department of Defense the following accounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Elements for Ordnance Remediation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program element for remediation of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents within each environmental restoration account established under subsection (a). In this subsection, the terms “discarded military munitions” and “munitions constituents” have the meanings given such terms in section 2710 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation of Authorized Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In proposing the budget for any fiscal year pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, the President shall set forth separately the amounts requested for environmental restoration programs of the Department of Defense and of each of the military departments under this chapter and under any other Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit of Amounts Recovered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The following amounts shall be credited to the appropriate environmental restoration account:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments of Fines and Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) None of the funds appropriated to the Environmental Restoration Account, Defense, or to any environmental restoration account of a military department, may be used for the payment of a fine or penalty (including any supplemental environmental project carried out as part of such penalty) imposed against the Department of Defense or a military department unless the act or omission for which the fine or penalty is imposed arises out of an activity funded by the environmental restoration account concerned and the payment of the fine or penalty has been specifically authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sole Source of Funds for Operation and Monitoring of Environmental Remedies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2703_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sole Source of Funds for Environmental Remediation at Certain Base Realignment and Closure Sites.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In the case of property disposed of pursuant to a base closure law and subject to a covenant that was required to be provided by paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 120(h) of CERCLA (42 U.S.C. 9620(h)), the sole source of funds for services procured under section 2701(d)(1) of this title shall be the Department of Defense Base Closure Account established under section 2906 of the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 (part A of title XXIX of Public Law 101–510; 10 U.S.C. 2687 note). The limitation in this subsection shall expire upon the closure of such base closure account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>