<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2705"><akn:num>2705</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of environmental restoration activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2705. Notice of environmental restoration activities(a) Expedited Notice.—The Secretary of Defense shall take such actions as necessary to ensure that the regional offices of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate State and local authorities for the State in which a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction is located receive prompt notice of each of the following:(1) The discovery of releases or threatened releases of hazardous substances at the facility.

(2) The extent of the threat to public health and the environment which may be associated with any such release or threatened release.

(3) Proposals made by the Secretary to carry out response actions with respect to any such release or threatened release.

(4) The initiation of any response action with respect to such release or threatened release and the commencement of each distinct phase of such activities.


(b) Comment by EPA and State and Local Authorities.—(1) Release notices.—The Secretary shall ensure that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate State and local officials have an adequate opportunity to comment on notices under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a).

(2) Proposals for response actions.—The Secretary shall require that an adequate opportunity for timely review and comment be afforded to the Administrator and to appropriate State and local officials after making a proposal referred to in subsection (a)(3) and before undertaking an activity or action referred to in subsection (a)(4). The preceding sentence does not apply if the action is an emergency removal taken because of imminent and substantial endangerment to human health or the environment and consultation would be impractical.


(c) Technical Review Committee.—Whenever possible and practical, the Secretary shall establish a technical review committee to review and comment on Department of Defense actions and proposed actions with respect to releases or threatened releases of haza</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall take such actions as necessary to ensure that the regional offices of the Environmental Protection Agency and appropriate State and local authorities for the State in which a facility under the Secretary’s jurisdiction is located receive prompt notice of each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comment by EPA and State and Local Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Review Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever possible and practical, the Secretary shall establish a technical review committee to review and comment on Department of Defense actions and proposed actions with respect to releases or threatened releases of hazardous substances at installations. Members of any such committee shall include at least one representative of the Secretary, the Administrator, and appropriate State and local authorities and shall include a public representative of the community involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restoration Advisory Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Involvement in Defense Environmental Restoration Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If a technical review committee or restoration advisory board is established with respect to an installation (or group of installations), the Secretary shall consult with and seek the advice of the committee or board on the following issues:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2705_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary shall, to the extent provided in appropriations Acts, make funds available for administrative expenses and technical assistance under this section using funds in the following accounts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>