<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2710"><akn:num>2710</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents at defens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2710. Inventory of unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents at defense sites (other than operational ranges)(a) Inventory Required.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall develop and maintain an inventory of defense sites that are known or suspected to contain unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents.

(2) The information in the inventory for each defense site shall include, at a minimum, the following:(A) A unique identifier for the defense site.

(B) An appropriate record showing the location, boundaries, and extent of the defense site, including identification of the State and political subdivisions of the State, including the county, where applicable, in which the defense site is located and any Tribal lands encompassed by the defense site.

(C) Known persons and entities, other than a military department, with any current ownership interest or control of lands encompassed by the defense site.

(D) Any restrictions or other land use controls currently in place at the defense site that might affect the potential for public and environmental exposure to the unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, or munitions constituents.



(b) Site Prioritization.—(1) The Secretary shall develop, in consultation with representatives of the States and Indian Tribes, a proposed protocol for assigning to each defense site a relative priority for response activities related to unexploded ordnance, discarded military munitions, and munitions constituents based on the overall conditions at the defense site. After public notice and comment on the proposed protocol, the Secretary shall issue a final protocol and shall apply the protocol to defense sites listed on the inventory. The level of response priority assigned the site shall be included with the information required by subsection (a)(2).

(2) In assigning the response priority for a defense site on the inventory, the Secretary shall primarily consi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Site Prioritization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates and Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section does not apply to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2710_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>