<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2715" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2715/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2715/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2715"><akn:num>2715</akn:num><akn:heading>Testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at military installations and f</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2715. Testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at military installations and facilities of the National Guard(a) In General.—Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, the Secretary of Defense shall complete preliminary assessment and site inspection testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at all military installations and facilities of the National Guard located in the United States that are identified as of March 31, 2021, as having a release of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.

(b) Determination of Contamination.—Testing conducted under subsection (a) at a military installation or facility of the National Guard shall determine—(1) whether the installation or facility has contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance; and

(2) whether activities in connection with such installation or facility have caused contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance outside of such installation or facility.


(c) Additional Response Actions.—Testing conducted under subsection (a) shall provide at least a preliminary basis for determining whether additional environmental response actions are necessary to address contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance.

(d) Type of Testing.—When testing for perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances under subsection (a) or any other provision of law, the Secretary shall use a method to measure for all perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances in drinking water that has been validated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.

(e) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “military installation” has the meaning given such term in section 2801(c)(4) of this title.

(2) The terms “perfluoroalkyl substance” and “polyfluoroalkyl substance” have the meanings </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, the Secretary of Defense shall complete preliminary assessment and site inspection testing for perfluoroalkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances at all military installations and facilities of the National Guard located in the United States that are identified as of March 31, 2021, as having a release of perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Contamination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Testing conducted under subsection (a) at a military installation or facility of the National Guard shall determine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Response Actions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Testing conducted under subsection (a) shall provide at least a preliminary basis for determining whether additional environmental response actions are necessary to address contamination from a perfluoroalkyl substance or polyfluoroalkyl substance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type of Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) When testing for perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances under subsection (a) or any other provision of law, the Secretary shall use a method to measure for all perfluoroalkyl substances or polyfluoroalkyl substances in drinking water that has been validated by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2715_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>