<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2733a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2733a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2733a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2733a"><akn:num>2733a</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical malpractice claims by members of the uniformed services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2733a. Medical malpractice claims by members of the uniformed services(a) In General.—Consistent with this section and under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe under subsection (h), the Secretary may allow, settle, and pay a claim against the United States for personal injury or death incident to the service of a member of the uniformed services that was caused by the medical malpractice of a Department of Defense health care provider.

(b) Requirement for Claims.—A claim may be allowed, settled, and paid under subsection (a) only if—(1) the claim is filed by the member of the uniformed services who is the subject of the medical malpractice claimed, or by an authorized representative on behalf of such member who is deceased or otherwise unable to file the claim due to incapacitation;

(2) the claim is for personal injury or death caused by the negligent or wrongful act or omission of a Department of Defense health care provider in the performance of medical, dental, or related health care functions while such provider was acting within the scope of employment;

(3) the act or omission constituting medical malpractice occurred in a covered military medical treatment facility;

(4) the claim is presented to the Department in writing within two years after the claim accrues;

(5) the claim is not allowed to be settled and paid under any other provision of law; and

(6) the claim is substantiated as prescribed in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense under subsection (h).


(c) Liability.—(1) The Department of Defense is liable for only the portion of compensable injury, loss, or damages attributable to the medical malpractice of a Department of Defense health care provider.

(2) The Department of Defense shall not be liable for the attorney fees of a claimant under this section.


(d) Payment of Claims.—(1) If the Secretary of Defense determines, pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary under subsection (h), that a cl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consistent with this section and under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe under subsection (h), the Secretary may allow, settle, and pay a claim against the United States for personal injury or death incident to the service of a member of the uniformed services that was caused by the medical malpractice of a Department of Defense health care provider.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A claim may be allowed, settled, and paid under subsection (a) only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Medical Malpractice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than 30 days after a determination of medical malpractice or the payment of all or part of a claim under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Director of the Defense Health Agency a report documenting such determination or payment to be used by the Director for all necessary and appropriate purposes, including medical quality assurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Justification of Denial.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) If a claim under this section is denied, the Secretary of Defense shall provide the claimant with detailed reasoning justifying the denial of the claim, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expert Medical Opinions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In using an expert medical opinion to evaluate a claim under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall use the opinion of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Attorney Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2733a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Not less frequently than annually until 2028, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on claims processed under this section that includes, with respect to the period covered by the report, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>