<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2775" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2775/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2775/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2775"><akn:num>2775</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of members assigned to military housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2775. Liability of members assigned to military housing(a)(1) A member of the armed forces shall be liable to the United States for damage to any family housing unit or unaccompanied personnel housing unit, or damage to or loss of any equipment or furnishings of any family housing unit or unaccompanied personnel housing unit, assigned to or provided such member if (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) the damage or loss was caused by the abuse or negligence of the member (or a dependent of the member) or of a guest of the member (or a dependent of the member).

(2) A member of the armed forces—(A) who is assigned or provided a family housing unit; and

(B) who fails to clean satisfactorily that housing unit (as determined under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy) upon termination of the assignment or provision of that housing unit,


shall be liable to the United States for the cost of cleaning made necessary as a result of that failure.


(b) The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may establish limitations on liability under this section, including (in the case of liability under subsection (a)(1)) different limitations based upon the degree of abuse or negligence involved, and may compromise or waive a claim of the United States under this section.

(c)(1) The Secretary concerned may deduct from a member’s pay an amount sufficient to pay for the cost of any repair or replacement made necessary as the result of any abuse or negligence referred to in subsection (a)(1), or the cost of any cleaning made necessary by a failure to clean satisfactorily a family housing unit re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2775_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2775_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, may establish limitations on liability under this section, including (in the case of liability under subsection (a)(1)) different limitations based upon the degree of abuse or negligence involved, and may compromise or waive a claim of the United States under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2775_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2775_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts received under this section shall be credited to the family housing operations and maintenance account, in the case of damage to a family housing unit (or the equipment or furnishings of a family housing unit) or failure to clean satisfactorily a family housing unit, or to the operations and maintenance account, in the case of damage to an unaccompanied personnel housing unit (or the equipment or furnishings of an unaccompanied personnel housing unit), of the military department or defense agency concerned, or the operating expenses account of the Coast Guard, as appropriate. Amounts so credited shall be available for use for the same purposes and under the same circumstances as other funds in those accounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2775_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of Homeland Security with respect to the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Such regulations shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>