<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2784a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2784a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2784a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2784a"><akn:num>2784a</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of travel cards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2784a. Management of travel cards(a) Disbursement of Travel Allowances Directly to Creditors.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall require that any part of a travel or transportation allowance of an employee of the Department of Defense or a member of the armed forces be disbursed directly to the issuer of a Defense travel card if the amount is disbursed to the issuer in payment of amounts of expenses of official travel that are charged by the employee or member on the Defense travel card.

(2) The Secretary of Defense may waive the requirement for a direct payment to a travel card issuer under paragraph (1) in any case the Secretary determines appropriate.

(3) For the purposes of this subsection, the travel and transportation allowances referred to in paragraph (1) are amounts to which an employee of the Department of Defense is entitled under section 5702 of title 5 or a member of the armed forces is entitled under section 452 of title 37.


(b) Offsets for Delinquent Travel Card Charges.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may require that there be deducted and withheld from any basic pay payable to an employee of the Department of Defense or a member of the armed forces any amount that is owed by the employee or member to a creditor by reason of one or more charges of expenses of official travel of the employee or member on a Defense travel card issued by the creditor if the employee or member—(A) is delinquent in the payment of such amount under the terms of the contract under which the card is issued; and

(B) does not dispute the amount of the delinquency.


(2) The amount deducted and withheld from pay under paragraph (1) with respect to a debt owed a creditor as described in that paragraph shall be disbursed to the creditor to reduce the amount of the debt.

(3) The amount of pay deducted and withheld from the pay owed to an employee or member with respect to a pay period under paragraph (1) may not exceed 15 percent of the disposable pay of the employee or membe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement of Travel Allowances Directly to Creditors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offsets for Delinquent Travel Card Charges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offsets of Retired Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the case of a former employee of the Department of Defense or a retired member of the armed forces who is receiving retired pay and who owes an amount to a creditor by reason of one or more charges on a Defense travel card that were made before the retirement of the employee or member, the Secretary may require amounts to be deducted and withheld from any retired pay of the former employee or retired member in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as the Secretary deducts and withholds amounts from basic pay payable to an employee or member under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Creditworthiness for Issuance of Defense Travel Card.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations on Disciplinary Action.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2784a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of Coast Guard.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) This section does not apply to the Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>