<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2790" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2790/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2790/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2790"><akn:num>2790</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of improperly disposed of Department of Defense property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2790. Recovery of improperly disposed of Department of Defense property(a) Prohibition.—No member of the armed forces, civilian employee of the United States Government, contractor personnel, or other person may sell, lend, pledge, barter, or give any clothing, arms, articles, equipment, or other military or Department of Defense property except in accordance with the statutes and regulations governing Government property.

(b) Transfer of Title or Interest Ineffective.—If property has been disposed of in violation of subsection (a), the person holding the property has no right or title to, or interest in, the property.

(c) Authority for Seizure of Improperly Disposed of Property.—If any person is in the possession of military or Department of Defense property without right or title to, or interest in, the property because it has been disposed of in material violation of subsection (a), any Federal, State, or local law enforcement official may seize the property wherever found. Unless an exception to the warrant requirement under the fourth amendment to the Constitution applies, seizure may be made only—(1) pursuant to—(A) a warrant issued by the district court of the United States for the district in which the property is located, or for the district in which the person in possession of the property resides or is subject to service; or

(B) pursuant to an order by such court, issued after a determination of improper transfer under subsection (e); and


(2) after such a court has issued such a warrant or order.


(d) Inapplicability to Certain Property.—Subsections (b) and (c) shall not apply to—(1) property on public display by public or private collectors or museums in secured exhibits; or

(2) property in the collection of any museum or veterans organization or held in a private collection for the purpose of public display, provided that any such property, the possession of which could undermine national security or create a hazard to public health or safety, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) No member of the armed forces, civilian employee of the United States Government, contractor personnel, or other person may sell, lend, pledge, barter, or give any clothing, arms, articles, equipment, or other military or Department of Defense property except in accordance with the statutes and regulations governing Government property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Title or Interest Ineffective.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If property has been disposed of in violation of subsection (a), the person holding the property has no right or title to, or interest in, the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for Seizure of Improperly Disposed of Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If any person is in the possession of military or Department of Defense property without right or title to, or interest in, the property because it has been disposed of in material violation of subsection (a), any Federal, State, or local law enforcement official may seize the property wherever found. Unless an exception to the warrant requirement under the fourth amendment to the Constitution applies, seizure may be made only—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to Certain Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subsections (b) and (c) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Violations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of Seized Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Any law enforcement official who seizes property under subsection (c) and is not authorized to retain it for the United States shall deliver the property to an authorized member of the armed forces or other authorized official of the Department of Defense or the Department of Justice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Enforcement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) This section shall apply to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The authority of this section is in addition to any other authority of the United States with respect to property to which the United States may have right or title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2790_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>