<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/281" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/281/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/281/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_281"><akn:num>281</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of equipment by State and local governments through the Department of Defense: equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 281. Procurement of equipment by State and local governments through the Department of Defense: equipment for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities(a) Procedures.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures in accordance with this subsection under which States and units of local government may purchase equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities through the Department of Defense. The procedures shall require the following:(A) Each State desiring to participate in a procurement of equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, or emergency response activities through the Department of Defense shall submit to the Department, in such form and manner and at such times as the Secretary prescribes, the following:(i) A request for equipment.

(ii) Advance payment for such equipment, in an amount determined by the Secretary based on estimated or actual costs of the equipment and administrative costs incurred by the Department.


(B) A State may include in a request submitted under subparagraph (A) only the type of equipment listed in the catalog produced under subsection (c).

(C) A request for equipment shall consist of an enumeration of the equipment that is desired by the State and units of local government within the State. The Governor of a State may establish such procedures as the Governor considers appropriate for administering and coordinating requests for equipment from units of local government within the State.

(D) A State requesting equipment shall be responsible for arranging and paying for shipment of the equipment to the State and localities within the State.


(2) In establishing the procedures, the Secretary of Defense shall coordinate with the General Services Administration and other Federal agencies for purposes of avoiding duplication of effort.


(b) Reimbursement of Administrative Costs.—In the case of any purchase made by a State or unit of local gover</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Administrative Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In the case of any purchase made by a State or unit of local government under the procedures established under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall require the State or unit of local government to reimburse the Department of Defense for the administrative costs to the Department of such purchase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>GSA Catalog.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator of General Services, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall produce and maintain a catalog of equipment suitable for counter-drug, homeland security, and emergency response activities for purchase by States and units of local government under the procedures established by the Secretary under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_281_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>