<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2815a"><akn:num>2815a</akn:num><akn:heading>Stormwater management, shoreline erosion control, and water resilience projects for installations an</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2815a. Stormwater management, shoreline erosion control, and water resilience projects for installations and defense access roads(a) Projects Authorized.—The Secretary concerned may carry out one or more of the following projects on or related to a military installation:(1) A stormwater management project for the purposes of—(A) improving military installation resilience or the resilience of a defense access road or other essential civilian infrastructure supporting a military installation; and

(B) protecting nearby waterways and stormwater-stressed ecosystems.


(2) A shoreline erosion control project for the purpose of improving, protecting, or repairing shoreline to protect the infrastructure of a military installation or a defense access road.

(3) A project to provide water storage and filtration, flood mitigation, or otherwise support water resilience.


(b) Project Methods and Funding Sources.—Using such amounts as may be provided in advance in appropriation Acts, the Secretary concerned may carry out a project under this section as, or as part of, any of the following:(1) An authorized military construction project.

(2) An unspecified minor military construction project under section 2805 of this title, including using appropriations available for operation and maintenance subject to the limitation in subsection (c) of such section.

(3) A military installation resilience project under section 2815 of this title, including the use of appropriations available for operations and maintenance subject to the limitation of subsection (e)(3) of such section.

(4) A defense community infrastructure resilience project under section 2391(d) of this title.

(5) A military installation resilience project under section 2684a of this title.

(6) A construction project under section 2914 of this title.

(7) A reserve component facility project under section 18233 of this title.

(8) A defense access road project under section 210 of title 23.


(c) Project Priorities.—</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may carry out one or more of the following projects on or related to a military installation:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Methods and Funding Sources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Using such amounts as may be provided in advance in appropriation Acts, the Secretary concerned may carry out a project under this section as, or as part of, any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Priorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In selecting projects to be carried out under this section, the Secretary concerned shall give a priority to a project proposal that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities carried out as part of a project under this section may include, but are not limited to, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>