<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2815/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2815"><akn:num>2815</akn:num><akn:heading>Military installation resilience projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2815. Military installation resilience projects(a) Projects Required.—The Secretary of Defense shall carry out military construction projects for military installation resilience, in accordance with section 2802 of this title (except as provided in subsections (d)(3) and (e)).

(b) Congressional Notification.—(1) When a decision is made to carry out a project under this section, the Secretary of Defense shall notify the congressional defense committees of that decision.

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall include in each notification submitted under paragraph (1) the rationale for how the project would—(A) enhance military installation resilience;

(B) enhance mission assurance;

(C) support mission critical functions; and

(D) address known vulnerabilities.



(c) Timing of Projects.—Except as provided in subsection (e)(2), a project may be carried out under this section only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date that notification with respect to that project under subsection (b) is received by the congressional defense committees in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title.

(d) Location of Projects.—Projects carried out pursuant to this section may be carried out—(1) on a military installation;

(2) on a facility used by the Department of Defense that is owned and operated by a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands, even if the facility is not under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense, if the Secretary of Defense determines that the facility is subject to significant use by the armed forces for testing or training; or

(3) outside of a military installation or facility described in paragraph (2) if the Secretary concerned determines that the project would preserve or enhance the resilience of—(A) a military installation;

(B) a facility described in paragraph (2); or

(C) community infrastructur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall carry out military construction projects for military installation resilience, in accordance with section 2802 of this title (except as provided in subsections (d)(3) and (e)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Except as provided in subsection (e)(2), a project may be carried out under this section only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date that notification with respect to that project under subsection (b) is received by the congressional defense committees in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects carried out pursuant to this section may be carried out—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Funding Source.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2815_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year until December 31, 2025, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the status of the planned and active projects carried out under this section (including completed projects), and shall include in the report with respect to each such project the following information:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>