<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2819" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2819/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2819/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2819"><akn:num>2819</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy and assessment with respect to non-operational, underutilized, and other Department of Defe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2819. Strategy and assessment with respect to non-operational, underutilized, and other Department of Defense facilities: assessments of historical significance(a) Strategy for Demolition.—Each Secretary concerned shall develop a strategy to demolish facilities under the respective jurisdiction of each such Secretary that—(1) are in poor or failing condition under the uniform index developed under section 2838 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 (Public Law 118–31);

(2) are not in operational use; or

(3) such Secretary determines are underutilized.


(b) Assessment of Certain Maintenance Costs.—Each Secretary concerned shall conduct an assessment to determine the total cost to the United States to maintain facilities that—(1) are not in operational use; and

(2) such Secretary determines are underutilized.


(c) Required Consideration.—In determining whether a facility is underutilized pursuant to subsections (a) or (b), each Secretary concerned shall compare the occupancy of such facility to the total square footage of such facility.

(d) Assessments of Historic Significance.—(1) Not later than December 1, 2025, and on an annual basis thereafter, each Secretary concerned shall conduct an assessment of each facility under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned that was constructed at least 25 years prior to the year covered by the assessment to determine whether the facility—(A) is historically significant; or

(B) will be historically significant at the end of the 25-year period beginning on the date of the completion of such assessment.


(2) For each facility described in paragraph (1) that a Secretary concerned determines is not, or will not be, historically significant pursuant to an assessment under such paragraph, the Secretary concerned shall—(A) conduct an assessment of the condition of such facility;

(B) make an initial determination of whether such facility will be modernized or demolished during such 25-year period; a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2819_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy for Demolition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each Secretary concerned shall develop a strategy to demolish facilities under the respective jurisdiction of each such Secretary that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2819_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of Certain Maintenance Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each Secretary concerned shall conduct an assessment to determine the total cost to the United States to maintain facilities that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2819_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In determining whether a facility is underutilized pursuant to subsections (a) or (b), each Secretary concerned shall compare the occupancy of such facility to the total square footage of such facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2819_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments of Historic Significance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2819_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Briefing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>