<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2827" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2827/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2827/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2827"><akn:num>2827</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation of military family housing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2827. Relocation of military family housing units(a) Relocation Authority.—Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary concerned may relocate existing military family housing units from any location where the number of such units exceeds requirements for military family housing to any military installation where there is a housing shortage.

(b) Notice and Wait Requirements.—A contract to carry out a relocation of military family housing units under subsection (a) may be awarded only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary concerned submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title, to the appropriate committees of Congress notice of the proposed new locations of the housing units to be relocated and the estimated cost of and source of funds for the relocation.

(Added Pub. L. 97–214, § 2(a), July 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 160; amended Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title X, § 1031(a)(42), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1602; Pub. L. 115–91, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2801(b)(2), Dec. 12, 2017, 131 Stat. 1842.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2017—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(b)(2)(A), inserted heading.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 115–91, § 2801(b)(2)(B), added subsec. (b) and struck out former subsec. (b) which read as follows: “A contract to carry out a relocation of military family housing units under subsection (a) may not be awarded until (1) the Secretary concerned has notified the appropriate committees of Congress of the proposed new locations of the housing units to be relocated and the estimated cost of and source of funds for the relocation, and (2) a period of 21 days has elapsed after the notification has been received by those committees or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days has elapsed after the date on which a copy of the notification is provided in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title.”
2003—Subsec. (b)(2). Pub. L. 108–136 inserted before period at end “or, if over sooner, a period of 14 days </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2827_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relocation Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (b), the Secretary concerned may relocate existing military family housing units from any location where the number of such units exceeds requirements for military family housing to any military installation where there is a housing shortage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2827_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Wait Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A contract to carry out a relocation of military family housing units under subsection (a) may be awarded only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary concerned submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title, to the appropriate committees of Congress notice of the proposed new locations of the housing units to be relocated and the estimated cost of and source of funds for the relocation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>