<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2851"><akn:num>2851</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of military construction projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2851. Supervision of military construction projects(a) Supervision of Military Department Projects.—Each contract entered into by the United States in connection with a military construction project or a military family housing project shall be carried out under the direction and supervision of the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers), the Secretary of the Navy (acting through the Commander of the Naval Facilities Engineering Command), or such other department or Government agency as the Secretary of Defense approves to assure the most efficient, expeditious, and cost-effective completion of the project.

(b) Supervision of Defense Agency Projects.—A military construction project for an activity or agency of the Department of Defense (other than a military department) financed from appropriations for military functions of the Department of Defense shall be accomplished by or through a military department designated by the Secretary of Defense.

(c) Maintenance of Military Construction Information on Internet; Access.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall maintain an Internet site that will permit a person to access and view on a separate page of the Internet site a document or other file containing the information required by paragraph (2) for the following:(A) Each military construction project or military family housing project that has been specifically authorized by Act of Congress.

(B) Each project carried out with funds authorized for the operation and maintenance of military family housing.

(C) Each project carried out with funds authorized for the improvement of military family housing units.

(D) Each unspecified minor construction project carried out under the authority of section 2805(a) of this title.

(E) Each military department project with a total cost in excess of $15,000,000 for Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization.

(F) Each military construction project, military department Facilities Sustainment, Resto</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of Military Department Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each contract entered into by the United States in connection with a military construction project or a military family housing project shall be carried out under the direction and supervision of the Secretary of the Army (acting through the Chief of Engineers), the Secretary of the Navy (acting through the Commander of the Naval Facilities Engineering Command), or such other department or Government agency as the Secretary of Defense approves to assure the most efficient, expeditious, and cost-effective completion of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of Defense Agency Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A military construction project for an activity or agency of the Department of Defense (other than a military department) financed from appropriations for military functions of the Department of Defense shall be accomplished by or through a military department designated by the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of Military Construction Information on Internet; Access.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on Supervision of Large Military Construction Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Before the award of a contract of a value greater than $500,000,000 in connection with a military construction project, the individual directing and supervising such military construction project under subsection (a) or the individual designated pursuant to subsection (b) (as applicable) shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the intended supervision, inspection, and overhead plan to manage such military construction project. Each such report shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report on Schedule Delays.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than March 1 of each year (beginning with 2018), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and Senate a report on each military construction project or military family housing project for which, as of the end of the most recent fiscal year, the estimated completion date is more than 1 year later than the completion date proposed at the time the contract for the project was awarded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>