<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2851a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2851a"><akn:num>2851a</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision of military housing by Chief Housing Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2851a. Supervision of military housing by Chief Housing Officer(a) In General.—The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall serve as the Chief Housing Officer, who shall oversee family housing and military unaccompanied housing under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or acquired or constructed under subchapter IV of this chapter (in this section referred to as “covered housing units”).

(b) Principal Duties.—(1) The Chief Housing Officer shall oversee all aspects of the provision of covered housing units, including the following:(A) Creation and standardization of policies and processes regarding covered housing units.

(B) Oversight of the administration of any Department of Defense-wide policies regarding covered housing units, to include, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, the housing documents developed pursuant to section 2890 of this title entitled Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights and Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities.


(2) The duties specified in paragraph (1) may not be further delegated.


(Added Pub. L. 116–92, div. B, title XXX, § 3012(a), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1921, § 2890a; renumbered § 2851a and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2811(a), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4323; Pub. L. 117–263, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2807, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 2995.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2022—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 117–263 amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:
“(1) The Secretary of Defense shall designate, from among officials of the Department of Defense who are appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate, a Chief Housing Officer who shall oversee family housing and military unaccompanied housing under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or acquired or constructed under subchapter IV of this chapter (in this section referred to as ‘covere</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment shall serve as the Chief Housing Officer, who shall oversee family housing and military unaccompanied housing under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense or acquired or constructed under subchapter IV of this chapter (in this section referred to as “covered housing units”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2851a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>