<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2854a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2854a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2854a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2854a"><akn:num>2854a</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of damaged or deteriorated military family housing; use of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2854a. Conveyance of damaged or deteriorated military family housing; use of proceeds(a) Authority To Convey.—(1) The Secretary concerned may convey any family housing facility that, due to damage or deterioration, is in a condition that is uneconomical to repair. Any conveyance of a family housing facility under this section may include a conveyance of the real property associated with the facility conveyed.

(2) The authority of this section does not apply to family housing facilities located at military installations approved for closure under a base closure law or family housing facilities located at an installation outside the United States at which the Secretary of Defense terminates operations.

(3) The aggregate total value of the family housing facilities conveyed by the Department of Defense under the authority in this subsection in any fiscal year may not exceed $5,000,000.

(4) For purposes of this subsection, a family housing facility is in a condition that is uneconomical to repair if the cost of the necessary repairs for the facility would exceed the amount equal to 70 percent of the cost of constructing a family housing facility to replace such facility.


(b) Consideration.—(1) As consideration for the conveyance of a family housing facility under subsection (a), the person to whom the facility is conveyed shall pay the United States an amount equal to the fair market value of the facility conveyed, including any real property conveyed along with the facility.

(2) The Secretary concerned shall determine the fair market value of any family housing facility and associated real property that is conveyed under subsection (a). Such determination shall be final.


(c) Notice and Wait Requirements.—(1) The Secretary concerned may enter into an agreement to convey a family housing facility under this section only after the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of thi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Convey.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Wait Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of Certain Property Disposal Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The following provisions of law do not apply to the conveyance of a family housing facility under this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Proceeds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The exact acreage and legal description of any family housing facility conveyed under this section, including any real property associated with such facility, shall be determined by such means as the Secretary concerned considers satisfactory, including by survey in the case of real property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2854a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary concerned may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the conveyance of family housing facilities under this section as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>