<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2856"><akn:num>2856</akn:num><akn:heading>Military unaccompanied housing: standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2856. Military unaccompanied housing: standards(a) Local Comparability in Floor Areas.—In the construction, acquisition, and improvement of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary concerned shall ensure that the floor areas of such housing in a particular locality (as designated by the Secretary concerned for purposes of this section) do not exceed the floor areas of similar housing in the private sector in that locality, except for purposes of meeting minimum area requirements under subsection (b)(1)(A).

(b) Floor Space and Number of Members Allowed.—In the design and configuration of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary of Defense shall establish uniform design standards that—(1) provide a minimum area of floor space, not including bathrooms or closets, per individual occupying a unit of covered military unaccompanied housing;

(2) ensure that not more than two individuals may occupy such a unit; and

(3) provide definitions and measures that specify—(A) criteria of design;

(B) quality of construction material to be used; and

(C) levels of maintenance to be required.



(c) Covered Military Unaccompanied Housing.—For purposes of this section, section 2856a, and section 2856b, the term “covered military unaccompanied housing” means Government-owned military housing intended to be occupied by members of the armed forces serving a tour of duty unaccompanied by dependents.

(Added Pub. L. 97–214, § 2(a), July 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 166; amended Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIII, § 1301(19), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1668; Pub. L. 109–364, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2807(a)(1), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2468; Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2831(a)(1), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 753; Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(a)(31), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2205.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2024—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 118–159 substituted “subsection (b)(1)(A).” for “subsection (b)(1)(A),.”.
2023—Pub. L. 118–31, § 2831(a)(1)(B)–(D), des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local Comparability in Floor Areas.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In the construction, acquisition, and improvement of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary concerned shall ensure that the floor areas of such housing in a particular locality (as designated by the Secretary concerned for purposes of this section) do not exceed the floor areas of similar housing in the private sector in that locality, except for purposes of meeting minimum area requirements under subsection (b)(1)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Floor Space and Number of Members Allowed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In the design and configuration of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary of Defense shall establish uniform design standards that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Military Unaccompanied Housing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) For purposes of this section, section 2856a, and section 2856b, the term “covered military unaccompanied housing” means Government-owned military housing intended to be occupied by members of the armed forces serving a tour of duty unaccompanied by dependents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>