<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2856b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2856b"><akn:num>2856b</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered military unaccompanied housing: standards for habitability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2856b. Covered military unaccompanied housing: standards for habitability(a) Standards Required.—For the purposes of assigning a member of the armed forces to a unit of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary of Defense shall establish uniform minimum standards for covered military unaccompanied housing, that shall include minimum requirements for—(1) condition;

(2) habitability, health, and environmental comfort;

(3) safety and security; and

(4) any other element the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.


(b) Limitation on Issuance of Waivers.—Any waiver of a uniform standard described in subsection (a) may only be issued by a Secretary of a military department.

(c) Certification.—The Secretary of Defense shall include, in conjunction with the submission of the budget of the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, a certification from each Secretary of a military department to the congressional defense committees that the cost for all needed repairs and improvements for each occupied covered military unaccompanied housing facility under the jurisdiction of such Secretary does not exceed 20 percent of the replacement cost of such facility, as mandated by Department of Defense Manual 4165.63 titled “DoD Housing Management” and dated October 28, 2010 (or a successor document).

(Added and amended Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, §§ 2832(a), 2834, Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 754, 757.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2832(a), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 754, which directed amendment of “Subchapter III of title 10” by adding this section after section 2856a of this title, was executed to subchapter III of chapter 169 of this title, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments2023—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 118–31, § 2834, added subsec. (c).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
GuidancePub. L. 118–31, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2832(b), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 754, provided that:</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of assigning a member of the armed forces to a unit of covered military unaccompanied housing, the Secretary of Defense shall establish uniform minimum standards for covered military unaccompanied housing, that shall include minimum requirements for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Issuance of Waivers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any waiver of a uniform standard described in subsection (a) may only be issued by a Secretary of a military department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2856b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall include, in conjunction with the submission of the budget of the President to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, a certification from each Secretary of a military department to the congressional defense committees that the cost for all needed repairs and improvements for each occupied covered military unaccompanied housing facility under the jurisdiction of such Secretary does not exceed 20 percent of the replacement cost of such facility, as mandated by Department of Defense Manual 4165.63 titled “DoD Housing Management” and dated October 28, 2010 (or a successor document).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>