<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2860" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2860/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2860/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2860"><akn:num>2860</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2860. Availability of appropriations
Funds appropriated to a military department or to the Secretary of Defense for a fiscal year for military construction or military family housing purposes may remain available for obligation beyond such fiscal year to the extent provided in appropriation Acts.
(Added Pub. L. 97–214, § 2(a), July 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 167; amended Pub. L. 99–167, title VIII, § 812(a), Dec. 3, 1985, 99 Stat. 991; Pub. L. 99–173, § 121(b), Dec. 10, 1985, 99 Stat. 1029; Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XIII, § 1343(a)(21)(A), Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3994.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1986—Pub. L. 99–661 substituted “to the Secretary of Defense” for “defense agency”, inserted “for obligation” after “remains available”, and struck out “the” before “appropriation Acts”.
1985—Pub. L. 99–173 substituted “Availability of appropriations” for “Availability of appropriations for five years” as section catchline, and amended text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Subject to the provisions of appropriation Acts, any funds appropriated to a military department or defense agency for the construction of military projects may be obligated for a military construction project or contract, or for any portion of such a project or contract, at any time before the end of the fourth fiscal year after the fiscal year for which funds for such project were appropriated if the funds obligated for such project (1) are obligated from funds available for military construction projects, and (2) do not exceed the amount appropriated for such project, plus any amount by which the cost of such project is increased pursuant to law.”
Pub. L. 99–167 struck out subsection designation “(a)” and “and except as otherwise provided under subsection (b)” after “provisions of appropriation Acts”, and struck out subsec. (b) which provided: “Should a requirement develop to obligate funds for a military construction project after the end of the fourth fiscal year after the fiscal </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>