<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2862"><akn:num>2862</akn:num><akn:heading>Turn-key selection procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2862. Turn-key selection procedures(a) Authority to Use for Certain Purposes.—The Secretary concerned may use one-step turn-key selection procedures for the purpose of entering into a contract for any of the following purposes:(1) The construction of an authorized military construction project.

(2) A repair project (as defined in section 2811(e) of this title) with an approved cost equal to or less than $4,000,000.11 See Temporary Expansion of Authority for Use of One-Step Turn-Key Procedures for Repair Projects note below.

(3) The construction of a facility as part of an authorized security assistance activity.


(b) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “one-step turn-key selection procedures” means procedures used for the selection of a contractor on the basis of price and other evaluation criteria to perform, in accordance with the provisions of a firm fixed-price contract, both the design and construction of a facility using performance specifications supplied by the Secretary concerned.

(2) The term “security assistance activity” means—(A) humanitarian and civic assistance authorized by sections 401 and 2561 of this title;

(B) foreign disaster assistance authorized by section 404 of this title;

(C) foreign military construction sales authorized by section 29 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2769);

(D) foreign assistance authorized under sections 607 and 632 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2357, 2392); and

(E) other international security assistance specifically authorized by law.



(Added Pub. L. 99–167, title VIII, § 807(a), Dec. 3, 1985, 99 Stat. 988; amended Pub. L. 100–26, § 7(k)(3), Apr. 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 284; Pub. L. 100–180, div. B, subdiv. 3, title I, § 2301, Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1214; Pub. L. 101–189, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2806, Nov. 29, 1989, 103 Stat. 1647; Pub. L. 102–190, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2802, Dec. 5, 1991, 105 Stat. 1537; Pub. L. 113–291, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2804, Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Use for Certain Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may use one-step turn-key selection procedures for the purpose of entering into a contract for any of the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>