<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2864" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2864/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2864/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2864"><akn:num>2864</akn:num><akn:heading>Master plans for major military installations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2864. Master plans for major military installations(a) Plans Required.—(1) At a time interval prescribed by the Secretary concerned (but not less frequently than once every 10 years), the commander of each major military installation under the jurisdiction of the Secretary shall ensure that an installation master plan is developed to address environmental planning, sustainable design and development, sustainable range planning, real property master planning, military installation resilience, and transportation planning.

(2) To address the requirements under paragraph (1), each installation master plan shall include consideration of—(A) planning for compact and infill development;

(B) horizontal and vertical mixed-use development;

(C) the full lifecycle costs of real property planning decisions;

(D) capacity planning through the establishment of growth boundaries around cantonment areas to focus development towards the core and preserve range and training space; and

(E) energy and climate resiliency efforts and military installation resilience.


(3)(A) The commander of a major military installation shall develop and update the master plan for that major military installation in consultation with representatives of the government of the State in which the installation is located and representatives of local governments in the vicinity of the installation to improve cooperation and consistency between the Department of Defense and such governments in addressing each component of the master plan described in paragraph (1).

(B) The consultation required by subparagraph (A) is in addition to the consultation specifically required by subsection (b)(1) in connection with the transportation component of the master plan for a major military installation.



(b) Transportation Component.—(1) The transportation component of the master plan for a major military installation shall be developed and updated in consultation with the metropolitan planning organization design</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation Component.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Installation Resilience Component.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To address military installation resilience under subsection (a)(1), each installation master plan shall discuss the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than March 1 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report listing all master plans completed pursuant to this section in the prior calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings Clause.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nothing in this section shall supersede the requirements of section 2859(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2864_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>