<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2875" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2875/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2875/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2875"><akn:num>2875</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2875. Investments(a) Investments Authorized.—The Secretary concerned may make investments in an eligible entity carrying out projects for the acquisition or construction of housing units suitable for use as military family housing or as military unaccompanied housing.

(b) Forms of Investment.—An investment under this section may take the form of an acquisition of a limited partnership interest by the United States, a purchase of stock or other equity instruments by the United States, a purchase of bonds or other debt instruments by the United States, or any combination of such forms of investment.

(c) Limitation on Value of Investment.—(1) The cash amount of an investment under this section in an eligible entity may not exceed an amount equal to 33⅓ percent 11 See Temporary Increase in Percentage of Value of Authorized Investment in Certain Privatized Military Housing Projects note below. of the capital cost (as determined by the Secretary concerned) of the project or projects that the eligible entity proposes to carry out under this section with the investment.

(2) If the Secretary concerned conveys land or facilities to an eligible entity as all or part of an investment in the eligible entity under this section, the total value of the investment by the Secretary under this section may not exceed an amount equal to 45 percent 1 of the capital cost (as determined by the Secretary) of the project or projects that the eligible entity proposes to carry out under this section with the investment.

(3) In this subsection, the term “capital cost”, with respect to a project for the acquisition or construction of housing, means the total amount of the costs included in the basis of the housing for Federal income tax purposes.


(d) Collateral Incentive Agreements.—The Secretary concerned shall enter into collateral incentive agreements with eligible entities in which the Secretary makes an investment under this section to ensure that a suitable preference will be affor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2875_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may make investments in an eligible entity carrying out projects for the acquisition or construction of housing units suitable for use as military family housing or as military unaccompanied housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2875_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms of Investment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An investment under this section may take the form of an acquisition of a limited partnership interest by the United States, a purchase of stock or other equity instruments by the United States, a purchase of bonds or other debt instruments by the United States, or any combination of such forms of investment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2875_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Value of Investment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2875_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collateral Incentive Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned shall enter into collateral incentive agreements with eligible entities in which the Secretary makes an investment under this section to ensure that a suitable preference will be afforded members of the armed forces and their dependents in the lease or purchase, as the case may be, of a reasonable number of the housing units covered by the investment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>