<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2878" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2878/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2878/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2878"><akn:num>2878</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance or lease of existing property and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2878. Conveyance or lease of existing property and facilities(a) Conveyance or Lease Authorized.—The Secretary concerned may convey or lease property or facilities (including ancillary supporting facilities) to eligible entities for purposes of using the proceeds of such conveyance or lease to carry out activities under this subchapter.

(b) Inapplicability to Property at Installation Approved for Closure.—The authority of this section does not apply to property or facilities located on or near a military installation approved for closure under a base closure law.

(c) Competitive Process.—The Secretary concerned shall ensure that the time, method, and terms and conditions of the reconveyance or lease of property or facilities under this section from the eligible entity permit full and free competition consistent with the value and nature of the property or facilities involved.

(d) Terms and Conditions.—(1) The conveyance or lease of property or facilities under this section shall be for such consideration and upon such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned considers appropriate for the purposes of this subchapter and to protect the interests of the United States.

(2) As part or all of the consideration for a conveyance or lease under this section, the purchaser or lessor (as the case may be) shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary to ensure that a suitable preference will be afforded members of the armed forces and their dependents in the lease or sublease of a reasonable number of the housing units covered by the conveyance or lease, as the case may be, or in the lease of other suitable housing units made available by the purchaser or lessee.


(e) Inapplicability of Certain Property Management Laws.—The conveyance or lease of property or facilities under this section shall not be subject to the following provisions of law:(1) Section 2667 of this title.

(2) Subtitle I of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance or Lease Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may convey or lease property or facilities (including ancillary supporting facilities) to eligible entities for purposes of using the proceeds of such conveyance or lease to carry out activities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability to Property at Installation Approved for Closure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The authority of this section does not apply to property or facilities located on or near a military installation approved for closure under a base closure law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned shall ensure that the time, method, and terms and conditions of the reconveyance or lease of property or facilities under this section from the eligible entity permit full and free competition consistent with the value and nature of the property or facilities involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of Certain Property Management Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The conveyance or lease of property or facilities under this section shall not be subject to the following provisions of law:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2878_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Lease Extensions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>