<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2885" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2885/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2885/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2885"><akn:num>2885</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight and accountability for privatization projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2885. Oversight and accountability for privatization projects(a) Oversight and Accountability Measures.—Each Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations to effectively oversee and manage military housing privatization projects carried out under this subchapter during the course of the construction or renovation of the housing units. The regulations shall include the following requirements for each privatization project:(1) The installation asset manager shall conduct monthly site visits and provide quarterly reports on the progress of the construction or renovation of the housing units. The reports shall be submitted quarterly to the assistant secretary for installations and environment of the respective military department.

(2) The installation asset manager, and, as applicable, the resident construction manager, privatization asset manager, bondholder representative, project owner, developer, general contractor, and construction consultant for the project shall conduct meetings to ensure that the construction or renovation of the units meets performance and schedule requirements and that appropriate operating and ground lease agreements are in place and adhered to.

(3) In the case of a project for new construction, if the project is 90 days or more behind schedule or otherwise appears to be substantially failing to adhere to the obligations or milestones under the contract, the assistant secretary for installations and environment of the respective military department shall submit a notice of deficiency to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment, the Secretary concerned, the managing member, and the trustee for the project.

(4)(A) Not later than 15 days after the submittal of a notice of deficiency under paragraph (3), the Secretary concerned or designated representative shall submit to the project owner, developer, or general contractor responsible for the project a summary of deficiencies related to the project.

(B</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight and Accountability Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations to effectively oversee and manage military housing privatization projects carried out under this subchapter during the course of the construction or renovation of the housing units. The regulations shall include the following requirements for each privatization project:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Qualifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned or designated representative shall ensure that the project owner, developer, or general contractor that is selected for each military housing privatization initiative project has construction experience commensurate with that required to complete the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonding Levels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned shall ensure that the project owner, developer, or general contractor responsible for a military housing privatization initiative project has sufficient payment and performance bonds or suitable instruments in place for each phase of a construction or renovation portion of the project to ensure successful completion of the work in amounts as agreed to in the project’s legal documents, but in no case less than 50 percent of the total value of the active phases of the project, prior to the commencement of work for that phase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of Efforts To Select Successor in Event of Default.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In the event a military housing privatization initiative project enters into default, the assistant secretary for installations and environment of the respective military department shall submit, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title, a report to the congressional defense committees every 90 days detailing the status of negotiations to award the project to a new project owner, developer, or general contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Notices of Deficiency on Contractors and Affiliated Entities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2885_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Integrity and Accountability Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>