<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2890" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2890/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2890/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2890"><akn:num>2890</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights and responsibilities of tenants of housing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2890. Rights and responsibilities of tenants of housing units(a) Development of Tenant Bill of Rights and Tenant Responsibilities Documents.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall develop two separate documents, to be known as the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights and the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities, for tenants of housing units.

(2) The Secretary of each military department shall ensure that the housing documents are attached to each lease agreement for a housing unit.

(3) The rights and responsibilities contained in the housing documents are not intended to be exclusive. The omission of a tenant right or responsibility shall not be construed to deny the existence of such a right or responsibility for tenants.

(4) Each contract between the Secretary concerned and a landlord shall incorporate the housing documents and guarantee the rights and responsibilities of tenants who reside in housing units covered by the contract.

(5) The Secretary of Defense shall develop the housing documents in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments.


(b) Elements of Tenant Bill of Rights.—At a minimum, the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights shall address the following rights of tenants of housing units:(1) The right to reside in a housing unit and community that meets applicable health and environmental standards.

(2) The right to reside in a housing unit that has working fixtures, appliances, and utilities and to reside in a community with well-maintained common areas and amenity spaces.

(3) The right to be provided with a maintenance history of the prospective housing unit before signing a lease, as provided in section 2892a of this title.

(4) The right to a written lease with clearly defined rental terms to establish tenancy in a housing unit, including any addendums and other regulations imposed by the landlord regarding occupancy of the housing unit and use o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of Tenant Bill of Rights and Tenant Responsibilities Documents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of Tenant Bill of Rights.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) At a minimum, the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Bill of Rights shall address the following rights of tenants of housing units:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of Tenant Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) At a minimum, the Military Housing Privatization Initiative Tenant Responsibilities shall address the following responsibilities of tenants of housing units:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress and Public Availability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation of Reports of Reprisals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2890_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Use of Nondisclosure Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>