<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2891a"><akn:num>2891a</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements relating to management of housing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2891a. Requirements relating to management of housing units(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each contract between the Secretary concerned and a landlord regarding the management of housing units for an installation of the Department of Defense includes the requirements set forth in this section.

(b) Requirements for Installation Commanders.—(1) The installation commander shall be responsible for—(A) reviewing, on an annual basis, the mold mitigation plan and pest control plan of each landlord managing housing units for the installation; and

(B) notifying the landlord and the major subordinate command of any deficiencies found in either plan.


(2) In response to a request by the head of the housing management office of an installation, the installation commander shall use the assigned bio-environmental personnel or contractor equivalent at the installation to test housing units for mold, unsafe water conditions, and other health and safety conditions.


(c) Requirements for Housing Management Office.—(1) The head of the housing management office of an installation shall be responsible for—(A) conducting a physical inspection of, and approving the habitability of, a vacant housing unit for the installation before the landlord managing the housing unit is authorized to offer the housing unit available for occupancy;

(B) conducting a physical inspection of the housing unit upon tenant move-out; and

(C) maintaining all test results relating to the health, environmental, and safety condition of the housing unit and the results of any inspection conducted by the housing management office, landlord, or third-party contractor for the life of the contract relating to that housing unit.


(2) The head of the installation housing management office shall be provided a list of any move-out charges that a landlord seeks to collect from an outgoing tenant.

(3) The head of the installation housing management office shall initiate contact with a tena</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that each contract between the Secretary concerned and a landlord regarding the management of housing units for an installation of the Department of Defense includes the requirements set forth in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Installation Commanders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Housing Management Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Landlords.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Secretary Concerned.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary concerned shall be responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition Against Collection of Amounts in Addition to Rent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>