<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2891/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2891"><akn:num>2891</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements relating to contracts for provision of housing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2891. Requirements relating to contracts for provision of housing units(a) In General.—The requirements of this section condition contracts entered into using the authorities provided to the Secretary concerned under section 2872 of this title and other authorities provided under subchapter IV of this chapter and this subchapter.

(b) Exclusion of Certain Employees.—A landlord providing a housing unit shall prohibit any employee of the landlord who commits work-order fraud under the contract from doing any work under the contract.

(c) Dispute Resolution Process.—Any decision the commander renders in favor of the tenant in the formal dispute resolution process established pursuant to section 2894 of this title will be taken into consideration in determining whether to pay or withhold all or part of any incentive fees for which a landlord may otherwise be eligible under the contract.

(d) Responsibility for Certain Medical Costs.—(1) Reimbursement required under certain circumstances.—If the Secretary concerned finds that a landlord fails to maintain safe and sanitary conditions for a housing unit under the contract and that, subject to paragraph (2), these conditions result in a tenant of the housing unit receiving medical evaluations and treatment, the landlord shall be responsible for reimbursing the Department of Defense for any costs incurred by the Department to provide the medical evaluations and treatment to the tenant, whether such evaluations and treatment are provided in a military medical treatment facility or through the TRICARE provider network.

(2) Review process.—Before the Secretary concerned may submit a claim under paragraph (1) to a landlord for reimbursement of Department medical evaluation and treatment costs—(A) a military medical professional must determine that the tenant’s medical conditions were caused by unsafe and unsanitary conditions of the housing unit; and

(B) the documentation of the medical evaluation showing causation must be s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The requirements of this section condition contracts entered into using the authorities provided to the Secretary concerned under section 2872 of this title and other authorities provided under subchapter IV of this chapter and this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of Certain Employees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A landlord providing a housing unit shall prohibit any employee of the landlord who commits work-order fraud under the contract from doing any work under the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dispute Resolution Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any decision the commander renders in favor of the tenant in the formal dispute resolution process established pursuant to section 2894 of this title will be taken into consideration in determining whether to pay or withhold all or part of any incentive fees for which a landlord may otherwise be eligible under the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Certain Medical Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for Relocation Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance Work Order System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A landlord providing a housing unit shall ensure that the maintenance work order system of the landlord (hardware and software) is up to date, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Disability Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of this subchapter and subchapter IV of this chapter, housing units shall be considered as military family housing for purposes of application of Department of Defense policy implementing section 804 of the Fair Housing Act (42 U.S.C. 3604) and title III of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (42 U.S.C. 12181 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2891_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary concerned shall create such legal documents as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>