<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2902"><akn:num>2902</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2902. Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council(a) There is a Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).

(b) The Council is composed of 12 members as follows:(1) The official within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering who is responsible for science and technology.

(2) The Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

(3) The official within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment who is responsible for environmental security.

(4) The Assistant Secretary of Energy for Defense programs.

(5) The Assistant Secretary of Energy responsible for environmental restoration and waste management.

(6) The Director of the Department of Energy Office of Science.

(7) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.

(8) One representative from each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard.

(9) The Executive Director of the Council (appointed pursuant to section 2903 of this title), who shall be a nonvoting member.


(c) The Secretary of Defense shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each odd numbered fiscal year. The Secretary of Energy shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each even-numbered fiscal year.

(d) The Council shall have the following responsibilities:(1) To prescribe policies and procedures to implement the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.

(2) To enter into contracts, grants, and other financial arrangements, in accordance with other applicable law, to carry out the purposes of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program.

(3) To prepare an annual report that contains the following:(A) A description of activities of the strategic environmental research and development program carried out during the fiscal year before the fiscal year in which the report is prepared.

(B) A general outline of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is a Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program Council (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Council is composed of 12 members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each odd numbered fiscal year. The Secretary of Energy shall designate a member of the Council as chairman for each even-numbered fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Council shall have the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In carrying out subsection (d)(1), the Council shall prescribe policies and procedures that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Council shall be subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense in prescribing policies and procedures under subsection (d)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Not later than February 1 of each year, the Council shall submit to the Secretary of Defense the annual report prepared pursuant to subsection (d)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>