<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2911" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2911/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2911/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2911"><akn:num>2911</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy policy of the Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2911. Energy policy of the Department of Defense(a) General Energy Policy.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure the readiness of the armed forces for their military missions by pursuing energy security and energy resilience.

(b) Authorities.—In order to achieve the policy set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may—(1) establish metrics and standards for the assessment of energy resilience;

(2) require the Secretary of a military department to perform mission assurance and readiness assessments of energy power systems for mission critical assets and supporting infrastructure, applying uniform mission standards established by the Secretary of Defense;

(3) require the Secretary of a military department to establish and maintain an energy resilience master plan for an installation;

(4) authorize the use of energy security and energy resilience, including the benefits of on-site generation resources that reduce or avoid the cost of backup power, as factors in the cost-benefit analysis for procurement of energy; and

(5) in selecting facility energy projects that will use renewable energy sources, pursue energy security and energy resilience by giving favorable consideration to projects that provide power directly to a military facility or into the installation electrical distribution network.


(c) Energy Performance Goals.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees the energy performance goals for the Department of Defense regarding transportation systems, support systems, utilities, and infrastructure and facilities.

(2) The energy performance goals shall be submitted annually not later than the date on which the President submits to Congress the budget for the next fiscal year under section 1105 of title 31 and cover that fiscal year as well as the next five, l0, and 20 years. The Secretary shall identify changes to the energy performance goals since the previous submission.

(3) The Secretary of Defense sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Energy Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure the readiness of the armed forces for their military missions by pursuing energy security and energy resilience.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In order to achieve the policy set forth in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Performance Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Performance Master Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) For the purpose of developing and implementing the energy performance goals and energy performance master plan, the Secretary of Defense shall consider at a minimum the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of Energy Conservation Measures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) For the purpose of implementing the energy performance master plan, the Secretary of Defense shall provide that the selection of energy conservation measures, including energy efficient maintenance, shall be limited to those measures that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goal Regarding Use of Renewable Energy To Meet Facility Energy Needs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of On-Site Energy Security and Energy Resilience.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of Life-cycle Costs and Performance of Potential Energy Resilience Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2911_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregate Energy Conservation Measures and Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>