<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2913" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2913/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2913/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2913"><akn:num>2913</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy savings contracts and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2913. Energy savings contracts and activities(a) Shared Energy Savings Contracts.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall develop a simplified method of contracting for shared energy savings contract services that will accelerate the use of these contracts with respect to military installations and will reduce the administrative effort and cost on the part of the Department of Defense as well as the private sector.

(2) In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense may—(A) request statements of qualifications (as prescribed by the Secretary of Defense), including financial and performance information, from firms engaged in providing shared energy savings contracting;

(B) designate from the statements received, with an update at least annually, those firms that are presumptively qualified to provide shared energy savings services;

(C) select at least three firms from the qualifying list to conduct discussions concerning a particular proposed project, including requesting a technical and price proposal from such selected firms for such project; and

(D) select from such firms the most qualified firm to provide shared energy savings services pursuant to a contractual arrangement that the Secretary determines is fair and reasonable, taking into account the estimated value of the services to be rendered and the scope and nature of the project.


(3) In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary may also provide for the direct negotiation, by departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Department of Defense, of contracts with shared energy savings contractors that have been selected competitively and approved by any gas or electric utility serving the department, agency, or instrumentality concerned.


(b) Participation in Gas or Electric Utility Programs.—The Secretary of Defense shall permit and encourage each military department, Defense Agency, and other instrumentality of the Department of Defense to participate in programs conducted by any gas or ele</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2913_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shared Energy Savings Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2913_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in Gas or Electric Utility Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall permit and encourage each military department, Defense Agency, and other instrumentality of the Department of Defense to participate in programs conducted by any gas or electric utility for the management of energy demand or for energy conservation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2913_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Financial Incentive, Goods, or Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may authorize any military installation to accept any financial incentive, goods, or services generally available from a State or local government or gas or electric utility, to adopt technologies and practices that the Secretary determines are in the interests of the United States and consistent with the energy performance goals for the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2913_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements With Gas or Electric Utilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>