<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2914" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2914/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/2914/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2914"><akn:num>2914</akn:num><akn:heading>Military construction projects for energy resilience, energy security, and energy conservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2914. Military construction projects for energy resilience, energy security, and energy conservation(a) Project Authorization Required.—The Secretary of Defense may carry out such military construction projects for energy resilience, energy security, and energy conservation as are authorized by law, using funds appropriated or otherwise made available for that purpose.

(b) Submission of Project Proposals.—(1) As part of the Department of Defense Form 1391 submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress for a military construction project covered by subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall include the following information:(A) The project title.

(B) The location of the project.

(C) A brief description of the scope of work.

(D) The original project cost estimate and the current working cost estimate, if different.

(E) Such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate.


(2) In the case of a military construction project for energy conservation, the Secretary also shall include the following information:(A) The original expected savings-to-investment ratio and simple payback estimates and measurement and verification cost estimate.

(B) The most current expected savings-to-investment ratio and simple payback estimates and measurement and verification plan and costs.

(C) A brief description of the measurement and verification plan and planned funding source.


(3) In the case of a military construction project for energy resilience or energy security, the Secretary also shall include the rationale for how the project would enhance mission assurance, support mission critical functions, and address known vulnerabilities.


(c) Alternative Funding Source.—(1) In addition to the authority under section 2805(c) of this title, in carrying out a military construction project for energy resilience, energy security, or energy conservation under this section, the Secretary concerned may use amounts available for operation and maintenance for the mili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project Authorization Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may carry out such military construction projects for energy resilience, energy security, and energy conservation as are authorized by law, using funds appropriated or otherwise made available for that purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of Project Proposals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Funding Source.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to Certain Other Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A project under this section may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation of Cybersecurity Supply Chain Risk Management Tools and Methods.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2914_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to Military Construction Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) This section shall apply to military construction projects covered by subsection (a) for which a Department of Defense Form 1391 is submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress in connection with the budget of the Department of Defense for fiscal year 2023 and thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>