<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3041" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3041/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3041/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3041"><akn:num>3041</akn:num><akn:heading>Major system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3041. Major system(a) In General.—In this part (other than in sections 4292(e) and 4321), the term “major system” means a combination of elements that will function together to produce the capabilities required to fulfill a mission need. The elements may include hardware, equipment, software or any combination thereof, but excludes construction or other improvements to real property.

(b) System Considered to Be a Major System.—A system shall be considered a major system if—(1) the conditions of subsection (c) or (d), as applicable, are satisfied; or

(2) the system is designated a “major system” by the head of the agency responsible for the system.


(c) Department of Defense Systems.—(1) In general.—For purposes of subsection (b), a system for which the Department of Defense is responsible shall be considered a major system if—(A) the total expenditures for research, development, test, and evaluation for the system are estimated to be more than $115,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars); or

(B) the eventual total expenditure for procurement for the system is estimated to be more than $540,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars).


(2) Adjustment authority.—Authority for the Secretary of Defense to adjust amounts and the base fiscal year in effect under this subsection is provided in section 4202(b) of this title.


(d) Civilian Agency Systems.—For purposes of subsection (b), a system for which a civilian agency is responsible shall be considered a major system if total expenditures for the system are estimated to exceed the greater of—(1) $750,000 (based on fiscal year 1980 constant dollars); or

(2) the dollar threshold for a “major system” established by the agency pursuant to Office of Management and Budget (OMB) Circular A–109, entitled “Major Systems Acquisitions”.


(Added and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1806(c), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4154.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The text of par. (5) of section 230</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3041_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this part (other than in sections 4292(e) and 4321), the term “major system” means a combination of elements that will function together to produce the capabilities required to fulfill a mission need. The elements may include hardware, equipment, software or any combination thereof, but excludes construction or other improvements to real property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3041_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>System Considered to Be a Major System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A system shall be considered a major system if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3041_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3041_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civilian Agency Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For purposes of subsection (b), a system for which a civilian agency is responsible shall be considered a major system if total expenditures for the system are estimated to exceed the greater of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>