<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_311"><akn:num>311</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of defense personnel between United States and friendly foreign countries: authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 311. Exchange of defense personnel between United States and friendly foreign countries: authority(a) Authority To Enter Into International Exchange Agreements.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may enter into international defense personnel exchange agreements. Any exchange of personnel under such an agreement is subject to paragraph (3).

(2) For purposes of this section, an international defense personnel exchange agreement is an agreement with the government of a friendly foreign country or international or regional security organization for the reciprocal or non-reciprocal exchange of—(A) members of the armed forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense; and

(B) military and civilian personnel of the defense or security ministry of that foreign government or international or regional security organization.


(3) An exchange of personnel under an international defense personnel exchange agreement under this section may only be made with the concurrence of the Secretary of State to the extent the exchange is with either of the following:(A) A non-defense security ministry of a foreign government.

(B) An international or regional security organization.



(b) Assignment of Personnel.—(1) Pursuant to an international defense personnel exchange agreement, personnel of the defense ministry of a foreign government may be assigned to positions in the Department of Defense and personnel of the Department of Defense may be assigned to positions in the defense ministry of such foreign government. Positions to which exchanged personnel are assigned may include positions of instructors.

(2) An agreement for the exchange of personnel engaged in research and development activities may provide for assignment of Department of Defense personnel to positions in private industry that support the defense ministry of the host foreign government, subject to the concurrence of the Secretary of State.

(3) An individual may not be assigned to a position pursuant to an int</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Enter Into International Exchange Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocity of Personnel Qualifications Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the case of an international defense personnel exchange agreement that provides for reciprocal exchanges, each government shall be required to provide personnel with qualifications, training, and skills that are essentially equal to those of the personnel provided by the other government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Personnel Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No personnel exchanged pursuant to an agreement under this section may take or be required to take an oath of allegiance to the host country or to hold an official capacity in the government of such country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_311_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The requirements in subsections (c) and (d) shall apply in the exercise of any authority of the Secretaries of the military departments to enter into an agreement with the government of a foreign country to provide for the exchange of members of the armed forces and military personnel of the defense or security ministry of that foreign country. The Secretary of Defense may prescribe regulations for the application of such subsections in the exercise of such authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>