<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3136"><akn:num>3136</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Modernization Account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3136. Defense Modernization Account(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Treasury an account to be known as the “Defense Modernization Account”.

(b) Funds Available for Account.—The Defense Modernization Account shall consist of the following:(1) Amounts appropriated to the Defense Modernization Account for the costs of projects described in subsection (d)(1), and amounts reimbursed to the Defense Modernization Account under subsection (c)(1)(B)(ii) out of savings derived from such projects.

(2) Amounts transferred to the Defense Modernization Account under subsection (c).


(c) Transfers to Account.—(1)(A) Upon a determination by the Secretary of a military department, or the Secretary of Defense with respect to Defense-wide appropriations accounts, of the availability and source of funds described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned may transfer to the Defense Modernization Account during any fiscal year any amount of funds available to the Secretary described in that subparagraph. Such funds may be transferred to that account only after the Secretary concerned notifies the congressional defense committees in writing of the amount and source of the proposed transfer.

(B) This subsection applies to the following funds that have been appropriated for fiscal years after fiscal year 2016 and are available to the Secretary concerned:(i) Unexpired funds in appropriations accounts that are available for new obligations and that, as a result of economies, efficiencies, and other savings achieved in carrying out an acquisition program, are excess to the requirements of that program.

(ii) Unexpired funds in appropriations accounts that are available for procurement or operation and maintenance of a system, if and to the extent that savings are achieved for such accounts through reductions in life cycle costs of such system that result from one or more projects undertaken with respect to such systems with funds made available from the Defense Moderniz</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Treasury an account to be known as the “Defense Modernization Account”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds Available for Account.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Defense Modernization Account shall consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers to Account.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funds in the Defense Modernization Account may be used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds by Appropriation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In addition to transfers under subsection (f), funds in the Defense Modernization Account may be made available for purposes set forth in subsection (d), but only to the extent authorized in an Act other than an appropriations Act. Funds deposited in the Defense Modernization Account shall remain available for obligation until the end of the third fiscal year that follows the fiscal year in which the amounts are deposited in the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary To Act Through Comptroller.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3136_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>