<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_321"><akn:num>321</akn:num><akn:heading>Training with friendly foreign countries: payment of training and exercise expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 321. Training with friendly foreign countries: payment of training and exercise expenses(a) Training Authorized.—(1) Training with foreign forces generally.—The armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense may train with the military forces or other security forces of a friendly foreign country if the Secretary determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States to do so.

(2) Limitation on training of general purpose forces.—The general purpose forces of the United States armed forces may train only with the military forces of a friendly foreign country.

(3) Training to support mission essential tasks.—Any training conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, support the mission essential tasks for which the unit of the United States armed forces participating in such training is responsible.

(4) Elements of training.—Any training conducted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, include elements that promote—(A) observance of and respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms; and

(B) respect for legitimate civilian authority within the foreign country concerned.



(b) Authority To Pay Training and Exercise Expenses.—Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary of a military department or the commander of a combatant command may pay, or authorize payment for, any of the following expenses:(1) Expenses of training forces assigned or allocated to that command in conjunction with training, and training with, the military forces or other security forces of a friendly foreign country under subsection (a).

(2) Expenses of deploying such forces for that training.

(3) The incremental expenses of a friendly foreign country as the direct result of participating in such training, as specified in the regulations.

(4) The incremental expenses of a friendly foreign country as the direct result of participating in an exercise with the arm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Pay Training and Exercise Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed pursuant to subsection (e), the Secretary of a military department or the commander of a combatant command may pay, or authorize payment for, any of the following expenses:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Training and Exercises.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds for Activities That Cross Fiscal Years.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts available for the authority to pay expenses in subsection (b) for a fiscal year may be used to pay expenses under that subsection for training and exercises that begin in such fiscal year but end in the next fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarterly Notice on Planned Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not later than the end of the first calendar quarter beginning after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017, and every calendar quarter thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice setting forth the schedule of planned training engagement pursuant to subsection (a) during the calendar quarter first following the calendar quarter in which such notice is submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_321_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>