<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3243"><akn:num>3243</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement of new competitors: qualification requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3243. Encouragement of new competitors: qualification requirement(a) Qualification Requirement Defined.—In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.

(b) Actions Before Establishing Qualification Requirement.—Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of the agency shall, before establishing a qualification requirement—(1) prepare a written justification stating the necessity for establishing the qualification requirement and specify why the qualification requirement must be demonstrated before contract award;

(2) specify in writing and make available to a potential offeror upon request all requirements which a prospective offeror, or its product, must satisfy in order to become qualified, such requirements to be limited to those least restrictive to meet the purposes necessitating the establishment of the qualification requirement;

(3) specify an estimate of the costs of testing and evaluation likely to be incurred by a potential offeror in order to become qualified;

(4) ensure that a potential offeror is provided, upon request and on a reimbursable basis, a prompt opportunity to demonstrate its ability to meet the standards specified for qualification using qualified personnel and facilities of the agency concerned or of another agency obtained through interagency agreement, or under contract, or other methods approved by the agency (including use of approved testing and evaluation services not provided under contract to the agency);

(5) if testing and evaluation services are provided under contract to the agency for the purposes of paragraph (4), provide to the extent possible that such services be provided by a contractor who is not expected to benefit from an absence of additional qualified sources and who shall be required in such contract to adhere to any restriction on technical data asserted by the pote</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification Requirement Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the term “qualification requirement” means a requirement for testing or other quality assurance demonstration that must be completed by an offeror before award of a contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions Before Establishing Qualification Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c), the head of the agency shall, before establishing a qualification requirement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability, Waiver Authority, and Referral of Offers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fewer Than 2 Actual Manufacturers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination and Revalidation of Qualification Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Within seven years after the establishment of a qualification requirement under subsection (b) or within seven years following an agency’s enforcement of a qualified products list, qualified manufacturers list, or qualified bidders list, any such qualification requirement shall be examined and revalidated in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b). The preceding sentence does not apply in the case of a qualification requirement for which a waiver is in effect under subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on Enforcement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Except in an emergency as determined by the head of the agency, whenever the head of the agency determines not to enforce a qualification requirement for a solicitation, the agency may not thereafter enforce that qualification requirement unless the agency complies with the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3243_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>