<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/331" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/331/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/331/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_331"><akn:num>331</akn:num><akn:heading>Friendly foreign countries: authority to provide support for conduct of operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 331. Friendly foreign countries: authority to provide support for conduct of operations(a) Authority.—The Secretary of Defense may provide support to friendly foreign countries in connection with the conduct of operations designated pursuant to subsection (b).

(b) Designated Operations.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Defense shall designate the operations for which support may be provided under the authority in subsection (a).

(2) Notice to congress.—The Secretary shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the designation of any operation pursuant to this subsection.

(3) Annual review for continuing designation.—The Secretary shall undertake on an annual basis a review of the operations currently designated pursuant to this subsection in order to determine whether each such operation merits continuing designation for purposes of this section for another year. If the Secretary determines that any operation so reviewed merits continuing designation for purposes of this section for another year, the Secretary—(A) may continue the designation of such operation under this subsection for such purposes for another year; and

(B) if the Secretary so continues the designation of such operation, shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the continuation of designation of such operation.



(c) Types of Support Authorized.—The types of support that may be provided under the authority in subsection (a) are the following:(1) Logistic support, supplies, and services to security forces of a friendly foreign country participating in—(A) an operation with the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Defense; or

(B) a military or stability operation that benefits the national security interests of the United States.


(2) Logistic support, supplies, and services—(A) to military forces of a friendly foreign country solely for the purpose of enhancing the interoperability of the logistical support systems of military forces participating </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may provide support to friendly foreign countries in connection with the conduct of operations designated pursuant to subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated Operations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of Support Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The types of support that may be provided under the authority in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of State Concurrence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The provision of support under subsection (a) may be made only with the concurrence of the Secretary of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support Otherwise Prohibited by Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense may not use the authority in subsection (a) to provide any type of support described in subsection (c) that is otherwise prohibited by any provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Value.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_331_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Logistic Support, Supplies, and Services Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “logistic support, supplies, and services” has the meaning given that term in section 2350(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>