<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/341" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/341/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/341/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_341"><akn:num>341</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense State Partnership Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 341. Department of Defense State Partnership Program(a) Authority.—(1) In general.—The Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, is authorized to establish a program of activities described in paragraph (2), to support the security cooperation objectives of the United States, between members of the National Guard of a State or territory and any of the following:(A) The military forces of a foreign country.

(B) The security forces of a foreign country.

(C) Governmental organizations of a foreign country whose primary functions include disaster response or emergency response.


(2) State partnership.—Each program established under this subsection shall be known as a “State Partnership”.


(b) Limitations.—(1) In general.—An activity with forces referred to in subsection (a)(1)(B) or organizations described in subsection (a)(1)(C) under a program established under subsection (a) may be carried out only if the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, determines and notifies the appropriate congressional committees not less than 15 days before initiating such activity that the activity is in the national security interests of the United States.

(2) Prohibition on activities with units that have committed gross violations of human rights.—The conduct of any assistance activities under a program established under subsection (a) shall be subject to the provisions of section 362 of this title.


(c) Coordination of Activities.—The Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall designate a director for each State and territory to be responsible for the coordination of activities under a program established under subsection (a) for such State or territory and reporting on activities under the program.

(d) Regulations.—This section shall be carried out in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall include accounting procedures to ensure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Chief of the National Guard Bureau shall designate a director for each State and territory to be responsible for the coordination of activities under a program established under subsection (a) for such State or territory and reporting on activities under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section shall be carried out in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe for purposes of this section. Such regulations shall include accounting procedures to ensure that expenditures of funds to carry out this section are accounted for and appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Authorized Funds for Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_341_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nothing in this section shall be construed to supersede any authority under title 10 as in effect on December 26, 2013.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>