<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_342"><akn:num>342</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Centers for Security Studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 342. Regional Centers for Security Studies(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Department of Defense Regional Centers for Security Studies in accordance with this section as international venues for bilateral and multilateral research, communication, exchange of ideas, and training involving military and civilian participants.

(b) Regional Centers Specified.—(1) A Department of Defense Regional Center for Security Studies is a Department of Defense institution that—(A) is operated, and designated as such, by the Secretary of Defense for the study of security issues relating to a specified geographic region of the world; and

(B) serves as a forum for bilateral and multilateral research, communication, exchange of ideas, and training involving military and civilian participants.


(2) The Department of Defense Regional Centers for Security Studies are the following:(A) The George C. Marshall European Center for Security Studies, established in 1993 and located in Garmisch-Partenkirchen, Germany.

(B) The Daniel K. Inouye Asia-Pacific Center for Security Studies, established in 1995 and located in Honolulu, Hawaii.

(C) The William J. Perry Center for Hemispheric Defense Studies, established in 1997 and located in Washington, D.C.

(D) The Africa Center for Strategic Studies, established in 1999 and located in Washington, D.C.

(E) The Near East South Asia Center for Strategic Studies, established in 2000 and located in Washington, D.C.

(F) The Ted Stevens Center for Arctic Security Studies, established in 2021 and located in Anchorage, Alaska.


(3) No institution or element of the Department of Defense may be designated as a Department of Defense Regional Center for Security Studies for purposes of this section, other than the institutions specified in paragraph (2).


(c) Regulations.—The administration of the Regional Centers under this section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. The regulations shall pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall administer the Department of Defense Regional Centers for Security Studies in accordance with this section as international venues for bilateral and multilateral research, communication, exchange of ideas, and training involving military and civilian participants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional Centers Specified.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The administration of the Regional Centers under this section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. The regulations shall prioritize within the respective areas of focus of each Regional Center the functional areas for engagement of territorial and maritime security, transnational and asymmetric threats, and defense sector governance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Participants in activities of the Regional Centers may include United States and foreign military, civilian, and nongovernmental personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment and Compensation of Faculty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) At each Regional Center, the Secretary may, subject to the availability of appropriations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support to Other Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Director of a Regional Center may enter into agreements with the Secretaries of the military departments, the heads of the Defense Agencies, and, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Defense, the heads of other Federal departments and agencies for the provision of services by that Regional Center under this section. Any such participating department and agency shall transfer to the Regional Center funds to pay the full costs of the services received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities Specific to Marshall Center.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities Specific to Inouye Center.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_342_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Review of Program Structure and Programs of Centers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>