<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/343" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/343/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/343/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_343"><akn:num>343</akn:num><akn:heading>Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 343. Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation(a) Establishment and Administration.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may operate an education and training facility for the purpose set forth in subsection (b). The facility shall be known as the “Western Hemisphere Institute for Security Cooperation”.

(2) The Secretary may designate the Secretary of a military department as the Department of Defense executive agent for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this section.


(b) Purpose.—The purpose of the Institute is to provide professional education and training to eligible personnel of countries of the Western Hemisphere within the context of the democratic principles set forth in the Charter of the Organization of American States (such charter being a treaty to which the United States is a party), while fostering mutual knowledge, transparency, confidence, and cooperation among the participating countries and promoting democratic values, respect for human rights, and knowledge and understanding of United States customs and traditions.

(c) Eligible Personnel.—(1) Subject to paragraph (2), personnel of countries of the Western Hemisphere are eligible for education and training at the Institute as follows:(A) Military personnel.

(B) Law enforcement personnel.

(C) Civilian personnel.


(2) The Secretary of State shall be consulted in the selection of foreign personnel for education or training at the Institute.


(d) Curriculum.—(1) The curriculum of the Institute shall include mandatory instruction for each student, for at least 8 hours, on human rights, the rule of law, due process, civilian control of the military, and the role of the military in a democratic society.

(2) The curriculum may include instruction and other educational and training activities on the following:(A) Leadership development.

(B) Counterdrug operations.

(C) Peace support operations.

(D) Disaster relief.

(E) Any other matter that the Secretary de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purpose of the Institute is to provide professional education and training to eligible personnel of countries of the Western Hemisphere within the context of the democratic principles set forth in the Charter of the Organization of American States (such charter being a treaty to which the United States is a party), while fostering mutual knowledge, transparency, confidence, and cooperation among the participating countries and promoting democratic values, respect for human rights, and knowledge and understanding of United States customs and traditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Curriculum.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Visitors.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Accept Foreign Gifts and Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fixed Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The fixed costs of operating and maintaining the Institute for a fiscal year may be paid from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tuition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tuition fees charged for persons who attend the Institute may not include the fixed costs of operating and maintaining the Institute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_343_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Not later than March 15 of each year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a detailed report on the activities of the Institute during the preceding year. The report shall include a copy of the latest report of the Board of Visitors received by the Secretary under subsection (e)(5), together with any comments of the Secretary on the Board’s report. The report shall be prepared in consultation with the Secretary of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>