<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/352" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/352/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/352/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_352"><akn:num>352</akn:num><akn:heading>Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 352. Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense may operate an education and training facility known as the “Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School” (in this section referred to as the “School”).

(b) Designation of Executive Agent.—The Secretary of Defense shall designate the Secretary of a military department as the Department of Defense executive agent for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this section.

(c) Purpose.—The purpose of the School shall be to provide to the military and other security forces of one or more friendly foreign countries education and training under any other provision of law related to naval small craft instruction and training and to increase professionalism, readiness, and respect for human rights through formal courses of instruction or mobile training teams for—(1) the operation, employment, maintenance, and logistics of specialized equipment;

(2) participation in—(A) joint exercises; or

(B) coalition or international military operations; and


(3) improved interoperability between—(A) the armed forces; and

(B) the military and other security forces of the one or more friendly foreign countries.



(d) Limitation on Personnel Eligible To Receive Education and Training.—The Secretary of Defense may not provide education or training at the School to any personnel of a country that is prohibited from receiving such education or training under any other provision of law.

(e) Costs.—(1) The fixed costs of the School may be paid from amounts made available for the Navy as follows:(A) The costs of operating and maintaining the School may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for operation and maintenance.

(B) The costs of the equipment requirements of the School may be paid from amounts made available to the Navy for procurement.

(C) The costs of the facilities construction requirements of the School may be paid f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may operate an education and training facility known as the “Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School” (in this section referred to as the “School”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Executive Agent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall designate the Secretary of a military department as the Department of Defense executive agent for carrying out the responsibilities of the Secretary of Defense under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The purpose of the School shall be to provide to the military and other security forces of one or more friendly foreign countries education and training under any other provision of law related to naval small craft instruction and training and to increase professionalism, readiness, and respect for human rights through formal courses of instruction or mobile training teams for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Personnel Eligible To Receive Education and Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense may not provide education or training at the School to any personnel of a country that is prohibited from receiving such education or training under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than March 15 each year, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a detailed report on the activities and operating costs of the School during the preceding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>