<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3531" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3531/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3531/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3531"><akn:num>3531</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear contracts: acquisition of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3531. Multiyear contracts: acquisition of services(a) Authority.—Subject to subsections (d) and (e), the head of an agency may enter into contracts for periods of not more than five years for services described in subsection (b), and for items of supply related to such services, for which funds would otherwise be available for obligation only within the fiscal year for which appropriated whenever the head of the agency finds that—(1) there will be a continuing requirement for the services consonant with current plans for the proposed contract period;

(2) the furnishing of such services will require a substantial initial investment in plant or equipment, or the incurrence of substantial contingent liabilities for the assembly, training, or transportation of a specialized work force; and

(3) the use of such a contract will promote the best interests of the United States by encouraging effective competition and promoting economies in operation.


(b) Covered Services.—The authority under subsection (a) applies to the following types of services:(1) Operation, maintenance, and support of facilities and installations.

(2) Maintenance or modification of aircraft, ships, vehicles, and other highly complex military equipment.

(3) Specialized training necessitating high quality instructor skills (for example, pilot and air crew members; foreign language training).

(4) Base services (for example, ground maintenance; in-plane refueling; bus transportation; refuse collection and disposal).

(5) Environmental remediation services for—(A) an active military installation;

(B) a military installation being closed or realigned under a base closure law; or

(C) a site formerly used by the Department of Defense.



(c) Applicable Principles.—In entering into multiyear contracts for services under the authority of this section, the head of the agency shall be guided by the following principles:(1) The portion of the cost of any plant or equipment amortized as a cost of contract</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsections (d) and (e), the head of an agency may enter into contracts for periods of not more than five years for services described in subsection (b), and for items of supply related to such services, for which funds would otherwise be available for obligation only within the fiscal year for which appropriated whenever the head of the agency finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The authority under subsection (a) applies to the following types of services:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable Principles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In entering into multiyear contracts for services under the authority of this section, the head of the agency shall be guided by the following principles:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions Applicable Generally.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation or Termination for Insufficient Funding After First Year.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In the event that funds are not made available for the continuation of a multiyear contract for services into a subsequent fiscal year, the contract shall be canceled or terminated, and the costs of cancellation or termination may be paid from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear Contract Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) For the purposes of this section, a multiyear contract is a contract for the purchase of services for more than one, but not more than five, program years. Such a contract may provide that performance under the contract during the second and subsequent years of the contract is contingent upon the appropriation of funds and (if it does so provide) may provide for a cancellation payment to be made to the contractor if such appropriations are not made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(g) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 843(a), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1553.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3531_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Installation Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “military installation” has the meaning given such term in section 2801(c)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>