<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3602"><akn:num>3602</akn:num><akn:heading>Middle tier of acquisition for rapid prototyping and rapid fielding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3602. Middle tier of acquisition for rapid prototyping and rapid fielding(a) Guidance Required.—The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in consultation with the Comptroller of the Department of Defense and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall establish pathways as described under subsection (b) to establish a process for conducting middle tier acquisitions for programs or projects that are intended to be completed in a period of two to five years.

(b) Acquisition Pathways.—The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall establish the following two acquisition pathways:(1) Rapid prototyping.—The rapid prototyping pathway shall provide for the use of innovative technologies to rapidly develop fieldable prototypes to demonstrate new capabilities and meet emerging military needs. The objective of an acquisition program or project under this pathway shall be to field a prototype that can be demonstrated in an operational environment and provide for a residual operational capability within five years of the development of an approved requirement.

(2) Rapid fielding.—The rapid fielding pathway shall provide for the use of proven technologies to field production quantities of new or upgraded systems with minimal development required. The objective of an acquisition program or project under this pathway shall be to begin production within six months and complete fielding within five years of the development of an approved requirement.


(c) Expedited Process.—(1) In general.—Before using the authority under this section, the Under Secretary shall develop a streamlined and coordinated requirements, budget, and acquisition process that results in the development of an approved requirement for each acquisition program or project in a period of not more than six months from the time that the process is initiated. Programs or projects carried out under the authority of this section shall not be subject to the Joint</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, in consultation with the Comptroller of the Department of Defense and the Vice Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, shall establish pathways as described under subsection (b) to establish a process for conducting middle tier acquisitions for programs or projects that are intended to be completed in a period of two to five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition Pathways.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall establish the following two acquisition pathways:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>