<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3677" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3677/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3677/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3677"><akn:num>3677</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for lease or use of vessels for a term of greater than two years but less than five years:</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3677. Contracts for lease or use of vessels for a term of greater than two years but less than five years: prior notice to congressional committees
The Secretary of a military department may make a contract for the lease of a vessel or for the provision of a service through use by a contractor of a vessel, the term of which is for a period of greater than two years, but less than five years, only if—(1) the Secretary has notified the congressional defense committees of the proposed contract and included in such notification—(A) a detailed description of the terms of the proposed contract and a justification for entering into the proposed contract rather than obtaining the capability provided for by the lease, charter, or services involved through purchase of the vessel;

(B) a determination that entering into the proposed contract as a means of obtaining the vessel is the most cost-effective means of obtaining such vessel; and

(C) a plan for meeting the requirement provided by the proposed contract upon completion of the term of the lease contract; and


(2) a period of 60 days has expired following the date on which notice was received by such committees.

(Added and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1825(a), (i), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4206, 4208.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The text of subsec. (h) of section 2401 of this title, which was transferred to this section and amended by Pub. L. 116–283, § 1825(i), was based on Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title X, § 1011, Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 303; Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title VIII, § 821, title X, § 1076(f)(26), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 1830, 1953.

Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283, § 1825(i), transferred subsec. (h) of section 2401 of this title to this section and struck out subsec. (h) designation at beginning.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection and amendment by Pub. L. 116–283 effective Jan. 1, 2022, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and applicabil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3677_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the Secretary has notified the congressional defense committees of the proposed contract and included in such notification—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3677_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) a period of 60 days has expired following the date on which notice was received by such committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>