<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3747" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3747/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3747/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3747"><akn:num>3747</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractor certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3747. Contractor certification(a) Content and Form.—A proposal for settlement of indirect costs applicable to a covered contract shall include a certification by an official of the contractor that, to the best of the certifying official’s knowledge and belief, all indirect costs included in the proposal are allowable. Any such certification shall be in a form prescribed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.

(b) Waiver.—The head of the agency or the Secretary of the military department concerned may, in an exceptional case, waive the requirement for certification under subsection (a) in the case of any contract if the head of the agency or the Secretary—(1) determines in such case that it would be in the interest of the United States to waive such certification; and

(2) states in writing the reasons for that determination and makes such determination available to the public.


(Added and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1832(a), (f), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4218, 4221.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The text of subsec. (h) of section 2324 of this title, which was transferred to this section and amended by Pub. L. 116–283, § 1832(f), was based on Pub. L. 99–145, title IX, § 911(a)(1), Nov. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 684; Pub. L. 99–190, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 8112(a)(2)], Dec. 19, 1985, 99 Stat. 1185, 1223; Pub. L. 103–355, title II, § 2101(a)(8), Oct. 13, 1994, 108 Stat. 3308; Pub. L. 104–106, div. D, title XLIII, § 4321(b)(9)(B), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 672.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 3746 was renumbered section 7276 of this title.

Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283, § 1832(f)(1)(A), transferred subsec. (h) of section 2324 of this title to this section and struck out subsec. (h) designation and heading “Contractor Certification Required” at beginning.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–283, § 1832(f)(1)(B), (2), redesignated par. (1) of section 2324(h) of this title as subsec. (a) of this section and inserted heading.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 116–283, § 1832(f)(1)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3747_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content and Form.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A proposal for settlement of indirect costs applicable to a covered contract shall include a certification by an official of the contractor that, to the best of the certifying official’s knowledge and belief, all indirect costs included in the proposal are allowable. Any such certification shall be in a form prescribed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3747_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The head of the agency or the Secretary of the military department concerned may, in an exceptional case, waive the requirement for certification under subsection (a) in the case of any contract if the head of the agency or the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>