<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3762" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3762/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3762/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3762"><akn:num>3762</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent research and development costs: allowable costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3762. Independent research and development costs: allowable costs(a) Regulations.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the payment by the Department of Defense of expenses incurred by contractors for independent research and development costs. Such regulations shall provide that expenses incurred for independent research and development shall be reported independently from other allowable indirect costs.

(b) Costs Treated as Fair and Reasonable, and Allowable, Expenses.—The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide that independent research and development costs shall be considered a fair and reasonable, and allowable, indirect expense on Department of Defense contracts.

(c) Additional Controls.—Subject to subsection (d), the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may include the following provisions:(1) Controls on the reimbursement of costs to the contractor for expenses incurred for independent research and development to ensure that such costs were incurred for independent research and development.

(2) Implementation of regular methods for transmission—(A) from the Department of Defense to contractors, in a reasonable manner, of timely and comprehensive information regarding planned or expected needs of the Department of Defense for future technology and advanced capability; and

(B) from contractors to the Department of Defense, in a reasonable manner, of information regarding progress by the contractor on the independent research and development programs of the contractor.



(d) Limitations on Regulations.—Regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may not include provisions that would infringe on the independence of a contractor to choose which technologies to pursue in its independent research and development program if the chief executive officer of the contractor determines that expenditures will advance the needs of the Department of Defense for future technology and advanced capability as transmitted </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3762_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the payment by the Department of Defense of expenses incurred by contractors for independent research and development costs. Such regulations shall provide that expenses incurred for independent research and development shall be reported independently from other allowable indirect costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3762_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs Treated as Fair and Reasonable, and Allowable, Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall provide that independent research and development costs shall be considered a fair and reasonable, and allowable, indirect expense on Department of Defense contracts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3762_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Controls.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to subsection (d), the regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may include the following provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3762_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations prescribed under subsection (a) may not include provisions that would infringe on the independence of a contractor to choose which technologies to pursue in its independent research and development program if the chief executive officer of the contractor determines that expenditures will advance the needs of the Department of Defense for future technology and advanced capability as transmitted pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3762_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Date.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall apply to indirect costs incurred on or after October 1, 2017.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>