<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_383"><akn:num>383</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment, monitoring, and evaluation of programs and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 383. Assessment, monitoring, and evaluation of programs and activities(a) Program Required.—The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a program of assessment, monitoring, and evaluation in support of the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.

(b) Program Elements and Requirements.—(1) Elements.—The program under subsection (a) shall provide for the following:(A) Initial assessments of partner capability requirements, potential programmatic risks, baseline information, and indicators of efficacy for purposes of planning, monitoring, and evaluation of security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.

(B) Monitoring of implementation of such programs and activities in order to measure progress in execution and, to the extent possible, achievement of desired outcomes.

(C) Evaluation of the efficiency and effectiveness of such programs and activities in achieving desired outcomes.

(D) Identification of lessons learned in carrying out such programs and activities, and development of recommendation for improving future security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.

(E) Incorporation of lessons learned from prior security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense that were carried out any time on or after September 11, 2001.


(2) Best practices.—The program shall be conducted in accordance with international best practices, interagency standards, and, if applicable, the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 (Public Law 103–62), and the amendments made by that Act, and the GPRA Modernization Act of 2010 (Public Law 111–352), and the amendments made by that Act.


(c) Availability of Funds.—(1) In general.—Funds available to the Defense Security Cooperation Agency, and other funds available to the Department of Defense for security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense, may be used to carry out the program required by subsec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall maintain a program of assessment, monitoring, and evaluation in support of the security cooperation programs and activities of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Elements and Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_383_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>