<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/3905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3905"><akn:num>3905</akn:num><akn:heading>Products of Federal Prison Industries: procedural requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3905. Products of Federal Prison Industries: procedural requirements(a) Products for Which Federal Prison Industries Does Not Have Significant Market Share.—(1) Before purchasing a product listed in the latest edition of the Federal Prison Industries catalog under section 4124(d) of title 18 for which Federal Prison Industries does not have a significant market share, the Secretary of Defense shall conduct market research to determine whether the product is comparable to products available from the private sector that best meet the needs of the Department in terms of price, quality, and time of delivery.

(2) If the Secretary determines that a Federal Prison Industries product described in paragraph (1) is not comparable in price, quality, or time of delivery to products of the private sector that best meets the needs of the Department in terms of price, quality, and time of delivery, the Secretary shall use competitive procedures for the procurement of the product, or shall make an individual purchase under a multiple award contract in accordance with the competition requirements applicable to such contract. In conducting such a competition, the Secretary shall consider a timely offer from Federal Prison Industries.


(b) Products for Which Federal Prison Industries Has Significant Market Share.—(1) The Secretary of Defense may purchase a product listed in the latest edition of the Federal Prison Industries catalog for which Federal Prison Industries has a significant market share only if the Secretary uses competitive procedures for the procurement of the product or makes an individual purchase under a multiple award contract in accordance with the competition requirements applicable to such contract. In conducting such a competition, the Secretary shall consider a timely offer from Federal Prison Industries.

(2) For purposes of this subsection, Federal Prison Industries shall be treated as having a significant share of the market for a product if the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products for Which Federal Prison Industries Does Not Have Significant Market Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Products for Which Federal Prison Industries Has Significant Market Share.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Market Research Determination Not Subject to Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A determination by a contracting officer regarding whether a product or service offered by Federal Prison Industries is comparable to products or services available from the private sector that best meet the Department’s needs in terms of price, quality, and time of delivery shall not be subject to review pursuant to section 4124(b) of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance as a Subcontractor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Classified and Sensitive Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of Defense may not enter into any contract with Federal Prison Industries under which an inmate worker would have access to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>