<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/392" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/392/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/392/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_392"><akn:num>392</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive agents for cyber test and training ranges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 392. Executive agents for cyber test and training ranges(a) Executive Agent.—The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Principal Cyber Advisor, shall—(1) designate a senior official from among the personnel of the Department of Defense to act as the executive agent for cyber and information technology test ranges; and

(2) designate a senior official from among the personnel of the Department of Defense to act as the executive agent for cyber and information technology training ranges.


(b) Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities.—(1) Establishment.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agents designated under subsection (a). Such roles, responsibilities, and authorities shall include the development of a biennial integrated plan for cyber and information technology test and training resources.

(2) Biennial integrated plan.—The biennial integrated plan required under paragraph (1) shall include plans for the following:(A) Developing and maintaining a comprehensive list of cyber and information technology ranges, test facilities, test beds, and other means of testing, training, and developing software, personnel, and tools for accommodating the mission of the Department. Such list shall include resources from both governmental and nongovernmental entities.

(B) Organizing and managing designated cyber and information technology test ranges, including—(i) establishing the priorities for cyber and information technology ranges to meet Department objectives;

(ii) enforcing standards to meet requirements specified by the United States Cyber Command, the training community, and the research, development, testing, and evaluation community;

(iii) identifying and offering guidance on the opportunities for integration amongst the designated cyber and information technology ranges regarding test, training, and development functions;

(iv) finding opportunities for cost reduction, integration, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Agent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Principal Cyber Advisor, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support Within Department of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that the military departments, Defense Agencies, and other components of the Department of Defense provide the executive agents designated under subsection (a) with the appropriate support and resources needed to perform the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance With Existing Directive.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall carry out this section in compliance with Directive 5101.1.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_392_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>