<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4021"><akn:num>4021</akn:num><akn:heading>Research projects: transactions other than contracts and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4021. Research projects: transactions other than contracts and grants(a) Additional Forms of Transactions Authorized.—The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may enter into transactions (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) under the authority of this subsection in carrying out basic, applied, and advanced research projects. The authority under this subsection is in addition to the authority provided in section 4001 of this title to use contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants in carrying out such projects.

(b) Exercise of Authority by Secretary of Defense.—In any exercise of the authority in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall act through the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Defense Innovation Unit, or any other element of the Department of Defense that the Secretary may designate.

(c) Advance Payments.—The authority provided under subsection (a) may be exercised without regard to section 3324 of title 31.

(d) Recovery of Funds.—(1) A cooperative agreement for performance of basic, applied, or advanced research authorized by section 4001 of this title and a transaction authorized by subsection (a) may include a clause that requires a person or other entity to make payments to the Department of Defense or any other department or agency of the Federal Government as a condition for receiving support under the agreement or other transaction.

(2) The amount of any payment received by the Federal Government pursuant to a requirement imposed under paragraph (1) may be credited, to the extent authorized by the Secretary of Defense, to the appropriate account established under subsection (f). Amounts so credited shall be merged with other funds in the account and shall be available for the same purposes and the same period for which other funds in such account are available.


(e) Conditions.—The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—(1) to the maximum extent practicable, no cooperative</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Forms of Transactions Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of each military department may enter into transactions (other than contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants) under the authority of this subsection in carrying out basic, applied, and advanced research projects. The authority under this subsection is in addition to the authority provided in section 4001 of this title to use contracts, cooperative agreements, and grants in carrying out such projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercise of Authority by Secretary of Defense.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In any exercise of the authority in subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense shall act through the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the Defense Innovation Unit, or any other element of the Department of Defense that the Secretary may designate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The authority provided under subsection (a) may be exercised without regard to section 3324 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support Accounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) There is hereby established on the books of the Treasury separate accounts for each of the military departments, the Defense Innovation Unit, and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency for support of research projects and development projects provided for in cooperative agreements containing a clause under subsection (d) and research projects provided for in transactions entered into under subsection (a). Funds in those accounts shall be available for the payment of such support.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and Training.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of Defense shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretary of Defense shall issue guidance to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4021_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Certain Information From Disclosure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>