<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4027" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4027/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4027/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4027"><akn:num>4027</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure requirements for recipients of research and development funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4027. Disclosure requirements for recipients of research and development funds(a) In General.—Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), an individual or entity (including a State or local government) that uses funds received from the Department of Defense to carry out research or development activities shall include, in any public document pertaining to such activities, a clear statement indicating the dollar amount of the funds received from the Department for such activities.

(b) Exception.—The disclosure requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply to a public document consisting of fewer than 280 characters.

(c) Waiver.—The Secretary of Defense may waive the disclosure requirement under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis.

(d) Public Document Defined.—In this section, the term “public document” means any document or other written statement made available for public reference or use, regardless of whether such document or statement is made available in hard copy or electronic format.

(Added Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title II, § 212(a)(1), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3456, § 2374b; renumbered § 4027, Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(e)(4)(A), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2139.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 4027 was renumbered section 7377 of this title.

Amendments2021—Pub. L. 117–81 renumbered section 2374b of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2021 AmendmentPub. L. 117–263, div. A, title VIII, § 881(a), Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 2744, provided that: “The amendments made by section 1701(e) and paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 802(b) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (Public Law 117–81) [renumbering this section and sections 4094, 4873, 4875, and 8755 of this title] shall be deemed to have taken effect immediately before the amendments made by section 1881 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsections (b) and (c), an individual or entity (including a State or local government) that uses funds received from the Department of Defense to carry out research or development activities shall include, in any public document pertaining to such activities, a clear statement indicating the dollar amount of the funds received from the Department for such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The disclosure requirement under subsection (a) shall not apply to a public document consisting of fewer than 280 characters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may waive the disclosure requirement under subsection (a) on a case-by-case basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Document Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “public document” means any document or other written statement made available for public reference or use, regardless of whether such document or statement is made available in hard copy or electronic format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>