<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4062" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4062/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4062/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4062"><akn:num>4062</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Acquisition Challenge Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4062. Defense Acquisition Challenge Program(a) Program Required.—(1) The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, shall carry out a program to provide opportunities for the increased introduction of innovative and cost-saving technology in acquisition programs of the Department of Defense.

(2) The program, to be known as the Defense Acquisition Challenge Program (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Challenge Program”), shall provide any person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense with the opportunity to propose alternatives, to be known as challenge proposals, at the component, subsystem, system, or system-of-systems level of an existing Department of Defense acquisition program, or to address any broader functional challenge to Department of Defense missions that may not fall within an acquisition program, that would result in improvements in performance, affordability, manufacturability, or operational capability of that acquisition program or function.


(b) Panels.—The Under Secretary shall establish one or more panels of highly qualified scientists and engineers (hereinafter in this section referred to as “Panels”) to provide preliminary evaluations of challenge proposals under subsection (c).

(c) Preliminary Evaluation by Panels.—(1) Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, a person or activity within or outside the Department of Defense may submit challenge proposals to a Panel, through the unsolicited proposal process or in response to a broad agency announcement.

(2) The Under Secretary shall establish procedures pursuant to which appropriate officials of the Department of Defense may identify proposals submitted through the unsolicited proposal process as challenge proposals. The procedures shall provide for the expeditious referral of such proposals to a Panel for preliminary evaluation under this subsection.

(3) The Under Secretary shall issue on an a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Panels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Under Secretary shall establish one or more panels of highly qualified scientists and engineers (hereinafter in this section referred to as “Panels”) to provide preliminary evaluations of challenge proposals under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary Evaluation by Panels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Full Review and Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action Upon Favorable Full Review and Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action Upon Unfavorable Full Review and Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Under procedures prescribed by the Under Secretary, if a challenge proposal is determined by a Panel to satisfy each of the criteria specified in subsection (c)(5), but is not determined under a full review and evaluation to satisfy such criteria, the following provisions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Technical Resources.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflicts of Interest and Confidentiality.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In carrying out each preliminary evaluation under subsection (c) and full review under subsection (d), the Under Secretary shall ensure the elimination of conflicts of interest and that the identity of any person or activity submitting a challenge proposal is not disclosed outside the Federal Government, prior to contract award, without the consent of the person or activity. For purposes of the proceeding sentence, the term “Federal Government” includes both employees of the Federal Government and employees of Federal Government contractors providing advisory and assistance services as described in part 37 of the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Use of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funds made available for the Challenge Program may be used only for activities authorized by this section, and not for implementation of challenge proposals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Use of Certain Procedures as Use of Competitive Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The use of general solicitation competitive procedures established under subsection (c) shall be considered to be the use of competitive procedures for purposes of sections 3201 through 3205 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>