<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4066" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4066/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4066/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4066"><akn:num>4066</akn:num><akn:heading>Global Research Watch Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4066. Global Research Watch Program(a) Program.—The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall carry out a Global Research Watch program in accordance with this section.

(b) Program Goals.—The goals of the program are as follows:(1) To monitor and analyze the basic and applied research activities and capabilities of foreign nations and private sector persons in areas of military interest, including allies and competitors.

(2) To provide standards for comparison and comparative analysis of research capabilities of foreign nations and private sector persons in relation to the research capabilities of the United States.

(3) To assist Congress and Department of Defense officials in making investment decisions for research in technical areas where the United States may not be the global leader.

(4) To identify areas where significant opportunities for cooperative research may exist.

(5) To coordinate and promote the international cooperative research and analysis activities of each of the armed forces and Defense Agencies.

(6) To establish and maintain an electronic database on international research capabilities, comparative assessments of capabilities, cooperative research opportunities, and ongoing cooperative programs.


(c) Focus of Program.—The program shall be focused on research and technologies at a technical maturity level equivalent to Department of Defense basic and applied research programs.

(d) Coordination.—(1) The Under Secretary shall coordinate the program with the international cooperation and analysis activities of the military departments and Defense Agencies.

(2) The Secretaries of the military departments and the directors of the Defense Agencies shall provide the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering such assistance as the Under Secretary may require for purposes of the program.

(3)(A) Funds available to a military department for a fiscal year for monitoring or analyzing the research activities and c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall carry out a Global Research Watch program in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Goals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The goals of the program are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Focus of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The program shall be focused on research and technologies at a technical maturity level equivalent to Department of Defense basic and applied research programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of Database Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information in electronic databases of the Global Research Watch program shall be maintained in unclassified form and, as determined necessary by the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, in classified form in such databases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4066_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The requirement to carry out the program under this section shall terminate on September 30, 2035.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>