<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4093" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4093/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4093/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4093"><akn:num>4093</akn:num><akn:heading>Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4093. Science, Mathematics, and Research for Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program(a) Requirement for Program.—The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide financial assistance for education in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology skills and disciplines that, as determined by the Secretary, are critical to the national security functions of the Department of Defense and are needed in the Department of Defense workforce.

(b) Financial Assistance.—(1) Under the program under this section, the Secretary of Defense may award a scholarship or fellowship in accordance with this section to a person who—(A) is a citizen of the United States or, subject to subsection (g), a country the government of which is a party to The Technical Cooperation Program (TTCP) memorandum of understanding of October 24, 1995;

(B) is pursuing an associates degree, undergraduate degree, or advanced degree in a critical skill or discipline described in subsection (a) at an accredited institution of higher education; and

(C) enters into a service agreement with the Secretary of Defense as described in subsection (c).


(2) The amount of the financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded to a person under this subsection shall be an amount determined by the Secretary of Defense.

(3) Financial assistance provided under a scholarship or fellowship awarded under this section may be paid directly to the recipient of such scholarship or fellowship or to an administering entity for disbursement of the funds.


(c) Service Agreement for Recipients of Financial Assistance.—(1) To receive financial assistance under this section—(A) in the case of an employee of the Department of Defense, the employee shall enter into a written agreement to continue in the employment of the department for the period of obligated service determined under paragraph (2); and

(B) in the case of a person not an employee of the Department of Defense, the pers</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall carry out a program to provide financial assistance for education in science, mathematics, engineering, and technology skills and disciplines that, as determined by the Secretary, are critical to the national security functions of the Department of Defense and are needed in the Department of Defense workforce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service Agreement for Recipients of Financial Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of Program Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refund for Period of Unserved Obligated Service.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Participation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4093_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of Higher Education Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1001).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>