<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4123" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4123/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4123/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4123"><akn:num>4123</akn:num><akn:heading>Mechanisms to provide funds for defense laboratories for research and development of technologies fo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4123. Mechanisms to provide funds for defense laboratories for research and development of technologies for military missions(a) Mechanisms to Provide Funds.—(1) The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall establish mechanisms under which the director of a defense laboratory may use an amount of funds equal to not less than two percent and not more than four percent of all funds available to the defense laboratory for the following purposes:(A) To fund innovative basic and applied research that is conducted at the defense laboratory and supports military missions.

(B) To fund development programs that support the transition of technologies developed by the defense laboratory into operational use.

(C) To fund workforce development activities that improve the capacity of the defense laboratory to recruit and retain personnel with necessary scientific and engineering expertise that support military missions.

(D) To fund the repair or minor military construction of the laboratory infrastructure and equipment, in accordance with subsection (b).


(2) The mechanisms established under paragraph (1) shall provide that funding shall be used under paragraph (1) at the discretion of the director of a defense laboratory in consultation with the science and technology executive of the military department concerned.

(3) The science and technology executive of a military department may develop policies and guidance to leverage funding and promote cross-laboratory collaboration, including with laboratories of other military departments.

(4) After consultation with the science and technology executive of the military department concerned, the director of a defense laboratory may charge customer activities a fixed percentage fee, in addition to normal costs of performance, in order to obtain funds to carry out activities authorized by this subsection. The fixed fee may not exceed four percent of costs.


(b) Availability of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4123_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mechanisms to Provide Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4123_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Funds for Infrastructure Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funds shall be available in accordance with subsection (a)(1)(D) only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4123_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release and Dissemination of Information on Contributions From Use of Authority to Military Missions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>