<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4124"><akn:num>4124</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4124. Centers for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership(a) Designation.—(1) The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall designate each science and technology reinvention laboratory as a Center for Science, Technology, and Engineering Partnership (in this section referred to as “Centers”) in the recognized core competencies of the designee.

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a policy to encourage the Secretary of each military department to reengineer management and business processes and adopt best-business and personnel practices at the Centers of the Secretary concerned in connection with the capability requirements of the Centers, so as to serve as recognized leaders in such capabilities throughout the Department of Defense and in the national technology and industrial base.

(3) The Secretary of Defense, acting through the directors of the Centers, may conduct one or more pilot programs, consistent with applicable requirements of law, to test any practices referred to in paragraph (2) that the Directors determine could—(A) improve the efficiency and effectiveness of operations at Centers;

(B) improve the support provided by the Centers for the elements of the Department of Defense who use the services of the Centers; and

(C) enhance capabilities by reducing the cost and improving the performance and efficiency of executing laboratory missions.



(b) Public-private Partnerships.—(1) To achieve one or more objectives set forth in paragraph (2), the Secretary may authorize and establish incentives for the Director of a Center to enter into public-private cooperative arrangements (in this section referred to as a “public-private partnership”) to provide for any of the following:(A) For employees of the Center, academia, private industry, State and local governments, or other entities outside the Department of Defense to perform (under contract, subcontract, or otherwise) work related to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public-private Partnerships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private Sector Use of Excess Capacity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any capability of a Center made available to the private sector may be used to perform research and testing activities in order to make more efficient and economical use of Government-owned capabilities and encourage the creation and preservation of jobs to ensure the availability of a workforce with the necessary research and technical skills to meet the needs of the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of Amounts for Performance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts received by a Center for work performed under a public-private partnership may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Excess Capacities to Private-sector Partners.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Capacities of a Center may be made available for use by a private-sector entity under this section only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Partnership Intermediaries to Promote Defense Research and Education.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of Provision.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize a change, otherwise prohibited by law, from the performance of work at a Center by personnel of the Department of Defense to performance by a contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4124_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>