<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4127" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4127/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4127/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4127"><akn:num>4127</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Innovation Unit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4127. Defense Innovation Unit(a) Establishment.—There is established in the Department of Defense a Defense Innovation Unit (referred to in this section as the “Unit”).

(b) Director and Deputy Director.—There is a Director of the Unit who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among persons with substantial experience in innovation and commercial technology, as determined by the Secretary.

(c) Authority of Director.—The Director is the head of the Unit. The Director—(1) shall serve as a principal staff assistant to the Secretary of Defense on matters within the responsibility of the Unit;

(2) shall report directly to the Secretary without intervening authority; and

(3) may communicate views on matters within the responsibility of the Unit directly to the Secretary without obtaining the approval or concurrence of any other official within the Department of Defense.


(d) Responsibilities.—The Unit shall have the following responsibilities:(1) Seek out, identify, and support development of and experimentation with commercial technologies that have the potential to be implemented within the Department of Defense.

(2) Accelerate the adoption or integration of commercial technologies within the Department of Defense to transform military capacity and capabilities.

(3) Serve as the principal liaison between the Department of Defense and individuals and entities in the national security innovation base, including entrepreneurs, startups, commercial technology companies, and venture capital sources.

(4) Carry out programs, projects, and other activities to strengthen the national security innovation base.

(5) Coordinate and harmonize the activities of other organizations and elements of the Department of Defense on matters relating to commercial technologies, dual use technologies, and the innovation of such technologies.

(6) Coordinate and advise efforts among elements of the Department of Defense on matters relating to the development, procurement,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established in the Department of Defense a Defense Innovation Unit (referred to in this section as the “Unit”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and Deputy Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) There is a Director of the Unit who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense from among persons with substantial experience in innovation and commercial technology, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Director is the head of the Unit. The Director—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Unit shall have the following responsibilities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for Multi-stakeholder Partnerships.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4127_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>