<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4171"><akn:num>4171</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational test and evaluation of defense acquisition programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4171. Operational test and evaluation of defense acquisition programs(a) Condition for Proceeding Beyond Low-rate Initial Production.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall provide that a covered major defense acquisition program, a covered designated major subprogram, or an element of the ballistic missile defense system may not proceed beyond low-rate initial production until initial operational test and evaluation of the program, subprogram, or element is completed.

(2) In this subsection:(A) The term “covered major defense acquisition program” means a major defense acquisition program that involves the acquisition of a weapon system that is a major system.

(B) The term “covered designated major subprogram” means a major subprogram designated under section 4203(a)(1) of this title that is a major subprogram of a covered major defense acquisition program.



(b) Operational Test and Evaluation.—(1) Operational testing of a major defense acquisition program may not be conducted until the Director of Operational Test and Evaluation of the Department of Defense approves (in writing) the adequacy of the plans (including the projected level of funding) for operational test and evaluation to be conducted in connection with that program.

(2) The Director shall analyze the results of the operational test and evaluation conducted for each major defense acquisition program. At the conclusion of such testing, the Director shall prepare a report stating—(A) the opinion of the Director as to—(i) whether the test and evaluation performed were adequate; and

(ii) whether the results of such test and evaluation confirm that the items or components actually tested are effective and suitable for combat; and


(B) additional information on the operational capabilities of the items or components that the Director considers appropriate based on the testing conducted.


(3) The Director shall submit each report under paragraph (2) to the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of De</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition for Proceeding Beyond Low-rate Initial Production.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational Test and Evaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Quantity of Articles Required for Operational Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The quantity of articles of a new system that are to be procured for operational testing shall be determined by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impartiality of Contractor Testing Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In the case of a major defense acquisition program (as defined in subsection (a)(2)), no person employed by the contractor for the system being tested may be involved in the conduct of the operational test and evaluation required under subsection (a). The limitation in the preceding sentence does not apply to the extent that the Secretary of Defense plans for persons employed by that contractor to be involved in the operation, maintenance, and support of the system being tested when the system is deployed in combat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impartial Contracted Advisory and Assistance Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of Funds for Testing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The costs for all tests required under subsection (a) shall be paid from funds available for the system being tested.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director’s Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) As part of the annual report of the Director under section 139 of this title, the Director shall describe for each program covered in the report the status of test and evaluation activities in comparison with the test and evaluation master plan for that program, as approved by the Director. The Director shall include in such annual report a description of each waiver granted under subsection (e)(2) since the last such report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4171_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operational Test and Evaluation Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “operational test and evaluation” has the meaning given that term in section 139(a)(2)(A) of this title. For purposes of subsection (a), that term does not include an operational assessment based exclusively on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>