<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4203"><akn:num>4203</akn:num><akn:heading>Major subprograms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4203. Major subprograms(a) Authority To Designate Major Subprograms as Subject to Acquisition Reporting Requirements.—(1)(A) If the Secretary of Defense determines that a major defense acquisition program requires the delivery of two or more categories of end items which differ significantly from each other in form and function, the Secretary may designate each such category of end items as a major subprogram for the purposes of acquisition reporting under this subpart.

(B) If the Secretary of Defense determines that a major defense acquisition program requires the delivery of two or more increments or blocks, the Secretary may designate each such increment or block as a major subprogram for the purposes of acquisition reporting under this subpart.


(2) The Secretary shall notify the congressional defense committees in writing of any proposed designation pursuant to paragraph (1) not less than 30 days before the date such designation takes effect.


(b) Reporting Requirements.—(1) If the Secretary designates a major subprogram of a major defense acquisition program in accordance with subsection (a), Selected Acquisition Reports, unit cost reports, and program baselines under this subpart shall reflect cost, schedule, and performance information—(A) for the major defense acquisition program as a whole (other than as provided in paragraph (2)); and

(B) for each major subprogram of the major defense acquisition program so designated.


(2) For a major defense acquisition program for which a designation of a major subprogram has been made under subsection (a), unit costs under this subpart shall be submitted in accordance with the definitions in subsection (d).


(c) Requirement to Cover Entire Major Defense Acquisition Program.—If a subprogram of a major defense acquisition program is designated as a major subprogram under subsection (a), all other elements of the major defense acquisition program shall be appropriately organized into one or more subprograms under</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Designate Major Subprograms as Subject to Acquisition Reporting Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to Cover Entire Major Defense Acquisition Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) If a subprogram of a major defense acquisition program is designated as a major subprogram under subsection (a), all other elements of the major defense acquisition program shall be appropriately organized into one or more subprograms under the major defense acquisition program, each of which subprograms, as so organized, shall be treated as a major subprogram under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4203_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 4351(a) of this title, in the case of a major defense acquisition program for which the Secretary has designated one or more major subprograms under this section for the purposes of this subpart—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>