<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4204"><akn:num>4204</akn:num><akn:heading>Milestone decision authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4204. Milestone decision authority(a) Service Acquisition Executive.—The milestone decision authority for a major defense acquisition program reaching Milestone A after October 1, 2016, shall be the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, unless the Secretary of Defense designates, under subsection (b), another official to serve as the milestone decision authority.

(b) Designation of Alternate Milestone Decision Authority.—The Secretary of Defense may designate an alternate milestone decision authority for a program with respect to which any of the following applies:(1) Subject to subsection (f), the Secretary determines that the program is addressing a joint requirement.

(2) The Secretary determines that the program is best managed by a Defense Agency.

(3) The program has incurred a unit cost increase greater than the significant cost threshold or critical cost threshold under sections 4371 through 4375 of this title.

(4) The program is critical to a major interagency requirement or technology development effort, or has significant international partner involvement.

(5) The Secretary determines that an alternate official serving as the milestone decision authority will best provide for the program to achieve desired cost, schedule, and performance outcomes.


(c) Reversion to Service Acquisition Executive.—(1) After designating an alternate milestone decision authority under subsection (b) for a program, the Secretary of Defense may revert the position of milestone decision authority for the program back to the service acquisition executive upon request of the Secretary of the military department concerned. A decision on the request shall be made within 180 days after receipt of the request from the Secretary of the military department concerned.

(2) If the Secretary of Defense denies the request for reversion of the milestone decision authority back to the service acquisition executive, the Secretary shall rep</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service Acquisition Executive.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The milestone decision authority for a major defense acquisition program reaching Milestone A after October 1, 2016, shall be the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, unless the Secretary of Defense designates, under subsection (b), another official to serve as the milestone decision authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Alternate Milestone Decision Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may designate an alternate milestone decision authority for a program with respect to which any of the following applies:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversion to Service Acquisition Executive.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4204_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certifications relating to program requirements and funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For each major defense acquisition program, the Secretary of the military department concerned and the Chief of the armed force concerned shall, in each Selected Acquisition Report required under section 4351 of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4204_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation and Oversight.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense shall review the acquisition oversight process for major defense acquisition programs and shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>