<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4211"><akn:num>4211</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4211. Acquisition strategy(a) Acquisition Strategy Required.—There shall be an acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program and each major system approved by a milestone decision authority.

(b) Responsible Official.—For each acquisition strategy required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, or the milestone decision authority, when the milestone decision authority is the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, is responsible for issuing and maintaining the requirements for—(1) the content of the strategy; and

(2) the review and approval process for the strategy.


(c) Considerations.—(1) In issuing requirements for the content of an acquisition strategy for a major defense acquisition program or major system, the Under Secretary, or the milestone decision authority, when the milestone decision authority is the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, shall ensure that—(A) the strategy clearly describes the proposed top-level business and technical management approach for the program or system, in sufficient detail to allow the milestone decision authority to assess the viability of the proposed approach, the method of implementing laws and policies, and program objectives;

(B) the strategy contains a clear explanation of how the strategy is designed to be implemented with available resources, such as time, funding, and management capacity;

(C) the strategy is tailored to address program requirements and constraints; and

(D) the strategy considers the items listed in paragraph (2).


(2) Each strategy shall, where appropriate, consider the following:(A) An approach that delivers required capability in increments, each depending on available mature technology, and that recognizes up front the need for future capability improvements.

(B) Acquisition approach, including industrial base considerations in acc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition Strategy Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There shall be an acquisition strategy for each major defense acquisition program and each major system approved by a milestone decision authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsible Official.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) For each acquisition strategy required by subsection (a), the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment, or the milestone decision authority, when the milestone decision authority is the service acquisition executive of the military department that is managing the program, is responsible for issuing and maintaining the requirements for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>