<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4231"><akn:num>4231</akn:num><akn:heading>Major systems: determination of quantity for low-rate initial production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4231. Major systems: determination of quantity for low-rate initial production(a) Determination of Quantities To Be Procured for Low-Rate Initial Production.—(1) In the course of the development of a major system, the determination of what quantity of articles of that system should be procured for low-rate initial production (including the quantity to be procured for preproduction verification articles) shall be made—(A) when the milestone B decision with respect to that system is made; and

(B) by the official of the Department of Defense who makes that decision.


(2) In this section, the term “milestone B decision” means the decision to approve the system development and demonstration of a major system by the official of the Department of Defense designated to have the authority to make that decision.

(3) Any increase from a quantity determined under paragraph (1) may only be made with the approval of the official making the determination.

(4) The quantity of articles of a major system that may be procured for low-rate initial production may not be less than one operationally configured production unit unless another quantity is established at the milestone B decision.

(5) The Secretary of Defense shall include a statement of the quantity determined under paragraph (1) in the first SAR submitted with respect to the program concerned after that quantity is determined. If the quantity exceeds 10 percent of the total number of articles to be produced, as determined at the milestone B decision with respect to that system, the Secretary shall include in the statement the reasons for such quantity. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “SAR” means a Selected Acquisition Report submitted under section 4351 of this title.


(b) Low-Rate Initial Production of Weapon Systems.—Except as provided in subsection (c), low-rate initial production with respect to a new system is production of the system in the minimum quantity necessary—(1) to provide production-configure</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Quantities To Be Procured for Low-Rate Initial Production.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-Rate Initial Production of Weapon Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Except as provided in subsection (c), low-rate initial production with respect to a new system is production of the system in the minimum quantity necessary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-Rate Initial Production of Naval Vessel and Satellite Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) With respect to naval vessel programs and military satellite programs, low-rate initial production is production of items at the minimum quantity and rate that (1) preserves the mobilization production base for that system, and (2) is feasible, as determined pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>