<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4253" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4253/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4253/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4253"><akn:num>4253</akn:num><akn:heading>Major defense acquisition programs: submissions to Congress on Milestone C</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4253. Major defense acquisition programs: submissions to Congress on Milestone C(a) Brief Summary Report.—Not later than 15 days after granting Milestone C approval for a major defense acquisition program, the milestone decision authority for the program shall provide to the congressional defense committees and, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees a brief summary report that contains the following:(1) The estimated cost and schedule for the program established by the military department concerned, including—(A) the dollar values estimated for the program acquisition unit cost, average procurement unit cost, and total life-cycle cost; and

(B) the planned dates for initial operational test and evaluation and initial operational capability.


(2) The independent estimated cost for the program established pursuant to section 3221(b)(6) of this title, and any independent estimated schedule for the program, including—(A) the dollar values estimated for the program acquisition unit cost, average procurement unit cost, and total life-cycle cost; and

(B) the planned dates for initial operational test and evaluation and initial operational capability.


(3) A summary of any production, manufacturing, and fielding risks associated with the program.

(4) An assessment of the sufficiency of the developmental test and evaluation completed, including the use of automated data analytics or modeling and simulation tools and methodologies.


(b) Additional Information.—At the request of any of the congressional defense committees or, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees, the milestone decision authority shall submit to the committee further information or underlying documentation for the information in a brief summary report submitted under subsection (a), including the independent cost and schedule estimates and the independent technical risk</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Brief Summary Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Not later than 15 days after granting Milestone C approval for a major defense acquisition program, the milestone decision authority for the program shall provide to the congressional defense committees and, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees a brief summary report that contains the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) At the request of any of the congressional defense committees or, in the case of intelligence or intelligence-related activities, the congressional intelligence committees, the milestone decision authority shall submit to the committee further information or underlying documentation for the information in a brief summary report submitted under subsection (a), including the independent cost and schedule estimates and the independent technical risk assessments referred to in that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4253_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Intelligence Committees Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this section, the term “congressional intelligence committees” has the meaning given that term in section 437(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>