<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/427" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/427/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/427/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_427"><akn:num>427</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict Records Research Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 427. Conflict Records Research Center(a) Center Authorized.—The Secretary of Defense may establish a center to be known as the “Conflict Records Research Center” (in this section referred to as the “Center”).

(b) Purposes.—The purposes of the Center shall be the following:(1) To establish a digital research database, including translations, and to facilitate research and analysis of records captured from countries, organizations, and individuals, now or once hostile to the United States, with rigid adherence to academic freedom and integrity.

(2) Consistent with the protection of national security information, personally identifiable information, and intelligence sources and methods, to make a significant portion of these records available to researchers as quickly and responsibly as possible while taking into account the integrity of the academic process and risks to innocents or third parties.

(3) To conduct and disseminate research and analysis to increase the understanding of factors related to international relations, counterterrorism, and conventional and unconventional warfare and, ultimately, enhance national security.

(4) To collaborate with members of academic and broad national security communities, both domestic and international, on research, conferences, seminars, and other information exchanges to identify topics of importance for the leadership of the United States Government and the scholarly community.


(c) Concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence.—The Secretary of Defense shall seek the concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence to the extent the efforts and activities of the Center involve the entities referred to in subsection (b)(4).

(d) Support From Other United States Government Departments or Agencies.—The head of any non-Department of Defense department or agency of the United States Government may—(1) provide to the Secretary of Defense services, including personnel support, to support the operations of the Ce</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense may establish a center to be known as the “Conflict Records Research Center” (in this section referred to as the “Center”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purposes of the Center shall be the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense shall seek the concurrence of the Director of National Intelligence to the extent the efforts and activities of the Center involve the entities referred to in subsection (b)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support From Other United States Government Departments or Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The head of any non-Department of Defense department or agency of the United States Government may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of Gifts and Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of Funds Transferred or Accepted.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funds transferred to or accepted by the Secretary of Defense under this section shall be credited to appropriations available to the Department of Defense for the Center, and shall be available for the same purposes, and subject to the same conditions and limitations, as the appropriations with which merged. Any funds so transferred or accepted shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>