<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4293" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4293/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4293/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4293"><akn:num>4293</akn:num><akn:heading>Major defense acquisition programs: incentive program for contractors to purchase capital assets man</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4293. Major defense acquisition programs: incentive program for contractors to purchase capital assets manufactured in United States(a) Establishment of Incentive Program.—The Secretary of Defense shall plan and establish an incentive program in accordance with this section for contractors to purchase capital assets manufactured in the United States in part with funds available to the Department of Defense.

(b) Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund May Be Used.—The Secretary of Defense may use the Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund, established under section 814 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004, for incentive payments under the program established under this section.

(c) Applicability to Major Defense Acquisition Program Contracts.—The incentive program shall apply to contracts for the procurement of a major defense acquisition program.

(d) Consideration.—The Secretary of Defense shall provide consideration in source selection in any request for proposals for a major defense acquisition program for offerors with eligible capital assets.

(Added Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VIII, § 822(a)(1), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1546, § 2436; renumbered § 4293, Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1847(f)(2), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4258.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 814 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004, referred to in subsec. (b), is section 814 of Pub. L. 108–136, which is set out in a note under section 4811 of this title.

Prior ProvisionsPrior sections 4301 to 4303 and 4306 were renumbered sections 7401 to 7403 and 7406 of this title, respectively.
Prior sections 4307 and 4308 were repealed by Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title XVI, § 1624(a)(1), (c) Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 522, effective on the earlier of the date on which the Secretary of the Army submits a certification in accordance with section 5523 of former Title 36, Patriotic Societies and Observances, or Oct. 1, 1996.
Section 4307, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4293_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Incentive Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall plan and establish an incentive program in accordance with this section for contractors to purchase capital assets manufactured in the United States in part with funds available to the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4293_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund May Be Used.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense may use the Defense Industrial Capabilities Fund, established under section 814 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004, for incentive payments under the program established under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4293_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Major Defense Acquisition Program Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The incentive program shall apply to contracts for the procurement of a major defense acquisition program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4293_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall provide consideration in source selection in any request for proposals for a major defense acquisition program for offerors with eligible capital assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>