<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/430a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/430a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/430a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_430a"><akn:num>430a</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive agent for management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 430a. Executive agent for management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures(a) Executive Agent.—The Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official from among the personnel of the Department of Defense to act as the Department of Defense executive agent for the management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures.

(b) Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities.—The Secretary shall prescribe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agent designated under subsection (a). Such roles, responsibilities, and authorities shall include the development of an annual management and oversight plan for Department-wide accountability and reporting to the congressional defense committees.

(Added Pub. L. 114–92, div. A, title X, § 1083(a)(1), Nov. 25, 2015, 129 Stat. 1003.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Agent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior official from among the personnel of the Department of Defense to act as the Department of Defense executive agent for the management and oversight of alternative compensatory control measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_430a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Roles, Responsibilities, and Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall prescribe the roles, responsibilities, and authorities of the executive agent designated under subsection (a). Such roles, responsibilities, and authorities shall include the development of an annual management and oversight plan for Department-wide accountability and reporting to the congressional defense committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>