<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4351"><akn:num>4351</akn:num><akn:heading>Selected Acquisition Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4351. Selected Acquisition Reports(a) In this section:(1) The term “program acquisition unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total cost for development and procurement of, and system-specific military construction for, the acquisition program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be produced for the acquisition program.

(2) The term “procurement unit cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means the amount equal to (A) the total of all funds programmed to be available for obligation for procurement for the program, divided by (B) the number of fully-configured end items to be procured.

(3) The term “major contract”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means each of the six largest prime, associate, or Government-furnished equipment contracts under the program that is in excess of $40,000,000 and that is not a firm, fixed price contract.

(4) The term “full life-cycle cost”, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, means all costs of development, procurement, military construction, and operations and support, without regard to funding source or management control.


(b)(1) The Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress at the end of each fiscal-year quarter a report on current major defense acquisition programs and any program that is estimated by the Secretary of Defense to require an eventual total expenditure for research, development, test, and evaluation of more than $300,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars) or an eventual total expenditure for procurement, including all planned increments or spirals, of more than $1,800,000,000 (based on fiscal year 1990 constant dollars). Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), each such report shall include a status report on each defense acquisition program that at the end of such quarter is a major defense acquisition program. Reports under this section shall be kn</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information to be included under this subsection in a Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report with respect to a major defense acquisition program is as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Each comprehensive annual Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 30 days after the date on which the President transmits the Budget to Congress for the following fiscal year, and each Quarterly Selected Acquisition Report shall be submitted within 45 days after the end of the fiscal-year quarter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The requirements of this section with respect to a major defense acquisition program or designated major subprogram shall cease to apply after 90 percent of the items to be delivered to the United States under the program or subprogram (shown as the total quantity of items to be purchased under the program or subprogram in the most recent Selected Acquisition Report) have been delivered or 90 percent of planned expenditures under the program or subprogram have been made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A Selected Acquisition Report required under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form without any designation relating to dissemination control, but may contain a classified annex.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4351_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The requirements under this section shall terminate after the final submission covering fiscal year 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>