<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4401"><akn:num>4401</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for modular open system approach in major defense acquisition programs; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4401. Requirement for modular open system approach in major defense acquisition programs; definitions(a) Modular Open System Approach Requirement.—A major defense acquisition program that receives Milestone A or Milestone B approval after January 1, 2019, shall be designed and developed, to the maximum extent practicable, with a modular open system approach to enable incremental development and enhance competition, innovation, and interoperability. Other defense acquisition programs shall also be designed and developed, to the maximum extent practicable, with a modular open system approach to enable incremental development and enhance competition, innovation, and interoperability.

(b) Disclosure Required.—Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall make publicly available any standards for implementation of the modular open system approaches for contracts, unless the service acquisition executive with respect to a specific contract submits to the Secretary a request to not disclose such standards and the Secretary approves such request.

(c) Definitions.—In this chapter:(1) The term “modular open system approach” means, with respect to a major defense acquisition program, an integrated business and technical strategy that—(A) employs a modular design that uses modular system interfaces between major systems, major system components and modular systems;

(B) is subjected to verification to ensure that relevant modular system interfaces—(i) comply with, if available and suitable, widely supported and consensus-based standards; or

(ii) are delivered pursuant to the requirements established in subsection (a)(2)(B) of section 804 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021, including the delivery of—(I) software-defined interface syntax and properties, specifically governing how values are validly passed and received between major subsystems and components, i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modular Open System Approach Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A major defense acquisition program that receives Milestone A or Milestone B approval after January 1, 2019, shall be designed and developed, to the maximum extent practicable, with a modular open system approach to enable incremental development and enhance competition, innovation, and interoperability. Other defense acquisition programs shall also be designed and developed, to the maximum extent practicable, with a modular open system approach to enable incremental development and enhance competition, innovation, and interoperability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall make publicly available any standards for implementation of the modular open system approaches for contracts, unless the service acquisition executive with respect to a specific contract submits to the Secretary a request to not disclose such standards and the Secretary approves such request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>