<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/444" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/444/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/444/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_444"><akn:num>444</akn:num><akn:heading>Support from Central Intelligence Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 444. Support from Central Intelligence Agency(a) Support Authorized.—The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may provide support in accordance with this section to the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency. The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may accept support provided under this section.

(b) Administrative and Contract Services.—(1) In furtherance of the national intelligence effort, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may provide administrative and contract services to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency as if that agency were an organizational element of the Central Intelligence Agency.

(2) Services provided under paragraph (1) may include the services of security police. For purposes of section 15 of the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 (50 U.S.C. 3515), an installation of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency that is provided security police services under this section shall be considered an installation of the Central Intelligence Agency.

(3) Support provided under this subsection shall be provided under terms and conditions agreed upon by the Secretary of Defense and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.


(c) Detail of Personnel.—The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may detail personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency indefinitely to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency without regard to any limitation on the duration of interagency details of Federal Government personnel.

(d) Reimbursable or Nonreimbursable Support.—Support under this section may be provided and accepted on either a reimbursable basis or a nonreimbursable basis.

(e) Authority To Transfer Funds.—(1) The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may transfer funds available for that agency to the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency for the Central Intelligence Agency.

(2) The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency—(A) may accept funds transferr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may provide support in accordance with this section to the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency. The Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency may accept support provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and Contract Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency may detail personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency indefinitely to the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency without regard to any limitation on the duration of interagency details of Federal Government personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursable or Nonreimbursable Support.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Support under this section may be provided and accepted on either a reimbursable basis or a nonreimbursable basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_444_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Transfer Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>