<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4502"><akn:num>4502</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of contract services: senior officials responsible for management of acquisition of cont</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4502. Procurement of contract services: senior officials responsible for management of acquisition of contract services(a) Senior Officials.—The management structure implemented pursuant to section 4501 of this title shall provide for the following:(1) The service acquisition executive of each military department shall be the senior official responsible for the management of acquisition of contract services for or on behalf of the military department.

(2) The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall be the senior official responsible for the management of acquisition of contract services for or on behalf of the Defense Agencies and other components of the Department of Defense outside the military departments.


(b) Duties and Responsibilities of Senior Officials Responsible for the Management of Acquisition of Contract Services.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the senior officials responsible for the management of acquisition of contract services shall assign responsibility for the review and approval of procurements in each contract services acquisition category established under section 4501(d) of this title to specific Department of Defense officials, subject to the direction, supervision, and oversight of such senior officials.

(2) With respect to the acquisition of contract services by a component or command of the Department of Defense the primary mission of which is the acquisition of products and services, such acquisition shall be conducted in accordance with policies, procedures, and best practices guidelines developed and maintained by the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment pursuant to section 4501 of this title, subject to oversight by the senior officials referred to in paragraph (1).


(c) Duties and Responsibilities.—In carrying out subsection (b)(1), each senior official responsible for the management of acquisition of contract services shall—(1) implement the requirements of this section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Officials.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The management structure implemented pursuant to section 4501 of this title shall provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Responsibilities of Senior Officials Responsible for the Management of Acquisition of Contract Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out subsection (b)(1), each senior official responsible for the management of acquisition of contract services shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4502_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>