<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4505"><akn:num>4505</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement of services: tracking of purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4505. Procurement of services: tracking of purchases(a) Data Collection Required.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a data collection system to provide management information with regard to each purchase of services by a military department or Defense Agency in excess of $3,000,000, regardless of whether such a purchase is made in the form of a contract, task order, delivery order, military interdepartmental purchase request, or any other form of interagency agreement, for services in the following service acquisition portfolio groups:(1) Logistics management services.

(2) Equipment related services.

(3) Knowledge-based services.

(4) Electronics and communications services.


(b) Data To Be Collected.—The data required to be collected under subsection (a) includes the following:(1) The services purchased.

(2) The total dollar amount of the purchase.

(3) The form of contracting action used to make the purchase.

(4) Whether the purchase was made through—(A) a performance-based contract, performance-based task order, or other performance-based arrangement that contains firm fixed prices for the specific tasks to be performed;

(B) any other performance-based contract, performance-based task order, or performance-based arrangement; or

(C) any contract, task order, or other arrangement that is not performance based.


(5) In the case of a purchase made through an agency other than the Department of Defense, the agency through which the purchase is made.

(6) The extent of competition provided in making the purchase and whether there was more than one offer.

(7) Whether the purchase was made from—(A) a small business concern;

(B) a small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; or

(C) a small business concern owned and controlled by women.



(c) Inventory Summary.—(1) Not later than the end of the third quarter of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Defense shall prepare an annual inventory, and submi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data Collection Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a data collection system to provide management information with regard to each purchase of services by a military department or Defense Agency in excess of $3,000,000, regardless of whether such a purchase is made in the form of a contract, task order, delivery order, military interdepartmental purchase request, or any other form of interagency agreement, for services in the following service acquisition portfolio groups:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data To Be Collected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The data required to be collected under subsection (a) includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory Summary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and Planning Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Within 90 days after the date on which an inventory is submitted under subsection (c), the Secretary of the military department or head of the Defense Agency responsible for activities in the inventory shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of Plan and Enforcement and Approval Mechanisms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of the military department or head of the Defense Agency responsible for activities in the inventory shall develop a plan, including an enforcement mechanism and approval process, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller General Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Not later than March 31, 2018, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on the status of the data collection required in subsection (a) and an assessment of the efforts by the Department of Defense to implement subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of Construction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the performance of personal services by a contractor except where expressly authorized by a provision of law other than this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4505_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>