<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/455" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/455/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/455/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_455"><akn:num>455</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps, charts, and geomatics data: public availability; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 455. Maps, charts, and geomatics data: public availability; exceptions(a) The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall offer for sale maps and charts at scales of 1:500,000 and smaller, except those withheld in accordance with subsection (b) or those specifically authorized under criteria established by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and in fact properly classified pursuant to such Executive order.

(b)(1) Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Defense may withhold from public disclosure any geomatics product in the possession of, or under the control of, the Department of Defense—(A) that was obtained or produced, or that contains information that was provided, pursuant to an international agreement that restricts disclosure of such product or information to government officials of the agreeing parties or that restricts use of such product or information to government purposes only;

(B) that contains information that the Secretary of Defense has determined in writing would, if disclosed, reveal sources and methods, or capabilities, used to obtain source material for production of the geomatics product; or

(C) that contains information that the Director of the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency has determined in writing would, if disclosed, jeopardize or interfere with ongoing military or intelligence operations, reveal military operational or contingency plans, or reveal, jeopardize, or compromise military or intelligence capabilities.


(2) In this subsection, the term “geomatics product” means imagery, imagery intelligence, or geospatial information.


(c)(1) Regulations to implement this section (including any amendments to such regulations) shall be published in the Federal Register for public comment for a period of not less than 30 days before they take effect.

(2) Regulations under this section shall address the conditions under which release of geomatics products a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_455_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency shall offer for sale maps and charts at scales of 1:500,000 and smaller, except those withheld in accordance with subsection (b) or those specifically authorized under criteria established by Executive order to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or foreign policy and in fact properly classified pursuant to such Executive order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_455_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_455_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>