<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4657" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4657/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4657/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4657"><akn:num>4657</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on criminal history inquiries by contractors prior to conditional offer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4657. Prohibition on criminal history inquiries by contractors prior to conditional offer(a) Limitation on Criminal History Inquiries.—(1) In general.—Except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), the head of an agency—(A) may not require that an individual or sole proprietor who submits a bid for a contract to disclose criminal history record information regarding that individual or sole proprietor before determining the apparent awardee; and

(B) shall require as a condition of receiving a Federal contract and receiving payments under such contract that the contractor may not verbally or through written form request the disclosure of criminal history record information regarding an applicant for a position related to work under such contract before such contractor extends a conditional offer to the applicant.


(2) Otherwise required by law.—The prohibition under paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to a contract if consideration of criminal history record information prior to a conditional offer with respect to the position is otherwise required by law.

(3) Exception for certain positions.—(A) In general.—The prohibition under paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to—(i) a contract that requires an individual hired under the contract to access classified information or to have sensitive law enforcement or national security duties; or

(ii) a position that the Secretary of Defense identifies under the regulations issued under subparagraph (B).


(B) Regulations.—(i) Issuance.—Not later than 16 months after the date of enactment of the Fair Chance to Compete for Jobs Act of 2019, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Administrator of General Services, shall issue regulations identifying additional positions with respect to which the prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply, giving due consideration to positions that involve interaction with minors, access to sensitive information, or managing financial transactions.

(ii) Compliance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4657_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Criminal History Inquiries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4657_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaint Procedures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall establish and publish procedures under which an applicant for a position with a Department of Defense contractor may submit a complaint, or any other information, relating to compliance by the contractor with subsection (a)(1)(B).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4657_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action for Violations of Prohibition on Criminal History Inquiries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4657_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>