<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4702" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4702/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4702/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4702"><akn:num>4702</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives and consideration for qualified training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4702. Incentives and consideration for qualified training programs(a) Incentives.—The Secretary of Defense shall develop workforce development investment incentives for a contractor that implements a qualified training program to develop the workforce of the contractor in a manner consistent with the needs of the Department of Defense.

(b) Consideration of Qualified Training Programs.—The Secretary of Defense shall revise the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to require that the system used by the Federal Government to monitor or record contractor past performance includes an analysis of the availability, quality, and effectiveness of a qualified training program of an offeror as part of the past performance rating of such offeror.

(c) Qualified Training Program Defined.—The term “qualified training program” means any of the following:(1) A program eligible to receive funds under the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.).

(2) A program eligible to receive funds under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.).

(3) A program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the “National Apprenticeship Act”; 50 Stat. 664; chapter 663; 29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.).

(4) Any other program determined to be a qualified training program for purposes of this section, and that meets the workforce needs of the Department of Defense, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.


(Added Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 864(a), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1522, § 2409a; renumbered § 4702 and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title X, § 1081(a)(40), title XVIII, § 1863(b), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3873, 4278.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), is Pub. L. 113–128, July 22, 2014, 128 Stat. 1425, which enacted chapter 32 (§ 3101 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor, repealed chapter 30 (§ 2801 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4702_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall develop workforce development investment incentives for a contractor that implements a qualified training program to develop the workforce of the contractor in a manner consistent with the needs of the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4702_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Qualified Training Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall revise the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to require that the system used by the Federal Government to monitor or record contractor past performance includes an analysis of the availability, quality, and effectiveness of a qualified training program of an offeror as part of the past performance rating of such offeror.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4702_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified Training Program Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “qualified training program” means any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>