<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4754" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4754/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4754/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4754"><akn:num>4754</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of purchase cards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4754. Management of purchase cards(a) Management of Purchase Cards.—The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the use and control of all purchase cards and convenience checks that are issued to Department of Defense personnel for official use. Those regulations shall be consistent with regulations that apply Government-wide regarding use of purchase cards by Government personnel for official purposes.

(b) Required Safeguards and Internal Controls.—Regulations under subsection (a) shall include safeguards and internal controls to ensure the following:(1) That there is a record in the Department of Defense of each holder of a purchase card issued by the Department of Defense for official use, annotated with the limitations on amounts that are applicable to the use of each such card by that purchase card holder.

(2) That each purchase card holder and individual issued a convenience check is assigned an approving official other than the card holder with the authority to approve or disapprove transactions.

(3) That the holder of a purchase card and each official with authority to authorize expenditures charged to the purchase card are responsible for—(A) reconciling the charges appearing on each statement of account for that purchase card with receipts and other supporting documentation; and

(B) forwarding that statement after being so reconciled to the designated disbursing office in a timely manner.


(4) That any disputed purchase card charge, and any discrepancy between a receipt and other supporting documentation and the purchase card statement of account, is resolved in the manner prescribed in the applicable Government-wide purchase card contract entered into by the Administrator of General Services.

(5) That payments on purchase card accounts are made promptly within prescribed deadlines to avoid interest penalties.

(6) That rebates and refunds based on prompt payment on purchase card accounts are properly recorded.

(7) That records </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4754_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Purchase Cards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations governing the use and control of all purchase cards and convenience checks that are issued to Department of Defense personnel for official use. Those regulations shall be consistent with regulations that apply Government-wide regarding use of purchase cards by Government personnel for official purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4754_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Safeguards and Internal Controls.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations under subsection (a) shall include safeguards and internal controls to ensure the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4754_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for Violations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The regulations prescribed under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>