<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/482" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/482/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/482/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_482"><akn:num>482</akn:num><akn:heading>Readiness reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 482. Readiness reports(a) Reports and Briefings.—(1) Not later than 30 days after the end of the second and fourth quarter of each calendar year, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report regarding the military readiness of the active and reserve components and the Space Force. The Secretary of Defense shall submit each such report in writing and shall also submit a copy of each such report to the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

(2) Not later than 30 days after the end of the first and third quarter of each calendar year, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to Congress a briefing regarding the military readiness of the active and reserve components and the Space Force.

(3) Each report under this subsection shall contain the elements required by subsection (b) for the quarter covered by the report, and each briefing shall address any changes to the elements described in subsection (b) since the submittal of the most recently submitted report.


(b) Required Elements.—The elements described in this subsection are each of the following:(1) A description of each readiness problem or deficiency that affects the ground, sea, air, space, cyber, or special operations forces, and any other area determined appropriate by the Secretary of Defense.

(2) The key contributing factors, indicators, and other relevant information related to each identified problem or deficiency.

(3) The short-term mitigation strategy the Department will employ to address each readiness problem or deficiency until a resolution is in place, as well as the timeline, cost, and any legislative remedies required to support the resolution.

(4) A summary of combat readiness ratings for the key force elements assessed, including specific information on personnel, supply, equipment, and training problems or deficiencies that affect the combat readiness ratings for each force element.

(5) The total number of upgrades and the total number of downgrades of the combat readiness o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_482_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and Briefings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_482_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Elements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The elements described in this subsection are each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_482_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Readiness Assessments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The information required under subsection (b) to be included in the report for a quarter shall be based on readiness assessments that are provided during that quarter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_482_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semi-Annual Joint Force Readiness Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_482_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classification of Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A report under this section shall be submitted in unclassified form. To the extent the Secretary of Defense determines necessary, the report may also be submitted in classified form.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>