<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/483" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/483/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/483/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_483"><akn:num>483</akn:num><akn:heading>Notifications related to basing decision-making process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 483. Notifications related to basing decision-making process(a) Notification Required.—At each point in the decision-making process specified in subsection (b), the Secretary concerned shall notify the congressional defense committees of the decision-making process to be used or the decision-making process used, whichever applies—(1) to select a military installation to serve as the first permanent location for a new major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system; or

(2) to make a permanent change in the basing of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system by relocating the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system from its current military installation to a different military installation.


(b) Deadlines for Submission of Notice.—The Secretary concerned shall provide the notice required by subsection (a) within seven days after each of the following decision points during the decision-making process:(1) When the Secretary concerned issues any formal internal guidance to begin the decision-making process regarding the location or relocation of a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.

(2) When the Secretary concerned selects between two and five military installations as the most likely candidate locations for a major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system in order to subject those installations to additional analysis.

(3) When the Secretary concerned selects a specific military installation as the preferred location for the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.


(c) Required Elements of Notification.—In a notice required by subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall include at a minimum the following:(1) A description of the manner in which the joint and all-domain training capabilities at each candidate location, if applicable to the type of basing decision-making process at issue, will be or was, whichever appl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) At each point in the decision-making process specified in subsection (b), the Secretary concerned shall notify the congressional defense committees of the decision-making process to be used or the decision-making process used, whichever applies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadlines for Submission of Notice.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall provide the notice required by subsection (a) within seven days after each of the following decision points during the decision-making process:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required Elements of Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In a notice required by subsection (a), the Secretary concerned shall include at a minimum the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Wait Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No irrevocable action may be taken to effect or implement a basing decision reached through the decision-making process described in subsection (a) until the end of the 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary concerned submits, in an electronic medium pursuant to section 480 of this title, the notice referred to in subsection (b)(3) regarding a preferred location for the major headquarters, covered military unit, or major weapon system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Reporting Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_483_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>