<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4841"><akn:num>4841</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturing Technology Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4841. Manufacturing Technology Program(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Manufacturing Technology Program to further the national security objectives of section 4811(a) of this title through the development and application of advanced manufacturing technologies and processes that will reduce the acquisition and supportability costs of defense weapon systems and reduce manufacturing and repair cycle times across the life cycles of such systems. The Secretary shall use the joint planning process of the directors of the Department of Defense laboratories in establishing the program. The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall administer the program.

(b) Purpose of Program.—The Secretary of Defense shall use the program—(1) to provide centralized guidance and direction (including goals, milestones, and priorities) to the military departments and the Defense Agencies on all matters relating to manufacturing technology;

(2) to direct the development and implementation of Department of Defense plans, programs, projects, activities, and policies that promote the development and application of advanced technologies to manufacturing processes, tools, and equipment;

(3) to improve the manufacturing quality, productivity, technology, and practices of businesses and workers providing goods and services to the Department of Defense;

(4) to focus Department of Defense support for the development and application of advanced manufacturing technologies and processes for use to meet manufacturing requirements that are essential to the national defense, as well as for repair and remanufacturing in support of the operations of systems commands, depots, air logistics centers, and shipyards;

(5) to disseminate information concerning improved manufacturing improvement concepts, including information on such matters as best manufacturing practices, product data exchange specifications, computer-aided acquisition and logistics support, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4841_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a Manufacturing Technology Program to further the national security objectives of section 4811(a) of this title through the development and application of advanced manufacturing technologies and processes that will reduce the acquisition and supportability costs of defense weapon systems and reduce manufacturing and repair cycle times across the life cycles of such systems. The Secretary shall use the joint planning process of the directors of the Department of Defense laboratories in establishing the program. The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering shall administer the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4841_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of Defense shall use the program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4841_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Execution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4841_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition and Cost Sharing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4841_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Five-Year Strategic Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>