<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4843" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4843/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4843/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4843"><akn:num>4843</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturing engineering education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4843. Manufacturing engineering education program(a) Establishment of Manufacturing Engineering Education Program.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program under which the Secretary makes grants or other awards to support—(A) the enhancement of existing programs in manufacturing engineering education to further a mission of the department; or

(B) the establishment of new programs in manufacturing engineering education that meet such requirements.


(2) Grants and awards under this section may be made to industry, not-for-profit institutions, institutions of higher education, or to consortia of such institutions or industry.

(3) The Secretary shall establish the program in consultation with the Secretary of Education, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the secretaries of such other relevant Federal agencies as the Secretary considers appropriate.

(4) The Secretary shall ensure that the program is coordinated with Department programs associated with advanced manufacturing.

(5) The program shall be known as the “Manufacturing Engineering Education Program”.


(b) Geographical Distribution of Grants and Awards.—In awarding grants and other awards under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, avoid geographical concentration of awards.

(c) Covered Programs.—A program of engineering education supported pursuant to this section shall meet the requirements of this section.

(d) Components of Program.—The program of education for which such a grant is made shall be a consolidated and integrated multidisciplinary program of education with an emphasis on the following components:(1) Multidisciplinary instruction that encompasses the total manufacturing engineering enterprise and that may include—(A) manufacturing engineering education and training through classroom activities, laboratory activities, thesis projects, individual or team projects, i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Manufacturing Engineering Education Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographical Distribution of Grants and Awards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Geographical Distribution of Grants and Awards.— In awarding grants and other awards under this subsection, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, avoid geographical concentration of awards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Programs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A program of engineering education supported pursuant to this section shall meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Components of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The program of education for which such a grant is made shall be a consolidated and integrated multidisciplinary program of education with an emphasis on the following components:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Defense shall solicit proposals for grants and other awards to be made pursuant to this section for the support of programs of manufacturing engineering education that are consistent with the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merit Competition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applications for awards shall be evaluated on the basis of merit pursuant to competitive procedures prescribed by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may select a proposal for an award pursuant to this section if the proposal, at a minimum, does each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4843_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of Higher Education Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1001(a)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>