<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4862" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4862/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4862/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4862"><akn:num>4862</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to buy certain articles from American sources; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4862. Requirement to buy certain articles from American sources; exceptions(a) Requirement.—Except as provided in subsections (c) through (h), funds appropriated or otherwise available to the Department of Defense may not be used for the procurement of an item described in subsection (b) if the item is not grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States.

(b) Covered Items.—An item referred to in subsection (a) is any of the following:(1) An article or item of—(A) food;

(B) clothing and the materials and components thereof, other than sensors, electronics, or other items added to, and not normally associated with, clothing (and the materials and components thereof);

(C) tents (and the structural components thereof), tarpaulins, or covers;

(D) cotton and other natural fiber products, woven silk or woven silk blends, spun silk yarn for cartridge cloth, synthetic fabric or coated synthetic fabric (including all textile fibers and yarns that are for use in such fabrics), canvas products, or wool (whether in the form of fiber or yarn or contained in fabrics, materials, or manufactured articles); or

(E) any item of individual equipment manufactured from or containing such fibers, yarns, fabrics, or materials.


(2) Hand or measuring tools.

[(3), (4) Repealed. Pub. L. 116–92, div. A, title VIII, § 854(a)(3), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 1512.]

(5) A flag of the United States.


(c) Availability Exception.—Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of any such article or item described in subsection (b) grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States cannot be procured as and when needed at United States market prices.

(d) Exception for Certain Procurements.—Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:(1) Procurements outside the United States in support of combat operations or procurements of any</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsections (c) through (h), funds appropriated or otherwise available to the Department of Defense may not be used for the procurement of an item described in subsection (b) if the item is not grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Items.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An item referred to in subsection (a) is any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity of any such article or item described in subsection (b) grown, reprocessed, reused, or produced in the United States cannot be procured as and when needed at United States market prices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Certain Procurements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Chemical Warfare Protective Clothing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsection (a) does not preclude the procurement of chemical warfare protective clothing produced outside the United States if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions for Certain Other Commodities and Items.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsection (a) does not preclude the procurement of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Commissaries, Exchanges, and Other Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subsection (a) does not apply to items purchased for resale purposes in commissaries, exchanges, or nonappropriated fund instrumentalities operated by the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Small Purchases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Contracts and Subcontracts for Procurement of Commercial Products.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) This section is applicable to contracts and subcontracts for the procurement of commercial products notwithstanding section 1906 of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4862_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic Coverage.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section, the term “United States” includes the possessions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>