<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4863" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4863/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4863/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4863"><akn:num>4863</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to buy strategic materials critical to national security from American sources; exceptio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4863. Requirement to buy strategic materials critical to national security from American sources; exceptions(a) Requirement.—Except as provided in subsections (b) through (m), the acquisition by the Department of Defense of the following items is prohibited:(1) The following types of end items, or components thereof, containing a specialty metal not melted or produced in the United States: aircraft, missile and space systems, ships, tank and automotive items, weapon systems, or ammunition.

(2) A specialty metal that is not melted or produced in the United States and that is to be purchased directly by the Department of Defense or a prime contractor of the Department.


(b) Availability Exception.—(1) Subsection (a) does not apply to the extent that the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that compliant specialty metal of satisfactory quality and sufficient quantity, and in the required form, cannot be procured as and when needed at a reasonable price. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “compliant specialty metal” means specialty metal melted or produced in the United States.

(2) This subsection applies to prime contracts and subcontracts at any tier under such contracts.

(3) The authority in subsection (b)(1)—(A) may be delegated to the head of contracting activity for the relevant component for an exception for a single acquisition program;

(B) may be delegated to the senior acquisition executive of a military department for an exception for multiple programs within such military department; and

(C) may be delegated to the Undersecretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment for an exception for more than one military department.



(c) Exception for Certain Acquisitions.—Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:(1) Acquisitions outside the United States in support of contingency operations or for use outside of the United States.

(2) Acquisitions for which the use of procedures othe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsections (b) through (m), the acquisition by the Department of Defense of the following items is prohibited:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Certain Acquisitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subsection (a) does not apply to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception Relating to Agreements With Foreign Governments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subsection (a)(1) does not preclude the acquisition of a specialty metal if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Commissaries, Exchanges, and Other Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentalities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsection (a) does not apply to items purchased for resale purposes in commissaries, exchanges, and nonappropriated fund instrumentalities operated by the Department of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Small Purchases.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsection (a) does not apply to acquisitions in amounts not greater than the simplified acquisition threshold referred to in section 3205 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for Purchases of Electronic Components.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subsection (a) does not apply to acquisitions of electronic components, unless the Secretary of Defense, upon the recommendation of the Strategic and Critical Materials Board of Directors pursuant to section 10 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (50 U.S.C. 98h–1), determines that the domestic availability of a particular electronic component is critical to national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Acquisitions of Commercial Products.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions for Purchases of Specialty Metals Below Minimum Threshold.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4863_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Streamlined Compliance for Commercial Derivative Military Articles.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>