<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4902"><akn:num>4902</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense Mentor-Protege Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4902. Department of Defense Mentor-Protege Program(a) Establishment of Program.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to be known as the “Mentor-Protege Program”.

(b) Purpose.—The purpose of the program is to provide incentives for major Department of Defense contractors to furnish disadvantaged small business concerns with assistance designed to—(1) enhance the capabilities of disadvantaged small business concerns to perform as subcontractors and suppliers under Department of Defense contracts and other contracts and subcontracts; and

(2) increase the participation of such business concerns as subcontractors and suppliers under Department of Defense contracts, other Federal Government contracts, and commercial contracts.


(c) Program Participants.—(1) A business concern meeting the eligibility requirements set out in subsection (d) may enter into agreements under subsection (e) and furnish assistance to disadvantaged small business concerns upon making application to the Secretary of Defense and being approved for participation in the program by the Secretary. A business concern participating in the program pursuant to such an approval shall be known, for the purposes of the program, as a “mentor firm”.

(2) A disadvantaged small business concern eligible for the award of Federal contracts may obtain assistance from a mentor firm upon entering into an agreement with the mentor firm as provided in subsection (e). A disadvantaged small business concern may not be a party to more than one agreement concurrently, and the authority to enter into agreements under subsection (e) shall only be available to such concern during the 5-year period beginning on the date such concern enters into the first such agreement. A disadvantaged small business concern receiving such assistance shall be known, for the purposes of the program, as a “protege firm”.

(3) In entering into an agreement pursuant to subsection (e), a mentor firm may rely in good faith on a writ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Program.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a program to be known as the “Mentor-Protege Program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The purpose of the program is to provide incentives for major Department of Defense contractors to furnish disadvantaged small business concerns with assistance designed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Participants.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor Firm Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor-Protege Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms of Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A mentor firm may provide a protege firm the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for Mentor Firms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Small Business Act.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in Mentor-Protege Program not To Be a Condition for Award of a Contract or Subcontract.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A mentor firm may not require a business concern to enter into an agreement with the mentor firm pursuant to subsection (e) as a condition for being awarded a contract by the mentor firm, including a subcontract under a contract awarded to the mentor firm.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4902_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations to carry out the Mentor-Protege Program. Such regulations shall include the requirements set forth in section 8(d) of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 637(d)) and shall prescribe procedures by which the parties may terminate participation in the program. The Department of Defense policy regarding the Mentor-Protege Program shall be published and maintained as an appendix to the Department of Defense Supplement to the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>