<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_492a"><akn:num>492a</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report on the plan for the nuclear weapons stockpile, nuclear weapons complex, nuclear weap</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 492a. Biennial report on the plan for the nuclear weapons stockpile, nuclear weapons complex, nuclear weapons delivery systems, and nuclear weapons command and control system(a) Report Required.—(1) In general.—Not later than 30 days after the submission to Congress of the budget of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, for each of the odd-numbered fiscal years 2013 through 2029, the President, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Energy, shall transmit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a detailed report on the plan for the nuclear weapons stockpile, nuclear weapons complex, nuclear weapons delivery systems, and nuclear weapons command and control system.

(2) Elements.—Each report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) A detailed description of the plan to enhance the safety, security, and reliability of the nuclear weapons stockpile of the United States.

(B) A detailed description of the plan to sustain and modernize the nuclear weapons complex, including improving the safety of facilities, modernizing the infrastructure, and maintaining the key capabilities and competencies of the nuclear weapons workforce, including designers and technicians.

(C) A detailed description of the plan to maintain, modernize, and replace delivery systems for nuclear weapons.

(D) A detailed description of the plan to sustain and modernize the nuclear weapons command and control system.

(E) A detailed description of any plans to retire, dismantle, or eliminate any nuclear warheads or bombs, nuclear weapons delivery systems, or any platforms (including silos and submarines) which carry such nuclear warheads, bombs, or delivery systems.

(F) In accordance with paragraph (3), a detailed estimate of the budget requirements associated with sustaining and modernizing the nuclear d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimate of Costs by Congressional Budget Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than July 1 of each year in which the President transmits a report required under subsection (a), the Director of the Congressional Budget Office shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller General Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Comptroller General of the United States shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent Assessment by United States Strategic Command.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>