<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/492b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_492b"><akn:num>492b</akn:num><akn:heading>Biannual briefing on nuclear weapons and related activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 492b. Biannual briefing on nuclear weapons and related activities(a) In General.—On or about May 1 and November 1 of each year, the officials specified in subsection (b) shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on matters relating to nuclear weapons policies, operations, technology development, and other similar topics as requested by such committees.

(b) Officials Specified.—The officials specified in this subsection are the following:(1) The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Acquisition.

(2) The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Nuclear Deterrence, Chemical, and Biological Defense Policy and Programs.

(3) The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Space Policy.

(4) The Deputy Administrator for Defense Programs of the National Nuclear Security Administration.

(5) The Director for Strategy, Plans, and Policy of the Joint Staff.

(6) The Director for Capability and Resource Integration for the United States Strategic Command.


(c) Delegation.—An official specified in subsection (b) may delegate the authority to provide a briefing under subsection (a) to a member of the Senior Executive Service who reports to the official.

(d) Termination.—The requirement to provide a briefing under subsection (a) shall terminate on January 1, 2028.

(Added Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI, § 1631, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 2934; amended Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1621(d)(2), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2171.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
As enacted by Pub. L. 117–263, “SEC.” preceding section designation and catchline text were editorially conformed to the style used in this title.

Amendments2024—Subsec. (b)(2). Pub. L. 118–159 substituted “Nuclear Deterrence, Chemical, and Biological Defense Policy and Programs” for “Nuclear, Chemical, and Biological Defense Programs”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) On or about May 1 and November 1 of each year, the officials specified in subsection (b) shall provide to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a briefing on matters relating to nuclear weapons policies, operations, technology development, and other similar topics as requested by such committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officials Specified.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The officials specified in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An official specified in subsection (b) may delegate the authority to provide a briefing under subsection (a) to a member of the Senior Executive Service who reports to the official.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_492b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The requirement to provide a briefing under subsection (a) shall terminate on January 1, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>