<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/493a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/493a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/493a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_493a"><akn:num>493a</akn:num><akn:heading>Industrial base monitoring for B–21 and Sentinel programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 493a. Industrial base monitoring for B–21 and Sentinel programs(a) Designation.—The Secretary of the Air Force, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, shall designate a senior official, who shall report to the Assistant Secretary, to monitor the combined industrial base supporting the acquisition of—(1) B–21 aircraft; and

(2) the Sentinel intercontinental ballistic missile weapon system.


(b) Requirements for Monitoring.—In monitoring the combined industrial base described in subsection (a), the senior official designated under such subsection shall—(1) have the authority to select staff to assist the senior official from among civilian employees of the Department and members of the armed forces, who may provide such assistance concurrently while serving in another position;

(2) monitor the acquisition by the combined industrial base of—(A) materials, technologies, and components associated with nuclear weapons systems; and

(B) commodities purchased on a large scale;


(3) monitor the hiring or contracting by the combined industrial base of personnel with critical skills; and

(4) assess whether personnel with critical skills and knowledge, intellectual property on manufacturing processes, and facilities and equipment necessary to design, develop, manufacture, repair, and support a program are available and affordable within the scopes of the B–21 aircraft program and the Sentinel intercontinental ballistic missile weapon system program.


(c) Annual Report.—At the same time as the submission of the budget of the President pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report with respect to the status of the combined industrial base described in subsection (a).

(Added Pub. L. 117–263, div. A, title XVI, § 1632, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 2934.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Conditional Requirements for Sentin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_493a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Air Force, acting through the Assistant Secretary of the Air Force for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics, shall designate a senior official, who shall report to the Assistant Secretary, to monitor the combined industrial base supporting the acquisition of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_493a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for Monitoring.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In monitoring the combined industrial base described in subsection (a), the senior official designated under such subsection shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_493a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) At the same time as the submission of the budget of the President pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report with respect to the status of the combined industrial base described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>