<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4957" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4957/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4957/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4957"><akn:num>4957</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcontractor information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4957. Subcontractor information(a) Contractors to Provide Information.—The Secretary of Defense shall require that any defense contractor in any year shall provide to an eligible entity with which the Secretary has entered into a cooperative agreement under this chapter, on the request of such entity, the information specified in subsection (b).

(b) Information to Be Provided.—Information to be provided under subsection (a) is a listing of the name of each appropriate employee of the contractor who has responsibilities with respect to entering into contracts on behalf of such contractor that constitute subcontracts of contracts being performed by such contractor, together with the business address and telephone number and area of responsibility of each such employee.

(c) Frequency.—A defense contractor need not provide information under this section to a particular eligible entity more frequently than once a year.

(d) Definition.—In this section, the term “defense contractor”, for any year, means a person awarded a contract with the Department of Defense in that year for an amount in excess of $1,000,000.

(Added Pub. L. 99–500, § 101(c) [title X, § 957(a)(1)(B)], Oct. 18, 1986, 100 Stat. 1783–82, 1783–174, and Pub. L. 99–591, § 101(c) [title X, § 957(a)(1)(B)], Oct. 30, 1986, 100 Stat. 3341–82, 3341–174, § 2416; Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title IX, formerly title IV, § 957(a)(1)(B), Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3954, renumbered title IX, Pub. L. 100–26, § 3(5), Apr. 21, 1987, 101 Stat. 273; Pub. L. 108–375, div. A, title VIII, § 816, Oct. 28, 2004, 118 Stat. 2015; renumbered § 4957 and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1872(a)(8), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4289; Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(b)(24), (m)(2)(D), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2135, 2145.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1701(m)(2)(F), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2145, amended Pub. L. 116–283, § 1872(a)(10), which had originally transferred section 241</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4957_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractors to Provide Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall require that any defense contractor in any year shall provide to an eligible entity with which the Secretary has entered into a cooperative agreement under this chapter, on the request of such entity, the information specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4957_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to Be Provided.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information to be provided under subsection (a) is a listing of the name of each appropriate employee of the contractor who has responsibilities with respect to entering into contracts on behalf of such contractor that constitute subcontracts of contracts being performed by such contractor, together with the business address and telephone number and area of responsibility of each such employee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4957_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Frequency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A defense contractor need not provide information under this section to a particular eligible entity more frequently than once a year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4957_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “defense contractor”, for any year, means a person awarded a contract with the Department of Defense in that year for an amount in excess of $1,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>