<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4958" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4958/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4958/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4958"><akn:num>4958</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to provide certain types of technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4958. Authority to provide certain types of technical assistance(a) Assistance Relating to Certain Non-defense Contracts.—The procurement technical assistance furnished by eligible entities assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter may include technical assistance relating to contracts entered into with (1) Federal departments and agencies other than the Department of Defense, and (2) State and local governments.

(b) Information Relating to Assistance and Other Programs Available.—An eligible entity assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter also may furnish information relating to assistance and other programs available pursuant to the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992.

(c) Education on Requirements Applicable to Small Businesses Under Certain Regulations.—An eligible entity assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter also may furnish education on the requirements applicable to small businesses under the regulations issued—(1) under section 38 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2778), and on compliance with those requirements;

(2) under section 9 of the Small Business Act (15 U.S.C. 638), and on compliance with those requirements;

(3) under clause 252.204–7012 of the Defense Acquisition Regulation Supplement, or any successor regulation, and on compliance with those requirements (and any successor requirements); and

(4) under section 847 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (Public Law 116–92; 133 Stat. 1505), and on compliance with those requirements (and any such successor requirements).


(Added Pub. L. 102–484, div. D, title XLII, § 4236(a)(1)(B), Oct. 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 2691, § 2418; amended Pub. L. 113–291, div. A, title VIII, § 823(b), Dec. 19, 2014, 128 Stat. 3436; Pub. L. 115–91, div. A, title XVII, § 1708, Dec. 12, 2017, 131 Stat. 1809; renumbered § 4958 and amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1872(a)(9), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4958_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance Relating to Certain Non-defense Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The procurement technical assistance furnished by eligible entities assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter may include technical assistance relating to contracts entered into with (1) Federal departments and agencies other than the Department of Defense, and (2) State and local governments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4958_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Relating to Assistance and Other Programs Available.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An eligible entity assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter also may furnish information relating to assistance and other programs available pursuant to the Defense Conversion, Reinvestment, and Transition Assistance Act of 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4958_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education on Requirements Applicable to Small Businesses Under Certain Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An eligible entity assisted by the Department of Defense under this chapter also may furnish education on the requirements applicable to small businesses under the regulations issued—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>