<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4974" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4974/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/4974/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4974"><akn:num>4974</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees charged and collected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4974. Fees charged and collected(a) Exposure Fees.—The Secretary of Defense shall charge a fee (known as “exposure fee”) for each guarantee issued under this subchapter.

(b) Amount of Exposure Fee.—To the extent that the cost of the loan guarantees under this subchapter is not otherwise provided for in appropriations Acts, the fee imposed under subsection (a) with respect to a loan guarantee shall be fixed in an amount that is sufficient to meet potential liabilities of the United States under the loan guarantee.

(c) Payment Terms.—The fee under subsection (a) for each guarantee shall become due as the guarantee is issued. In the case of a guarantee for a loan which is disbursed incrementally, and for which the guarantee is correspondingly issued incrementally as portions of the loan are disbursed, the fee shall be paid incrementally in proportion to the amount of the guarantee that is issued.

(d) Administrative Fees.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall charge a fee for each guarantee issued under this subchapter to reflect the additional administrative costs of the Department of Defense that are directly attributable to the administration of the program under this subchapter. Such fees shall be credited to a special account in the Treasury. Amounts in the special account shall be available, to the extent and in amounts provided in appropriations Acts, for paying the costs of administrative expenses of the Department of Defense that are attributable to the loan guarantee program under this subchapter.

(2)(A) If for any fiscal year amounts in the special account established under paragraph (1) are not available (or are not anticipated to be available) in a sufficient amount for administrative expenses of the Department of Defense for that fiscal year that are directly attributable to the administration of the program under this subchapter, the Secretary may use amounts currently available for operations and maintenance for Defense-wide activities, not to exceed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4974_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exposure Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall charge a fee (known as “exposure fee”) for each guarantee issued under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4974_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Exposure Fee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) To the extent that the cost of the loan guarantees under this subchapter is not otherwise provided for in appropriations Acts, the fee imposed under subsection (a) with respect to a loan guarantee shall be fixed in an amount that is sufficient to meet potential liabilities of the United States under the loan guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4974_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment Terms.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The fee under subsection (a) for each guarantee shall become due as the guarantee is issued. In the case of a guarantee for a loan which is disbursed incrementally, and for which the guarantee is correspondingly issued incrementally as portions of the loan are disbursed, the fee shall be paid incrementally in proportion to the amount of the guarantee that is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4974_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>