<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/499a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/499a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/499a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_499a"><akn:num>499a</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection, storage, and sharing of data relating to nuclear security enterprise and nuclear forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 499a. Collection, storage, and sharing of data relating to nuclear security enterprise and nuclear forces(a) In General.—The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, and the Administrator for Nuclear Security, acting through the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation, shall collect and store cost, programmatic, and technical data relating to programs and projects of the nuclear security enterprise and nuclear forces.

(b) Sharing of Data.—If the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation or the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation requests data relating to programs or projects from any element of the Department of Defense or from any element of the nuclear security enterprise of the National Nuclear Security Administration, that element shall provide that data in a timely manner.

(c) Storage of Data.—(1) Data collected by the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation and the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation under this section shall be—(A) stored in the data storage system of the Defense Cost and Resource Center, or successor center, or in a data storage system of the National Nuclear Security Administration that is comparable to the data storage system of the Defense Cost and Resource Center; and

(B) made accessible to other Federal agencies as such Directors consider appropriate.


(2) The Secretary and the Administrator shall ensure that the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation and the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation have sufficient information system support, as determined by such Directors, to facilitate the timely hosting, handling, and sharing of data relating to programs and projects of the nuclear security enterprise under this section at the appropriate level of classification.

(3) The Deputy Administrator for Naval Reactors of the National Nuclear Security Administration may coordinate with the Director </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_499a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, and the Administrator for Nuclear Security, acting through the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation, shall collect and store cost, programmatic, and technical data relating to programs and projects of the nuclear security enterprise and nuclear forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_499a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sharing of Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation or the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation requests data relating to programs or projects from any element of the Department of Defense or from any element of the nuclear security enterprise of the National Nuclear Security Administration, that element shall provide that data in a timely manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_499a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Storage of Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_499a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary and the Administrator shall ensure that any relevant contract relating to a program or project of the nuclear security enterprise and nuclear forces that is entered into after December 11, 2017, appropriately includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_499a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Security Enterprise Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section, the term “nuclear security enterprise” has the meaning given that term in section 4002 of the Atomic Energy Defense Act (50 U.S.C. 2501).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>