<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/527" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/527/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/527/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_527"><akn:num>527</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to suspend sections 523, 525, and 526</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 527. Authority to suspend sections 523, 525, and 526
In time of war, or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President after November 30, 1980, the President may suspend the operation of any provision of section 523, 525, or 526 of this title. So long as such war or national emergency continues, any such suspension may be extended by the President. Any such suspension shall, if not sooner ended, end on the last day of the two-year period beginning on the date on which the suspension (or the last extension thereof) takes effect or on the last day of the one-year period beginning on the date of the termination of the war or national emergency, whichever occurs first. With respect to the end of any such suspension, the preceding sentence supersedes the provisions of title II of the National Emergencies Act (50 U.S.C. 1621–1622) which provide that powers or authorities exercised by reason of a national emergency shall cease to be exercised after the date of the termination of the emergency.
(Added Pub. L. 96–513, title I, § 103, Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 2845, § 526; renumbered § 527 and amended Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(b)(1)(A), (2), July 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 840; Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title XVI, § 1671(c)(4), Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 3014.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe National Emergencies Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 94–412, Sept. 14, 1976, 90 Stat. 1255, as amended. Title II of the National Emergencies Act is classified generally to subchapter II (§ 1621 et seq.) of chapter 34 of Title 50, War and National Defense. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1601 of Title 50 and Tables.

Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–337 struck out “524,” after “523,” in section catchline and in text.
1988—Pub. L. 100–370 renumbered section 526 of this title as this section, substituted “524, 525, and 526” for “524, and 525” in section catchline, and “524, 525, or 526” for “524, or 525” in text.

Statutory</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>