<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5537" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5537/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5537/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5537"><akn:num>5537</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Missile Defense Agency production of satellites and ground systems associated with ope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5537. Limitation on Missile Defense Agency production of satellites and ground systems associated with operation of such satellites(a) Production of Satellites and Ground Systems.—The Director of the Missile Defense Agency may not authorize or obligate funding for a program of record for the production of satellites or ground systems associated with the operation of such satellites.

(b) Prototype Satellites.—(1) The Director, with the concurrence of the Space Acquisition Council established by section 9021 of this title, may authorize the production of one or more prototype satellites, consistent with the requirements of the Missile Defense Agency.

(2) Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Space Acquisition Council concurs with the Director with respect to authorizing the production of a prototype satellite under paragraph (1), the chair of the Council shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report explaining the reasons for such concurrence.

(3) The Director may not obligate funds for the production of a prototype satellite under paragraph (1) before the date on which the Space Acquisition Council submits the report for such prototype satellite under paragraph (2).


(Added Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(a), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2197.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVI, § 1662(a), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2103, which was set out in a note under section 4022 of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(2), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2199.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5537_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production of Satellites and Ground Systems.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Director of the Missile Defense Agency may not authorize or obligate funding for a program of record for the production of satellites or ground systems associated with the operation of such satellites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5537_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prototype Satellites.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>