<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5551" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5551/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/5551/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5551"><akn:num>5551</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions relating to missile defense information and systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5551. Prohibitions relating to missile defense information and systems(a) Certain “Hit-to-kill” Technology and Telemetry Data.—None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with “hit-to-kill” technology and telemetry data for missile defense interceptors or target vehicles.

(b) Other Sensitive Missile Defense Information.—None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with—(1) information relating to velocity at burnout of missile defense interceptors or targets of the United States; or

(2) classified or otherwise controlled missile defense information.


(c) Exception.—The prohibitions in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to the United States providing to the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China information regarding ballistic missile early warning.

(d) Integration.—None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be obligated or expended to integrate a missile defense system of the Russian Federation or a missile defense system of the People’s Republic of China into any missile defense system of the United States.

(Added and amended Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, §§ 1641, 1649(a), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2182, 2198.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in section 130h of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 118–159, div. A, title XVI, § 1649(b)(1), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2199.

Amendments2024—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 118–159, § 1641(1), inserted “or the People’s Republic of China” after “the Russian Federation”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 118–159, § 1641(2), inserted “or the People’s Republ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain “Hit-to-kill” Technology and Telemetry Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with “hit-to-kill” technology and telemetry data for missile defense interceptors or target vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Sensitive Missile Defense Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be used to provide the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The prohibitions in subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply to the United States providing to the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China information regarding ballistic missile early warning.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5551_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available for any fiscal year for the Department of Defense may be obligated or expended to integrate a missile defense system of the Russian Federation or a missile defense system of the People’s Republic of China into any missile defense system of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>