<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_628"><akn:num>628</akn:num><akn:heading>Special selection boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 628. Special selection boards(a) Persons Not Considered by Promotion Boards Due to Administrative Error.—(1) If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that because of administrative error a person who should have been considered for selection for promotion from in or above the promotion zone by a promotion board was not so considered, the Secretary shall convene a special selection board under this subsection to determine whether that person (whether or not then on active duty) should be recommended for promotion.

(2) A special selection board convened under paragraph (1) shall consider the record of the person whose name was referred to it for consideration as that record would have appeared to the board that should have considered him. That record shall be compared with a sampling of the records of those officers of the same competitive category who were recommended for promotion, and those officers who were not recommended for promotion, by the board that should have considered him.

(3) If a special selection board convened under paragraph (1) does not recommend for promotion a person whose name was referred to it for consideration for selection for appointment to a grade other than a general officer or flag officer grade, the person shall be considered to have failed of selection for promotion.


(b) Persons Considered by Promotion Boards in Unfair Manner.—(1) If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines, in the case of a person who was considered for selection for promotion by a promotion board but was not selected, that there was material unfairness with respect to that person, the Secretary may convene a special selection board under this subsection to determine whether that person (whether or not then on active duty) should be recommended for promotion. In order to determine that there was material unfairness, the Secretary must determine that—(A) the action of the promotion board that considered the person was </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Not Considered by Promotion Boards Due to Administrative Error.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons Considered by Promotion Boards in Unfair Manner.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports of Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Persons Selected by Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deceased Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If a person whose name is being considered for referral to a special selection board under this section dies before the completion of proceedings under this section with respect to that person, this section shall be applied to that person posthumously.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convening of Boards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A board convened under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations of Other Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No official or court of the United States may, with respect to a claim based to any extent on the failure of a person to be selected for promotion by a promotion board—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section limits—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>