<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/628a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_628a"><akn:num>628a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special selection review boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 628a. Special selection review boards(a) In General.—(1)(A) If the Secretary of the military department concerned determines that a person recommended by a promotion board for promotion to a grade at or below the grade of major general or rear admiral in the Navy is the subject of credible information of an adverse nature, including any substantiated adverse finding or conclusion described in section 615(a)(3)(A) of this title, that was not furnished to the promotion board during its consideration of the person for promotion as otherwise required by such section, the Secretary shall convene a special selection review board under this section to review the person and recommend whether the recommendation for promotion of the person should be sustained.

(B) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent a Secretary concerned from deferring consideration of adverse information concerning an officer subject to this section until the next regularly scheduled promotion board applicable to such officer, in lieu of furnishing such adverse information to a special selection review board under this section.


(2) If a person and the recommendation for promotion of the person is subject to review under this section by a special selection review board convened under this section, the name of the person—(A) shall not be disseminated or publicly released on the list of officers recommended for promotion by the promotion board recommending the promotion of the person; and

(B) shall not be forwarded for appointment or nomination to the Secretary of Defense, the President, or the Senate, as applicable.



(b) Convening.—(1) Any special selection review board convened under this section shall be convened in accordance with the provisions of section 628(f) of this title.

(2) Any special selection review board convened under this section may review such number of persons, and recommendations for promotion of such persons, as the Secretary of the military department concerned</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Convening.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information Considered.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Persons.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_628a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion Board Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “promotion board” means a selection board convened by the Secretary of a military department under section 611(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>