<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/629" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/629/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/629/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_629"><akn:num>629</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal from a list of officers recommended for promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 629. Removal from a list of officers recommended for promotion(a) Removal by President.—The President may remove the name of any officer from a list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter.

(b) Removal Due to Senate Not Giving Advice and Consent.—If, after consideration of a list of officers approved for promotion by the President to a grade for which appointment is required by section 624(c) of this title to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the Senate does not give its advice and consent to the appointment of an officer whose name is on the list, that officer’s name shall be removed from the list.

(c) Removal After 18 Months.—(1) If an officer whose name is on a list of officers approved for promotion under section 624(a) of this title to a grade for which appointment is required by section 624(c) of this title to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate is not appointed to that grade under such section during the officer’s promotion eligibility period, the officer’s name shall be removed from the list unless as of the end of such period the Senate has given its advice and consent to the appointment.

(2) Before the end of the promotion eligibility period with respect to an officer under paragraph (1), the President may extend that period for purposes of paragraph (1) by an additional 12 months.

(3) Paragraph (1) does not apply when the military department concerned is not able to obtain and provide to the Senate the information the Senate requires to give its advice and consent to the appointment concerned because that information is under the control of a department or agency of the Federal Government other than the Department of Defense.

(4) In this subsection, the term “promotion eligibility period” means, with respect to an officer whose name is on a list of officers approved for promotion under section 624(a) of this title to a grade for which appointment is required</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal by President.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President may remove the name of any officer from a list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board convened under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal Due to Senate Not Giving Advice and Consent.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If, after consideration of a list of officers approved for promotion by the President to a grade for which appointment is required by section 624(c) of this title to be made by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the Senate does not give its advice and consent to the appointment of an officer whose name is on the list, that officer’s name shall be removed from the list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal After 18 Months.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Removal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, if an officer on the active-duty list is discharged or dropped from the rolls or transferred to a retired status after having been recommended for promotion to a higher grade under this chapter, but before being promoted, the officer’s name shall be administratively removed from the list of officers recommended for promotion by a selection board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued Eligibility for Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>