<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/649b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/649b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/649b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_649b"><akn:num>649b</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection for promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 649b. Selection for promotion(a) In General.—Except as provided in this section, the selection for promotion of officers in any competitive category of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter shall be governed by the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter.

(b) No Recommendation for Promotion of Officers Below Promotion Zone.—Section 616(b) of this title shall not apply to the selection for promotion of officers described in subsection (a).

(c) Recommendation for Officers To Be Excluded From Future Consideration for Promotion.—In making recommendations pursuant to section 616 of this title for purposes of the administration of this subchapter, a selection board convened under section 611(a) of this title may recommend that an officer considered by the board be excluded from future consideration for promotion under this chapter.

(Added Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 507(a)(1), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1744.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_649b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in this section, the selection for promotion of officers in any competitive category of officers designated for purposes of this subchapter shall be governed by the provisions of subchapter I of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_649b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Recommendation for Promotion of Officers Below Promotion Zone.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Section 616(b) of this title shall not apply to the selection for promotion of officers described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_649b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendation for Officers To Be Excluded From Future Consideration for Promotion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In making recommendations pursuant to section 616 of this title for purposes of the administration of this subchapter, a selection board convened under section 611(a) of this title may recommend that an officer considered by the board be excluded from future consideration for promotion under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>