<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/654" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/654/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/654/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_654"><akn:num>654</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum service requirement for certain cyberspace occupational specialties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 654. Minimum service requirement for certain cyberspace occupational specialties(a) Cyberspace Operations Officer.—The minimum service obligation for any member who successfully completes training in the armed forces in direct accession to the cyberspace operations officer occupational specialty of the Marine Corps shall be eight years.

(b) Service Obligation Defined.—In this section, the term “service obligation” means the period of active duty or, in the case of a member of a reserve component who completed cyberspace operations training in an active duty for training status as a member of a reserve component, the period of service in an active status in the Selected Reserve, required to be served after completion of cyberspace operations training.

(Added Pub. L. 118–31, div. A, title V, § 509(b), Dec. 22, 2023, 137 Stat. 243.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 654, added Pub. L. 103–160, div. A, title V, § 571(a)(1), Nov. 30, 1993, 107 Stat. 1670, related to policy concerning homosexuality in the armed forces, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 111–321, § 2(f)(1)(A), Dec. 22, 2010, 124 Stat. 3516.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Don’t Ask, Don’t Tell RepealPub. L. 111–321, Dec. 22, 2010, 124 Stat. 3515, repealed former section 654 of this title effective 60 days after the later of the Secretary of Defense receiving a report, which was released Nov. 30, 2010, and the President transmitting to the congressional defense committees a written certification, which was transmitted July 22, 2011.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cyberspace Operations Officer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The minimum service obligation for any member who successfully completes training in the armed forces in direct accession to the cyberspace operations officer occupational specialty of the Marine Corps shall be eight years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_654_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service Obligation Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In this section, the term “service obligation” means the period of active duty or, in the case of a member of a reserve component who completed cyberspace operations training in an active duty for training status as a member of a reserve component, the period of service in an active status in the Selected Reserve, required to be served after completion of cyberspace operations training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>