<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/688a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/688a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/688a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_688a"><akn:num>688a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to order to active duty in high-demand, low-density assignments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 688a. Authority to order to active duty in high-demand, low-density assignments(a) Authority.—The Secretary of a military department may order to active duty a retired member who agrees to serve on active duty in an assignment intended to alleviate a high-demand, low-density military capability or in any other specialty designated by the Secretary as critical to meet wartime or peacetime requirements. Any such order may be made only with the consent of the member ordered to active duty and in accordance with an agreement between the Secretary and the member.

(b) Duration.—The period of active duty of a member under an order to active duty under subsection (a) shall be specified in the agreement entered into under that subsection.

(c) Limitation.—No more than a total of 1,000 members may be on active duty at any time under subsection (a).

(d) Relationship to Other Authority.—The authority to order a retired member to active duty under this section is in addition to the authority under section 688 of this title or any other provision of law authorizing the Secretary concerned to order a retired member to active duty.

(e) Inapplicability of Certain Provisions.—Retired members ordered to active duty under subsection (a) shall not be counted for purposes of section 688 or 690 of this title.

(f) Exceptions During Periods of War or National Emergency.—The limitation in subsection (c) shall not apply during a time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President.

(g) High-Demand, Low-Density Military Capability Defined.—In this section, the term “high-demand, low-density military capability” means a combat, combat support or service support capability, unit, system, or occupational specialty that the Secretary of Defense determines has funding, equipment, or personnel levels that are substantially below the levels required to fully meet or sustain actual or expected operational requirements set by regional commanders.

(Added Pub. L. 107–314, di</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of a military department may order to active duty a retired member who agrees to serve on active duty in an assignment intended to alleviate a high-demand, low-density military capability or in any other specialty designated by the Secretary as critical to meet wartime or peacetime requirements. Any such order may be made only with the consent of the member ordered to active duty and in accordance with an agreement between the Secretary and the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The period of active duty of a member under an order to active duty under subsection (a) shall be specified in the agreement entered into under that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No more than a total of 1,000 members may be on active duty at any time under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The authority to order a retired member to active duty under this section is in addition to the authority under section 688 of this title or any other provision of law authorizing the Secretary concerned to order a retired member to active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of Certain Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Retired members ordered to active duty under subsection (a) shall not be counted for purposes of section 688 or 690 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions During Periods of War or National Emergency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The limitation in subsection (c) shall not apply during a time of war or of national emergency declared by Congress or the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_688a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-Demand, Low-Density Military Capability Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section, the term “high-demand, low-density military capability” means a combat, combat support or service support capability, unit, system, or occupational specialty that the Secretary of Defense determines has funding, equipment, or personnel levels that are substantially below the levels required to fully meet or sustain actual or expected operational requirements set by regional commanders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>