<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7419" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7419/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7419/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7419"><akn:num>7419</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruit basic training: separate housing for male and female recruits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7419. Recruit basic training: separate housing for male and female recruits(a) Physically Separate Housing.—(1) The Secretary of the Army shall provide for housing male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other during basic training.

(2) To meet the requirements of paragraph (1), the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for male recruits shall be physically separated from the sleeping areas and latrine areas provided for female recruits by permanent walls, and the areas for male recruits and the areas for female recruits shall have separate entrances.

(3) The Secretary shall ensure that, when a recruit is in an area referred to in paragraph (2), the area is supervised by one or more persons who are authorized and trained to supervise the area.


(b) Alternative Separate Housing.—If male recruits and female recruits cannot be housed as provided under subsection (a) by October 1, 2001, at a particular installation, the Secretary of the Army shall require (on and after that date) that male recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for males and that female recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for females.

(c) Construction Planning.—In planning for the construction of housing to be used for housing recruits during basic training, the Secretary of the Army shall ensure that the housing is to be constructed in a manner that facilitates the housing of male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other.

(d) Basic Training Defined.—In this section, the term ‘basic training’ means the initial entry training program of the Army that constitutes the basic training of new recruits.

(Added Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title V, § 521(a)(1), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2009, § 4319; renumbered § 7419, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(c)(1), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7419_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physically Separate Housing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7419_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Separate Housing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) If male recruits and female recruits cannot be housed as provided under subsection (a) by October 1, 2001, at a particular installation, the Secretary of the Army shall require (on and after that date) that male recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for males and that female recruits in basic training at such installation be housed in barracks or other troop housing facilities that are only for females.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7419_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction Planning.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In planning for the construction of housing to be used for housing recruits during basic training, the Secretary of the Army shall ensure that the housing is to be constructed in a manner that facilitates the housing of male recruits and female recruits separately and securely from each other.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7419_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic Training Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term ‘basic training’ means the initial entry training program of the Army that constitutes the basic training of new recruits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>