<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7542"><akn:num>7542</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical data packages for large-caliber cannon: prohibition on transfers to foreign countries; exc</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7542. Technical data packages for large-caliber cannon: prohibition on transfers to foreign countries; exception(a) General Rule.—Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used—(1) to transfer to a foreign country a technical data package for a defense item being manufactured or developed in an arsenal; or

(2) to assist a foreign country in producing such a defense item.


(b) Exception.—The Secretary of the Army may use funds appropriated to the Department of Defense to transfer a technical data package, or to provide assistance, described in subsection (a) if—(1) the transfer or provision of assistance is to a friendly foreign country (as determined by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of State);

(2) the Secretary of the Army determines that such action—(A) would have a clear benefit to the preservation of the production base for the production of cannon at the arsenal concerned; and

(B) would not transfer technology (including production techniques) considered unique to the arsenal concerned, except as provided in subsection (e); and


(3) the Secretary of Defense enters into an agreement with the country concerned described in subsection (c) or (d).


(c) Coproduction Agreements.—An agreement under this subsection shall be in the form of a Government-to-Government Memorandum of Understanding and shall include provisions that—(1) prescribe the content of the technical data package or assistance to be transferred to the foreign country participating in the agreement;

(2) require that production by the participating foreign country of the defense item to which the technical data package or assistance relates be shared with the arsenal concerned;

(3) subject to such exceptions as may be approved under subsection (f), prohibit transfer by the participating foreign country to a third party or country of—(A) any defense article, technical data package, technology, or assistance provided by the United States under the ag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Rule.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Funds appropriated to the Department of Defense may not be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Army may use funds appropriated to the Department of Defense to transfer a technical data package, or to provide assistance, described in subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coproduction Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An agreement under this subsection shall be in the form of a Government-to-Government Memorandum of Understanding and shall include provisions that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Project Agreements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An agreement under this subsection is a cooperative project agreement under section 27 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2767) which includes provisions that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing Fees and Royalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The limitation in subsection (b)(2)(B) shall not apply if the technology (or production technique) transferred is subject to nonexclusive license and payment of any negotiated licensing fee or royalty that reflects the cost of development, implementation, and prove-out of the technology or production technique. Any negotiated license fee or royalty shall be placed in the operating fund of the arsenal concerned for the purpose of capital investment and technology development at that arsenal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers to Third Parties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A transfer described in subsection (c)(3) may be made if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Reports to Congress.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7542_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arsenal Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section, the term “arsenal” means a Government-owned, Government-operated defense plant that manufactures large-caliber cannon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>