<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7544" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7544/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7544/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7544"><akn:num>7544</akn:num><akn:heading>Army industrial facilities: cooperative activities with non-Army entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7544. Army industrial facilities: cooperative activities with non-Army entities(a) Cooperative Arrangements Authorized.—A working-capital funded Army industrial facility may enter into a contract or other cooperative arrangement with a non-Army entity to carry out with the non-Army entity a military or commercial project described in subsection (b), subject to the conditions prescribed in subsection (c).

(b) Authorized Activities.—A cooperative arrangement entered into by an Army industrial facility under subsection (a) may provide for any of the following activities:(1) The sale of articles manufactured by the facility or services performed by the facility to persons outside the Department of the Army.

(2) The performance of work by a non-Army entity at the facility.

(3) The performance of work by the facility for a non-Army entity.

(4) The sharing of work by the facility and a non-Army entity.

(5) The leasing, or use under a facilities use contract or otherwise, of the facility (including excess capacity) or equipment (including excess equipment) of the facility by a non-Army entity.

(6) The preparation and submission of joint offers by the facility and a non-Army entity for competitive procurements entered into with Federal agency.


(c) Conditions.—An activity authorized by subsection (b) may be carried out at an Army industrial facility under a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a) only under the following conditions:(1) In the case of an article to be manufactured or services to be performed by the facility, the articles can be substantially manufactured, or the services can be substantially performed, by the facility without subcontracting for more than incidental performance.

(2) The activity does not interfere with performance of—(A) work by the facility for the Department of Defense; or

(B) a military mission of the facility.


(3) The activity meets one of the following objectives:(A) Maximized utilization of the capacity of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative Arrangements Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A working-capital funded Army industrial facility may enter into a contract or other cooperative arrangement with a non-Army entity to carry out with the non-Army entity a military or commercial project described in subsection (b), subject to the conditions prescribed in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A cooperative arrangement entered into by an Army industrial facility under subsection (a) may provide for any of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An activity authorized by subsection (b) may be carried out at an Army industrial facility under a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a) only under the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Arrangement Methods and Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) To establish a cooperative arrangement under subsection (a) with a non-Army entity, the approval authority described in subsection (f) for an Army industrial facility may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proceeds Credited to Working Capital Fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The proceeds received from the sale of an article or service pursuant to a contract or other cooperative arrangement under this section shall be credited to the working capital fund that incurs the cost of manufacturing the article or performing the service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The authority of an Army industrial facility to enter into a cooperative arrangement under subsection (a) shall be exercised at the level of the commander of the major subordinate command of the Army that has responsibility for the facility. The commander may approve such an arrangement on a case-by-case basis or a class basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial Sales.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Except in the case of work performed for the Department of Defense, for a contract of the Department of Defense, for foreign military sales, or for authorized foreign direct commercial sales (defense articles or defense services sold to a foreign government or international organization under export controls), a sale of articles or services may be made under this section only if the approval authority described in subsection (f) determines that the articles or services are not available from a commercial source located in the United States in the required quantity or quality, or within the time required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion From Depot-Level Maintenance and Repair Percentage Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amounts expended for the performance of a depot-level maintenance and repair workload by non-Federal Government personnel at an Army industrial facility shall not be counted for purposes of applying the percentage limitation in section 2466(a) of this title if the personnel are provided by a non-Army entity pursuant to a cooperative arrangement entered into under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the application of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7544_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>