<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/7721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7721"><akn:num>7721</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and responsibilities of the Secretary of the Army</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7721. Authority and responsibilities of the Secretary of the Army(a) General Authority.—The Secretary of the Army shall develop, operate, manage, administer, oversee, and fund the Army National Military Cemeteries specified in subsection (b) in a manner and to standards that fully honor the service and sacrifices of the deceased members of the armed forces buried or inurned in the Cemeteries.

(b) Army National Military Cemeteries.—The Army National Military Cemeteries (in this chapter referred to as the “Cemeteries”) consist of the following:(1) Arlington National Cemetery in Arlington, Virginia.

(2) The United States Soldiers’ and Airmen’s Home National Cemetery in the District of Colombia.


(c) Administrative Jurisdiction.—The Cemeteries shall be under the jurisdiction of Headquarters, Department of the Army.

(d) Regulations and Other Policies.—The Secretary of the Army shall prescribe such regulations and policies as may be necessary to administer the Cemeteries.

(e) Budgetary and Reporting Requirements.—The Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives an annual budget request (and detailed justifications for the amount of the request) to fund administration, operation and maintenance, and construction related to the Cemeteries. The Secretary may include, as necessary, proposals for new or amended statutory authority related to the Cemeteries.

(Added Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title V, § 591(a)(1), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1439, § 4721; renumbered § 7721, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 808(d), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1839.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 7721 was renumbered section 8891 of this title.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–232 renumbered section 4721 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 115–232 effective Feb. 1, 2019, with prov</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Army shall develop, operate, manage, administer, oversee, and fund the Army National Military Cemeteries specified in subsection (b) in a manner and to standards that fully honor the service and sacrifices of the deceased members of the armed forces buried or inurned in the Cemeteries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Army National Military Cemeteries.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Army National Military Cemeteries (in this chapter referred to as the “Cemeteries”) consist of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Cemeteries shall be under the jurisdiction of Headquarters, Department of the Army.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7721_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and Other Policies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of the Army shall prescribe such regulations and policies as may be necessary to administer the Cemeteries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7721_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budgetary and Reporting Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of the Army shall submit to the congressional defense committees and the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives an annual budget request (and detailed justifications for the amount of the request) to fund administration, operation and maintenance, and construction related to the Cemeteries. The Secretary may include, as necessary, proposals for new or amended statutory authority related to the Cemeteries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>