<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/774" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/774/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/774/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_774"><akn:num>774</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious apparel: wearing while in uniform</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 774. Religious apparel: wearing while in uniform(a) General Rule.—Except as provided under subsection (b), a member of the armed forces may wear an item of religious apparel while wearing the uniform of the member’s armed force.

(b) Exceptions.—The Secretary concerned may prohibit the wearing of an item of religious apparel—(1) in circumstances with respect to which the Secretary determines that the wearing of the item would interfere with the performance of the member’s military duties; or

(2) if the Secretary determines, under regulations under subsection (c), that the item of apparel is not neat and conservative.


(c) Regulations.—The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations concerning the wearing of religious apparel by members of the armed forces under the Secretary’s jurisdiction while the members are wearing the uniform. Such regulations shall be consistent with subsections (a) and (b).

(d) Religious Apparel Defined.—In this section, the term “religious apparel” means apparel the wearing of which is part of the observance of the religious faith practiced by the member.

(Added Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title V, § 508(a)(2), Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1086.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 774 was renumbered section 776 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
RegulationsPub. L. 100–180, div. A, title V, § 508(c), Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1087, directed the Secretary concerned to prescribe the regulations required by subsec. (c) of this section not later than the end of the 120-day period beginning on Dec. 4, 1987.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Rule.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided under subsection (b), a member of the armed forces may wear an item of religious apparel while wearing the uniform of the member’s armed force.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned may prohibit the wearing of an item of religious apparel—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations concerning the wearing of religious apparel by members of the armed forces under the Secretary’s jurisdiction while the members are wearing the uniform. Such regulations shall be consistent with subsections (a) and (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_774_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious Apparel Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section, the term “religious apparel” means apparel the wearing of which is part of the observance of the religious faith practiced by the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>