<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8013"><akn:num>8013</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of the Navy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8013. Secretary of the Navy(a)(1) There is a Secretary of the Navy, appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Secretary shall, to the greatest extent practicable, be appointed from among persons most highly qualified for the position by reason of background and experience, including persons with appropriate management or leadership experience. The Secretary is the head of the Department of the Navy.

(2) A person may not be appointed as Secretary of the Navy within seven years after relief from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.


(b) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense and subject to the provisions of chapter 6 of this title, the Secretary of the Navy is responsible for, and has the authority necessary to conduct, all affairs of the Department of the Navy, including the following functions:(1) Recruiting.

(2) Organizing.

(3) Supplying.

(4) Equipping (including research and development).

(5) Training.

(6) Servicing.

(7) Mobilizing.

(8) Demobilizing.

(9) Administering (including the morale and welfare of personnel).

(10) Maintaining.

(11) The construction, outfitting, and repair of military equipment.

(12) The construction, maintenance, and repair of buildings, structures, and utilities and the acquisition of real property and interests in real property necessary to carry out the responsibilities specified in this section.


(c) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy is also responsible to the Secretary of Defense for—(1) the functioning and efficiency of the Department of the Navy;

(2) the formulation of policies and programs by the Department of the Navy that are fully consistent with national security objectives and policies established by the President or the Secretary of Defense;

(3) the effective and timely implementation of policy, program</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense and subject to the provisions of chapter 6 of this title, the Secretary of the Navy is responsible for, and has the authority necessary to conduct, all affairs of the Department of the Navy, including the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy is also responsible to the Secretary of Defense for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of the Navy is also responsible for such other activities as may be prescribed by law or by the President or Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) After first informing the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Navy may make such recommendations to Congress relating to the Department of Defense as he considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of the Navy may assign such of his functions, powers, and duties as he considers appropriate to the Under Secretary of the Navy and to the Assistant Secretaries of the Navy. Officers of the Navy and the Marine Corps shall, as directed by the Secretary, report on any matter to the Secretary, the Under Secretary, or any Assistant Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8013_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary of the Navy may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>