<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8039" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8039/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8039/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8039"><akn:num>8039</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command for the Supervision of Shipbuilding, Conversion, a</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8039. Deputy Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command for the Supervision of Shipbuilding, Conversion, and Repair(a) In General.—The Secretary of the Navy shall establish and appoint an individual to the position of Deputy Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command for the Supervision of Shipbuilding, Conversion, and Repair (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Commander”).

(b) Qualifications.—The Deputy Commander shall be a flag officer of the Navy or an employee of the Navy in a Senior Executive Service position who possesses the expertise required to carry out the responsibilities specified in this section.

(c) Reporting.—The Deputy Commander shall report directly to the Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command.

(d) General Responsibilities.—The Deputy Commander shall oversee—(1) the independent administration and management of the execution of Department of Defense contracts awarded to commercial entities for shipbuilding, conversion, and repair at the facilities of such entities;

(2) the designated contract administration office of the Department responsible for performing contract administration services for such contracts;

(3) enforcement of requirements of such contracts to ensure satisfaction of all contractual obligations;

(4) the work performed on such contracts to facilitate greater quality and economy in the products and services being procured; and

(5) on-site quality assurance by the Government for such contracts, including inspections.


(e) Non-Contract Administration Services Functions.—The Deputy Commander shall manage the complexities and unique demands of shipbuilding, conversion, and repair by overseeing the performance of the following non-contract administration services functions for Navy Program Executives Offices, fleet commanders, and the Naval Sea Systems Command headquarters:(1) Project oversight, including the following:(A) Coordinating responses to non-contractual emergent problems, as assigned by the Commander of N</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Navy shall establish and appoint an individual to the position of Deputy Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command for the Supervision of Shipbuilding, Conversion, and Repair (in this section referred to as the “Deputy Commander”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Deputy Commander shall be a flag officer of the Navy or an employee of the Navy in a Senior Executive Service position who possesses the expertise required to carry out the responsibilities specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Deputy Commander shall report directly to the Commander of the Naval Sea Systems Command.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Deputy Commander shall oversee—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Contract Administration Services Functions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Deputy Commander shall manage the complexities and unique demands of shipbuilding, conversion, and repair by overseeing the performance of the following non-contract administration services functions for Navy Program Executives Offices, fleet commanders, and the Naval Sea Systems Command headquarters:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive Contract Management.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Deputy Commander shall maintain direct relationships with the Director of the Defense Contract Management Agency and the Director of the Defense Contract Audit Agency to facilitate comprehensive contract management and oversight of commercial entities awarded a contract described in subsection (d)(1) and subcontractors (at any tier).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcontractor Audits.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Deputy Commander shall request that the Director of the Defense Contract Audit Agency perform periodic audits of subcontractors that perform cost-type subcontracts or incentive subcontracts—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8039_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Written Assessment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>