<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8101"><akn:num>8101</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescribed number; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8101. Prescribed number; vacancies
In this chapter, the term “prescribed number” or “number . . . prescribed” as applied to a grade, means the number of officers of a described corps, designation, or other category that shall be maintained in the grade concerned. Except as otherwise specifically provided, the actual number of officers in a grade may not exceed the prescribed number. Vacancies occur whenever, and to the extent that, the actual number falls below the prescribed number.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 299, § 5441; Pub. L. 96–513, title III, § 313(a), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 2889; Pub. L. 101–189, div. A, title XVI, § 1622(e)(8), Nov. 29, 1989, 103 Stat. 1605; renumbered § 8101, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(1), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1834.)

Historical and Revision NotesThis section is derived from the distribution-in-grade provisions of the Officers Personnel Act of 1947. It is inserted here to show clearly what is meant by the “authorized number” of officers in a grade as used in the distribution-in-grade sections of the Officer Personnel Act. “Prescribed number” is substituted for “authorized number” because the latter, as used in other provisions of law, means simply the maximum number of persons authorized to be in a designated category. As used in the distribution-in-grade provisions of the Officer Personnel Act the term means not only the maximum number of officers that may be in a particular grade, but also the number of officers that should be maintained in that grade. It places not only a ceiling but a floor on the number of officers for the grade concerned. This is accomplished by establishing vacancies when the actual number of officers in the grade concerned falls below the “authorized” or, as used here, the “prescribed” number. Where there is a prescribed number for a grade, an officer should, in the absence of other controlling provisions of law, be promoted to that grade to fill an existing vacancy, as of the dat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>