<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8186" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8186/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8186/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8186"><akn:num>8186</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical institutions: detail of naval officers to promote knowledge of naval engineering and naval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8186. Technical institutions: detail of naval officers to promote knowledge of naval engineering and naval architecture(a) To promote a knowledge of naval engineering and naval architecture, the President, upon the application of any established scientific school or college in the United States, the Commonwealths or possessions, may detail a qualified officer of the Navy as a professor in that school or college. The number of officers detailed under this section may not exceed 25 at any one time.

(b) The President may prescribe regulations for detailing such officers and may recall them when the public interest requires.

(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 374, § 5986; Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title X, § 1057(a)(5), Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3440; renumbered § 8186, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(b)(6), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1834.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


598634 U.S.C. 1126.Feb. 26, 1879, ch. 105, 20 Stat. 322.


In subsection (a) the words “To promote” are substituted for the words “For the purposes of promoting” for brevity and the words “among the young men of the United States” are omitted as surplusage. The words “naval engineering” are substituted for the words “steam engineering” and the words “naval architecture” are substituted for the words “iron-ship building” to conform to current terminology and to express more clearly the intent of the statute. The words “the Territories, Commonwealths, or possessions” are inserted, since the words “United States” in the source statute are considered to have included all areas under the United States flag.
Section 1 of the Act of March 3, 1899, ch. 413, 30 Stat. 1004, transferred officers of the Engineer Corps of the Navy to the line of the Navy; therefore, in subsection (a) the words “qualified officer” are substituted for the words “engineer officer” to preserve the meaning of the section and to include any officer posse</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8186_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) To promote a knowledge of naval engineering and naval architecture, the President, upon the application of any established scientific school or college in the United States, the Commonwealths or possessions, may detail a qualified officer of the Navy as a professor in that school or college. The number of officers detailed under this section may not exceed 25 at any one time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8186_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The President may prescribe regulations for detailing such officers and may recall them when the public interest requires.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>