<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8373" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8373/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8373/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8373"><akn:num>8373</akn:num><akn:heading>Navy Reserve and Marine Corps Reserve; officers: elimination from active status; computation of tota</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8373. Navy Reserve and Marine Corps Reserve; officers: elimination from active status; computation of total commissioned service(a) Subject to section 12645 of this title, an officer in an active status in the Navy Reserve in the permanent grade of lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade), and an officer in an active status in the Marine Corps Reserve in the permanent grade of captain or first lieutenant, who is considered as having twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade while on the active-duty list may, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Navy, be eliminated from an active status or released from active duty and placed on the reserve active-status list.

(b) An officer who is to be eliminated from an active status under subsection (a) shall, if qualified, be given an opportunity to request transfer to the appropriate Retired Reserve and, if he requests it, shall be so transferred. If he is not so transferred, he shall, in the discretion of the Secretary, be transferred to the appropriate inactive status list or be discharged from the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve.

(c)(1) An officer in an active status in the Navy Reserve in the permanent grade of lieutenant commander or commander, and an officer in an active status in the Marine Corps Reserve in the permanent grade of major or lieutenant colonel, who is considered as having twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade while on the active-duty list shall, if qualified, be given an opportunity to request transfer to the appropriate Retired Reserve. If he is not so transferred, he shall be discharged from the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve if he has completed a period of total commissioned service equal to that specified below for the permanent grade in which he is serving:







GradeTotal commissioned service

NavyMarine Corps


CommanderLieutenant colonel28 years.
Lieutenant commanderMajor20 years.




(2) Notwithstanding the first sentenc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8373_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to section 12645 of this title, an officer in an active status in the Navy Reserve in the permanent grade of lieutenant or lieutenant (junior grade), and an officer in an active status in the Marine Corps Reserve in the permanent grade of captain or first lieutenant, who is considered as having twice failed of selection for promotion to the next higher grade while on the active-duty list may, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Navy, be eliminated from an active status or released from active duty and placed on the reserve active-status list.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8373_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An officer who is to be eliminated from an active status under subsection (a) shall, if qualified, be given an opportunity to request transfer to the appropriate Retired Reserve and, if he requests it, shall be so transferred. If he is not so transferred, he shall, in the discretion of the Secretary, be transferred to the appropriate inactive status list or be discharged from the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8373_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8373_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For the purposes of subsection (c), the total commissioned service of an officer who has served continuously in the Navy Reserve or the Marine Corps Reserve following appointment therein in the permanent grade of ensign or second lieutenant, as the case may be, shall be computed from June 30 of the fiscal year in which he accepted the appointment. Each other officer is considered to have for this purpose as much total commissioned service as the years of active commissioned service of any regular officer on the active-duty list of the Navy not restricted in the performance of duty, or any regular officer on the active-duty list of the Marine Corps not restricted in the performance of duty, as appropriate, who has served continuously since original appointment as an ensign on the active-duty list of the Navy or as a second lieutenant on the active-duty list of the Marine Corps, has not lost numbers or prec­edence, and is, or has been after September 6, 1947, junior to that other off</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>