<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8454" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8454/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8454/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8454"><akn:num>8454</akn:num><akn:heading>Midshipmen: number</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8454. Midshipmen: number(a) The authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen (determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,400 or such lower number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy under subsection (h). Subject to that limitation, midshipmen are selected as follows:(1) 65 selected in order of merit as established by competitive examination from the children of members of the armed forces who were killed in action or died of, or have a service-connected disability rated at not less than 100 per centum resulting from, wounds or injuries received or diseases contracted in, or preexisting injury or disease aggravated by, active service, children of members who are in a “missing status” as defined in section 551(2) of title 37, and children of civilian employees who are in “missing status” as defined in section 5561(5) of title 5. The determination of the Department of Veterans Affairs as to service connection of the cause of death or disability, and the percentage at which the disability is rated, is binding upon the Secretary of the Navy.

(2) Five nominated at large by the Vice President or, if there is no Vice President, by the President pro tempore of the Senate.

(3) Ten from each State, five of whom are nominated by each Senator from that State.

(4) Five nominated by each Representative in Congress.

(5) Five from the District of Columbia, nominated by the Delegate to the House of Representatives from the District of Columbia.

(6) Four from the Virgin Islands, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from the Virgin Islands.

(7) Six from Puerto Rico, five of whom are nominated by the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico and one who is a native of Puerto Rico nominated by the Governor of Puerto Rico.

(8) Five from Guam, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from Guam.

(9) Three from American Samoa, nominated by the Delegate in Congress from American Samoa.

(10) Three from the Commonwealth of the No</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen (determined for any year as of the day before the last day of the academic year) is 4,400 or such lower number as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy under subsection (h). Subject to that limitation, midshipmen are selected as follows: Each Senator, Representative, and Delegate in Congress, including the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico, is entitled to nominate 15 persons 11 See Applicability of Amendment note below. for each vacancy that is available to him under this section. Nominees may be submitted without ranking or with a principal candidate and 9 ranked or unranked alternates. Qualified nominees not selected for appointment under this subsection shall be considered qualified alternates for the purposes of selection under other provisions of this chapter. When a nominee of a Senator, Representative, or Delegate is selected for appointment as a midshipman, the Senator, Representative, or Delegate shall be n</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In addition there may be appointed each year at the Academy midshipmen as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The President may also appoint as midshipmen at the Academy children of persons who have been awarded the medal of honor for acts performed while in the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Superintendent of the Naval Academy may nominate for appointment each year 50 persons from the country at large. Persons nominated under this paragraph may not displace any appointment authorized under paragraphs (2) through (9) of subsection (a) and may not cause the total strength of midshipmen at the Naval Academy to exceed the authorized number.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of the Navy may limit the number of midshipmen appointed under subsection (b)(5). When he does so, if the total number of midshipmen, upon admission of a new class at the Academy, will be more than 3,737, no appointments may be made under subsection (b)(2) or (3) of this section or section 8456 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall furnish to any Member of Congress, upon the written request of such Member, the name of the Congressman or other nominating authority responsible for the nomination of any named or identified person for appointment to the Academy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For purposes of the limitation in subsection (a) establishing the aggregate authorized strength of the Brigade of Midshipmen, the Secretary of the Navy may for any year permit a variance in that limitation by not more than one percent. In applying that limitation, and any such variance, the last day of an academic year shall be considered to be graduation day.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8454_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>