<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/846" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/846/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/846/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_846"><akn:num>846</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 46. Opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence in trials by court-martial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 846. Art. 46. Opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence in trials by court-martial(a) Opportunity To Obtain Witnesses and Other Evidence.—In a case referred for trial by court-martial, the trial counsel, the defense counsel, and the court-martial shall have equal opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence in accordance with such regulations as the President may prescribe.

(b) Subpoena and Other Process Generally.—Any subpoena or other process issued under this section (article)—(1) shall be similar to that which courts of the United States having criminal jurisdiction may issue;

(2) shall be executed in accordance with regulations prescribed by the President; and

(3) shall run to any part of the United States and to the Commonwealths and possessions of the United States.


(c) Subpoena and Other Process for Witnesses.—A subpoena or other process may be issued to compel a witness to appear and testify—(1) before a court-martial, military commission, or court of inquiry;

(2) at a deposition under section 849 of this title (article 49); or

(3) as otherwise authorized under this chapter.


(d) Subpoena and Other Process for Evidence.—(1) In general.—A subpoena or other process may be issued to compel the production of evidence—(A) for a court-martial, military commission, or court of inquiry;

(B) for a deposition under section 849 of this title (article 49);

(C) for an investigation of an offense under this chapter; or

(D) as otherwise authorized under this chapter.


(2) Investigative subpoena.—An investigative subpoena under paragraph (1)(C) may be issued before referral of charges to a court-martial only if a general court-martial convening authority has authorized counsel for the Government to issue such a subpoena or a military judge issues such a subpoena pursuant to section 830a of this title (article 30a).

(3) Warrant or order for wire or electronic communications.—With respect to an investigation of an offense under this chapter, a m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_846_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity To Obtain Witnesses and Other Evidence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In a case referred for trial by court-martial, the trial counsel, the defense counsel, and the court-martial shall have equal opportunity to obtain witnesses and other evidence in accordance with such regulations as the President may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_846_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena and Other Process Generally.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any subpoena or other process issued under this section (article)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_846_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena and Other Process for Witnesses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A subpoena or other process may be issued to compel a witness to appear and testify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_846_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoena and Other Process for Evidence.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_846_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for Relief From Subpoena or Other Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If a person requests relief from a subpoena or other process under this section (article) on grounds that compliance is unreasonable or oppressive or is prohibited by law, a military judge detailed in accordance with section 826 or 830a of this title (article 26 or 30a) shall review the request and shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>