<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8471" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8471/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8471/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8471"><akn:num>8471</akn:num><akn:heading>Midshipmen’s store, trade shops, dairy, and laundry: nonappropriated fund instrumentality and accoun</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8471. Midshipmen’s store, trade shops, dairy, and laundry: nonappropriated fund instrumentality and accounts(a) Operation as Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentality.—The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall operate the Naval Academy activities referred to in subsection (b) as a nonappropriated fund instrumentality under the jurisdiction of the Navy.

(b) Covered Activities.—The nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a) shall consist of the following Naval Academy activities:(1) The midshipmen’s store.

(2) The barber shop.

(3) The cobbler shop.

(4) The tailor shop.

(5) The dairy (if any).

(6) The laundry.


(c) Nonappropriated Fund Accounts.—The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall administer a separate nonappropriated fund account for each of the Naval Academy activities included in the nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a).

(d) Crediting of Revenue.—The Superintendent shall credit all revenue received from a Naval Academy activity referred to in subsection (b) to the account administered with respect to that activity under subsection (c), and amounts so credited shall be available for operating expenses of that activity.

(e) Regulations.—This section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.

(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 435, § 6971; Pub. L. 89–718, § 38, Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1120; Pub. L. 103–337, div. A, title III, § 376, Oct. 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 2736; Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title III, § 370(a), Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2498; Pub. L. 105–85, div. B, title XXVIII, § 2871(c)(1), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 2015; renumbered § 8471, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(c)(1), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6971(a)34 U.S.C. 1108b (less last proviso).July 26, 1946, ch. 675, § 2 (less last proviso), 60 Stat. 704.
6971(b)34 U.S.C. 1106.Aug. 5, 193</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8471_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation as Nonappropriated Fund Instrumentality.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall operate the Naval Academy activities referred to in subsection (b) as a nonappropriated fund instrumentality under the jurisdiction of the Navy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8471_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Activities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a) shall consist of the following Naval Academy activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8471_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonappropriated Fund Accounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Superintendent of the Naval Academy shall administer a separate nonappropriated fund account for each of the Naval Academy activities included in the nonappropriated fund instrumentality required under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8471_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crediting of Revenue.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Superintendent shall credit all revenue received from a Naval Academy activity referred to in subsection (b) to the account administered with respect to that activity under subsection (c), and amounts so credited shall be available for operating expenses of that activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8471_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) This section shall be carried out under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>