<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8545" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8545/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8545/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8545"><akn:num>8545</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers of the other armed forces; enlisted members: admission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8545. Officers of the other armed forces; enlisted members: admission(a)(1) The Secretary of the Navy may permit officers of the Army, Air Force, Space Force, and Coast Guard to receive instruction at the Naval Postgraduate School. The numbers and grades of such officers shall be as agreed upon by the Secretary of the Navy with the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Air Force, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, respectively.

(2)(A) The Secretary may permit an enlisted member of the armed forces to receive instruction at the Naval Postgraduate School through attendance at an executive level seminar.

(B) The Secretary may permit an eligible enlisted member of the armed forces to receive instruction at the Postgraduate School in connection with pursuit of a program of education in a cyber discipline as a participant in the Cyber Scholarship program under chapter 112 of this title. To be eligible for instruction under this subparagraph, the enlisted member must have been awarded a baccalaureate degree by an institution of higher education.

(C) The Secretary may permit an eligible enlisted member of the armed forces to receive instruction from the Postgraduate School in certificate programs and courses required for the performance of the member’s duties.

(D)(i) The Secretary may permit an eligible enlisted member of the armed forces to receive graduate-level instruction at the Naval Postgraduate School in a program leading to a master’s degree in a technical, analytical, or engineering curriculum.

(ii) To be eligible to be provided instruction under this subparagraph, the enlisted member must have been awarded a baccalaureate degree by an institution of higher education.

(iii) Instruction under this subparagraph may be provided.

(iv) An enlisted member who successfully completes a course of instruction under this subparagraph may be awarded a master’s degree under section 8548 of this title.

(v) Instruction under this subparagraph shall be provide</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8545_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8545_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8545_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) While receiving instruction at the Postgraduate School, members of the Army, Air Force, Space Force, and Coast Guard are subject to such regulations, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of the Navy, as apply to students who are members of the naval service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8545_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may not award a baccalaureate, masters, or doctorate degree to an enlisted member based upon instruction received at the Postgraduate School under subsection (a)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>