<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8617" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8617/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8617/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8617"><akn:num>8617</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum of the United States Navy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8617. National Museum of the United States Navy(a) Authority to Support Development and Operation of Museum.—(1) The Secretary of the Navy may select and enter into a contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with one or more eligible nonprofit organizations to support the development, design, construction, renovation, or operation of a multipurpose museum to serve as the National Museum of the United States Navy.

(2) The Secretary may—(A) authorize a partner organization to contract for each phase of development, design, construction, renovation, or operation of the museum, or all such phases; or

(B) authorize acceptance of funds from a partner organization for each or all such phases.



(b) Purposes of Museum.—(1) The museum shall be used for the identification, curation, storage, and public viewing of artifacts and artwork of significance to the Navy, as agreed to by the Secretary of the Navy.

(2) The museum also may be used to support such education, training, research, and associated activities as the Secretary considers compatible with and in support of the museum and the mission of the Naval History and Heritage Command.


(c) Acceptance Upon Completion.—Upon the satisfactory completion, as determined by the Secretary of the Navy, of any phase of the museum, and upon the satisfaction of any financial obligations incident thereto, the Secretary shall accept such phase of the museum from the partner organization, and all right, title, and interest in and to such phase of the museum shall vest in the United States. Upon becoming the property of the United States, the Secretary shall assume administrative jurisdiction over such phase of the museum.

(d) Lease Authority.—(1) The Secretary of the Navy may lease portions of the museum to an eligible nonprofit organization for use in generating revenue for the support of activities of the museum and for such administrative purposes as may be necessary for support of the museum. Such a lease may not in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Support Development and Operation of Museum.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes of Museum.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance Upon Completion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Upon the satisfactory completion, as determined by the Secretary of the Navy, of any phase of the museum, and upon the satisfaction of any financial obligations incident thereto, the Secretary shall accept such phase of the museum from the partner organization, and all right, title, and interest in and to such phase of the museum shall vest in the United States. Upon becoming the property of the United States, the Secretary shall assume administrative jurisdiction over such phase of the museum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to Accept Gifts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretary of the Navy may require such additional terms and conditions in connection with a contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement under subsection (a) or a lease under subsection (d) as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Navy Indicators.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8617_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>