<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8669b"><akn:num>8669b</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Technical Authority for each naval vessel class</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8669b. Senior Technical Authority for each naval vessel class(a) Senior Technical Authority.—(1) Designation for each vessel class required.—The Secretary of the Navy shall designate, in writing, a Senior Technical Authority for each class of naval vessels as follows:(A) In the case of a class of vessels which has received Milestone A approval, an approval to enter into technology maturation and risk reduction, or an approval to enter into a subsequent Department of Defense or Department of the Navy acquisition phase as of the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020, not later than 30 days after such date of enactment.

(B) In the case of any class of vessels which has not received any approval described in subparagraph (A) as of such date of enactment, at or before the first of such approvals.


(2) Individuals eligible for designation.—Each individual designated as a Senior Technical Authority under paragraph (1) shall be an employee of the Navy in the Senior Executive Service in an organization of the Navy that—(A) possesses the technical expertise required to carry out the responsibilities specified in subsection (b); and

(B) operates independently of chains-of-command for acquisition program management.


(3) Term.—Each Senior Technical Authority shall be designated for a fixed term, not shorter than the time anticipated to establish demonstrated successful performance of the class of vessels concerned in accordance with its approved capabilities document, as determined by the Secretary at the time of designation.

(4) Voluntary departure.—If an individual designated as a Senior Technical Authority voluntarily departs the position before demonstrated successful performance of the class of vessels concerned, the Secretary shall designate, in writing, a replacement, and shall notify, in writing, the congressional defense committees not later than 90 days after such departure.

(5) Removal.—An individual may be remov</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Technical Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities and Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Each Senior Technical Authority shall be responsible for, and have the authority to, establish, monitor, and approve technical standards, tools, and processes for the class of naval vessels for which designated under this section in conformance with applicable laws and Department of Defense and Department of the Navy policies, requirements, architectures, and standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Obligation of Funds on Lead Vessel in Vessel Class.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>