<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8669a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8669a"><akn:num>8669a</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of combatant and escort vessels and assignment of vessel projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8669a. Construction of combatant and escort vessels and assignment of vessel projects(a) The assignment of naval vessel conversion, alteration, and repair projects shall be based on economic and military considerations and may not be restricted by a requirement that certain parts of naval shipwork be assigned to a particular type of shipyard or geographical area or by a similar requirement.

(b) In evaluating bids or proposals for a contract for the overhaul, repair, or maintenance of a naval vessel, the Secretary of the Navy shall, in determining the cost or price of work to be performed in an area outside the area of the homeport of the vessel, consider foreseeable costs of moving the vessel and its crew from the homeport to the outside area and from the outside area back to the homeport at the completion of the contract.

(c)(1) Before issuing a solicitation for a contract for short-term work for the overhaul, repair, or maintenance of a naval vessel, the Secretary of the Navy shall determine if there is adequate competition available among firms able to perform the work at the homeport of the vessel. If the Secretary determines that there is adequate competition among such firms, the Secretary—(A) shall issue such a solicitation only to firms able to perform the work at the homeport of the vessel; and

(B) may not award such contract to a firm other than a firm that will perform the work at the homeport of the vessel.


(2) Paragraph (1) applies notwithstanding subsection (a) or any other provision of law.

(3) Paragraph (1) does not apply in the case of voyage repairs.

(4) In this subsection, the term “short-term work” means work that will be for a period of 12 months or less.


(Added Pub. L. 97–295, § 1(48)(A), Oct. 12, 1982, 96 Stat. 1298, § 7299a; amended Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title XII, § 1201(a), Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3967; Pub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XI, § 1101, Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1145; Pub. L. 101–510, div. A, title XIV, § 1422, Nov. 5, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The assignment of naval vessel conversion, alteration, and repair projects shall be based on economic and military considerations and may not be restricted by a requirement that certain parts of naval shipwork be assigned to a particular type of shipyard or geographical area or by a similar requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In evaluating bids or proposals for a contract for the overhaul, repair, or maintenance of a naval vessel, the Secretary of the Navy shall, in determining the cost or price of work to be performed in an area outside the area of the homeport of the vessel, consider foreseeable costs of moving the vessel and its crew from the homeport to the outside area and from the outside area back to the homeport at the completion of the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8669a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>