<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8673" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8673/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8673/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8673"><akn:num>8673</akn:num><akn:heading>Model Basin; investigation of hull designs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8673. Model Basin; investigation of hull designs
The Secretary of the Navy may authorize experiments to be made at the Model Basin for private persons. The costs of experiments made for private persons shall be paid by those persons under regulations prescribed by the Secretary. The results of private experiments are confidential and may not be divulged without the consent of the persons for whom they are made. However, the data obtained from such experiments may be used by the Secretary for governmental purposes, subject to the patent laws of the United States.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 451, § 7303; Pub. L. 89–718, § 41, Nov. 2, 1966, 80 Stat. 1120; renumbered § 8673 and amended Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(2), title X, § 1015(a), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836, 1949.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


73035 U.S.C. 430a.May 6, 1936, ch. 333, 49 Stat. 1263; June 20, 1940, ch. 400, § 1(a), (b), 54 Stat. 492.


In subsection (a) the authority to purchase a site and construct the model basin is omitted as executed. The words “David W. Taylor Model Basin, Carderock, Maryland” are inserted to designate the model basin established under this authority. The words “investigations to determine” are substituted for the words “work of investigating and determining.” The phrase “vessels, including aircraft” is changed to read “vessels and aircraft”, and the words “their design” are substituted for “ship design”.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–232, § 807(d)(2), renumbered section 7303 of this title as this section.
Pub. L. 115–232, § 1015(a), struck out subsec. (b) designation before “The Secretary” and struck out subsec. (a) which read as follows: “An office or agency in the Department of the Navy designated by the Secretary of the Navy shall conduct at the David W. Taylor Model Basin, Carderock, Maryland, investigations to determine the most suitable shapes and forms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>