<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8677" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8677/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8677/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8677"><akn:num>8677</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposals to foreign nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8677. Disposals to foreign nations(a) Larger or Newer Vessels.—A naval vessel that is in excess of 3,000 tons or that is less than 20 years of age may not be disposed of to another nation (whether by sale, lease, grant, loan, barter, transfer, or otherwise) unless the disposal of that vessel, or of a vessel of the class of that vessel, is authorized by law enacted after August 5, 1974. A lease or loan of such a vessel under such a law may be made only in accordance with the provisions of chapter 6 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2796 et seq.) or chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2311 et seq.). In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of such a vessel that names a specific vessel as being authorized for such disposal, the Secretary of Defense may substitute another vessel of the same class, if the vessel substituted has virtually identical capabilities as the named vessel. In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of vessels of a specified class, the Secretary may dispose of vessels of that class pursuant to that authorization only in the number of such vessels specified in that law as being authorized for disposal.

(b) Other Vessels.—(1) A naval vessel not subject to subsection (a) may be disposed of to another nation (whether by sale, lease, grant, loan, barter, transfer, or otherwise) in accordance with applicable provisions of law, but only after—(A) the Secretary of the Navy notifies the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives in writing of the proposed disposition; and

(B) 30 days of continuous session of Congress have expired following the date on which such notice is sent to those committees.


(2) For purposes of paragraph (1)(B), the continuity of a session of Congress is broken only by an adjournment of the Congress sine die, and the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of mor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8677_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Larger or Newer Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A naval vessel that is in excess of 3,000 tons or that is less than 20 years of age may not be disposed of to another nation (whether by sale, lease, grant, loan, barter, transfer, or otherwise) unless the disposal of that vessel, or of a vessel of the class of that vessel, is authorized by law enacted after August 5, 1974. A lease or loan of such a vessel under such a law may be made only in accordance with the provisions of chapter 6 of the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2796 et seq.) or chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2311 et seq.). In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of such a vessel that names a specific vessel as being authorized for such disposal, the Secretary of Defense may substitute another vessel of the same class, if the vessel substituted has virtually identical capabilities as the named vessel. In the case of an authorization by law for the disposal of vessels of a specified class, the Secretary may dispos</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8677_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Vessels.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>