<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8680" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8680/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8680/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8680"><akn:num>8680</akn:num><akn:heading>Overhaul, repair, etc. of vessels in foreign shipyards: restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8680. Overhaul, repair, etc. of vessels in foreign shipyards: restrictions(a) Vessels Under Jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy With Homeport in United States or Guam.—(1) A naval vessel the homeport of which is in the United States or Guam may not be overhauled, repaired, or maintained in a shipyard outside the United States or Guam.

(2)(A) Notwithstanding paragraph (1) and subject to subparagraph (B), in the case of a naval vessel classified as a Littoral Combat Ship and operating on deployment, corrective and preventive maintenance or repair (whether intermediate or depot level) and facilities maintenance may be performed on the vessel—(i) in a foreign shipyard;

(ii) at a facility outside of a foreign shipyard; or

(iii) at any other facility convenient to the vessel.


(B)(i)(I) Corrective and preventive maintenance or repair may be performed on a vessel as described in subparagraph (A) if the work is performed by United States Government personnel or United States contractor personnel.

(II) Notwithstanding subclause (I), foreign workers may be used to perform corrective and preventive maintenance or repair on a vessel as described in subparagraph (A) only if the Secretary of the Navy determines that travel by United States Government personnel or United States contractor personnel to perform the corrective or preventive maintenance or repair is not advisable for health or safety reasons. The Secretary of the Navy may not delegate the authority to make a determination under this subclause.

(III) Not later than 30 days after making a determination under subclause (II), the Secretary of the Navy shall submit to the congressional defense committees written notification of the determination. The notification shall include the reasons why travel by United States personnel is not advisable for health or safety reasons, the location where the corrective and preventive maintenance or repair will be performed, and the approximate duration of the corrective an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8680_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Under Jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Navy With Homeport in United States or Guam.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8680_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessel Changing Homeports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8680_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repair and Refurbishment of Certain Submarines.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8680_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>