<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8683" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8683/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8683/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8683"><akn:num>8683</akn:num><akn:heading>Ship overhaul work: availability of appropriations for unusual cost overruns and for changes in scop</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8683. Ship overhaul work: availability of appropriations for unusual cost overruns and for changes in scope of work(a) Unusual Cost Overruns.—(1) Appropriations available to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year may be used for payment of unusual cost overruns incident to ship overhaul, maintenance, and repair for a vessel inducted into an industrial-fund activity or contracted for during a prior fiscal year.

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall notify Congress promptly before an obligation is incurred for any payment under paragraph (1).


(b) Changes in Scope of Work.—An appropriation available to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year may be used after the otherwise-applicable expiration of the availability for obligation of that appropriation—(1) for payments to an industrial-fund activity for amounts required because of changes in the scope of work for ship overhaul, maintenance, and repair, in the case of work inducted into the industrial-fund activity during the fiscal year; and

(2) for payments under a contract for amounts required because of changes in the scope of work, in the case of a contract entered into during the fiscal year for ship overhaul, maintenance, and repair.


(c) Treatment of Amounts Appropriated After End of Period of Obligation.—In the application of section 1553(c) of title 31 to funds appropriated in the Operation and Maintenance, Navy account that are available for ship overhaul, the Secretary of the Navy may treat the limitation specified in paragraph (1) of such section to be “$10,000,000” rather than “$4,000,000”.

(Added Pub. L. 100–370, § 1(n)(1), July 19, 1988, 102 Stat. 850, § 7313; renumbered § 8683, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(2), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title III, § 367, Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3551.)

Historical and Revision NotesSection is based on Pub. L. 99–190, § 101(b) [title VIII, § 8005(j), (k)], Dec. 19, 1985, 99 Stat. 1185, 1203.
In two instance</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8683_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unusual Cost Overruns.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8683_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in Scope of Work.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An appropriation available to the Department of Defense for a fiscal year may be used after the otherwise-applicable expiration of the availability for obligation of that appropriation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8683_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of Amounts Appropriated After End of Period of Obligation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In the application of section 1553(c) of title 31 to funds appropriated in the Operation and Maintenance, Navy account that are available for ship overhaul, the Secretary of the Navy may treat the limitation specified in paragraph (1) of such section to be “$10,000,000” rather than “$4,000,000”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>