<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8687" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8687/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8687/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8687"><akn:num>8687</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Government rights in the designs of vessels, boats, and craft, and components thereof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8687. Status of Government rights in the designs of vessels, boats, and craft, and components thereof(a) In General.—Government rights in the design of a vessel, boat, or craft, and its components, including the hull, decks, superstructure, and all shipboard equipment and systems, shall be determined solely as follows:(1) In the case of a vessel, boat, craft, or component procured through a contract, in accordance with the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 275 of this title.

(2) In the case of a vessel, boat, craft, or component procured through an instrument not governed by subchapter I of chapter 275 of this title, by the terms of the instrument (other than a contract) under which the design for such vessel, boat, craft, or component, as applicable, was developed for the Government.


(b) Construction of Superseding Authorities.—This section may be modified or superseded by a provision of statute only if such provision expressly refers to this section in modifying or superseding this section.

(Added Pub. L. 110–417, [div. A], title VIII, § 825(a), Oct. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 4534, § 7317; renumbered § 8687, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(2), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1833(p), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4234.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 8687, acts Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 536; Sept. 2, 1958, Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(188), 72 Stat. 1534; Sept. 7, 1962, Pub. L. 87–649, § 6(d), 76 Stat. 494, related to compensation for members of Air Force other than Regular Air Force prior to repeal by Pub. L. 99–661, div. A, title VI, § 604(f)(1)(A), Nov. 14, 1986, 100 Stat. 3877.

Amendments2021—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–283 substituted “subchapter I of chapter 275” for “section 2320” in pars. (1) and (2).
2018—Pub. L. 115–232 renumbered section 7317 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2021 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 116–283 effec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8687_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Government rights in the design of a vessel, boat, or craft, and its components, including the hull, decks, superstructure, and all shipboard equipment and systems, shall be determined solely as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8687_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of Superseding Authorities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) This section may be modified or superseded by a provision of statute only if such provision expressly refers to this section in modifying or superseding this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>