<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/869" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/869/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/869/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_869"><akn:num>869</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 69. Review by Judge Advocate General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 869. Art. 69. Review by Judge Advocate General(a) In General.—Upon application by the accused or receipt of the record pursuant to section 864(c)(3) of this title (article 64(c)(3)) and subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Judge Advocate General may—(1) with respect to a summary court-martial, modify or set aside, in whole or in part, the findings and sentence; or

(2) with respect to a general or special court-martial, order such court-martial to be reviewed under section 866 of this title (article 66).


(b) Timing.—(1) To qualify for consideration, an application under subsection (a) must be submitted to the Judge Advocate General not later than—(A) for a summary court-martial, one year after the date of completion of review under section 864 of this title (article 64); or

(B) for a general or special court-martial, one year after the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date the accused is provided notice of appellate rights under section 865(c) of this title (article 65(c)), unless the accused submitted a waiver or withdrawal of appellate review under section 861 of this title (article 61) before being provided notice of appellate rights, in which case the application must be submitted to the Judge Advocate General not later than one year after the entry of judgment under section 860c of this title (article 60c).


(2) The Judge Advocate General may, for good cause shown, extend the period for submission of an application, except that—(A) in the case of an application for review of a summary court martial, the Judge Advocate may not consider an application submitted more than three years after the completion date referred to in paragraph (1)(A); and

(B) in case of an application for review of a general or special court-martial, the Judge Advocate may not consider an application submitted more than three years after the end of the applicable period under paragraph (1)(B).



(c) Scope.—(1)(A) In a case reviewed under section 864 of this title (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Upon application by the accused or receipt of the record pursuant to section 864(c)(3) of this title (article 64(c)(3)) and subject to subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Judge Advocate General may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court of Criminal Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action Only on Matters of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notwithstanding section 866 of this title (article 66), in any case reviewed by a Court of Criminal Appeals under subsection (d), the Court may take action only with respect to matters of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>