<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8690" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8690/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8690/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8690"><akn:num>8690</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on length of overseas forward deployment of naval vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8690. Limitation on length of overseas forward deployment of naval vessels(a) Limitation.—The Secretary of the Navy shall ensure that no naval vessel specified in subsection (b) that is listed in the Naval Vessel Register is forward deployed overseas for a period in excess of ten years. At the end of a period of overseas forward deployment, the vessel shall be assigned a homeport in the United States.

(b) Vessels Specified.—A naval vessel specified in this subsection is any of the following:(1) Aircraft carrier.

(2) Amphibious ship.

(3) Cruiser.

(4) Destroyer.

(5) Frigate.

(6) Littoral Combat Ship.


(c) Waiver.—The Secretary of the Navy may waive the limitation under subsection (a) with respect to a naval vessel if the Secretary submits to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of—(1) the waiver of such limitation with respect to the vessel;

(2) the date on which the period of overseas forward deployment of the vessel is expected to end; and

(3) the factors used by the Secretary to determine that a longer period of deployment would promote the national defense or be in the public interest.


(Added § 7320 and renumbered § 8690, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title III, § 323(a)(1), title VIII, § 807(d)(2), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1719, 1836.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 8690, act Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 538, exempted enlisted members of Air Force, while on active duty, from arrest for any debt, unless it was contracted before enlistment and amounted to at least $20 when first contracted, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 90–235, § 7(b)(1), Jan. 2, 1968, 81 Stat. 763.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–232, § 807(d)(2), renumbered section 7320 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by section 807(d)(2) of Pub. L. 115–232 effective Feb. 1, 2019, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see section 800</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8690_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Navy shall ensure that no naval vessel specified in subsection (b) that is listed in the Naval Vessel Register is forward deployed overseas for a period in excess of ten years. At the end of a period of overseas forward deployment, the vessel shall be assigned a homeport in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8690_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vessels Specified.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A naval vessel specified in this subsection is any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8690_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the Navy may waive the limitation under subsection (a) with respect to a naval vessel if the Secretary submits to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>