<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8729" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8729/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8729/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8729"><akn:num>8729</akn:num><akn:heading>Re-lease of certain lands: lessee’s preferential right</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8729. Re-lease of certain lands: lessee’s preferential right
The Secretary, on terms prescribed by him, may re-lease lands in the naval petroleum reserves that were covered by leases made before July 1, 1936, and terminated by law at the expiration of their initial twenty-year periods. If any such land is to be re-leased, the Secretary shall give to the former lessee preferential rights to the new lease.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 460, § 7429; Pub. L. 94–258, title II, § 201(10), Apr. 5, 1976, 90 Stat. 309; renumbered § 8729, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(5), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


742934 U.S.C. 524 (6th par., less proviso).June 4, 1920, ch. 228 (6th par., less proviso, of amended 3d and 4th provisos), 41 Stat. 813; June 30, 1938, ch. 851, § 1, 52 Stat. 1253; June 17, 1944, ch. 262, 58 Stat. 282.


The source law provided that leases of lands of the United States within the naval petroleum reserves in existence before July 1, 1936, except leases that had become part of an approved unit or cooperative plan and agreement, should terminate at the end of their initial 20-year period, and that the lands covered by these leases could then be re-leased by the Secretary of the Navy. All of the leases covered by this provision have terminated as provided therein. Thus the provision for the termination of the leases is executed and the only remaining effect of the source is to authorize the re-lease of the lands formerly covered by the terminated leases. This section is worded accordingly. Reference to the classes of leases that were excepted from the termination is omitted as unnecessary because these leases were, of course, not terminated. They are not affected, since this section refers only to leases that were “terminated by law”. The word “conditions” is omitted as included in the word “terms”.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>