<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8743" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8743/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8743/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8743"><akn:num>8743</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8743. Employment of aliens
Laws prohibiting payment of compensation to a person who is not a citizen of the United States do not apply to a person whose employment by the Department of the Navy is determined by the Secretary of the Navy to be necessary to obtain for the armed forces the benefits of the special technical or scientific knowledge or experience possessed by that person and not readily obtainable from a citizen.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 462, § 7473; renumbered § 8743, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(6), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1836.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


74735 U.S.C. 415b.Feb. 26, 1946, ch. 36, 60 Stat. 31.


The word “Laws” is substituted for the words “Statutory provisions” for clarity. The words “armed forces” are substituted for the words “military services of the United States” for uniformity. The words “of the United States” at the end of the section are omitted as surplusage.

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsPrior sections 8743 to 8745 were renumbered sections 9273 to 9275 of this title, respectively.

Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–232 renumbered section 7473 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 115–232 effective Feb. 1, 2019, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232, set out as a note preceding section 3001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>