<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8755" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8755/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8755/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8755"><akn:num>8755</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures for offerors for certain shipbuilding major defense acquisition program contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8755. Disclosures for offerors for certain shipbuilding major defense acquisition program contracts(a) In General.—Any covered offeror seeking to be awarded a shipbuilding construction contract as part of a major defense acquisition program with funds from the Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy account shall disclose along with the offer and any subsequent revisions of the offer (including the final proposal revision offer) if any part of the planned contract performance will or is expected to include foreign government subsidized performance, foreign financing, foreign financial guarantees, or foreign tax concessions.

(b) Requirements.—A disclosure required under subsection (a) shall be made in a form prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy and shall include a specific description of the extent to which the planned contract performance will include, with or without contingencies, any foreign government subsidized performance, foreign financing, foreign financial guarantees, or foreign tax concessions.

(c) Congressional Notification.—Not later than 5 days after awarding a contract described under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy shall notify the congressional defense committees and summarize the disclosure provided under such subsection.

(d) Definitions.—In this section:(1) Covered offeror.—The term “covered offeror” means any offeror that requires or may reasonably be expected to require, during the period of performance on a shipbuilding construction contract described in subsection (a), a method to mitigate or negate foreign ownership under section 2004.34(f)(6) of title 32, Code of Federal Regulations.

(2) Foreign government subsidized performance.—The term “foreign government subsidized performance” means any financial support, materiel, services, or guarantees of support, services, supply, performance, or intellectual property concessions, that may be provided to or for the covered offeror or the customer of the offeror by a foreign government or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8755_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any covered offeror seeking to be awarded a shipbuilding construction contract as part of a major defense acquisition program with funds from the Shipbuilding and Conversion, Navy account shall disclose along with the offer and any subsequent revisions of the offer (including the final proposal revision offer) if any part of the planned contract performance will or is expected to include foreign government subsidized performance, foreign financing, foreign financial guarantees, or foreign tax concessions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8755_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A disclosure required under subsection (a) shall be made in a form prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy and shall include a specific description of the extent to which the planned contract performance will include, with or without contingencies, any foreign government subsidized performance, foreign financing, foreign financial guarantees, or foreign tax concessions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8755_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Notification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Not later than 5 days after awarding a contract described under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy shall notify the congressional defense committees and summarize the disclosure provided under such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8755_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>