<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8772" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8772/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8772/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8772"><akn:num>8772</akn:num><akn:heading>Quarters: accommodations in place for members on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with com</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8772. Quarters: accommodations in place for members on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship(a) If public quarters are not available, the Secretary of the Navy may provide lodging accommodations for any—(1) member of the naval service;

(2) member of the Coast Guard when it is operating as a service in the Navy; or

(3) member of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration serving with the Navy;


on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship who is deprived of his quarters on board ship because of repairs, because the ship is under construction and is not yet habitable, or because of other conditions that make his quarters uninhabitable. Lodging accommodations so provided may not be occupied by the member’s dependents.

[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(a)(7), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2136.]

(c) The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by subsection (a) to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.

(d)(1) A member of the naval service on sea duty who is deprived of quarters on board ship because of repairs or because of other conditions that make the member’s quarters uninhabitable may be reimbursed for expenses incurred in obtaining housing if it is impracticable to furnish the member with accommodations under subsection (a).

(2) The total amount that a member may be reimbursed under this subsection may not exceed an amount equal to the basic allowance for housing of a member of that member’s grade.

(3) This subsection shall not apply to a member who is entitled to basic allowance for housing.

(4) The Secretary may prescribe regulations to carry out this subsection.


(e)(1) The Secretary may reimburse a member of the naval service assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship in Pascagoula, Mississip</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8772_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If public quarters are not available, the Secretary of the Navy may provide lodging accommodations for any— on sea duty or assigned to duty in connection with commissioning or fitting out of a ship who is deprived of his quarters on board ship because of repairs, because the ship is under construction and is not yet habitable, or because of other conditions that make his quarters uninhabitable. Lodging accommodations so provided may not be occupied by the member’s dependents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8772_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>[(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title X, § 1069(a)(7), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2136.]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8772_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary, to the extent he considers proper, may delegate the authority conferred by subsection (a) to any person in the Department of the Navy, with or without the authority to make successive redelegations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8772_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8772_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>