<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8782" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8782/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8782/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8782"><akn:num>8782</akn:num><akn:heading>Naval and Marine Corps Historical Centers: fee for providing historical information to the public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8782. Naval and Marine Corps Historical Centers: fee for providing historical information to the public(a) Authority.—Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Navy may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center that is requested by that person.

(b) Exceptions.—A fee may not be charged under this section—(1) to a person for information that the person requests to carry out a duty as a member of the armed forces or an officer or employee of the United States; or

(2) for a release of information under section 552 of title 5.


(c) Limitation on Amount.—A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.

(d) Retention of Fees.—Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from that historical center during that fiscal year.

(e) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “United States Naval Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Navy that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.

(2) The term “Marine Corps Historical Center” means the archive for historical records and materials of the Marine Corps that the Secretary of the Navy designates as the primary archive for such records and materials.

(3) The terms “officer of the United States” and “employee of the United States” have the meanings given the terms “officer” and “employee”, respectively, in sections 2104 and 2105, respectively, of title 5.


(Added Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A], title X, § 1085(b)(1)], Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1654, 1654A–288, § 7582; renumbered § 8782, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8782_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary of the Navy may charge a person a fee for providing the person with information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center that is requested by that person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8782_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A fee may not be charged under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8782_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A fee charged for providing information under this section may not exceed the cost of providing the information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8782_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of Fees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amounts received under subsection (a) for providing information from the United States Naval Historical Center or the Marine Corps Historical Center in any fiscal year shall be credited to the appropriation or appropriations charged the costs of providing information to the public from that historical center during that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8782_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>