<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8895" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8895/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8895/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8895"><akn:num>8895</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay extended or shortened</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8895. Stay extended or shortened
The Secretary of the Navy, when a stay under this chapter is in effect, may file with the court, or a judge of the court, a certificate extending or shortening the time stated in the prior certificate. The filing of such a new certificate extends or shortens the stay to the period specified in the new certificate or terminates the stay if the new certificate so states.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 484, § 7725; renumbered § 8895, Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 807(d)(10), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1837.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


772546 U.S.C. 794 (1st, and 9th (less proviso), sentences).July 3, 1944, ch. 399, § 4 (1st, and 9th (less proviso), sentences), 58 Stat. 724.


The words “or suspension”, “either of prosecution of the suit or of the taking of testimony”, “during which the prosecution of such suit or taking of such deposition or production of evidence would tend to endanger the security of the United States or of such operations in time of war, or to interfere therewith”, “as the case may be”, and “in relation to which it is made shall continue in effect” are omitted as surplusage.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–232 renumbered section 7725 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 115–232 effective Feb. 1, 2019, with provision for the coordination of amendments and special rule for certain redesignations, see section 800 of Pub. L. 115–232, set out as a note preceding section 3001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>