<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8932" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8932/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/8932/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8932"><akn:num>8932</akn:num><akn:heading>Ocean Policy Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8932. Ocean Policy Committee(a) Committee.—There is established an Ocean Policy Committee (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”). The Committee shall retain broad and inclusive membership.

(b) Responsibilities.—The Committee shall—(1) continue the activities of that Committee as it was in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021;

(2) engage and collaborate, pursuant to existing laws and regulations, with stakeholders, including regional ocean partnerships, to address ocean-related matters that may require interagency or intergovernmental solutions;

(3) facilitate coordination and integration of Federal activities in ocean and coastal waters to inform ocean policy and identify priority ocean research, technology, and data needs;

(4) prescribe policies and procedures to implement the National Oceanographic Partnership Program, including developing guidelines for review, selection, identification, and approval of partnership projects, in conjunction with Federal agencies participating in the program, for implementation under the program, based on—(A) whether the project addresses important research objectives or operational goals;

(B) whether the project has, or is designed to have, appropriate participation or support from public, academic, commercial, and private entities within the oceanographic community;

(C) whether the partners have a long-term commitment to the objectives of the project;

(D) whether the resources supporting the project are shared among the partners;

(E) whether the project has been subjected to adequate scientific and technical merit review according to each participating agency; and

(F) the approval of such guidelines by a consensus of the members of the Committee; and


(5) for projects under the purview of the Committee, establish or designate one or more systems for ocean-related and ocean-mapping-related documents prepare</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) There is established an Ocean Policy Committee (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”). The Committee shall retain broad and inclusive membership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report and Briefing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnership Program Office.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract and Grant Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Committee may authorize one or more of the departments or agencies represented on the Committee to enter into contracts and make grants, using funds appropriated pursuant to an authorization of appropriations for the National Oceanographic Partnership Program, for the purpose of implementing the program and carrying out the responsibilities of the Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and Forms of Partnership Projects.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of Document System.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The systems established or designated under subsection (b)(5) may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8932_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate Congressional Committees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>