<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/895" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/895/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/895/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_895"><akn:num>895</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 95. Offenses by sentinel or lookout</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 895. Art. 95. Offenses by sentinel or lookout(a) Drunk or Sleeping on Post, or Leaving Post Before Being Relieved.—Any sentinel or lookout who is drunk on post, who sleeps on post, or who leaves post before being regularly relieved, shall be punished—(1) if the offense is committed in time of war, by death or such other punishment as a court-martial may direct; and

(2) if the offense is committed other than in time of war, by such punishment, other than death, as a court-martial may direct.


(b) Loitering or Wrongfully Sitting on Post.—Any sentinel or lookout who loiters or wrongfully sits down on post shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 72, § 913; renumbered § 895 and amended Pub. L. 114–328, div. E, title LX, §§ 5401(8), 5411, Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2938, 2943.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


91350:707.May 5, 1950, ch. 169, § 1 (Art. 113), 64 Stat. 139.



Prior ProvisionsA prior section 895 was renumbered section 887a of this title.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2016—Pub. L. 114–328, § 5411, amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “Any sentinel or look-out who is found drunk or sleeping upon his post, or leaves it before he is regularly relieved, shall be punished, if the offense is committed in time of war, by death or such other punishment as a court-martial may direct, but if the offense is committed at any other time, by such punishment other than death as a court-martial may direct.”
Pub. L. 114–328, § 5401(8), renumbered section 913 of this title as this section.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2016 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 114–328 effective on Jan. 1, 2019, as designated by the President, with implementing regulations and provisions relating to applicability to various situations, see section 5542 of Pub. L. 114–328 and Ex. Ord. No. 13825, set out as notes under section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_895_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drunk or Sleeping on Post, or Leaving Post Before Being Relieved.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any sentinel or lookout who is drunk on post, who sleeps on post, or who leaves post before being regularly relieved, shall be punished—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_895_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loitering or Wrongfully Sitting on Post.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any sentinel or lookout who loiters or wrongfully sits down on post shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>