<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9039" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9039/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9039/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9039"><akn:num>9039</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief of Chaplains: appointment; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9039. Chief of Chaplains: appointment; duties(a) Chief of Chaplains.—(1) There is a Chief of Chaplains for the Air Force and the Space Force, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, from officers of the Air Force designated under section 9067(h) of this title as chaplains who—(A) are serving on active duty; and

(B) have served on active duty as a chaplain for at least eight years.


(2) An officer appointed as the Chief of Chaplains shall be appointed for a term of three years. However, the President may terminate or extend the appointment at any time.

(3) The Chief of Chaplains shall perform such duties as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Air Force and by law.


(b) Selection Board.—Under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Air Force, in selecting an officer for recommendation to the President for appointment as the Chief of Chaplains, shall ensure that the officer selected is recommended by a board of officers that, insofar as practicable, is subject to the procedures applicable to the selection boards convened under chapter 36 of this title.

(c) Grade of Chief of Chaplains.—The Chief of Chaplains, while so serving, holds the grade of major general.

(Added Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title V, § 508(a), Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 1716, § 8039; amended Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title V, § 502(mm), Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2106; renumbered § 9039 and amended Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title V, § 510(c), title VIII, §§ 806(c), 809(a), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1751, 1833, 1840; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 923(b)(8), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3809.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–283 substituted “for the Air Force and the Space Force” for “in the Air Force”.
2018—Pub. L. 115–232, § 806(c), renumbered section 8039 of this title as this section.
Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 115–232, § 809(a), substituted “section 9067(h)” for “section 8067(h)” in introductory provisi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9039_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief of Chaplains.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9039_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection Board.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations approved by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Air Force, in selecting an officer for recommendation to the President for appointment as the Chief of Chaplains, shall ensure that the officer selected is recommended by a board of officers that, insofar as practicable, is subject to the procedures applicable to the selection boards convened under chapter 36 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9039_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grade of Chief of Chaplains.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Chief of Chaplains, while so serving, holds the grade of major general.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>