<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/910" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/910/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/910/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_910"><akn:num>910</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 110. Improper hazarding of vessel or aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 910. Art. 110. Improper hazarding of vessel or aircraft(a) Willful and Wrongful Hazarding.—Any person subject to this chapter who, willfully and wrongfully, hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel or aircraft of the armed forces shall be punished by death or such other punishment as a court-martial may direct.

(b) Negligent Hazarding.—Any person subject to this chapter who negligently hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel or aircraft of the armed forces shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 71; Pub. L. 114–328, div. E, title LX, § 5422, Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2947.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


910(a)910(b)50:704(a).50:704(b).May 5, 1950, ch. 169, § 1 (Art. 110), 64 Stat. 139.



Editorial Notes
Amendments2016—Pub. L. 114–328 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows:
“(a) Any person subject to this chapter who willfully and wrongfully hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel of the armed forces shall suffer death or such other punishment as a court-martial may direct.
“(b) Any person subject to this chapter who negligently hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel of the armed forces shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2016 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 114–328 effective on Jan. 1, 2019, as designated by the President, with implementing regulations and provisions relating to applicability to various situations, see section 5542 of Pub. L. 114–328 and Ex. Ord. No. 13825, set out as notes under section 801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_910_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Willful and Wrongful Hazarding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any person subject to this chapter who, willfully and wrongfully, hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel or aircraft of the armed forces shall be punished by death or such other punishment as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_910_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negligent Hazarding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any person subject to this chapter who negligently hazards or suffers to be hazarded any vessel or aircraft of the armed forces shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>