<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/912a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/912a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/912a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_912a"><akn:num>912a</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 112a. Wrongful use, possession, etc., of controlled substances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 912a. Art. 112a. Wrongful use, possession, etc., of controlled substances(a) Any person subject to this chapter who wrongfully uses, possesses, manufactures, distributes, imports into the customs territory of the United States, exports from the United States, or introduces into an installation, vessel, vehicle, or aircraft used by or under the control of the armed forces a substance described in subsection (b) shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(b) The substances referred to in subsection (a) are the following:(1) Opium, heroin, cocaine, amphetamine, lysergic acid diethylamide, methamphetamine, phencyclidine, barbituric acid, and marijuana and any compound or derivative of any such substance.

(2) Any substance not specified in clause (1) that is listed on a schedule of controlled substances prescribed by the President for the purposes of this article.

(3) Any other substance not specified in clause (1) or contained on a list prescribed by the President under clause (2) that is listed in schedules I through V of section 202 of the Controlled Substances Act (21 U.S.C. 812).


(Added Pub. L. 98–209, § 8(a), Dec. 6, 1983, 97 Stat. 1403.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective first day of eighth calendar month beginning after Dec. 6, 1983, but not applicable to any offense committed before that date and not to be construed to invalidate the prosecution of any offense committed before that date, see section 12(a)(1), (5) of Pub. L. 98–209, set out as an Effective Date of 1983 Amendment note under section 801 of this title.

Procedures for Forensic Examination of Certain Physiological EvidencePub. L. 100–180, div. A, title XII, § 1248, Dec. 4, 1987, 101 Stat. 1166, provided that:
“(a) Establishment of Procedures.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish procedures to ensure that whenever, in connection with a criminal investigation conducted by or for a military department, a physiological specimen is obtained from a p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_912a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any person subject to this chapter who wrongfully uses, possesses, manufactures, distributes, imports into the customs territory of the United States, exports from the United States, or introduces into an installation, vessel, vehicle, or aircraft used by or under the control of the armed forces a substance described in subsection (b) shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_912a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The substances referred to in subsection (a) are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>