<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/920" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/920/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/920/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_920"><akn:num>920</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 120. Rape and sexual assault generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 920. Art. 120. Rape and sexual assault generally(a) Rape.—Any person subject to this chapter who commits a sexual act upon another person by—(1) using unlawful force against that other person;

(2) using force causing or likely to cause death or grievous bodily harm to any person;

(3) threatening or placing that other person in fear that any person will be subjected to death, grievous bodily harm, or kidnapping;

(4) first rendering that other person unconscious; or

(5) administering to that other person by force or threat of force, or without the knowledge or consent of that person, a drug, intoxicant, or other similar substance and thereby substantially impairing the ability of that other person to appraise or control conduct;


is guilty of rape and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(b) Sexual Assault.—Any person subject to this chapter who—(1) commits a sexual act upon another person by—(A) threatening or placing that other person in fear;

(B) making a fraudulent representation that the sexual act serves a professional purpose; or

(C) inducing a belief by any artifice, pretense, or concealment that the person is another person;


(2) commits a sexual act upon another person—(A) without the consent of the other person; or

(B) when the person knows or reasonably should know that the other person is asleep, unconscious, or otherwise unaware that the sexual act is occurring; or


(3) commits a sexual act upon another person when the other person is incapable of consenting to the sexual act due to—(A) impairment by any drug, intoxicant, or other similar substance, and that condition is known or reasonably should be known by the person; or

(B) a mental disease or defect, or physical disability, and that condition is known or reasonably should be known by the person;



is guilty of sexual assault and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(c) Aggravated Sexual Contact.—Any person subject to this chapter who commits or causes sexual c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rape.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any person subject to this chapter who commits a sexual act upon another person by— is guilty of rape and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sexual Assault.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any person subject to this chapter who— is guilty of sexual assault and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggravated Sexual Contact.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any person subject to this chapter who commits or causes sexual contact upon or by another person, if to do so would violate subsection (a) (rape) had the sexual contact been a sexual act, is guilty of aggravated sexual contact and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abusive Sexual Contact.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Any person subject to this chapter who commits or causes sexual contact upon or by another person, if to do so would violate subsection (b) (sexual assault) had the sexual contact been a sexual act, is guilty of abusive sexual contact and shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of Threat.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) In a prosecution under this section, in proving that a person made a threat, it need not be proven that the person actually intended to carry out the threat or had the ability to carry out the threat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An accused may raise any applicable defenses available under this chapter or the Rules for Court-Martial. Marriage is not a defense for any conduct in issue in any prosecution under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_920_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>