<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9229" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9229/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9229/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9229"><akn:num>9229</akn:num><akn:heading>Command: commissioned officers in certain designated categories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9229. Command: commissioned officers in certain designated categories
An officer designated as a medical, dental, veterinary, medical service, or biomedical sciences officer or as a nurse is not entitled to exercise command because of rank, except within the categories prescribed in subsection (a), (b), (c), (d), (e), (f), or (i) of section 9067 of this title, or over persons placed under his charge.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 531, § 8579; Pub. L. 85–861, § 1(156), (185), Sept. 2, 1958, 72 Stat. 1513, 1533; Pub. L. 96–513, title II, § 212(b), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 2885; renumbered § 9229 and amended Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, §§ 806(b)(7), 809(a), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1832, 1840.)











Historical and Revision Notes



1956 Act


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


8579(a)10:82.R.S. 1169.
8579(b)10:166e (less 1st sentence).Apr. 16, 1947, ch. 38, § 106 (less 1st sentence), 61 Stat. 44.


In subsection (a), the words “Except as provided in section 94 of this title”, not contained in section 1169 of the Revised Statutes, but contained in the United States Code, are omitted as surplusage, since 10:94 deals exclusively with assignments. The words “except within the categories prescribed in section 8067(a)–(d) of this title” are substituted for the words “in the line or in other staff corps”. Air Force nurses and women medical specialists are not covered by subsection (a), since their command authority is specifically stated in subsection (b).
In subsection (b), the words “may exercise command only” are substituted for the words “shall not be entitled * * * to command except”. The words “by virtue of their rank” and “by competent authority” are omitted as surplusage. 10:166(e) (last 22 words of last sentence) is omitted as superseded by section 8012(e) of this title.











1958 Act


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


8579(b)10 App.:166b–3.Aug. 9, 1955, ch. 654, § 1, 69 Stat. 579.


</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>