<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/924a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/924a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/924a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_924a"><akn:num>924a</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 124a. Bribery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 924a. Art. 124a. Bribery(a) Asking, Accepting, or Receiving Thing of Value.—Any person subject to this chapter—(1) who occupies an official position or who has official duties; and

(2) who wrongfully asks, accepts, or receives a thing of value with the intent to have the person’s decision or action influenced with respect to an official matter in which the United States is interested;


shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(b) Promising, Offering, or Giving Thing of Value.—Any person subject to this chapter who wrongfully promises, offers, or gives a thing of value to another person, who occupies an official position or who has official duties, with the intent to influence the decision or action of the other person with respect to an official matter in which the United States is interested, shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.

(Added Pub. L. 114–328, div. E, title LX, § 5437, Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2952.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on Jan. 1, 2019, as designated by the President, with implementing regulations and provisions relating to applicability to various situations, see section 5542 of Pub. L. 114–328 and Ex. Ord. No. 13825, set out as notes under section 801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_924a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Asking, Accepting, or Receiving Thing of Value.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Any person subject to this chapter— shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_924a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promising, Offering, or Giving Thing of Value.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Any person subject to this chapter who wrongfully promises, offers, or gives a thing of value to another person, who occupies an official position or who has official duties, with the intent to influence the decision or action of the other person with respect to an official matter in which the United States is interested, shall be punished as a court-martial may direct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>