<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9414b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9414b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9414b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9414b"><akn:num>9414b</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Air Force Institute of Technology: administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9414b. United States Air Force Institute of Technology: administration(a) Director and Chancellor.—(1) Selection.—The Director and Chancellor of the United States Air Force Institute of Technology shall be selected by the Secretary of the Air Force.

(2) Eligibility.—The Director and Chancellor shall be one of the following:(A) An officer of the Air Force or the Space Force on active duty in a grade not below the grade of colonel who possesses such qualifications as the Secretary considers appropriate and is assigned or detailed to such position.

(B) A member of the Senior Executive Service or a civilian individual, including an individual who was retired from the Air Force or the Space Force in a grade not below brigadier general, who has the qualifications appropriate for the position of Director and Chancellor and is selected by the Secretary as the best qualified from among candidates for the position in accordance with a process and criteria determined by the Secretary.


(3) Term for civilian director and chancellor.—An individual selected for the position of Director and Chancellor under paragraph (2)(B) shall serve in that position for a term of not more than five years and may be continued in that position for an additional term of up to five years.


(b) Provost and Chief Academic Officer.—(1) In general.—There is established at the United States Air Force Institute of Technology the civilian position of Provost and Chief Academic Officer who shall be selected by the Secretary.

(2) Term.—An individual selected for the position of Provost and Chief Academic Officer shall serve in that position for a term of not more than five years and may be continued in that position for an additional term of up to five years.

(3) Compensation.—The individual serving as Provost and Chief Academic Officer is entitled to such compensation for such service as the Secretary shall prescribe for purposes of this section, but not more than the rate of compensation authorize</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and Chancellor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9414b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provost and Chief Academic Officer.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>