<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/942" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/942/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/942/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_942"><akn:num>942</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 142. Judges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 942. Art. 142. Judges(a) Number.—The United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces consists of five judges.

(b) Appointment; Qualification.—(1) Each judge of the court shall be appointed from civilian life by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, for a specified term determined under paragraph (2). A judge may serve as a senior judge as provided in subsection (e).

(2)(A) The term of a judge shall expire as follows:(i) In the case of a judge who is appointed after January 31 and before July 31 of any year, the term shall expire on July 31 of the year in which the fifteenth anniversary of the appointment occurs.

(ii) In the case of a judge who is appointed after July 31 of any year and before February 1 of the following year, the term shall expire fifteen years after such July 31.


(B) If at the time of the appointment of a judge the date that is otherwise applicable under subparagraph (A) for the expiration of the term of service of the judge is the same as the date for the expiration of the term of service of a judge already on the court, then the term of the judge being appointed shall expire on the first July 31 after such date on which no term of service of a judge already on the court will expire.


(3) No person may be appointed to be a judge of the court unless the person is a member of the bar of a Federal court or the highest court of a State.

(4) A person may not be appointed as a judge of the court within seven years after retirement from active duty as a commissioned officer of a regular component of an armed force.


(c) Removal.—Judges of the court may be removed from office by the President, upon notice and hearing, for—(1) neglect of duty;

(2) misconduct; or

(3) mental or physical disability.


A judge may not be removed by the President for any other cause.

(d) Pay and Allowances.—Each judge of the court is entitled to the same salary and travel allowances as are, and from time to time may be, provided for j</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces consists of five judges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment; Qualification.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Judges of the court may be removed from office by the President, upon notice and hearing, for— A judge may not be removed by the President for any other cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay and Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Each judge of the court is entitled to the same salary and travel allowances as are, and from time to time may be, provided for judges of the United States Courts of Appeals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior Judges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of Article III Judges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_942_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Vacancy on Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A vacancy on the court does not impair the right of the remaining judges to exercise the powers of the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>