<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/946" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/946/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/946/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_946"><akn:num>946</akn:num><akn:heading>Art. 146. Military Justice Review Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 946. Art. 146. Military Justice Review Panel(a) Establishment.—The Secretary of Defense shall establish a panel to conduct independent periodic reviews and assessments of the operation of this chapter. The panel shall be known as the “Military Justice Review Panel” (in this section referred to as the “Panel”).

(b) Members.—(1) Number of members.—The Panel shall be composed of thirteen members.

(2) Appointment of certain members.—Each of the following shall appoint one member of the Panel:(A) The Secretary of Defense (in consultation with the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating when it is not operating as a service in the Navy).

(B) The Attorney General.

(C) The Judge Advocates General of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Coast Guard, and the Staff Judge Advocate to the Commandant of the Marine Corps.


(3) Appointment of remaining members by secretary of defense.—The Secretary of Defense shall appoint the remaining members of the Panel, taking into consideration recommendations made by each of the following:(A) The chairman and ranking minority member of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.

(B) The Chief Justice of the United States.

(C) The Chief Judge of the United States Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces.


(4) Establishment of staggered terms.—Notwithstanding subsection (e), members of the Panel appointed to serve on the Panel to fill vacancies that exist due to terms of appointment expiring during the period beginning on August 1, 2030, and ending on November 30, 2030, shall be appointed to terms as follows:(A) Three members designated by the Secretary of Defense shall serve a term of two years.

(B) Three members designated by the Secretary of Defense shall serve a term of four years.

(C) Three members designated by the Secretary of Defense shall serve a term of six years.

(D) Four members designated by the Secretary of Defense shall serve a t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense shall establish a panel to conduct independent periodic reviews and assessments of the operation of this chapter. The panel shall be known as the “Military Justice Review Panel” (in this section referred to as the “Panel”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications of Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The members of the Panel shall be appointed from among private United States citizens with expertise in criminal law, as well as appropriate and diverse experience in investigation, prosecution, defense, victim representation, or adjudication with respect to courts-martial, Federal civilian courts, or State courts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary of Defense shall select the chair of the Panel from among the members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term; Vacancies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviews and Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Panel may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Panel considers appropriate to carry out its duties under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information From Federal Agencies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Upon request of the chair of the Panel, a department or agency of the Federal Government shall provide information that the Panel considers necessary to carry out its duties under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative Matters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_946_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of Title 5.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the Panel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>