<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/948l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/948l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/948l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_948l"><akn:num>948l</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail or employment of reporters and interpreters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 948l. Detail or employment of reporters and interpreters(a) Court Reporters.—Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter shall detail to or employ for the military commission qualified court reporters, who shall prepare a verbatim record of the proceedings of and testimony taken before the military commission.

(b) Interpreters.—Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may detail to or employ for the military commission interpreters who shall interpret for the military commission, and, as necessary, for trial counsel and defense counsel for the military commission, and for the accused.

(c) Transcript; Record.—The transcript of a military commission under this chapter shall be under the control of the convening authority of the military commission, who shall also be responsible for preparing the record of the proceedings of the military commission.

(Added Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802, Oct. 28, 2009, 123 Stat. 2578.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 948l, added Pub. L. 109–366, § 3(a)(1), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2605, related to detail or employment of reporters and interpreters, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 111–84.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_948l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court Reporters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter shall detail to or employ for the military commission qualified court reporters, who shall prepare a verbatim record of the proceedings of and testimony taken before the military commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_948l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interpreters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under such regulations as the Secretary of Defense may prescribe, the convening authority of a military commission under this chapter may detail to or employ for the military commission interpreters who shall interpret for the military commission, and, as necessary, for trial counsel and defense counsel for the military commission, and for the accused.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_948l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transcript; Record.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The transcript of a military commission under this chapter shall be under the control of the convening authority of the military commission, who shall also be responsible for preparing the record of the proceedings of the military commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>