<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9497" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9497/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9497/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9497"><akn:num>9497</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9497. Board of Governors(a) Governing Body.—The Board of Governors of the Civil Air Patrol is the governing body of the Civil Air Patrol.

(b) Composition.—The Board of Governors is composed of 11 members as follows:(1) Four members appointed by the Secretary of the Air Force, who may be active or retired officers of the Air Force (including reserve components of the Air Force), employees of the United States, or private citizens.

(2) Four members of the Civil Air Patrol, selected in accordance with the constitution and bylaws of the Civil Air Patrol.

(3) Three members appointed or selected as provided in subsection (c) from among personnel of any Federal Government agencies, public corporations, nonprofit associations, and other organizations that have an interest and expertise in civil aviation and the Civil Air Patrol mission.


(c) Appointments From Interested Organizations.—(1) Subject to paragraph (2), the members of the Board of Governors referred to in subsection (b)(3) shall be appointed jointly by the Secretary of the Air Force and the National Commander of the Civil Air Patrol.

(2) Any vacancy in the position of a member referred to in paragraph (1) that is not filled under that paragraph within 90 days shall be filled by majority vote of the other members of the Board.


(d) Chairman.—The Chairman of the Board of Governors shall be chosen by the members of the Board of Governors from among the members of the Board referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and shall serve for a term of two years. The position of Chairman shall be held on a rotating basis between members of the Board appointed by the Secretary of the Air Force under paragraph (1) of subsection (b) and members of the Board selected under paragraph (2) of that subsection.

(e) Powers.—(1) The Board of Governors shall, subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), exercise the powers granted to the Civil Air Patrol under section 40304 of title 36.

(2) Any exercise by the Board of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing Body.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Board of Governors of the Civil Air Patrol is the governing body of the Civil Air Patrol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Board of Governors is composed of 11 members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointments From Interested Organizations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Chairman of the Board of Governors shall be chosen by the members of the Board of Governors from among the members of the Board referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) and shall serve for a term of two years. The position of Chairman shall be held on a rotating basis between members of the Board appointed by the Secretary of the Air Force under paragraph (1) of subsection (b) and members of the Board selected under paragraph (2) of that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal Liability for Breach of a Fiduciary Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9497_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal Liability for Breach of a Fiduciary Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>