<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_949f"><akn:num>949f</akn:num><akn:heading>Challenges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 949f. Challenges(a) Challenges Authorized.—The military judge and primary or alternate members of a military commission under this chapter may be challenged by the accused or trial counsel for cause stated to the military commission. The military judge shall determine the relevance and validity of challenges for cause, and may not receive a challenge to more than one person at a time. Challenges by trial counsel shall ordinarily be presented and decided before those by the accused are offered.

(b) Peremptory Challenges.—The accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge, but the military judge may not be challenged except for cause. Nothing in this section prohibits the military judge from awarding to each party such additional peremptory challenges as may be required in the interests of justice.

(c) Challenges Against Additional Members.—Whenever additional members are detailed to a military commission under this chapter, and after any challenges for cause against such additional members are presented and decided, the accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge against members not previously subject to peremptory challenge.

(Added Pub. L. 111–84, div. A, title XVIII, § 1802, Oct. 28, 2009, 123 Stat. 2586; amended Pub. L. 113–66, div. A, title X, § 1031(b), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 850.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 949f, added Pub. L. 109–366, § 3(a)(1), Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2613, related to challenges, prior to the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 111–84.

Amendments2013—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 113–66, § 1031(b)(1), inserted “primary or alternate” before “members”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 113–66, § 1031(b)(2), inserted at end “Nothing in this section prohibits the military judge from awarding to each party such additional peremptory challenges as may be required in the interests of justice.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Challenges Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The military judge and primary or alternate members of a military commission under this chapter may be challenged by the accused or trial counsel for cause stated to the military commission. The military judge shall determine the relevance and validity of challenges for cause, and may not receive a challenge to more than one person at a time. Challenges by trial counsel shall ordinarily be presented and decided before those by the accused are offered.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peremptory Challenges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge, but the military judge may not be challenged except for cause. Nothing in this section prohibits the military judge from awarding to each party such additional peremptory challenges as may be required in the interests of justice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Challenges Against Additional Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever additional members are detailed to a military commission under this chapter, and after any challenges for cause against such additional members are presented and decided, the accused and trial counsel are each entitled to one peremptory challenge against members not previously subject to peremptory challenge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>