<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_949p_4"><akn:num>949p–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Discovery of, and access to, classified information by the accused</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 949p–4. Discovery of, and access to, classified information by the accused(a) Limitations on Discovery or Access by the Accused.—(1) Declarations by the united states of damage to national security.—In any case before a military commission in which the United States seeks to delete, withhold, or otherwise obtain other relief with respect to the discovery of or access to any classified information, the trial counsel shall submit a declaration invoking the United States’ classified information privilege and setting forth the damage to the national security that the discovery of or access to such information reasonably could be expected to cause. The declaration shall be signed by a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information.

(2) Standard for authorization of discovery or access.—Upon the submission of a declaration under paragraph (1), the military judge may not authorize the discovery of or access to such classified information unless the military judge determines that such classified information would be noncumulative, relevant, and helpful to a legally cognizable defense, rebuttal of the prosecution’s case, or to sentencing, in accordance with standards generally applicable to discovery of or access to classified information in Federal criminal cases. If the discovery of or access to such classified information is authorized, it shall be addressed in accordance with the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) Discovery of Classified Information.—(1) Substitutions and other relief.—The military judge, in assessing the accused’s discovery of or access to classified information under this section, may authorize the United States—(A) to delete or withhold specified items of classified information;

(B) to substitute a summary for classified information; or

(C) to substitute a statement admitting relevant facts that the classified information or material would tend to prove.


(2) Ex parte presentations.—The military judge shall </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Discovery or Access by the Accused.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discovery of Classified Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reconsideration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) An order of a military judge authorizing a request of the trial counsel to substitute, summarize, withhold, or prevent access to classified information under this section is not subject to a motion for reconsideration by the accused, if such order was entered pursuant to an ex parte showing under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>