<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/949p–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_949p_6"><akn:num>949p–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure for cases involving classified information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 949p–6. Procedure for cases involving classified information(a) Motion for Hearing.—(1) Request for hearing.—Within the time specified by the military judge for the filing of a motion under this section, either party may request the military judge to conduct a hearing to make all determinations concerning the use, relevance, or admissibility of classified information that would otherwise be made during the trial or pretrial proceeding.

(2) Conduct of hearing.—Upon a request by either party under paragraph (1), the military judge shall conduct such a hearing and shall rule prior to conducting any further proceedings.

(3) In camera hearing upon declaration to court by appropriate official of risk of disclosure of classified information.—Any hearing held pursuant to this subsection (or any portion of such hearing specified in the request of a knowledgeable United States official) shall be held in camera if a knowledgeable United States official possessing authority to classify information submits to the military judge a declaration that a public proceeding may result in the disclosure of classified information. Classified information is not subject to disclosure under this section unless the information is relevant and necessary to an element of the offense or a legally cognizable defense and is otherwise admissible in evidence.

(4) Military judge to make determinations in writing.—As to each item of classified information, the military judge shall set forth in writing the basis for the determination.


(b) Notice and Use of Classified Information by the Government.—(1) Notice to accused.—Before any hearing is conducted pursuant to a request by the trial counsel under subsection (a), trial counsel shall provide the accused with notice of the classified information that is at issue. Such notice shall identify the specific classified information at issue whenever that information previously has been made available to the accused by the United States. When the United</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Motion for Hearing.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Use of Classified Information by the Government.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substitutions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative Procedure for Disclosure of Classified Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sealing of Records of in Camera Hearings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) If at the close of an in camera hearing under this section (or any portion of a hearing under this section that is held in camera), the military judge determines that the classified information at issue may not be disclosed or elicited at the trial or pretrial proceeding, the record of such in camera hearing shall be sealed and preserved for use in the event of an appeal. The accused may seek reconsideration of the military judge’s determination prior to or during trial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Disclosure of Classified Information by the Accused; Relief for Accused When the United States Opposes Disclosure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_949p_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>