<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_950d"><akn:num>950d</akn:num><akn:heading>Interlocutory appeals by the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 950d. Interlocutory appeals by the United States(a) Interlocutory Appeal.—Except as provided in subsection (b), in a trial by military commission under this chapter, the United States may take an interlocutory appeal to the United States Court of Military Commission Review of any order or ruling of the military judge—(1) that terminates proceedings of the military commission with respect to a charge or specification;

(2) that excludes evidence that is substantial proof of a fact material in the proceeding;

(3) that relates to a matter under subsection (c) or (d) of section 949d of this title; or

(4) that, with respect to classified information—(A) authorizes the disclosure of such information;

(B) imposes sanctions for nondisclosure of such information; or

(C) refuses a protective order sought by the United States to prevent the disclosure of such information.



(b) Limitation.—The United States may not appeal under subsection (a) an order or ruling that is, or amounts to, a finding of not guilty by the military commission with respect to a charge or specification.

(c) Scope of Appeal Right With Respect to Classified Information.—The United States has the right to appeal under paragraph (4) of subsection (a) whenever the military judge enters an order or ruling that would require the disclosure of classified information, without regard to whether the order or ruling appealed from was entered under this chapter, another provision of law, a rule, or otherwise. Any such appeal may embrace any preceding order, ruling, or reasoning constituting the basis of the order or ruling that would authorize such disclosure.

(d) Timing and Action on Interlocutory Appeals Relating to Classified Information.—(1) Appeal to be expedited.—An appeal taken pursuant to paragraph (4) of subsection (a) shall be expedited by the United States Court of Military Commission Review.

(2) Appeals before trial.—If such an appeal is taken before trial, the appeal shall be taken within 10 d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interlocutory Appeal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), in a trial by military commission under this chapter, the United States may take an interlocutory appeal to the United States Court of Military Commission Review of any order or ruling of the military judge—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The United States may not appeal under subsection (a) an order or ruling that is, or amounts to, a finding of not guilty by the military commission with respect to a charge or specification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of Appeal Right With Respect to Classified Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The United States has the right to appeal under paragraph (4) of subsection (a) whenever the military judge enters an order or ruling that would require the disclosure of classified information, without regard to whether the order or ruling appealed from was entered under this chapter, another provision of law, a rule, or otherwise. Any such appeal may embrace any preceding order, ruling, or reasoning constituting the basis of the order or ruling that would authorize such disclosure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing and Action on Interlocutory Appeals Relating to Classified Information.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and Timing of Other Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The United States shall take an appeal of an order or ruling under subsection (a), other than an appeal under paragraph (4) of that subsection, by filing a notice of appeal with the military judge within 5 days after the date of the order or ruling.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of Appeal.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) An appeal under this section shall be forwarded, by means specified in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, directly to the United States Court of Military Commission Review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals Court To Act Only With Respect to Matter of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In ruling on an appeal under paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a), the appeals court may act only with respect to matters of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent Appeal Rights of Accused Not Affected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) An appeal under paragraph (4) of subsection (a), and a decision on such appeal, shall not affect the right of the accused, in a subsequent appeal from a judgment of conviction, to claim as error reversal by the military judge on remand of a ruling appealed from during trial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>