<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/950g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_950g"><akn:num>950g</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit; writ of certiorari to</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 950g. Review by United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit; writ of certiorari to Supreme Court(a) Exclusive Appellate Jurisdiction.—Except as provided in subsection (b), the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction to determine the validity of a final judgment rendered by a military commission (as approved by the convening authority and, where applicable, as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review) under this chapter.

(b) Exhaustion of Other Appeals.—The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may not review a final judgment described in subsection (a) until all other appeals under this chapter have been waived or exhausted.

(c) Time for Seeking Review.—A petition for review by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit must be filed in the Court of Appeals—(1) not later than 20 days after the date on which written notice of the final decision of the United States Court of Military Commission Review is served on the parties; or

(2) if the accused submits, in the form prescribed by section 950c of this title, a written notice waiving the right of the accused to review by the United States Court of Military Commission Review, not later than 20 days after the date on which such notice is submitted.


(d) Scope and Nature of Review.—The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may act under this section only with respect to the findings and sentence as approved by the convening authority and as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review, and shall take action only with respect to matters of law, including the sufficiency of the evidence to support the verdict.

(e) Review by Supreme Court.—The Supreme Court may review by writ of certiorari pursuant to section 1254 of title 28 the fina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusive Appellate Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Except as provided in subsection (b), the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit shall have exclusive jurisdiction to determine the validity of a final judgment rendered by a military commission (as approved by the convening authority and, where applicable, as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review) under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exhaustion of Other Appeals.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may not review a final judgment described in subsection (a) until all other appeals under this chapter have been waived or exhausted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Seeking Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A petition for review by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit must be filed in the Court of Appeals—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope and Nature of Review.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit may act under this section only with respect to the findings and sentence as approved by the convening authority and as affirmed or set aside as incorrect in law by the United States Court of Military Commission Review, and shall take action only with respect to matters of law, including the sufficiency of the evidence to support the verdict.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_950g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Supreme Court.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Supreme Court may review by writ of certiorari pursuant to section 1254 of title 28 the final judgment of the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>