<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9512" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9512/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9512/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9512"><akn:num>9512</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Reserve Air Fleet contracts: payment rate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9512. Civil Reserve Air Fleet contracts: payment rate(a) Authority.—The Secretary shall determine a fair and reasonable rate of payment for airlift services provided to the Department of Defense by air carriers who are participants in the Civil Reserve Air Fleet program.

(b) Regulations.—The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of subsection (a). The Secretary may exclude from the applicability of those regulations any airlift services contract made through the use of competitive procedures.

(c) Commitment of Aircraft as a Business Factor.—The Secretary may, in determining the quantity of business to be received under an airlift services contract for which the rate of payment is determined in accordance with subsection (a), use as a factor the relative amount of airlift capability committed by each air carrier to the Civil Reserve Air Fleet.

(d) Inapplicable Provisions of Law.—An airlift services contract for which the rate of payment is determined in accordance with subsection (a) shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 271 of this title or to the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of section 1502 of title 41.

(Added Pub. L. 112–81, div. A, title III, § 366(a), Dec. 31, 2011, 125 Stat. 1380, § 9511a; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XVIII, § 1831(j)(6), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4217; renumbered § 9512 and amended Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title X, § 1083(a)(2)(A), (c)(1)(A), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 1922, 1923.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 9512 was renumbered section 9513 of this title.

Amendments2021—Pub. L. 117–81 renumbered section 9511a of this title as this section and substituted “Secretary” for “Secretary of Defense” in subsecs. (a) and (b).
Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 116–283 substituted “chapter 271” for “section 2306a”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2021 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 116–283 effective Jan. 1, 2022, with additional provisions for delayed implementation and app</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9512_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall determine a fair and reasonable rate of payment for airlift services provided to the Department of Defense by air carriers who are participants in the Civil Reserve Air Fleet program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9512_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall prescribe regulations for purposes of subsection (a). The Secretary may exclude from the applicability of those regulations any airlift services contract made through the use of competitive procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9512_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commitment of Aircraft as a Business Factor.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may, in determining the quantity of business to be received under an airlift services contract for which the rate of payment is determined in accordance with subsection (a), use as a factor the relative amount of airlift capability committed by each air carrier to the Civil Reserve Air Fleet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9512_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicable Provisions of Law.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An airlift services contract for which the rate of payment is determined in accordance with subsection (a) shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 271 of this title or to the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of section 1502 of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>