<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9515" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9515/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9515/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9515"><akn:num>9515</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter air transportation services: minimum annual purchase amount for carriers participating in Ci</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9515. Charter air transportation services: minimum annual purchase amount for carriers participating in Civil Reserve Air Fleet(a) In General.—The Secretary shall take steps to—(1) improve the predictability in Department of Defense charter requirements;

(2) strengthen Civil Reserve Airlift Fleet participation to assure adequate capacity is available to meet steady-state, surge and mobilization requirements; and

(3) provide incentives for commercial air carriers to provide newer, more efficient and reliable aircraft for Department of Defense service rather than older, fully depreciated aircraft.


(b) Consideration of Recommendations.—In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the recommendations on courses of action for the Civil Reserve Air Fleet as outlined in the report required by section 356 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (Public Law 110–181).

(c) Contracts for Charter Air Transportation Services.—The Secretary may award to an air carrier or an air carrier contractor team arrangement participating in the Civil Reserve Air Fleet on a fiscal year basis a one-year contract for charter air transportation services with a minimum purchase amount under such contract determined in accordance with this section.

(d) Eligible Charter Air Transportation Carriers.—In order to be eligible for payments under the minimum purchase amount provided by this section, an air carrier (or any air carrier participating in an air carrier contractor team arrangement)—(1) if under contract with the Department of Defense in the prior fiscal year, shall have an average on-time pick up rate, based on factors within such air carrier’s control, of at least 90 percent;

(2) shall offer such amount of commitment to the Civil Reserve Air Fleet in excess of the minimum required for participation in the Civil Reserve Air Fleet as the Secretary shall specify for purposes of this section; and

(3) may not have refused a Department of Defense re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall take steps to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of Recommendations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the recommendations on courses of action for the Civil Reserve Air Fleet as outlined in the report required by section 356 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 (Public Law 110–181).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for Charter Air Transportation Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may award to an air carrier or an air carrier contractor team arrangement participating in the Civil Reserve Air Fleet on a fiscal year basis a one-year contract for charter air transportation services with a minimum purchase amount under such contract determined in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Charter Air Transportation Carriers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In order to be eligible for payments under the minimum purchase amount provided by this section, an air carrier (or any air carrier participating in an air carrier contractor team arrangement)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aggregate Minimum Purchase Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of Minimum Purchase Among Charter Air Transportation Contracts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of Amounts.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) If any amount available under this section for the minimum purchase of charter air transportation services from a carrier or air carrier contractor team arrangement for a fiscal year under a contract under subsection (c) is not utilized to purchase charter air transportation services from the carrier or arrangement in such fiscal year, such amount shall be provided to the carrier or arrangement before the first day of the following fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commitment of Funds.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Airlift Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9515_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section, the term “charter air transportation” has the meaning given such term in section 40102(14) of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>