<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/9564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9564"><akn:num>9564</akn:num><akn:heading>Navy and Marine Corps: camp equipment and transportation; when on shore duty with Air Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9564. Navy and Marine Corps: camp equipment and transportation; when on shore duty with Air Force
While any detachment of the Navy or Marine Corps is on shore duty in cooperation with troops of the Air Force, the Secretary of the Air Force shall, upon the requisition of the officer of the Navy or Marine Corps in command of the detachment, issue rations and camp equipment, and furnish transportation, to that detachment.
(Aug. 10, 1956, ch. 1041, 70A Stat. 578.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


956410:1259d.10:1259e.34:541.R.S. 1143; June 28, 1950, ch. 383, § 402(a), 64 Stat. 272.
  R.S. 1135; June 28, 1950, ch. 383, § 402(a), 64 Stat. 272.


The words “While * * * on shore duty” are substituted for the words “under orders to act on shore”, in 10:1259d and 1259e, and 34:541. The words “the Secretary of the Air Force” are substituted for the words “the branch, office, or officers of the Army, the Secretary of the Army may from time to time designate”, in 10:1259d and 1259e, and 34:541, since the functions which, for the Army, are assigned by statute to subordinate officers of the Army, are, for the Air Force, assigned to the Secretary of the Air Force. The words “during the time such detachment is so acting or proceeding to act”, in 10:1259d and 1259e, and 34:541, are omitted as surplusage. The words “their baggage, provisions, and cannon”, in 10:1259e and 34:541, are omitted as surplusage. The words “and shall furnish the naval officer commanding any such detachment, and his necessary aides, with horses, accouterments, and forage”, in 10:1259e and 34:541, are omitted as obsolete.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>