<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/974" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/974/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/974/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_974"><akn:num>974</akn:num><akn:heading>Military musical units and musicians: performance policies; restriction on performance in competitio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 974. Military musical units and musicians: performance policies; restriction on performance in competition with local civilian musicians(a) Military Musicians Performing in an Official Capacity.—(1) A military musical unit, and a member of the armed forces who is a member of such a unit performing in an official capacity, may not engage in the performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians.

(2) For purposes of paragraph (1), the following shall, except as provided in paragraph (3), be included among the performances that are considered to be a performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians:(A) A performance that is more than incidental to an event that—(i) is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; and

(ii) is not free to the public.


(B) A performance of background, dinner, dance, or other social music at an event that—(i) is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; and

(ii) is held at a location not on a military installation.



(3) For purposes of paragraph (1), the following shall not be considered to be a performance of music in competition with local civilian musicians:(A) A performance (including background, dinner, dance, or other social music) at an official United States Government event that is supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds.

(B) A performance at a concert, parade, or other event, that—(i) is a patriotic event or a celebration of a national holiday; and

(ii) is free to the public.


(C) A performance that is incidental to an event that—(i) is not supported, in whole or in part, by United States Government funds; or

(ii) is not free to the public.


(D) A performance (including background, dinner, dance, or other social music) at—(i) an event that is sponsored by a military welfare society, as defined in section 2566 of this title;

(ii) an event that is a traditional military event intended to foster the morale an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Musicians Performing in an Official Capacity.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of Military Musicians Accepting Additional Remuneration for Official Performances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A military musical unit, and a member of the armed forces who is a member of such a unit performing in an official capacity, may not receive remuneration for an official performance, other than applicable military pay and allowances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordings.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private Donations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performances at Foreign Locations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsection (a) does not apply to a performance outside the United States, its commonwealths, or its possessions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_974_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Military Musical Unit Defined.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) In this section, the term “military musical unit” means a band, ensemble, chorus, or similar musical unit of the armed forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>