<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/977" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/977/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/977/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_977"><akn:num>977</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion of military medical and dental positions to civilian medical and dental positions: limita</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 977. Conversion of military medical and dental positions to civilian medical and dental positions: limitation(a) Process.—The Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall establish a process to define the military medical and dental personnel requirements necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements.

(b) Requirements Relating to Conversion.—A military medical or dental position within the Department of Defense may be converted to a civilian medical or dental position if the Secretary determines that the position is not necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements, as determined pursuant to subsection (a).

(c) Grade or Level Converted.—In carrying out a conversion under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense—(1) shall convert the applicable military position to a civilian position with a level of compensation commensurate with the skills and experience necessary to carry out the duties of such civilian position; and

(2) may not place any limitation on the grade or level to which the military position is so converted.


(d) Definitions.—In this section:(1) The term “military medical or dental position” means a position for the performance of health care functions within the armed forces held by a member of the armed forces.

(2) The term “civilian medical or dental position” means a position for the performance of health care functions within the Department of Defense held by an employee of the Department or of a contractor of the Department.

(3) The term “conversion”, with respect to a military medical or dental position, means a change of the position to a civilian medical or dental position, effective as of the date of the manning authorization document of the military department making the change (through a change in designation from military to civilian in the document, the elimination of the listing of the position as a military position in the document, or thro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_977_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall establish a process to define the military medical and dental personnel requirements necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_977_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements Relating to Conversion.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A military medical or dental position within the Department of Defense may be converted to a civilian medical or dental position if the Secretary determines that the position is not necessary to meet operational medical force readiness requirements, as determined pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_977_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grade or Level Converted.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out a conversion under subsection (b), the Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_977_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>