<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/987" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/987/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/10/987/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_987"><akn:num>987</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of consumer credit extended to members and dependents: limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 987. Terms of consumer credit extended to members and dependents: limitations(a) Interest.—A creditor who extends consumer credit to a covered member of the armed forces or a dependent of such a member shall not require the member or dependent to pay interest with respect to the extension of such credit, except as—(1) agreed to under the terms of the credit agreement or promissory note;

(2) authorized by applicable State or Federal law; and

(3) not specifically prohibited by this section.


(b) Annual Percentage Rate.—A creditor described in subsection (a) may not impose an annual percentage rate of interest greater than 36 percent with respect to the consumer credit extended to a covered member or a dependent of a covered member.

(c) Mandatory Loan Disclosures.—(1) Information required.—With respect to any extension of consumer credit (including any consumer credit originated or extended through the internet) to a covered member or a dependent of a covered member, a creditor shall provide to the member or dependent the following information orally and in writing before the issuance of the credit:(A) A statement of the annual percentage rate of interest applicable to the extension of credit.

(B) Any disclosures required under the Truth in Lending Act (15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.).

(C) A clear description of the payment obligations of the member or dependent, as applicable.


(2) Terms.—Such disclosures shall be presented in accordance with terms prescribed by the regulations issued by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to implement the Truth in Lending Act (15 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.).


(d) Preemption.—(1) Inconsistent laws.—Except as provided in subsection (f)(2), this section preempts any State or Federal law, rule, or regulation, including any State usury law, to the extent that such law, rule, or regulation is inconsistent with this section, except that this section shall not preempt any such law, rule, or regulation that provides protection to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A creditor who extends consumer credit to a covered member of the armed forces or a dependent of such a member shall not require the member or dependent to pay interest with respect to the extension of such credit, except as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Percentage Rate.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A creditor described in subsection (a) may not impose an annual percentage rate of interest greater than 36 percent with respect to the consumer credit extended to a covered member or a dependent of a covered member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory Loan Disclosures.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) It shall be unlawful for any creditor to extend consumer credit to a covered member or a dependent of such a member with respect to which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties and Remedies.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Servicemembers Civil Relief Act Protections Unaffected.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nothing in this section may be construed to limit or otherwise affect the applicability of section 207 of the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. 3937).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_987_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>