<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/1006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/1006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/1006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1006"><akn:num>1006</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1006. Advance payments(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service may be paid in advance—(1) not more than three months’ pay of such member upon such member’s change of permanent station; or

(2) the amount of an allotment made from such member’s pay to a dependent if such member is assigned or scheduled for assignment to sea duty or other duty with a unit or command deployed or to be deployed outside the United States and the allotment is made by such member not more than sixty days before the scheduled date of the assignment of such member to such duty.


(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service who is on duty at a distant station where the pay and emoluments to which he is entitled cannot be disbursed regularly, may be paid in advance.

(c) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, an advance of pay to a member of a uniformed service who is on duty outside the United States, or other place designated by the Secretary of Defense, of not more than two months’ basic pay may be made to a member if the member or the dependents of the member are ordered evacuated by competent authority. An advance of pay under this subsection is not subject to the conditions under which advances of pay may be made under subsection (a) or (b). An advance may be made on the basis of the evacuation of a member’s dependents only if all dependents of members of the uniformed services are ordered evacuated from the place where the member’s dependents are located. In the case of a member with dependents, the payment may be made directly to dependents previously designated by the member. The Secretary concerned or his designee may waive any right of recovery of not more than one month’s basic pay advanced under this subsection if he finds that recovery of the advance would be against equity and good conscience or against the public interest.

(d) If a person to whom an advance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service may be paid in advance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, a member of a uniformed service who is on duty at a distant station where the pay and emoluments to which he is entitled cannot be disbursed regularly, may be paid in advance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, an advance of pay to a member of a uniformed service who is on duty outside the United States, or other place designated by the Secretary of Defense, of not more than two months’ basic pay may be made to a member if the member or the dependents of the member are ordered evacuated by competent authority. An advance of pay under this subsection is not subject to the conditions under which advances of pay may be made under subsection (a) or (b). An advance may be made on the basis of the evacuation of a member’s dependents only if all dependents of members of the uniformed services are ordered evacuated from the place where the member’s dependents are located. In the case of a member with dependents, the payment may be made directly to dependents previously designated by the member. The Secretary concerned or his designee may waive any right of recovery of not more than one month’s basic pay advanced under this subsection if he </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) If a person to whom an advance of pay is made under subsection (a), (b), or (c) dies or is separated from his uniformed service, before liquidation of that advance, the amount remaining unliquidated at the time of his death or separation shall be credited to the account of the disbursing officer concerned. However, the unliquidated amount remains a debt of that person or his estate to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, an advance of pay of not more than three months’ pay may be made to an officer of the Coast Guard who is ordered to sea duty or to or from shore duty beyond the seas. In addition, the Commandant of the Coast Guard may direct such advances as he considers necessary and proper to members of the Coast Guard stationed at distant stations where the pay and emoluments to which they are entitled cannot be paid regularly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, the dislocation allowance authorized by section 452(c)(2) of this title for a member of a uniformed service whose dependents are covered by section 452(b)(11) of this title may be paid in advance of the evacuation of the dependents and to the dependents designated by the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of section 3324 of title 31, the Secretary concerned may, when the last day of the pay period falls on a Saturday, Sunday, or legal holiday, authorize the payment of pay and allowances to members of uniformed service under his jurisdiction on the preceding workday but not more than three days before the last day of that pay period. If a member dies after he has received an advance payment under this subsection, but before the last day of the pay period for which the payment is made, no part of the amount so advance is recoverable by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, not more than one month’s pay may be paid in advance to a member of the Armed Forces Health Professions Scholarship program upon reporting for a period of active duty required by section 2121(c) of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1006_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, not more than one month’s pay may be paid in advance to a member of the Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps who is ordered to field training or a practice required under section 2109 of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>