<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/301b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/301b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/301b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_301b"><akn:num>301b</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: aviation career officers extending period of active duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 301b. Special pay: aviation career officers extending period of active duty(a) Bonus Authorized.—An aviation officer described in subsection (b) who, during the period beginning on January 1, 1989, and ending on December 31, 2018, executes a written agreement to remain on active duty in aviation service for at least one year may, upon the acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid a retention bonus as provided in this section.

(b) Covered Officers.—An aviation officer referred to in subsection (a) is an officer of a uniformed service who—(1) is entitled to aviation career incentive pay under section 301a of this title;

(2) is in a pay grade below pay grade O–7;

(3) is qualified to perform operational flying duty; and

(4) has completed any active duty service commitment incurred for undergraduate aviator training or is within one year of completing such commitment.


(c) Amount of Bonus.—The amount of a retention bonus paid under this section may not be more than $25,000 for each year covered by the written agreement to remain on active duty.

(d) Proration.—The term of an agreement under subsection (a) and the amount of the bonus under subsection (c) may be prorated as long as such agreement does not extend beyond the date on which the officer making such agreement would complete 25 years of aviation service.

(e) Payment of Bonus.—Upon the acceptance of a written agreement under subsection (a) by the Secretary concerned, the total amount payable pursuant to the agreement becomes fixed and may be paid by the Secretary in either a lump sum or installments.

(f) Additional Pay.—A retention bonus paid under this section is in addition to any other pay and allowances to which an officer is entitled.

(g) Repayment.—An officer who does not complete the period of active duty specified in the agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.

(h) Regulations.—The Secretaries</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonus Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An aviation officer described in subsection (b) who, during the period beginning on January 1, 1989, and ending on December 31, 2018, executes a written agreement to remain on active duty in aviation service for at least one year may, upon the acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid a retention bonus as provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An aviation officer referred to in subsection (a) is an officer of a uniformed service who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The amount of a retention bonus paid under this section may not be more than $25,000 for each year covered by the written agreement to remain on active duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term of an agreement under subsection (a) and the amount of the bonus under subsection (c) may be prorated as long as such agreement does not extend beyond the date on which the officer making such agreement would complete 25 years of aviation service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Upon the acceptance of a written agreement under subsection (a) by the Secretary concerned, the total amount payable pursuant to the agreement becomes fixed and may be paid by the Secretary in either a lump sum or installments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A retention bonus paid under this section is in addition to any other pay and allowances to which an officer is entitled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An officer who does not complete the period of active duty specified in the agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_301b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>