<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302c"><akn:num>302c</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: psychologists and nonphysician health care providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302c. Special pay: psychologists and nonphysician health care providers(a) Public Health Service Corps.—A member who is—(1) an officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Public Health Service and is designated as a psychologist; and

(2) has been awarded a diploma as a Diplomate in Psychology by the American Board of Professional Psychology,


is entitled to special pay, as provided in subsection (b).

(b) Rate of Special Pay.—The rate of special pay to which an officer is entitled pursuant to subsection (a) shall be—(1) $2,000 per year, if the officer has less than 10 years of creditable service;

(2) $2,500 per year, if the officer has at least 10 but less than 12 years of creditable service;

(3) $3,000 per year, if the officer has at least 12 but less than 14 years of creditable service;

(4) $4,000 per year, if the officer has at least 14 but less than 18 years of creditable service; or

(5) $5,000 per year, if the officer has 18 or more years of creditable service.


(c) Army, Navy, and Air Force Psychologists.—The Secretary of Defense may provide special pay at the rates specified in subsection (b) to an officer who—(1) is an officer in the Medical Service Corps of the Army or Navy or a biomedical sciences officer in the Air Force;

(2) is designated as a psychologist; and

(3) has been awarded a diploma as a Diplomate in Psychology by the American Board of Professional Psychology.


(d) Nonphysician Health Care Providers.—The Secretary concerned may authorize the payment of special pay at the rates specified in subsection (b) to an officer who—(1) is an officer in the Medical Service Corps of the Army or Navy, a biomedical sciences officer in the Air Force, an officer in the Army Medical Specialist Corps, an officer of the Nurse Corps of the Army or Navy, an officer of the Air Force designated as a nurse, an officer of the Coast Guard or Coast Guard Reserve designated as a physician assistant, or an officer in the Regu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Health Service Corps.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A member who is— is entitled to special pay, as provided in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of Special Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The rate of special pay to which an officer is entitled pursuant to subsection (a) shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Army, Navy, and Air Force Psychologists.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Defense may provide special pay at the rates specified in subsection (b) to an officer who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonphysician Health Care Providers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned may authorize the payment of special pay at the rates specified in subsection (b) to an officer who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>