<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302c_1"><akn:num>302c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: accession and retention bonuses for psychologists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302c–1. Special pay: accession and retention bonuses for psychologists(a) Accession Bonus.—(1) Accession bonus authorized.—A person described in paragraph (2) who executes a written agreement described in subsection (d) to accept a commission as an officer of the armed forces and remain on active duty for a period of not less than four consecutive years may, upon acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid an accession bonus in an amount, subject to subsection (c)(1), determined by the Secretary concerned.

(2) Eligible persons.—A person described in paragraph (1) is any person who—(A) is a graduate of an accredited school of psychology; and

(B) holds a valid State license to practice as a doctoral level psychologist.


(3) Limitation on eligibility.—A person may not be paid a bonus under this subsection if—(A) the person, in exchange for an agreement to accept an appointment as an officer, received financial assistance from the Department of Defense to pursue a course of study in psychology; or

(B) the Secretary concerned determines that the person is not qualified to become and remain certified as a psychologist.



(b) Multiyear Retention Bonus.—(1) Retention bonus authorized.—An officer described in paragraph (2) who executes a written agreement described in subsection (d) to remain on active duty for up to four years after completion of any other active-duty service commitment may, upon acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid a retention bonus as provided in this section.

(2) Eligible officers.—An officer described in paragraph (1) is an officer of the armed forces who—(A) is a psychologist of the armed forces;

(B) is in a pay grade below pay grade O–7;

(C) has at least eight years of creditable service (computed as described in section 302b(f) of this title) or has completed any active-duty service commitment incurred for psychology education and training;

(D) has completed initial residency training (or will</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accession Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiyear Retention Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Amount of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The agreement referred to in subsections (a) and (b) shall provide that, consistent with the needs of the armed force concerned, the person or officer executing the agreement will be assigned to duty, for the period of obligated service covered by the agreement, as an officer of such armed force as a psychologist.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302c_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No agreement under subsection (a) or (b) may be entered into after December 31, 2018.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>