<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302g"><akn:num>302g</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: Selected Reserve health care professionals in critically short wartime specialties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302g. Special pay: Selected Reserve health care professionals in critically short wartime specialties(a) Special Pay Authorized.—An officer of a reserve component of the armed forces described in subsection (b) who executes a written agreement under which the officer agrees to serve in the Selected Reserve of an armed force for a period of not less than one year nor more than three years, beginning on the date the officer accepts the award of special pay under this section, may be paid special pay at an annual rate not to exceed $25,000.

(b) Eligible Officers.—An officer referred to in subsection (a) is an officer in a health care profession who is qualified in a specialty designated by regulations as a critically short wartime specialty.

(c) Time for Payment.—Special pay under this section shall be paid annually at the beginning of each twelve-month period for which the officer has agreed to serve.

(d) Repayment.—An officer who does not complete the period of service in the Selected Reserve specified in the agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.

(e) Termination of Agreement Authority.—No agreement under this section may be entered into after December 31, 2018.

(Added Pub. L. 104–106, div. A, title VI, § 614(a)(1), Feb. 10, 1996, 110 Stat. 360; amended Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 611(a), Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2543; Pub. L. 105–85, div. A, title VI, § 611(a), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 1785; Pub. L. 105–261, div. A, title VI, § 611(a), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2038; Pub. L. 106–65, div. A, title VI, § 611(a), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 649; Pub. L. 106–398, § 1 [[div. A], title VI, § 621(a)], Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1654, 1654A–151; Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 611(a), Dec. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 1135; Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI, § 612(e), Dec. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 2567; Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VI, § 612(e), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1501; Pub. L. 108–3</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Pay Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) An officer of a reserve component of the armed forces described in subsection (b) who executes a written agreement under which the officer agrees to serve in the Selected Reserve of an armed force for a period of not less than one year nor more than three years, beginning on the date the officer accepts the award of special pay under this section, may be paid special pay at an annual rate not to exceed $25,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Officers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An officer referred to in subsection (a) is an officer in a health care profession who is qualified in a specialty designated by regulations as a critically short wartime specialty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special pay under this section shall be paid annually at the beginning of each twelve-month period for which the officer has agreed to serve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An officer who does not complete the period of service in the Selected Reserve specified in the agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Agreement Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No agreement under this section may be entered into after December 31, 2018.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>