<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/302h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_302h"><akn:num>302h</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: accession bonus for dental officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 302h. Special pay: accession bonus for dental officers(a) Accession Bonus Authorized.—(1) A person who is a graduate of an accredited dental school and who, during the period beginning on September 23, 1996, and ending on December 31, 2018, executes a written agreement described in subsection (c) to accept a commission as an officer of the armed forces and remain on active duty for a period of not less than four years may, upon the acceptance of the agreement by the Secretary concerned, be paid an accession bonus in an amount determined by the Secretary concerned.

(2) The amount of an accession bonus under paragraph (1) may not exceed $200,000.


(b) Limitation on Eligibility for Bonus.—A person may not be paid a bonus under subsection (a) if—(1) the person, in exchange for an agreement to accept an appointment as an officer, received financial assistance from the Department of Defense to pursue a course of study in dentistry; or

(2) the Secretary concerned determines that the person is not qualified to become and remain certified and licensed as a dentist.


(c) Agreement.—The agreement referred to in subsection (a) shall provide that, consistent with the needs of the armed service concerned, the person executing the agreement will be assigned to duty, for the period of obligated service covered by the agreement, as an officer of the Dental Corps of the Army or the Navy or an officer of the Air Force designated as a dental officer.

(d) Repayment.—A person who, after signing an agreement under subsection (a), is not commissioned as an officer of the armed forces, does not become licensed as a dentist, or does not complete the period of active duty specified in the agreement shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.

(Added Pub. L. 104–201, div. A, title VI, § 615(c)(1), Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2545; amended Pub. L. 107–107, div. A, title VI, § 618, Dec. 28, 2001, 115 Stat. 1137; Pub. L. 107–314, div. A, title VI, § 612(f),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accession Bonus Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Eligibility for Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A person may not be paid a bonus under subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The agreement referred to in subsection (a) shall provide that, consistent with the needs of the armed service concerned, the person executing the agreement will be assigned to duty, for the period of obligated service covered by the agreement, as an officer of the Dental Corps of the Army or the Navy or an officer of the Air Force designated as a dental officer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_302h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A person who, after signing an agreement under subsection (a), is not commissioned as an officer of the armed forces, does not become licensed as a dentist, or does not complete the period of active duty specified in the agreement shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>