<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/305a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/305a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/305a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_305a"><akn:num>305a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: career sea pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 305a. Special pay: career sea pay(a) Availability of Special Pay.—A member of a uniformed service who is entitled to basic pay is also entitled, while on sea duty, to special pay at the applicable rate under subsection (b).

(b) Rates; Maximum.—The Secretary concerned shall prescribe the monthly rates for special pay applicable to members of each armed force under the Secretary’s jurisdiction. No monthly rate may exceed $750.

(c) Premium.—A member of a uniformed service entitled to career sea pay under this section who has served 36 consecutive months of sea duty is also entitled to a career sea pay premium for the thirty-seventh consecutive month and each subsequent consecutive month of sea duty served by such member. The monthly amount of the premium shall be prescribed by the Secretary concerned, but may not exceed $350.

(d) Regulations.—The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section for the armed force or armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. The entitlements under this section shall be subject to the regulations.

(e) Definition of Sea Duty.—(1) In this section, the term “sea duty” means duty performed by a member—(A) while permanently or temporarily assigned to a ship and—(i) while serving on a ship the primary mission of which is accomplished while under way;

(ii) while serving as a member of the off-crew of a two-crewed submarine;

(iii) while serving as a member of a tender-class ship (with the hull classification of submarine or destroyer); or

(iv) while serving as an off-cycle crewmember of a multi-crewed ship; or


(B) while permanently or temporarily assigned to a ship and while serving on a ship the primary mission of which is normally accomplished while in port, but only during a period that the ship is away from its homeport.


(2) The Secretary concerned may designate duty performed by a member while serving on a ship the primary mission of which is accomplished either while under way</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Special Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A member of a uniformed service who is entitled to basic pay is also entitled, while on sea duty, to special pay at the applicable rate under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates; Maximum.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary concerned shall prescribe the monthly rates for special pay applicable to members of each armed force under the Secretary’s jurisdiction. No monthly rate may exceed $750.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A member of a uniformed service entitled to career sea pay under this section who has served 36 consecutive months of sea duty is also entitled to a career sea pay premium for the thirty-seventh consecutive month and each subsequent consecutive month of sea duty served by such member. The monthly amount of the premium shall be prescribed by the Secretary concerned, but may not exceed $350.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary concerned shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section for the armed force or armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary. The entitlements under this section shall be subject to the regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Sea Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>