<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/308h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/308h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/308h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_308h"><akn:num>308h</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: bonus for reenlistment, enlistment, or voluntary extension of enlistment in elements of</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 308h. Special pay: bonus for reenlistment, enlistment, or voluntary extension of enlistment in elements of the Ready Reserve other than the Selected Reserve(a) Authority and Eligibility Requirements.—(1) The Secretary concerned may pay a bonus as provided in subsection (b) to an eligible person who reenlists, enlists, or voluntarily extends an enlistment in a reserve component of an armed force for assignment to an element (other than the Selected Reserve) of the Ready Reserve of that armed force if the reenlistment, enlistment, or extension is for a period of three years, or for a period of six years, beyond any other period the person is obligated to serve.

(2) A person is eligible for a bonus under this section if the person—(A) is or has been a member of an armed force;

(B) is qualified in a skill or specialty designated by the Secretary concerned as a critically short wartime skill or critically short wartime specialty; and

(C) has not failed to complete satisfactorily any original term of enlistment in the armed forces.


(3) For the purposes of this section, the Secretary concerned may designate a skill or specialty as a critically short wartime skill or critically short wartime specialty for an armed force under the jurisdiction of the Secretary if the Secretary determines that—(A) the skill or specialty is critical to meet wartime requirements of the armed force; and

(B) there is a critical shortage of personnel in that armed force who are qualified in that skill or specialty.


(4) The Secretary concerned may waive the eligibility requirement in paragraph (2)(B) in the case of a reenlistment or voluntary extension of enlistment by a member of the armed forces that is entered into as described in this subsection while the member is serving on active duty in Afghanistan, Iraq, or Kuwait in support of Operation Enduring Freedom and Operation Iraqi Freedom.


(b) Bonus Amounts; Payment.—(1) Eligibility for and the amount and method of payment of a bonus </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_308h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and Eligibility Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_308h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonus Amounts; Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_308h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) A person who does not complete the period of enlistment or extension of enlistment for which the bonus was paid under this section shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_308h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_308h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A bonus may not be paid under this section to any person for a reenlistment, enlistment, or voluntary extension of an enlistment after December 31, 2018.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>