<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/310" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/310/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/310/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_310"><akn:num>310</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: duty subject to hostile fire or imminent danger</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 310. Special pay: duty subject to hostile fire or imminent danger(a) Eligibility.—Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member of a uniformed service may be paid special pay under subsection (b) for any day or portion of a day in which—(1) the member was entitled to basic pay or compensation under section 204 or 206 of this title; and

(2) the member—(A) was subject to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines;

(B) was on duty in an area in which the member was in imminent danger of being exposed to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines and in which, during the period the member was on duty in the area, other members of the uniformed services were subject to hostile fire or explosion of hostile mines;

(C) was killed, injured, or wounded by hostile fire, explosion of a hostile mine, or any other hostile action; or

(D) was on duty in a foreign area in which the member was subject to the threat of physical harm or imminent danger on the basis of civil insurrection, civil war, terrorism, or wartime conditions.



(b) Special Pay Amount.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amount of special pay authorized by subsection (a) for qualifying service during a day or portion of a day shall be the amount equal to 1/30th of the maximum monthly amount of special pay payable to a member as specified in paragraph (3).

(2) In the case of a member who is exposed to hostile fire or a hostile mine explosion event in or for a day or portion of a day, the Secretary concerned may, at the election of the Secretary, pay the member special pay under subsection (a) for such service in an amount not to exceed the maximum monthly amount of special pay payable to a member as specified in paragraph (3).

(3) The maximum monthly amount of special pay payable to a member under this subsection for any month is $225.


(c) Continuation During Hospitalization.—(1) A member described in paragraph (2) may be paid special pay under this section for any day (or p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_310_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, a member of a uniformed service may be paid special pay under subsection (b) for any day or portion of a day in which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_310_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Pay Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_310_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation During Hospitalization.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_310_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and Administration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_310_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Fact.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any determination of fact that is made in administering this section is conclusive. Such a determination may not be reviewed by any other officer or agency of the United States unless there has been fraud or gross negligence. However, the determination may be changed on the basis of new evidence or for other good cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>