<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/316" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/316/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/316/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_316"><akn:num>316</akn:num><akn:heading>Special pay: bonus for members with foreign language proficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 316. Special pay: bonus for members with foreign language proficiency(a) Availability of Bonus.—Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary concerned may pay a bonus under this section to a member of the uniformed services who—(1) is qualified in a uniformed services specialty requiring proficiency in a foreign language identified by the Secretary concerned as a foreign language in which it is necessary to have personnel proficient because of national defense or public health considerations;

(2) received training, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary concerned, designed to develop a proficiency in such a foreign language;

(3) is assigned to duties requiring a proficiency in such a foreign language; or

(4) is proficient in a foreign language for which the uniformed service may have a critical need, as determined by the Secretary concerned.


(b) Bonus Amount; Time for Payment.—A bonus under subsection (a) may not exceed $12,000 per one-year certification period under subsection (c). The Secretary concerned may pay the bonus in a single lump sum at the beginning of the certification period or in installments during the certification period. The bonus is in addition to any other pay or allowance payable to a member under any other provision of law.

(c) Certification of Proficiency.—To be eligible to receive a bonus under this section, a member described in subsection (a) must be certified by the Secretary concerned as being proficient in the foreign language for which the bonus is offered. The certification of the member shall expire at the end of the one-year period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning on or after the certification date.

(d) Certification Interrupted by Contingency Operation.—(1) Notwithstanding subsection (c), the Secretary concerned may waive the certification requirement under such subsection and pay a bonus under this section to a member who—(A) is assigned to duty in connection with a contingency operation;

(B) is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subject to subsection (c), the Secretary concerned may pay a bonus under this section to a member of the uniformed services who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bonus Amount; Time for Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A bonus under subsection (a) may not exceed $12,000 per one-year certification period under subsection (c). The Secretary concerned may pay the bonus in a single lump sum at the beginning of the certification period or in installments during the certification period. The bonus is in addition to any other pay or allowance payable to a member under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of Proficiency.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To be eligible to receive a bonus under this section, a member described in subsection (a) must be certified by the Secretary concerned as being proficient in the foreign language for which the bonus is offered. The certification of the member shall expire at the end of the one-year period beginning on the first day of the first month beginning on or after the certification date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification Interrupted by Contingency Operation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A member who receives a bonus under this section, but who does not satisfy an eligibility requirement specified in paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4) of subsection (a) for the entire certification period, shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_316_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) This section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense for the armed forces under the jurisdiction of the Secretary, by the Secretary of Homeland Security for the Coast Guard when the Coast Guard is not operating as a service in the Navy, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services for the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service, and by the Secretary of Commerce for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>