<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/326" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/326/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/326/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_326"><akn:num>326</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentive bonus: conversion to military occupational specialty to ease personnel shortage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 326. Incentive bonus: conversion to military occupational specialty to ease personnel shortage(a) Incentive Bonus Authorized.—The Secretary concerned may pay a bonus under this section to an eligible member of a regular or reserve component of the armed forces who executes a written agreement to convert to, and serve for a period of not less than three years in, a military occupational specialty for which there is a shortage of trained and qualified personnel.

(b) Eligible Members.—A member is eligible to enter into an agreement under subsection (a) if, at the time the agreement is executed, the member is serving in—(1) pay grade E–6, with not more than 10 years of service computed under section 205 of this title; or

(2) pay grade E–5 or below, regardless of years of service.


(c) Amount and Payment of Bonus.—(1) A bonus under this section may not exceed $4,000.

(2) A bonus payable under this section shall be disbursed in one lump sum when the member’s conversion to the military occupational specialty is approved by the chief personnel officer of the regular or reserve component of the member’s armed force.


(d) Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances.—A bonus paid to a member under this section is in addition to any other pay and allowances to which the member is entitled.

(e) Repayment.—A member who does not convert to and complete the period of service in the military occupational specialty specified in the agreement executed under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.

(f) Regulations.—The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense.

(g) Termination of Authority.—No agreement under this section may be entered into after December 31, 2018.

(Added Pub. L. 108–136, div. A, title VI, § 625(a), Nov. 24, 2003, 117 Stat. 1506; amended Pub. L. 108–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentive Bonus Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may pay a bonus under this section to an eligible member of a regular or reserve component of the armed forces who executes a written agreement to convert to, and serve for a period of not less than three years in, a military occupational specialty for which there is a shortage of trained and qualified personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A member is eligible to enter into an agreement under subsection (a) if, at the time the agreement is executed, the member is serving in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and Payment of Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) A bonus paid to a member under this section is in addition to any other pay and allowances to which the member is entitled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) A member who does not convert to and complete the period of service in the military occupational specialty specified in the agreement executed under subsection (a) shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The Secretaries concerned shall prescribe regulations to carry out this section. Regulations prescribed by the Secretary of a military department shall be subject to the approval of the Secretary of Defense.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_326_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No agreement under this section may be entered into after December 31, 2018.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>