<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/333" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/333/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/333/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_333"><akn:num>333</akn:num><akn:heading>Special bonus and incentive pay authorities for nuclear officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 333. Special bonus and incentive pay authorities for nuclear officers(a) Nuclear Officer Bonus.—The Secretary of the Navy may pay a nuclear officer bonus under this section to a person, including an officer in the Navy, who—(1) is selected for the officer naval nuclear power training program in connection with the supervision, operation, and maintenance of naval nuclear propulsion plants and agrees to serve, upon completion of such training, on active duty in connection with the supervision, operation, and maintenance of naval nuclear propulsion plants; or

(2) has the current technical qualification for duty in connection with the supervision, operation, and maintenance of naval nuclear propulsion plants and agrees to remain on active duty in connection with the supervision, operation, and maintenance of naval nuclear propulsion plants.


(b) Nuclear Officer Incentive Pay.—The Secretary of the Navy may pay nuclear officer incentive pay under this section to an officer in the Navy who—(1) is entitled to basic pay under section 204 of this title; and

(2) remains on active duty for a specified period while maintaining current technical qualifications, as approved by the Secretary, for duty in connection with the supervision, operation, and maintenance of naval nuclear propulsion plants.


(c) Additional Eligibility Criteria.—The Secretary of the Navy may impose such additional criteria for the receipt of a nuclear officer bonus or nuclear officer incentive pay under this section as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.

(d) Maximum Amount and Method of Payment.—(1) Maximum amount.—The Secretary of the Navy shall determine the amounts of a nuclear officer bonus or nuclear officer incentive pay to be paid under this section, except that—(A) a nuclear officer bonus paid under subsection (a) may not exceed $75,000 for each 12-month period of the agreement under subsection (e); and

(B) the amount of nuclear officer incentive paid under subsection (b) may not exce</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Officer Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of the Navy may pay a nuclear officer bonus under this section to a person, including an officer in the Navy, who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Officer Incentive Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Navy may pay nuclear officer incentive pay under this section to an officer in the Navy who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Eligibility Criteria.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of the Navy may impose such additional criteria for the receipt of a nuclear officer bonus or nuclear officer incentive pay under this section as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Amount and Method of Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Written Agreement for Bonus.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A nuclear officer bonus or nuclear officer incentive pay paid to a person or officer under this section is in addition to any other pay and allowance to which the person or officer is entitled, except that a person or officer may not receive a payment under this section and section 332 or 353 of this title for the same skill and period of service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) A person or officer who receives a nuclear officer bonus or nuclear officer incentive pay under this section and who fails to complete the officer naval nuclear power training program, maintain required technical and operational qualifications, complete the period of service, or meet the types or conditions of service for which the bonus or incentive pay is paid, as specified in the written agreement under subsection (e) in the case of a nuclear officer bonus, shall be subject to the repayment provisions of section 373 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) This section shall be administered under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Navy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_333_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No agreement may be entered into under this section after December 31, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>