<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_351"><akn:num>351</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous duty pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 351. Hazardous duty pay(a) Hazardous Duty Pay.—The Secretary concerned may pay hazardous duty pay under this section to a member of a regular or reserve component of the uniformed services entitled to basic pay under section 204 of this title or compensation under section 206 of this title who—(1) performs duty in a hostile fire area designated by the Secretary concerned, is exposed to a hostile fire event, explosion of a hostile explosive device, or any other hostile action, or is on duty during a month in an area in which a hostile event occurred which placed the member in grave danger of physical injury;

(2) performs duty designated by the Secretary concerned as hazardous duty based upon the inherent dangers of that duty and risks of physical injury; or

(3) performs duty in a foreign area designated by the Secretary concerned as an area in which the member is subject to imminent danger of physical injury due to threat conditions.


(b) Maximum Amount.—The amount of hazardous duty pay paid to a member under subsection (a) shall be based on the type of duty and the area in which the duty is performed, as follows:(1) In the case of a member who performs duty in a designated hostile fire area, as described in subsection (a)(1), hazardous duty pay may not exceed $450 per month.

(2) In the case of a member who performs a designated hazardous duty, as described in subsection (a)(2), hazardous duty pay may not exceed $275 per month.

(3) In the case of a member who performs duty in a foreign area designated as an imminent danger area, as described in subsection (a)(3), hazardous duty pay may not exceed $275 per month.


(c) Method of Payment; Proration.—(1) Monthly payment.—Subject to paragraph (2), hazardous duty pay shall be paid on a monthly basis.

(2) Proration.—If a member does not satisfy the eligibility requirements specified in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) for an entire month for receipt of hazardous duty pay—(A) in the case of hazardous dut</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous Duty Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned may pay hazardous duty pay under this section to a member of a regular or reserve component of the uniformed services entitled to basic pay under section 204 of this title or compensation under section 206 of this title who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Amount.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The amount of hazardous duty pay paid to a member under subsection (a) shall be based on the type of duty and the area in which the duty is performed, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of Payment; Proration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and Retroactive Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The effective date for the designation of a hostile fire area, as described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a), and for the designation of a foreign area as an imminent danger area, as described in paragraph (3) of such subsection, may be a date that occurs before, on, or after the actual date of the designation by the Secretary concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Fact.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Any determination of fact that is made in connection with determining whether a triggering event has occurred for the provision of hazardous duty pay under subsection (a)(1) is conclusive. The determination may not be reviewed by any other officer or agency of the United States unless there has been fraud or gross negligence. However, the Secretary concerned may change the determination on the basis of new evidence or for other good cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to Other Pay and Allowances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on Variable Rates.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The regulations prescribed to administer this section may not include varied criteria or rates for payment of hazardous duty for officers and enlisted members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No hazardous duty pay under this section may be paid after December 31, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>