<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_402a"><akn:num>402a</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental subsistence allowance for low-income members with dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 402a. Supplemental subsistence allowance for low-income members with dependents(a) Supplemental Allowance Required.—(1) The Secretary concerned shall increase the basic allowance for subsistence to which a member of the armed forces described in subsection (b) is otherwise entitled under section 402 of this title by an amount (in this section referred to as the “supplemental subsistence allowance”) designed to remove the member’s household from eligibility for benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.

(2) The supplemental subsistence allowance may not exceed $1,100 per month. In establishing the amount of the supplemental subsistence allowance to be paid an eligible member under this paragraph, the Secretary shall take into consideration the amount of the basic allowance for housing that the member receives under section 403 of this title or would otherwise receive under such section, in the case of a member who is not entitled to that allowance as a result of assignment to quarters of the United States or a housing facility under the jurisdiction of a uniformed service.

(3) In the case of a member described in subsection (b) who establishes to the satisfaction of the Secretary concerned that the allotment of the member’s household under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, calculated in the absence of the supplemental subsistence allowance, would exceed the amount established by the Secretary concerned under paragraph (2), the amount of the supplemental subsistence allowance for the member shall be equal to the lesser of the following:(A) The value of that allotment.

(B) $1,100.



(b) Members Entitled to Allowance.—(1) Subject to subsection (d) and paragraph (4), a member of the armed forces with dependents is entitled to receive the supplemental subsistence allowance if the Secretary concerned determines that the member’s income, together with the income of the rest of the member’s household (if any), is within the highest incom</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Allowance Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members Entitled to Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To request the supplemental subsistence allowance, a member shall submit an application to the Secretary concerned in such form and containing such information as the Secretary concerned may prescribe. A member applying for the supplemental subsistence allowance shall furnish such evidence regarding the member’s satisfaction of the eligibility criteria under subsection (b) as the Secretary concerned may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The entitlement of a member to receive the supplemental subsistence allowance terminates upon the occurrence of any of the following events, even though the member continues to meet the eligibility criteria described in subsection (b):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reapplication.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Upon the termination of the effective period of the supplemental subsistence allowance for a member, or in anticipation of the imminent termination of the allowance, a member may reapply for the allowance under subsection (c), and the Secretary concerned shall approve the application and resume payment of the allowance to the member, if the member continues to meet, or once again meets, the eligibility criteria described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for Other Federal Assistance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>