<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/402b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_402b"><akn:num>402b</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic needs allowance for members on active service in the Armed Forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 402b. Basic needs allowance for members on active service in the Armed Forces(a) Allowance Required.—The Secretary concerned shall pay to each member who is eligible under subsection (b) a basic needs allowance in the amount determined for such member under subsection (c).

(b) Eligible Members.—A member on active service in the armed forces is eligible for the allowance under subsection (a) if—(1) the member has completed initial entry training;

(2) the gross household income of the member during the most recent calendar year did not exceed an amount equal to 200 percent of the Federal poverty guidelines of the Department of Health and Human Services for the location of the member and the number of individuals in the household of the member for such year; and

(3) the member—(A) is not ineligible for the allowance under subsection (d); and

(B) does not elect under subsection (g) not to receive the allowance.



(c) Amount of Allowance.—The amount of the monthly allowance payable to a member under subsection (a) shall be the amount equal to—(1)(A) 200 percent of the Federal poverty guidelines of the Department of Health and Human Services for the calendar year during which the allowance is paid based on the location of the member and the number of individuals in the household of the member during the month for which the allowance is paid; minus

(B) the gross household income of the member during the preceding calendar year; divided by


(2) 12.


(d) Bases of Ineligibility.—(1) In general.—The following members are ineligible for the allowance under subsection (a):(A) A member who does not have any dependents.

(B) A cadet at the United States Military Academy, the United States Air Force Academy, or the Coast Guard Academy, a midshipman at the United States Naval Academy, or a cadet or midshipman serving elsewhere in the armed forces.


(2) Household with more than one eligible member.—In the event a household contains two or more members determined under subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance Required.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary concerned shall pay to each member who is eligible under subsection (b) a basic needs allowance in the amount determined for such member under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) A member on active service in the armed forces is eligible for the allowance under subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The amount of the monthly allowance payable to a member under subsection (a) shall be the amount equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bases of Ineligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application by Members Seeking Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election Not to Receive Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule for Members Stationed Outside United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) In the case of a member assigned to a duty location outside the United States, the Secretary concerned shall make the calculations described in subsections (b)(2) and (c)(1) using the Federal poverty guidelines of the Department of Health and Human Services for the continental United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022, the Secretary of Defense shall prescribe regulations for the administration of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_402b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Period.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>