<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_403"><akn:num>403</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic allowance for housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 403. Basic allowance for housing(a) General Entitlement.—(1) Except as otherwise provided by law, a member of a uniformed service who is entitled to basic pay is entitled to a basic allowance for housing at the monthly rates prescribed under this section or another provision of law with regard to the applicable component of the basic allowance for housing. The amount of the basic allowance for housing for a member will vary according to the pay grade in which the member is assigned or distributed for basic pay purposes, the dependency status of the member, and the geographic location of the member. The basic allowance for housing may be paid in advance.

(2) A member of a uniformed service with dependents is not entitled to a basic allowance for housing as a member with dependents unless the member makes a certification to the Secretary concerned indicating the status of each dependent of the member. The certification shall be made in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Defense.


(b) Basic Allowance for Housing Inside the United States.—(1) The Secretary of Defense shall prescribe the rates of the basic allowance for housing that are applicable for the various military housing areas in the United States. The rates for an area shall be based on the costs of adequate housing determined for the area under paragraph (2).

(2) The Secretary of Defense shall determine the costs of adequate housing in a military housing area in the United States for all members of the uniformed services entitled to a basic allowance for housing in that area. The Secretary shall base the determination upon the costs of adequate housing for civilians with comparable income levels in the same area. After June 30, 2001, the Secretary may not differentiate between members with dependents in pay grades E–1 through E–4 in determining what constitutes adequate housing for members.

(3)(A) The monthly amount of the basic allowance for housing for an area of the United Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Entitlement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic Allowance for Housing Inside the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic Allowance for Housing Outside the United States.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic Allowance for Housing When Dependents Do Not Accompany Member.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Assignment to Quarters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility During Initial Field Duty or Sea Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental of Public Quarters.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notwithstanding any other law (including those restricting the occupancy of housing facilities under the jurisdiction of a department or agency of the United States by members, and their dependents, of the armed forces above specified grades, or by members, and their dependents, of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Public Health Service), a member of a uniformed service, and the dependents of the member, may be accepted as tenants in, and may occupy on a rental basis, any of those housing facilities, other than public quarters constructed or designated for assignment to an occupancy without charge by such a member and the dependents of the member, if any. Such a member may not, because of occupancy under this subsection, be deprived of any money allowance to which the member is otherwise entitled for the rental of quarters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary Housing Allowance While in Travel or Leave Status.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) A member of a uniformed service is entitled to a temporary basic allowance for housing (at a rate determined by the Secretary of Defense) while the member is in a travel or leave status between permanent duty stations, including time granted as delay en route or proceed time, when the member is not assigned to quarters of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_403_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aviation Cadets.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) The eligibility of an aviation cadet of the Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard for a basic allowance for housing shall be determined as if the aviation cadet were a member of the uniformed services in pay grade E–4.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>