<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/427" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/427/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/427/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_427"><akn:num>427</akn:num><akn:heading>Family separation allowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 427. Family separation allowance(a) Entitlement to Allowance.—(1) In addition to any allowance or per diem to which he otherwise may be entitled under this title a member of a uniformed service with dependents is entitled to a monthly allowance of not less than $250, and not more than $400, if—(A) the movement of his dependents to his permanent station or a place near that station is not authorized at the expense of the United States under section 452 of this title and his dependents do not reside at or near that station;

(B) he is on duty on board a ship away from the home port of the ship (or under orders to remain on board the ship while at the home port) for a continuous period of more than 30 days; or

(C) he is on temporary duty away from his permanent station for a continuous period of more than 30 days and his dependents do not reside at or near his temporary duty station.


(2) A member who becomes entitled to an allowance under this subsection by virtue of duty prescribed in subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (1) for a continuous period of more than 30 days is entitled to the allowance effective as of the earlier of—(A) the first day of that period; or

(B) the first day the member ceased being entitled to a previous allowance under this subsection by reason of the end of duty prescribed in such subparagraphs, if the member ceased being entitled to the previous allowance within 30 days before the first day of that period.



(b) Entitlement When No Residence or Household Maintained for Dependents.—An allowance is payable under subsection (a) even though the member does not maintain for his primary dependents who would otherwise normally reside with him, a residence or household, subject to his management and control, which he is likely to share with them as a common household when his duty assignment permits.

(c) Effect of Election to Serve Unaccompanied Tour of Duty.—(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2) or (3), a member who elects to serve a tour</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to Allowance.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement When No Residence or Household Maintained for Dependents.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An allowance is payable under subsection (a) even though the member does not maintain for his primary dependents who would otherwise normally reside with him, a residence or household, subject to his management and control, which he is likely to share with them as a common household when his duty assignment permits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of Election to Serve Unaccompanied Tour of Duty.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_427_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement While Spouse Entitled to Basic Pay.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>