<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/433a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/433a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/433a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_433a"><akn:num>433a</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance for participation in Ready Reserve screening</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 433a. Allowance for participation in Ready Reserve screening(a) Allowance Authorized.—(1) Under regulations prescribed by the Secretaries concerned, a member of the Individual Ready Reserve may be paid a stipend for participation in the screening performed pursuant to section 10149 of title 10, in lieu of muster duty performed under section 12319 of title 10, if such participation is conducted through electronic means.

(2) The stipend paid a member under this section shall constitute the sole monetary allowance authorized for participation in the screening described in paragraph (1), and shall constitute payment in full to the member for participation in such screening, regardless of the grade or rank in which the member is serving.


(b) Maximum Payment.—The aggregate amount of the stipend paid a member of the Individual Ready Reserve under this section in any calendar year may not exceed $50.

(c) Payment Requirements.—(1) The stipend authorized by this section may not be disbursed in kind.

(2) Payment of a stipend to a member of the Individual Ready Reserve under this section for participation in screening shall be made on or after the date of participation in such screening, but not later than 30 days after such date.


(Added Pub. L. 110–181, div. A, title VI, § 633(a)(1), Jan. 28, 2008, 122 Stat. 154.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_433a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowance Authorized.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_433a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum Payment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The aggregate amount of the stipend paid a member of the Individual Ready Reserve under this section in any calendar year may not exceed $50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_433a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>