<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/453" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/453/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/453/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_453"><akn:num>453</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable travel and transportation: specific authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 453. Allowable travel and transportation: specific authorities(a) In General.—In addition to any other authority for the provision of travel and transportation allowances, the administering Secretaries may provide travel and transportation allowances under this subchapter in accordance with this section.

(b) Authorized Absence From Temporary Duty Location.—An authorized traveler may be paid travel and transportation allowances, or reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses of travel, incurred at a temporary duty location during an authorized absence from that location.

(c) Movement of Personal Property.—(1) A member of a uniformed service may be allowed moving expenses and transportation allowances for self and dependents associated with the movement of personal property and household goods, including such expenses when associated with a self-move.

(2) The authority in paragraph (1) includes the movement and temporary and non-temporary storage of personal property, household goods, and privately owned vehicles in connection with the temporary or permanent move between authorized locations.

(3) For movement of household goods, the administering Secretaries shall prescribe weight allowances in regulations under section 464 of this title. The prescribed weight allowances may not exceed 18,000 pounds (including household goods in temporary storage, but excluding packing and crating), except that the administering Secretary may, on a case-by-case basis, authorize additional weight allowances as necessary.

(4) The administering Secretary may prescribe the terms, rates, and conditions that authorize a member of the uniformed services to ship or store privately owned vehicles.

(5) No carrier, port agent, warehouseman, freight forwarder, or other person involved in the transportation of property may have any lien on, or hold, impound, or otherwise interfere with, the movement of baggage and household goods being transported under this section.


(d) Unusual or Emer</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In addition to any other authority for the provision of travel and transportation allowances, the administering Secretaries may provide travel and transportation allowances under this subchapter in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized Absence From Temporary Duty Location.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An authorized traveler may be paid travel and transportation allowances, or reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses of travel, incurred at a temporary duty location during an authorized absence from that location.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Movement of Personal Property.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unusual or Emergency Circumstances.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) An authorized traveler may be provided travel and transportation allowances under this section for unusual, extraordinary, hardship, or emergency circumstances, including circumstances warranting evacuation from a permanent duty assignment location.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Particular Separation Provisions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The administering Secretary may provide travel-in-kind and transportation-in-kind for the following persons in accordance with regulations prescribed under section 464 of this title:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance at Memorial Ceremonies and Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) A family member or member of the uniformed services who attends a deceased member’s repatriation, burial, or memorial ceremony or service may be provided travel and transportation allowances to the extent provided in regulations prescribed under section 464 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Qualifying Spouse Relicensing Costs and Business Costs.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for Transportation of Pets Arising From Certain Permanent Changes of Stations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_453_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attendance at Professional Military Education Institution or Training Classes.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>