<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_501"><akn:num>501</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments for unused accrued leave</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 501. Payments for unused accrued leave(a) In this section, the term “discharge” means—(1) in the case of an enlisted member, separation or release from active duty under honorable conditions, termination of an enlistment in conjunction with the commencement of a successive enlistment (without regard to the date of the expiration of the term of the enlistment being terminated), or appointment as an officer;

(2) in the case of an officer, separation or release from active duty under honorable conditions;

(3) in the case of either an officer or an enlisted member, death while on active duty unless the decedent was put to death as lawful punishment for a crime or a military offense;

(4) in the case of an officer or an enlisted member of a reserve component who is not serving on active duty, separation or release from the reserve component under honorable conditions, or death; and

(5) in the case of an enlisted member of a reserve component who is not serving on active duty, termination of enlistment in conjunction with the commencement of a successive enlistment, or appointment as an officer.


(b)(1) A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, Coast Guard, or National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, who has accrued leave to the member’s credit at the time of the member’s discharge, is entitled to be paid in cash or by a check on the Treasurer of the United States for such leave on the basis of the basic pay to which the member was entitled on the date of discharge.

(2) Payment may not be made under this subsection to a member who is discharged for the purpose of accepting an appointment or a warrant in any uniformed service.

(3) Payment may not be made to a member for any leave he elects to have carried over to a new enlistment in any uniformed service on the day after the date of his discharge; but payment may be made to a member for any leave he elects not to carry over to a new enlistment. However, the number of days of leave fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In this section, the term “discharge” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unused accrued leave for which payment is made under subsection (b) is not considered as service for any purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The number of days upon which payment under subsection (b) or (g) is based may not exceed sixty, less the number of days for which payment has been previously made under such subsections after February 9, 1976. For the purposes of this subsection, the number of days upon which payment may be based shall be determined without regard to any break in service or change in status in the uniformed services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) An officer of the Regular Corps of the Public Health Service, or an officer of the Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Public Health Service on active duty, who is credited with accumulated and accrued annual leave on the date of his separation, retirement, or release from active duty, shall, if his application for that leave is approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, be paid for that leave in a lump-sum on the basis of his basic pay, subsistence allowance, and allowance for quarters whether or not he is receiving that allowance on that date. However, the number of days upon which the lump-sum payment is based is subject to subsection (f). A lump-sum payment may not be made under this subsection to an officer— In this subsection, the term “accumulated annual leave” means unused accrued annual leave carried forward from one leave year into the next leave year, and the term “accrued annual leave” means the annual leave accruing to an officer during </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_501_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Payment shall be made for all leave accumulated under section 701(f) of title 10 as soon as possible after the name of the person concerned is removed from a missing status, as defined in section 551(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>