<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/37/906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_906"><akn:num>906</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of enlistment: effect on pay and allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 906. Extension of enlistment: effect on pay and allowances
A member of the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, Space Force, or Coast Guard, as the case may be, who extends his enlistment under section 509 of title 10 is entitled to the same pay and allowances as though he had reenlisted. For the purposes of determining entitlement to reenlistment bonus or to travel and transportation allowances upon discharge, all such extensions of an enlistment are considered one continuous extension.
(Pub. L. 87–649, Sept. 7, 1962, 76 Stat. 489; Pub. L. 90–235, § 2(c), Jan. 2, 1968, 81 Stat. 757; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 925(j), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3829.)











Historical and Revision Notes


Revised sectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


906(a)10:3263(b).[None.]
 10:8263(b).[None.]
906(b)10:5539(b).[None.]


In subsection (a), the words “who extends his enlistment” are substituted for the words “While serving under an enlistment extended”. The words “same pay and allowances as though he had reenlisted” are substituted for the last 31 words of section 3263(b) of title 10 and the last 31 words of section 8263(b) of title 10.

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 116–283 inserted “Space Force,” after “Marine Corps,”.
1968—Pub. L. 90–235 struck out provisions formerly set out as subsec. (a) which provided that a member of the Army or Air Force who had extended his enlistment was entitled to the same pay as though he had reenlisted, redesignated as entire section provisions formerly set out as subsec. (b) and substituted “Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, or Coast Guard” for “Regular Navy or the Regular Marine Corps” and “section 509 of title 10” for “section 5539 of title 10”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of authorities, functions, personnel, and assets of the Coast Guard, including the authorities and functions of the Secretary of Transportation relating thereto, to the Department of Homela</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>