<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1003"><akn:num>1003</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1003. Leasing procedures(a) NominationsThe Secretary shall accept nominations of land to be leased at any time from qualified companies and individuals under this chapter.


(b) Competitive lease sale required(1) In generalExcept as otherwise specifically provided by this chapter, all land to be leased that is not subject to leasing under subsection (c) shall be leased as provided in this subsection to the highest responsible qualified bidder, as determined by the Secretary.


(2) Competitive lease salesThe Secretary shall hold a competitive lease sale at least once every 2 years for land in a State that has nominations pending under subsection (a) if the land is otherwise available for leasing.


(3) Lands subject to mining claimsLands that are subject to a mining claim for which a plan of operations has been approved by the relevant Federal land management agency may be available for noncompetitive leasing under this section to the mining claim holder.


(4) Land subject to oil and gas leaseLand under an oil and gas lease issued pursuant to the Mineral Leasing Act (30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.) or the Mineral Leasing Act for Acquired Lands (30 U.S.C. 351 et seq.) that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring may be available for noncompetitive leasing under subsection (c) by the holder of the oil and gas lease—(A) on a determination that geothermal energy will be produced from a well producing or capable of producing oil and gas; and

(B) to provide for the coproduction of geothermal energy with oil and gas.



(c) Noncompetitive leasingThe Secretary shall make available for a period of 2 years for noncompetitive leasing any tract for which a competitive lease sale is held, but for which the Secretary does not receive any bids in a competitive lease sale.


(d) Pending lease applications(1) In generalIt shall be a priority for the Secretary, and for the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to National</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nominations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nominations The Secretary shall accept nominations of land to be leased at any time from qualified companies and individuals under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive lease sale required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Competitive lease sale required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompetitive leasing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Noncompetitive leasing The Secretary shall make available for a period of 2 years for noncompetitive leasing any tract for which a competitive lease sale is held, but for which the Secretary does not receive any bids in a competitive lease sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending lease applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pending lease applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leases sold as a block</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Leases sold as a block If information is available to the Secretary indicating a geothermal resource that could be produced as 1 unit can reasonably be expected to underlie more than 1 parcel to be offered in a competitive lease sale, the parcels for such a resource may be offered for bidding as a block in the competitive lease sale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing for direct use of geothermal resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Leasing for direct use of geothermal resources Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may identify areas in which the land to be leased under this chapter exclusively for direct use of geothermal resources, without sale for purposes other than commercial generation of electricity, may be leased to any qualified applicant that first applies for such a lease under regulations issued by the Secretary, if the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area subject to lease for direct use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Area subject to lease for direct use</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>