<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1005"><akn:num>1005</akn:num><akn:heading>Lease term and work commitment requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1005. Lease term and work commitment requirements(a) In general(1) Primary termA geothermal lease shall be for a primary term of 10 years.


(2) Initial extensionThe Secretary shall extend the primary term of a geothermal lease for 5 years if, for each year after the 10th year of the lease—(A) the Secretary determined under subsection (b) that the lessee satisfied the work commitment requirements that applied to the lease for that year; or

(B) the lessee paid in annual payments accordance with subsection (c).


(3) Additional extensionThe Secretary shall extend the primary term of a geothermal lease (after an initial extension under paragraph (2)) for an additional 5 years if, for each year of the initial extension under paragraph (2), the Secretary determined under subsection (b) that the lessee satisfied the minimum work requirements that applied to the lease for that year.



(b) Requirement to satisfy annual minimum work requirement(1) In generalThe lessee for a geothermal lease shall, for each year after the 10th year of the lease, satisfy minimum work requirements prescribed by the Secretary that apply to the lease for that year.


(2) Prescription of minimum work requirementsThe Secretary shall issue regulations prescribing minimum work requirements for geothermal leases, that—(A) establish a geothermal potential; and

(B) if a geothermal potential has been established, confirm the existence of producible geothermal resources.



(c) Payments in lieu of minimum work requirementsIn lieu of the minimum work requirements set forth in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall by regulation establish minimum annual payments which may be made by the lessee for a limited number of years that the Secretary determines will not impair achieving diligent development of the geothermal resource, but in no event shall the number of years exceed the duration of the extension period provided in subsection (a).


(d) Transition rules for leases issued prior to August 8, 2005T</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to satisfy annual minimum work requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement to satisfy annual minimum work requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in lieu of minimum work requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments in lieu of minimum work requirements In lieu of the minimum work requirements set forth in subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall by regulation establish minimum annual payments which may be made by the lessee for a limited number of years that the Secretary determines will not impair achieving diligent development of the geothermal resource, but in no event shall the number of years exceed the duration of the extension period provided in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition rules for leases issued prior to August 8, 2005</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transition rules for leases issued prior to The Secretary shall by regulation establish transition rules for leases issued before August 8, 2005, including terms under which a lease that is near the end of its term on August 8, 2005, may be extended for up to 2 years—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geothermal lease overlying mining claim</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Geothermal lease overlying mining claim</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of application of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination of application of requirements Minimum work requirements prescribed under this section shall not apply to a geothermal lease after the date on which the geothermal resource is utilized under the lease in commercial quantities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative or unit plan for drilling operations; extension of term; renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cooperative or unit plan for drilling operations; extension of term; renewal Any lease for land on which, or for which under an approved cooperative or unit plan of development or operation, actual drilling operations were commenced prior to the end of its primary term and are being diligently prosecuted at that time shall be extended for five years and so long thereafter, but not more than thirty-five years, as geothermal steam is produced or utilized in commercial quantities. If, at the end of such extended term, steam is being produced or utilized in commercial quantities and the lands are not needed for other purposes, the lessee shall have a preferential right to a renewal of such lease for a second term in accordance with such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Produced or utilized in commercial quantities” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Produced or utilized in commercial quantities” defined Except as otherwise provided for in this section, for purposes of this section the term “produced or utilized in commercial quantities” means the completion of a well producing geothermal steam in commercial quantities. Such term shall also include the completion of a well capable of producing geothermal steam in commercial quantities so long as the Secretary determines that diligent efforts are being made toward the utilization of the geothermal steam.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1005_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles for location of minerals under mining laws when minerals are not associated with geothermal resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Principles for location of minerals under mining laws when minerals are not associated with geothermal resources Minerals locatable under the mining laws of the United States in lands subject to a geothermal lease issued under the provisions of this chapter which are not associated with the geothermal resources of such lands as defined in section 1001(c) of this title shall be locatable under said mining laws in accordance with the principles of the Multiple Mineral Development Act (68 Stat. 708; found in 30 U.S.C. 521 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>