<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1006"><akn:num>1006</akn:num><akn:heading>Acreage limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1006. Acreage limitations
A geothermal lease shall embrace a reasonably compact area of not more than 5,120 acres, except where a departure therefrom is occasioned by an irregular subdivision or subdivisions. No person, association, or corporation, except as otherwise provided in this chapter, shall take, hold, own, or control at one time, whether acquired directly from the Secretary under this chapter or otherwise, any direct or indirect interest in Federal geothermal leases in any one State exceeding 51,200 acres, including leases acquired under the provisions of section 1003 of this title.
(Pub. L. 91–581, § 7, Dec. 24, 1970, 84 Stat. 1569; Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 235, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 671.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2005—Pub. L. 109–58 inserted section catchline, substituted “5,120 acres” for “two thousand five hundred and sixty acres” and “51,200 acres” for “twenty thousand four hundred and eighty acres” in text, and struck out second par. which read as follows: “At any time after fifteen years from December 24, 1970, the Secretary, after public hearings, may increase this maximum holding in any one State by regulation, not to exceed fifty-one thousand two hundred acres.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>