<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1211"><akn:num>1211</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1211. Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department of the Interior, the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”).


(b) Appointment, compensation, duties, etc., of Director; employeesThe Office shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be compensated at the rate provided for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 11 So in original. Probably should be section “5316”. of title 5, and such other employees as may be required. Pursuant to section 5108 of title 5, and after consultation with the Secretary, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall determine the necessary number of positions in general schedule employees in grade 16, 17, and 18 to perform functions of this subchapter and shall allocate such positions to the Secretary. The Director shall have the responsibilities provided under subsection (c) of this section and those duties and responsibilities relating to the functions of the Office which the Secretary may assign, consistent with this chapter. Employees of the Office shall be recruited on the basis of their professional competence and capacity to administer the provisions of this chapter. The Office may use, on a reimbursable basis when appropriate, employees of the Department and other Federal agencies to administer the provisions of this chapter, providing that no legal authority, program, or function in any Federal agency which has as its purpose promoting the development or use of coal or other mineral resources or regulating the health and safety of miners under provisions of the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969 (83 Stat. 742) [30 U.S.C. 801 et seq.], shall be transferred to the Office.


(c) Duties of SecretaryThe Secretary, acting through the Office, shall—(1) administer the programs for controlling surface c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Department of the Interior, the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement (hereinafter referred to as the “Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment, compensation, duties, etc., of Director; employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment, compensation, duties, etc., of Director; employees The Office shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall be compensated at the rate provided for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 11 So in original. Probably should be section “5316”. of title 5, and such other employees as may be required. Pursuant to section 5108 of title 5, and after consultation with the Secretary, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall determine the necessary number of positions in general schedule employees in grade 16, 17, and 18 to perform functions of this subchapter and shall allocate such positions to the Secretary. The Director shall have the responsibilities provided under subsection (c) of this section and those duties and responsibilities relating to the functions of the Office which the Secretary may assign, consistent with this chapter. Employees of the Office shall be rec</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of Secretary The Secretary, acting through the Office, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of Federal coal mine health and safety inspectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Restriction on use of Federal coal mine health and safety inspectors The Director shall not use either permanently or temporarily any person charged with responsibility of inspecting coal mines under the Federal Coal Mine Health and Safety Act of 1969 [30 U.S.C. 801 et seq.], unless he finds and publishes such finding in the Federal Register, that such activities would not interfere with such inspections under the 1969 Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 96–511, § 4(b), Dec. 11, 1980, 94 Stat. 2826</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conflict of interest; penalties; rules and regulations; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Conflict of interest; penalties; rules and regulations; report to Congress No employee of the Office or any other Federal employee performing any function or duty under this chapter shall have a direct or indirect financial interest in underground or surface coal mining operations. Whoever knowingly violates the provisions of the above sentence shall, upon conviction, be punished by a fine of not more than $2,500, or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both. The Director shall (1) within sixty days after August 3, 1977, publish regulations, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, to establish the methods by which the provisions of this subsection will be monitored and enforced, including appropriate provisions for the filing by such employees and the review of statements and supplements thereto concerning their financial interests which may be affected by this subsection, and (2) report to the Congress as part of the annual report (section 1296 of this title) on the a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1211_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for issuance, amendment, or repeal of rule; filing; hearing or investigation; notice of denial</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Petition for issuance, amendment, or repeal of rule; filing; hearing or investigation; notice of denial</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>