<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1231a"><akn:num>1231a</akn:num><akn:heading>Abandoned mine reclamation fund authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1231a. Abandoned mine reclamation fund authorization of appropriations(a) In generalThere is authorized to be appropriated, for deposit into the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund established by section 401(a) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1231(a)) $11,293,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.


(b) Use of funds(1) In generalSubject to subsection (g), amounts made available under subsection (a) shall be used to provide, as expeditiously as practicable, to States and Indian Tribes described in paragraph (2) annual grants for abandoned mine land and water reclamation projects under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.).


(2) Eligible grant recipientsGrants may be made under paragraph (1) to—(A) States and Indian Tribes that have a State or Tribal program approved under section 405 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1235);

(B) States and Indian Tribes that are certified under section 411(a) of that Act (30 U.S.C. 1240a(a)); and

(C) States and Indian Tribes that are referred to in section 402(g)(8)(B) of that Act (30 U.S.C. 1232(g)(8)(B)).


(3) Contract aggregationIn applying for grants under paragraph (1), States and Indian Tribes may aggregate bids into larger statewide or regional contracts.



(c) Covered activities(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), grants under subsection (b)(1) shall only be used for activities described in subsections (a) and (b) of section 403 and section 410 of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1233, 1240).


(2) Long-term abandoned mine land reclamation(A) In generalNot more than 30 percent of the total amount of a grant made annually under subsection (b)(1) may be retained by the recipient of the grant if those amounts are deposited into a long-term abandoned mine land reclamation fund established under State law, from which amounts (together with all </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is authorized to be appropriated, for deposit into the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund established by section 401(a) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1231(a)) $11,293,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Covered activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Total amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Total amount of grant The total amount of grant funding provided under subsection (b)(1) to an eligible State or Indian Tribe shall be not less than $20,000,000, to the extent that the amount needed for reclamation projects described in that subsection on the land of the State or Indian Tribe is not less than $20,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Priority In addition to the priorities described in section 403(a) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1233(a)), in providing grants under this section, priority may also be given to reclamation projects described in subsection (b)(1) that provide employment for current and former employees of the coal industry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reservation Of the funds made available under subsection (a), $25,000,000 shall be made available to the Secretary of the Interior to provide States and Indian Tribes with the financial and technical assistance necessary for the purpose of making amendments to the inventory maintained under section 403(c) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (30 U.S.C. 1233(c)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>