<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1231"><akn:num>1231</akn:num><akn:heading>Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1231. Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund(a) Establishment; administration; State fundsThere is created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund (hereinafter referred to as the “fund”) which shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior. State abandoned mine reclamation funds (State funds) generated by grants from this subchapter shall be established by each State pursuant to an approved State program.


(b) Sources of deposits to fundThe fund shall consist of amounts deposited in the fund, from time to time derived from—(1) the reclamation fees levied under section 1232 of this title;

(2) any user charge imposed on or for land reclaimed pursuant to this subchapter after expenditures for maintenance have been deducted;

(3) donations by persons, corporations, associations, and foundations for the purposes of this subchapter;

(4) recovered moneys as provided for in this subchapter; and

(5) interest credited to the fund under subsection (e).


(c) Use of moneysMoneys in the fund may be used for the following purposes:(1) reclamation and restoration of land and water resources adversely affected by past coal mining, including but not limited to reclamation and restoration of abandoned surface mine areas, abandoned coal processing areas, and abandoned coal refuse disposal areas; sealing and filling abandoned deep mine entries and voids; planting of land adversely affected by past coal mining to prevent erosion and sedimentation; prevention, abatement, treatment, and control of water pollution created by coal mine drainage including restoration of stream beds, and construction and operation of water treatment plants; prevention, abatement, and control of burning coal refuse disposal areas and burning coal in situ; prevention, abatement, and control of coal mine subsidence; and establishment of self-sustaining, individual State administered programs to insure private property against damage</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; administration; State funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; administration; State funds There is created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund (hereinafter referred to as the “fund”) which shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior. State abandoned mine reclamation funds (State funds) generated by grants from this subchapter shall be established by each State pursuant to an approved State program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of deposits to fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sources of deposits to fund The fund shall consist of amounts deposited in the fund, from time to time derived from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of moneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of moneys Moneys in the fund may be used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of moneys; no fiscal year limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of moneys; no fiscal year limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interest The Secretary of the Interior shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury as to what portion of the fund is not, in his judgment, required to meet current withdrawals. The Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the fund in public debt securities with maturities suitable for achieving the purposes of the transfers under section 1232(h) of this title and bearing interest at rates determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration current market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturities. The income on such investments shall be credited to, and form a part of, the fund for the purpose of the transfers under section 1232(h) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1231_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>General limitation on obligation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) General limitation on obligation authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>