<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1233" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1233/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1233/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1233"><akn:num>1233</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives of fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1233. Objectives of fund(a) PrioritiesExpenditure of moneys from the fund on lands and water eligible pursuant to section 1234 of this title for the purposes of this subchapter, except as provided for under section 1240a of this title, shall reflect the following priorities in the order stated:(1)(A) the protection; 11 So in original. of public health, safety, and property from extreme danger of adverse effects of coal mining practices;

(B) the restoration of land and water resources and the environment that—(i) have been degraded by the adverse effects of coal mining practices; and

(ii) are adjacent to a site that has been or will be remediated under subparagraph (A);



(2)(A) the protection of public health and safety from adverse effects of coal mining practices;

(B) the restoration of land and water resources and the environment that—(i) have been degraded by the adverse effects of coal mining practices; and

(ii) are adjacent to a site that has been or will be remediated under subparagraph (A); and



(3) the restoration of land and water resources and the environment previously degraded by adverse effects of coal mining practices including measures for the conservation and development of soil, water (excluding channelization), woodland, fish and wildlife, recreation resources, and agricultural productivity.


(b) Water supply restoration(1) Any State or Indian tribe not certified under section 1240a(a) of this title may expend funds allocated to such State or Indian tribe in any year through the grants made available under paragraphs (1) and (5) of section 1232(g) of this title for the purpose of protecting, repairing, replacing, constructing, or enhancing facilities relating to water supply, including water distribution facilities and treatment plants, to replace water supplies adversely affected by coal mining practices.

(2) If the adverse effect on water supplies referred to in this subsection occurred both prior to and after August 3, 1977, or as th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1233_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Priorities Expenditure of moneys from the fund on lands and water eligible pursuant to section 1234 of this title for the purposes of this subchapter, except as provided for under section 1240a of this title, shall reflect the following priorities in the order stated:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1233_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water supply restoration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Water supply restoration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1233_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inventory For the purposes of assisting in the planning and evaluation of reclamation projects pursuant to section 1235 of this title, and assisting in making the certification referred to in section 1240a(a) of this title, the Secretary shall maintain an inventory of eligible lands and waters pursuant to section 1234 of this title which meet the priorities stated in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a). Under standardized procedures established by the Secretary, States and Indian tribes with approved abandoned mine reclamation programs pursuant to section 1235 of this title may offer amendments, subject to the approval of the Secretary, to update the inventory as it applies to eligible lands and waters under the jurisdiction of such States or tribes. The Secretary shall provide such States and tribes with the financial and technical assistance necessary for the purpose of making inventory amendments. The Secretary shall compile and maintain an inventory for States and Indian l</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>