<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1237" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1237/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1237/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1237"><akn:num>1237</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition and reclamation of land adversely affected by past coal mining practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1237. Acquisition and reclamation of land adversely affected by past coal mining practices(a) Findings of fact; notice; right of entryIf the Secretary or the State pursuant to an approved State program, makes a finding of fact that—(1) land or water resources have been adversely affected by past coal mining practices; and

(2) the adverse effects are at a stage where, in the public interest, action to restore, reclaim, abate, control, or prevent should be taken; and

(3) the owners of the land or water resources where entry must be made to restore, reclaim, abate, control, or prevent the adverse effects of past coal mining practices are not known, or readily available; or

(4) the owners will not give permission for the United States, the States, political subdivisions, their agents, employees, or contractors to enter upon such property to restore, reclaim, abate, control, or prevent the adverse effects of past coal mining practices;


then, upon giving notice by mail to the owners if known or if not known by posting notice upon the premises and advertising once in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipality in which the land lies, the Secretary, his agents, employees, or contractors, or the State pursuant to an approved State program, shall have the right to enter upon the property adversely affected by past coal mining practices and any other property to have access to such property to do all things necessary or expedient to restore, reclaim, abate, control, or prevent the adverse effects. Such entry shall be construed as an exercise of the police power for the protection of public health, safety, and general welfare and shall not be construed as an act of condemnation of property nor of trespass thereon. The moneys expended for such work and the benefits accruing to any such premises so entered upon shall be chargeable against such land and shall mitigate or offset any claim in or any action brought by any owner of any interest in such premises for a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings of fact; notice; right of entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings of fact; notice; right of entry If the Secretary or the State pursuant to an approved State program, makes a finding of fact that— then, upon giving notice by mail to the owners if known or if not known by posting notice upon the premises and advertising once in a newspaper of general circulation in the municipality in which the land lies, the Secretary, his agents, employees, or contractors, or the State pursuant to an approved State program, shall have the right to enter upon the property adversely affected by past coal mining practices and any other property to have access to such property to do all things necessary or expedient to restore, reclaim, abate, control, or prevent the adverse effects. Such entry shall be construed as an exercise of the police power for the protection of public health, safety, and general welfare and shall not be construed as an act of condemnation of property nor of trespass thereon. The moneys expended for such work and the benefits accruin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies or exploratory work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Studies or exploratory work The Secretary, his agents, employees, or contractors or the State pursuant to an approved State program, shall have the right to enter upon any property for the purpose of conducting studies or exploratory work to determine the existence of adverse effects of past coal mining practices and to determine the feasibility of restoration, reclamation, abatement, control, or prevention of such adverse effects. Such entry shall be construed as an exercise of the police power for the protection of public health, safety, and general welfare and shall not be construed as an act of condemnation of property nor trespass thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for acquisition of affected land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for acquisition of affected land The Secretary or the State pursuant to an approved State program, may acquire any land, by purchase, donation, or condemnation, which is adversely affected by past coal mining practices if the Secretary determines that acquisition of such land is necessary to successful reclamation and that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Title to affected land; value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Title to affected land; value Title to all lands acquired pursuant to this section shall be in the name of the United States or, if acquired by a State pursuant to an approved program, title shall be in the name of the State. The price paid for land acquired under this section shall reflect the market value of the land as adversely affected by past coal mining practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State participation; grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State participation; grants States are encouraged as part of their approved State programs, to reclaim abandoned and unreclaimed mined lands within their boundaries and, if necessary, to acquire or to transfer such lands to the Secretary or the appropriate State regulatory authority under appropriate Federal regulations. The Secretary is authorized to make grants on a matching basis to States in such amounts as he deems appropriate for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter but in no event shall any grant exceed 90 per centum of the cost of acquisition of the lands for which the grant is made. When a State has made any such land available to the Federal Government under this subchapter, such State shall have a preference right to purchase such lands after reclamation at fair market value less the State portion of the original acquisition price. Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of subsection (c), reclaimed land may be sold to the State or local </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rules and regulations The Secretary, in formulating regulations for making grants to the States to acquire land pursuant to this section, shall specify that acquired land meet the criteria provided for in subsections (c) and (d) of this section. The Secretary may provide by regulation that money derived from the lease, rental, or user charges of such acquired land and facilities thereon will be deposited in the fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public sale; notice and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public sale; notice and hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1237_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction or rehabilitation of housing for disabled, displaced, or dislocated persons; grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Construction or rehabilitation of housing for disabled, displaced, or dislocated persons; grants In addition to the authority to acquire land under subsection (d) of this section the Secretary is authorized to use money in the fund to acquire land by purchase, donation, or condemnation, and to reclaim and transfer acquired land to any State or to a political subdivision thereof, or to any person, firm, association, or corporation, if he determines that such is an integral and necessary element of an economically feasible plan for the project to construct or rehabilitate housing for persons disabled as the result of employment in the mines or work incidental thereto, persons displaced by acquisition of land pursuant to this section, or persons dislocated as the result of adverse effects of coal mining practices which constitute an emergency as provided in section 1240 of this title or persons dislocated as the result of natural disasters or catastrophic failures from any cause. Such</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>