<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1240a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1240a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1240a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1240a"><akn:num>1240a</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1240a. Certification(a) Certification of completion of coal reclamation(1) The Governor of a State, or the head of a governing body of an Indian tribe, with an approved abandoned mine reclamation program under section 1235 of this title may certify to the Secretary that all of the priorities stated in section 1233(a) of this title for eligible lands and waters pursuant to section 1234 of this title have been achieved. The Secretary, after notice in the Federal Register and opportunity for public comment, shall concur with such certification if the Secretary determines that such certification is correct.

(2)(A) The Secretary may, on the initiative of the Secretary, make the certification referred to in paragraph (1) on behalf of any State or Indian tribe referred to in paragraph (1) if on the basis of the inventory referred to in section 1233(c) of this title all reclamation projects relating to the priorities described in section 1233(a) of this title for eligible land and water pursuant to section 1234 of this title in the State or tribe have been completed.

(B) The Secretary shall only make the certification after notice in the Federal Register and opportunity for public comment.



(b) Eligible lands, waters, and facilitiesIf the Secretary has concurred in a State or tribal certification under subsection (a), for purposes of determining the eligibility of lands and waters for annual grants under section 1232(g)(1) of this title, section 1234 of this title shall not apply, and eligible lands, waters, and facilities shall be those—(1) which were mined or processed for minerals or which were affected by such mining or processing, and abandoned or left in an inadequate reclamation status prior to August 3, 1977; and

(2) for which there is no continuing reclamation responsibility under State or other Federal laws. In determining the eligibility under this subsection of Federal lands, waters, and facilities under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service or Bureau of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of completion of coal reclamation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certification of completion of coal reclamation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible lands, waters, and facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible lands, waters, and facilities If the Secretary has concurred in a State or tribal certification under subsection (a), for purposes of determining the eligibility of lands and waters for annual grants under section 1232(g)(1) of this title, section 1234 of this title shall not apply, and eligible lands, waters, and facilities shall be those—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priorities Expenditures of moneys for lands, waters, and facilities referred to in subsection (b) shall reflect the following objectives and priorities in the order stated (in lieu of the priorities set forth in section 1233 of this title):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific sites and areas not eligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Specific sites and areas not eligible Sites and areas designated for remedial action pursuant to the Uranium Mill Tailings Radiation Control Act of 1978 (42 U.S.C. 7901 and following) or which have been listed for remedial action pursuant to the Comprehensive Environmental Response Compensation and Liability Act of 1980 (42 U.S.C. 9601 and following) shall not be eligible for expenditures from the Fund under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilities and other facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Utilities and other facilities Reclamation projects involving the protection, repair, replacement, construction, or enhancement of utilities, such as those relating to water supply, roads, and such other facilities serving the public adversely affected by mineral mining and processing practices, and the construction of public facilities in communities impacted by coal or other mineral mining and processing practices, shall be deemed part of the objectives set forth, and undertaken as they relate to, the priorities stated in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public facilities related to coal or minerals industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public facilities related to coal or minerals industry Notwithstanding subsection (e), where the Secretary has concurred in the certification referenced in subsection (a) and where the Governor of a State or the head of a governing body of an Indian tribe determines there is a need for activities or construction of specific public facilities related to the coal or minerals industry in States impacted by coal or minerals development and the Secretary concurs in such need, then the State or Indian tribe, as the case may be, may use annual grants made available under section 1232(g)(1) of this title to carry out such activities or construction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of other provisions The provisions of sections 1237 and 1238 of this title shall apply to subsections (a) through (e) of this section, except that for purposes of this section the references to coal in sections 1237 and 1238 of this title shall not apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1240a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States and Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Payments to States and Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>