<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1257" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1257/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1257/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1257"><akn:num>1257</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1257. Application requirements(a) FeeEach application for a surface coal mining and reclamation permit pursuant to an approved State program or a Federal program under the provisions of this chapter shall be accompanied by a fee as determined by the regulatory authority. Such fee may be less than but shall not exceed the actual or anticipated cost of reviewing, administering, and enforcing such permit issued pursuant to a State or Federal program. The regulatory authority may develop procedures so as to enable the cost of the fee to be paid over the term of the permit.


(b) Submittal; contentsThe permit application shall be submitted in a manner satisfactory to the regulatory authority and shall contain, among other things—(1) the names and addresses of (A) the permit applicant; (B) every legal owner of record of the property (surface and mineral), to be mined; (C) the holders of record of any leasehold interest in the property; (D) any purchaser of record of the property under a real estate contract; and (E) the operator if he is a person different from the applicant; and (F) if any of these are business entities other than a single proprietor, the names and addresses of the principals, officers, and resident agent;

(2) the names and addresses of the owners of record of all surface and subsurface areas adjacent to any part of the permit area;

(3) a statement of any current or previous surface coal mining permits in the United States held by the applicant and the permit identification and each pending application;

(4) if the applicant is a partnership, corporation, association, or other business entity, the following where applicable: the names and addresses of every officer, partner, director, or person performing a function similar to a director, of the applicant, together with the name and address of any person owning, of record 10 per centum or more of any class of voting stock of the applicant and a list of all names under which the applicant, partner, or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fee Each application for a surface coal mining and reclamation permit pursuant to an approved State program or a Federal program under the provisions of this chapter shall be accompanied by a fee as determined by the regulatory authority. Such fee may be less than but shall not exceed the actual or anticipated cost of reviewing, administering, and enforcing such permit issued pursuant to a State or Federal program. The regulatory authority may develop procedures so as to enable the cost of the fee to be paid over the term of the permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submittal; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submittal; contents The permit application shall be submitted in a manner satisfactory to the regulatory authority and shall contain, among other things—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to small coal operators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to small coal operators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reclamation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reclamation plan Each applicant for a permit shall be required to submit to the regulatory authority as part of the permit application a reclamation plan which shall meet the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public inspection Each applicant for a surface coal mining and reclamation permit shall file a copy of his application for public inspection with the recorder at the courthouse of the county or an appropriate public office approved by the regulatory authority where the mining is proposed to occur, except for that information pertaining to the coal seam itself.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance certificate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Insurance certificate Each applicant for a permit shall be required to submit to the regulatory authority as part of the permit application a certificate issued by an insurance company authorized to do business in the United States certifying that the applicant has a public liability insurance policy in force for the surface mining and reclamation operations for which such permit is sought, or evidence that the applicant has satisfied other State or Federal self-insurance requirements. Such policy shall provide for personal injury and property damage protection in an amount adequate to compensate any persons damaged as a result of surface coal mining and reclamation operations including use of explosives and entitled to compensation under the applicable provisions of State law. Such policy shall be maintained in full force and effect during the terms of the permit or any renewal, including the length of all reclamation operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Blasting plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Blasting plan Each applicant for a surface coal mining and reclamation permit shall submit to the regulatory authority as part of the permit application a blasting plan which shall outline the procedures and standards by which the operator will meet the provisions of section 1265(b)(15) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1257_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reimbursement of costs A coal operator that has received assistance pursuant to subsection (c)(1) or (2) shall reimburse the regulatory authority for the cost of the services rendered if the program administrator finds that the operator’s actual and attributed annual production of coal for all locations exceeds 300,000 tons during the 12 months immediately following the date on which the operator is issued the surface coal mining and reclamation permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>