<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1261" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1261/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1261/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1261"><akn:num>1261</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1261. Revision of permits(a) Application and revised reclamation plan; requirements; extensions to area covered(1) During the term of the permit the permittee may submit an application for a revision of the permit, together with a revised reclamation plan, to the regulatory authority.

(2) An application for a revision of a permit shall not be approved unless the regulatory authority finds that reclamation as required by this chapter and the State or Federal program can be accomplished under the revised reclamation plan. The revision shall be approved or disapproved within a period of time established by the State or Federal program. The regulatory authority shall establish guidelines for a determination of the scale or extent of a revision request for which all permit application information requirements and procedures, including notice and hearings, shall apply: Provided, That any revisions which propose significant alterations in the reclamation plan shall, at a minimum, be subject to notice and hearing requirements.

(3) Any extensions to the area covered by the permit except incidental boundary revisions must be made by application for another permit.


(b) Transfer, assignment, or sale of rights under permitNo transfer, assignment, or sale of the rights granted under any permit issued pursuant to this chapter shall be made without the written approval of the regulatory authority.


(c) Review of outstanding permitsThe regulatory authority shall within a time limit prescribed in regulations promulgated by the regulatory authority, review outstanding permits and may require reasonable revision or modification of the permit provisions during the term of such permit: Provided, That such revision or modification shall be based upon a written finding and subject to notice and hearing requirements established by the State or Federal program.


(Pub. L. 95–87, title V, § 511, Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 483.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1261_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and revised reclamation plan; requirements; extensions to area covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application and revised reclamation plan; requirements; extensions to area covered</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1261_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer, assignment, or sale of rights under permit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer, assignment, or sale of rights under permit No transfer, assignment, or sale of the rights granted under any permit issued pursuant to this chapter shall be made without the written approval of the regulatory authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1261_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of outstanding permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review of outstanding permits The regulatory authority shall within a time limit prescribed in regulations promulgated by the regulatory authority, review outstanding permits and may require reasonable revision or modification of the permit provisions during the term of such permit: Provided, That such revision or modification shall be based upon a written finding and subject to notice and hearing requirements established by the State or Federal program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>