<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1269" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1269/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1269/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1269"><akn:num>1269</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of performance bonds or deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1269. Release of performance bonds or deposits(a) Filing of request; submittal of copy of advertisement; notification by letter of intent to seek releaseThe permittee may file a request with the regulatory authority for the release of all or part of a performance bond or deposit. Within thirty days after any application for bond or deposit release has been filed with the regulatory authority, the operator shall submit a copy of an advertisement placed at least once a week for four successive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in the locality of the surface coal mining operation. Such advertisement shall be considered part of any bond release application and shall contain a notification of the precise location of the land affected, the number of acres, the permit and the date approved, the amount of the bond filed and the portion sought to be released, and the type and appropriate dates of reclamation work performed, and a description of the results achieved as they relate to the operator’s approved reclamation plan. In addition, as part of any bond release application, the applicant shall submit copies of letters which he has sent to adjoining property owners, local governmental bodies, planning agencies, and sewage and water treatment authorities, or water companies in the locality in which the surface coal mining and reclamation activities took place, notifying them of his intention to seek release from the bond.


(b) Inspection and evaluation; notification of decisionUpon receipt of the notification and request, the regulatory authority shall within thirty days conduct an inspection and evaluation of the reclamation work involved. Such evaluation shall consider, among other things, the degree of difficulty to complete any remaining reclamation, whether pollution of surface and subsurface water is occurring, the probability of continuance of future occurrence of such pollution, and the estimated cost of abating such pollution. The regulatory authority </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of request; submittal of copy of advertisement; notification by letter of intent to seek release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing of request; submittal of copy of advertisement; notification by letter of intent to seek release The permittee may file a request with the regulatory authority for the release of all or part of a performance bond or deposit. Within thirty days after any application for bond or deposit release has been filed with the regulatory authority, the operator shall submit a copy of an advertisement placed at least once a week for four successive weeks in a newspaper of general circulation in the locality of the surface coal mining operation. Such advertisement shall be considered part of any bond release application and shall contain a notification of the precise location of the land affected, the number of acres, the permit and the date approved, the amount of the bond filed and the portion sought to be released, and the type and appropriate dates of reclamation work performed, and a description of the results achieved as they relate to the operator’s approved reclamation plan. In a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection and evaluation; notification of decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inspection and evaluation; notification of decision Upon receipt of the notification and request, the regulatory authority shall within thirty days conduct an inspection and evaluation of the reclamation work involved. Such evaluation shall consider, among other things, the degree of difficulty to complete any remaining reclamation, whether pollution of surface and subsurface water is occurring, the probability of continuance of future occurrence of such pollution, and the estimated cost of abating such pollution. The regulatory authority shall notify the permittee in writing of its decision to release or not to release all or part of the performance bond or deposit within sixty days from the filing of the request, if no public hearing is held pursuant to subsection (f), and if there has been a public hearing held pursuant to subsection (f), within thirty days thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for release</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for release The regulatory authority may release in whole or in part said bond or deposit if the authority is satisfied the reclamation covered by the bond or deposit or portion thereof has been accomplished as required by this chapter according to the following schedule:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice of disapproval If the regulatory authority disapproves the application for release of the bond or portion thereof, the authority shall notify the permittee, in writing, stating the reasons for disapproval and recommending corrective actions necessary to secure said release and allowing opportunity for a public hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to municipality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice to municipality When any application for total or partial bond release is filed with the regulatory authority, the regulatory authority shall notify the municipality in which a surface coal mining operation is located by certified mail at least thirty days prior to the release of all or a portion of the bond.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objections to release; hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Objections to release; hearing Any person with a valid legal interest which might be adversely affected by release of the bond or the responsible officer or head of any Federal, State, or local governmental agency which has jurisdiction by law or special expertise with respect to any environmental, social, or economic impact involved in the operation, or is authorized to develop and enforce environmental standards with respect to such operations shall have the right to file written objections to the proposed release from bond to the regulatory authority within thirty days after the last publication of the above notice. If written objections are filed, and a hearing requested, the regulatory authority shall inform all the interested parties, of the time and place of the hearing, and hold a public hearing in the locality of the surface coal mining operation proposed for bond release within thirty days of the request for such hearing. The date, time, and location of such public hearin</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informal conference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Informal conference Without prejudice to the rights of the objectors, the applicant, or the responsibilities of the regulatory authority pursuant to this section, the regulatory authority may establish an informal conference as provided in section 1263 of this title to resolve such written objections.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1269_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Power of regulatory authority with respect to informal conference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Power of regulatory authority with respect to informal conference For the purpose of such hearing the regulatory authority shall have the authority and is hereby empowered to administer oaths, subpena witnesses, or written or printed materials, compel the attendance of witnesses, or production of the materials, and take evidence including but not limited to inspections of the land affected and other surface coal mining operations carried on by the applicant in the general vicinity. A verbatim record of each public hearing required by this chapter shall be made, and a transcript made available on the motion of any party or by order of the regulatory authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>