<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1315"><akn:num>1315</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council on Coal Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1315. Advisory Council on Coal Research(a) Establishment; membersThere is established an Advisory Council on Coal Research which shall be composed of—(1) the Secretary of Energy, who shall be Chairman;

(2) the Director of the United States Bureau of Mines of the Department of the Interior;

(3) the President of the National Academy of Sciences;

(4) the President of the National Academy of Engineering;

(5) the Director of the United States Geological Survey; and

(6) six members appointed by the Secretary of Energy from among individuals who, by virtue of experience or training, are knowledgeable in the field of coal research and mining, and who are representatives of institutions of higher education, industrial users of coal and coal-derived fuels, the coal industry, mine workers, nonindustrial consumer groups, and institutions concerned with the preservation of the environment.


(b) Furnishing advice to Secretary of EnergyThe Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary of Energy with respect to the general administration of this subchapter, and furnish such additional advice as he may request.


(c) Annual report to President; transmittal to CongressThe Advisory Council shall make an annual report of its findings and recommendations (including recommendations for changes in the provisions of this subchapter) to the President not later than December 31 of each calendar year. The President shall transmit each such report to the Congress.


(d) Compensation and travel expenses(1) Members of the Council who are not regular officers or employees of the United States Government shall, while serving on business of the Council, be entitled to receive compensation at rates fixed by the Secretary of Energy but not exceeding the daily rate prescribed for GS-18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 and while so serving away from their homes or regular places of business, they may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as au</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; members There is established an Advisory Council on Coal Research which shall be composed of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furnishing advice to Secretary of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Furnishing advice to Secretary of Energy The Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary of Energy with respect to the general administration of this subchapter, and furnish such additional advice as he may request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to President; transmittal to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report to President; transmittal to Congress The Advisory Council shall make an annual report of its findings and recommendations (including recommendations for changes in the provisions of this subchapter) to the President not later than December 31 of each calendar year. The President shall transmit each such report to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and travel expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1315_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternate members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Alternate members Whenever a member of the Council appointed under clauses (1) through (5) is unable to attend a meeting, that member shall appoint an appropriate alternate to represent him for that meeting.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>