<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1321"><akn:num>1321</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1321. Fellowship awards(a) Graduate study and research in areas of applied science and engineering relating to production, conservation, and utilization of fuels and energyThe Secretary of Energy is authorized to award under the provisions of this subchapter not to exceed one thousand fellowships for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1979, and each of the five succeeding fiscal years. Fellowships shall be awarded under the provisions of this subchapter for graduate study and research in those areas of applied science and engineering that are related to the production, conservation, and utilization of fuels and energy. Fellowships shall be awarded to students in programs leading to master’s degrees. Such fellowships may be awarded for graduate study and research at any institution of higher education, library, archive, or any other research center approved by the Secretary of Energy after consultation with the Secretary of Education.


(b) TermSuch fellowships shall be awarded for such periods as the Secretary of Energy may determine, but not to exceed two years.


(c) Replacement awardsIn addition to the number of fellowships authorized to be awarded by subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of Energy is authorized to award fellowships equal to the number previously awarded during any fiscal year under this subchapter but vacated prior to the end of the period for which they were awarded; except that each fellowship awarded under this subsection shall be for such period of graduate work or research, not in excess of the remainder of the period for which the fellowship which it replaces was awarded as the Secretary of Energy may determine.


(Pub. L. 95–87, title IX, § 901, Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 529; Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 301(a), title VII, §§ 703, 707, Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 577, 606, 607; Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1), title V, § 507, Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 677, 692.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
In subsec. (a), the words “(hereafter re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Graduate study and research in areas of applied science and engineering relating to production, conservation, and utilization of fuels and energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Graduate study and research in areas of applied science and engineering relating to production, conservation, and utilization of fuels and energy The Secretary of Energy is authorized to award under the provisions of this subchapter not to exceed one thousand fellowships for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1979, and each of the five succeeding fiscal years. Fellowships shall be awarded under the provisions of this subchapter for graduate study and research in those areas of applied science and engineering that are related to the production, conservation, and utilization of fuels and energy. Fellowships shall be awarded to students in programs leading to master’s degrees. Such fellowships may be awarded for graduate study and research at any institution of higher education, library, archive, or any other research center approved by the Secretary of Energy after consultation with the Secretary of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Term Such fellowships shall be awarded for such periods as the Secretary of Energy may determine, but not to exceed two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Replacement awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Replacement awards In addition to the number of fellowships authorized to be awarded by subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary of Energy is authorized to award fellowships equal to the number previously awarded during any fiscal year under this subchapter but vacated prior to the end of the period for which they were awarded; except that each fellowship awarded under this subsection shall be for such period of graduate work or research, not in excess of the remainder of the period for which the fellowship which it replaces was awarded as the Secretary of Energy may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>