<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1402"><akn:num>1402</akn:num><akn:heading>International objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1402. International objectives(a) Disclaimer of extraterritorial sovereigntyBy the enactment of this chapter, the United States—(1) exercises its jurisdiction over United States citizens and vessels, and foreign persons and vessels otherwise subject to its jurisdiction, in the exercise of the high seas freedom to engage in exploration for, and commercial recovery of, hard mineral resources of the deep seabed in accordance with generally accepted principles of international law recognized by the United States; but

(2) does not thereby assert sovereignty or sovereign or exclusive rights or jurisdiction over, or the ownership of, any areas or resources in the deep seabed.


(b) Secretary of State(1) The Secretary of State is encouraged to negotiate successfully a comprehensive Law of the Sea Treaty which, among other things, provides assured and nondiscriminatory access to the hard mineral resources of the deep seabed for all nations, gives legal definition to the principle that the resources of the deep seabed are the common heritage of mankind, and provides for the establishment of requirements for the protection of the quality of the environment as stringent as those promulgated pursuant to this chapter.

(2) Until such a Treaty is concluded, the Secretary of State is encouraged to promote any international actions necessary to adequately protect the environment from adverse impacts which may result from any exploration for and commercial recovery of hard mineral resources of the deep seabed carried out by persons not subject to this chapter.


(Pub. L. 96–283, § 3, June 28, 1980, 94 Stat. 555.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclaimer of extraterritorial sovereignty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclaimer of extraterritorial sovereignty By the enactment of this chapter, the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1402_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretary of State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>