<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1419" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1419/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1419/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1419"><akn:num>1419</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of the environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1419. Protection of the environment(a) Environmental assessment(1) Deep ocean mining environmental study (DOMES)The Administrator shall expand and accelerate the program assessing the effects on the environment from exploration and commercial recovery activities, including seabased processing and the disposal at sea of processing wastes, so as to provide an assessment, as accurate as practicable, of environmental impacts of such activities for the implementation of subsections (b), (c), and (d).


(2) Supporting ocean researchThe Administrator also shall conduct a continuing program of ocean research to support environmental assessment activity through the period of exploration and commercial recovery authorized by this chapter. The program shall include the development, acceleration, and expansion, as appropriate, of studies of the ecological, geological, and physical aspects of the deep seabed in general areas of the ocean where exploration and commercial development under the authority of this chapter are likely to occur, including, but not limited to—(A) natural diversity of the deep seabed biota;

(B) life histories of major benthic, midwater, and surface organisms most likely to be affected by commercial recovery activities;

(C) long- and short-term effects of commercial recovery on the deep seabed biota; and

(D) assessment of the effects of seabased processing activities.


Within 160 days after June 28, 1980, the Administrator shall prepare a plan to carry out the program described in this subsection, including necessary funding levels for the next five fiscal years, and shall submit the plan to the Congress.


(b) Terms, conditions, and restrictionsEach license and permit issued under this subchapter shall contain such terms, conditions, and restrictions, established by the Administrator, which prescribe the actions the licensee or permittee shall take in the conduct of exploration and commercial recovery activities to assure protection of the environme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms, conditions, and restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms, conditions, and restrictions Each license and permit issued under this subchapter shall contain such terms, conditions, and restrictions, established by the Administrator, which prescribe the actions the licensee or permittee shall take in the conduct of exploration and commercial recovery activities to assure protection of the environment. The Administrator shall require in all activities under new permits, and wherever practicable in activities under existing permits, the use of the best available technologies for the protection of safety, health, and the environment wherever such activities would have a significant effect on safety, health, or the environment, except where the Administrator determines that the incremental benefits are clearly insufficient to justify the incremental costs of using such technologies. Before establishing such terms, conditions, and restrictions, the Administrator shall consult with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, th</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programmatic environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programmatic environmental impact statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statements on issuance of licenses and permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Environmental impact statements on issuance of licenses and permits The issuance of, but not the certification of an application for, any license or permit under this subchapter shall be deemed to be a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for purposes of section 4332 of title 42. In preparing an environmental impact statement pursuant to this subsection, the Administrator shall consult with the agency heads referred to in subsection (b) and shall take into account, and give due consideration to, the relevant information contained in any applicable studies and any other environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to this section. Each draft environmental impact statement prepared pursuant to this subsection shall be published, with the terms, conditions, and restrictions proposed pursuant to section 1415(b) of this title, within 180 days (or such longer period as the Administrator may establish for good cause shown in writing) follow</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect on other law For the purposes of this chapter, any vessel or other floating craft engaged in commercial recovery or exploration shall not be deemed to be “a vessel or other floating craft” under section 502(12)(B) of the Clean Water Act [33 U.S.C. 1362(12)(B)] and any discharge of a pollutant from such vessel or other floating craft shall be subject to the Clean Water Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stable reference areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Stable reference areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>