<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1426"><akn:num>1426</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice and hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1426. Public notice and hearings(a) Required proceduresThe Administrator may issue regulations to carry out this chapter, establish and significantly modify terms, conditions, and restrictions in licenses and permits issued under this subchapter, and issue or transfer licenses and permits under this subchapter, only after public notice and opportunity for comment and hearings in accordance with the following:(1) The Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register notice of all applications for licenses and permits, all proposals to issue or transfer licenses and permits, all regulations implementing this chapter, all terms, conditions, and restrictions on licenses and permits, and all proposals to significantly modify licenses and permits. Interested persons shall be permitted to examine the materials relevant to any of these actions, and shall have at least 60 days after publication of such notice to submit written comments to the Administrator.

(2) The Administrator shall hold a public hearing in an appropriate location and may employ such additional methods as the Administrator deems appropriate to inform interested persons about each action specified in paragraph (1) and to invite their comments thereon.


(b) Adjudicatory hearingIf the Administrator determines that there exists one or more specific and material factual issues which require resolution by formal processes, at least one adjudicatory hearing shall be held in the District of Columbia in accordance with the provisions of section 554 of title 5. The record developed in any such adjudicatory hearing shall be part of the basis for the Administrator’s decision to take any action referred to in subsection (a). Hearings held pursuant to this section shall be consolidated insofar as practicable with hearings held by other agencies.


(Pub. L. 96–283, title I, § 116, June 28, 1980, 94 Stat. 573.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required procedures The Administrator may issue regulations to carry out this chapter, establish and significantly modify terms, conditions, and restrictions in licenses and permits issued under this subchapter, and issue or transfer licenses and permits under this subchapter, only after public notice and opportunity for comment and hearings in accordance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudicatory hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjudicatory hearing If the Administrator determines that there exists one or more specific and material factual issues which require resolution by formal processes, at least one adjudicatory hearing shall be held in the District of Columbia in accordance with the provisions of section 554 of title 5. The record developed in any such adjudicatory hearing shall be part of the basis for the Administrator’s decision to take any action referred to in subsection (a). Hearings held pursuant to this section shall be consolidated insofar as practicable with hearings held by other agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>