<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1468" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1468/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1468/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1468"><akn:num>1468</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1468. Regulations(a) Proposed regulationsNot later than 270 days after June 28, 1980, the Administrator shall solicit the views of the agency heads referred to in section 1419(b) of this title and of interested persons, and issue, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, such proposed regulations as are required by or are necessary and appropriate to implement subchapters I and II and this subchapter. The Administrator shall hold at least one public hearing on such proposed regulations.


(b) Final regulationsNot later than 180 days after the date on which proposed regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall solicit the views of the agency heads referred to in section 1419(b) of this title and of interested persons, consider the comments received during the public hearing required in subsection (a) and any written comments on the proposed regulations received by the Administrator, and issue, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, such regulations as are required by or are necessary and appropriate to implement subchapters I and II and this subchapter.


(c) AmendmentsThe Administrator may at any time amend regulations issued pursuant to subsection (b) as the Administrator determines to be necessary and appropriate in order to provide for the conservation of natural resources within the meaning of section 1420 of this title, protection of the environment, and the safety of life and property at sea. Such amended regulations shall apply to all exploration or commercial recovery activities conducted under any license or permit issued or maintained pursuant to this chapter; except that any such amended regulations which provide for conservation of natural resources shall apply to exploration or commercial recovery conducted under an existing license or permit during the present term of such license or permit only if the Administrator determines that such amended regulations providing for conservation of natural resources will not im</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposed regulations Not later than 270 days after June 28, 1980, the Administrator shall solicit the views of the agency heads referred to in section 1419(b) of this title and of interested persons, and issue, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, such proposed regulations as are required by or are necessary and appropriate to implement subchapters I and II and this subchapter. The Administrator shall hold at least one public hearing on such proposed regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Final regulations Not later than 180 days after the date on which proposed regulations are issued pursuant to subsection (a), the Administrator shall solicit the views of the agency heads referred to in section 1419(b) of this title and of interested persons, consider the comments received during the public hearing required in subsection (a) and any written comments on the proposed regulations received by the Administrator, and issue, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, such regulations as are required by or are necessary and appropriate to implement subchapters I and II and this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amendments The Administrator may at any time amend regulations issued pursuant to subsection (b) as the Administrator determines to be necessary and appropriate in order to provide for the conservation of natural resources within the meaning of section 1420 of this title, protection of the environment, and the safety of life and property at sea. Such amended regulations shall apply to all exploration or commercial recovery activities conducted under any license or permit issued or maintained pursuant to this chapter; except that any such amended regulations which provide for conservation of natural resources shall apply to exploration or commercial recovery conducted under an existing license or permit during the present term of such license or permit only if the Administrator determines that such amended regulations providing for conservation of natural resources will not impose serious or irreparable economic hardship on the licensee or permittee. Any amendment to regulations und</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1468_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consistency This chapter and the regulations issued under this chapter shall not be deemed to supersede any other Federal laws or treaties or regulations issued thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>