<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1604" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1604/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1604/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1604"><akn:num>1604</akn:num><akn:heading>Program administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1604. Program administration(a) President; preparation of plan and submission to Congress of reportWithin 1 year after December 27, 2020, the President shall submit to the Congress—(1) a program plan to implement such existing or prospective proposals and organizational structures within the executive branch as he finds necessary to carry out the provisions set forth in sections 1602 and 1603 of this title. The plan shall include program and budget proposals and organizational structures providing for the following minimum elements:(A) policy analysis and decision determination within the Executive Office of the President;

(B) continuing long-range analysis of materials use to meet national security, economic, industrial and social needs; the adequacy and stability of supplies; and the industrial and economic implications of supply shortages or disruptions;

(C) continuing private sector consultation in Federal materials programs; and

(D) interagency coordination at the level of the President’s Cabinet;


(2) recommendations for the collection, analysis, and dissemination of information concerning domestic and international long-range materials demand, supply and needs, including consideration of the establishment of a separate materials information agency patterned after the Bureau of Labor Statistics; and

(3) recommendations for legislation and administrative initiatives necessary to reconcile policy conflicts and to establish programs and institutional structures necessary to achieve the goals of a national materials policy.


(b) Director of Office of Science and Technology Policy; coordination, etc., activitiesIn accordance with the provisions of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (42 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall:(1) through the National Science and Technology Council coordinate Federal materials research and development and related activities in ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>President; preparation of plan and submission to Congress of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) President; preparation of plan and submission to Congress of report Within 1 year after December 27, 2020, the President shall submit to the Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Office of Science and Technology Policy; coordination, etc., activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Director of Office of Science and Technology Policy; coordination, etc., activities In accordance with the provisions of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (42 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Commerce; consultative, etc., requirements; identification and assessment activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretary of Commerce; consultative, etc., requirements; identification and assessment activities The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with such other members of the Cabinet as may be appropriate, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of Defense and other Cabinet members; assessment, etc., activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Secretary of Defense and other Cabinet members; assessment, etc., activities The Secretary of Defense, together with such other members of the Cabinet as are deemed necessary by the President, shall prepare a report assessing critical materials needs related to national security and identifying the steps necessary to meet those needs. The report shall include an assessment of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (50 U.S.C. App. 2061 et seq.) [now 50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.], and the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (50 U.S.C. App. 98 et seq.) [50 U.S.C. 98 et seq.]. Such report shall be made available to the Congress within 1 year after December 27, 2020, and shall be revised periodically as deemed necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of the Interior; initiation of actions; report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Secretary of the Interior; initiation of actions; report The Secretary of the Interior shall promptly initiate actions to— A report summarizing actions required by this subsection shall be made available to the Congress within 1 year after December 27, 2020.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1604_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary of the Interior; collection, evaluation, and analysis activities concerning information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Secretary of the Interior; collection, evaluation, and analysis activities concerning information In furtherance of the policies of this chapter, the Secretary of the Interior shall collect, evaluate, and analyze information concerning mineral occurrence, production, and use from industry, academia, and Federal and State agencies. Notwithstanding the provisions of section 552 of title 5, data and information provided to the Department by persons or firms engaged in any phase of mineral or mineral-material production or large-scale consumption shall not be disclosed outside of the Department of the Interior in a nonaggregated form so as to disclose data and information supplied by a single person or firm, unless there is no objection to the disclosure of such data and information by the donor: Provided, however, That the Secretary may disclose nonaggregated data and information to Federal defense agencies, or to the Congress upon official request for appropriate purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>