<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1712"><akn:num>1712</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of lessees, operators, and motor vehicle transporters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1712. Duties of lessees, operators, and motor vehicle transporters(a) Liability for royalty paymentsIn order to increase receipts and achieve effective collections of royalty and other payments, a lessee who is required to make any royalty or other payment under a lease or under the mineral leasing laws, shall make such payments in the time and manner as may be specified by the Secretary or the applicable delegated State. A lessee may designate a person to make all or part of the payments due under a lease on the lessee’s behalf and shall notify the Secretary or the applicable delegated State in writing of such designation, in which event said designated person may, in its own name, pay, offset or credit monies, make adjustments, request and receive refunds and submit reports with respect to payments required by the lessee. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, a designee shall not be liable for any payment obligation under the lease. The person owning operating rights in a lease shall be primarily liable for its pro rata share of payment obligations under the lease. If the person owning the legal record title in a lease is other than the operating rights owner, the person owning the legal record title shall be secondarily liable for its pro rata share of such payment obligations under the lease.


(b) Development of and compliance with site security plan and minimum site security measures by operators; notification to Secretary of well productionAn operator shall—(1) develop and comply with a site security plan designed to protect the oil or gas produced or stored on an onshore lease site from theft, which plan shall conform with such minimum standards as the Secretary may prescribe by rule, taking into account the variety of circumstances at lease sites;

(2) develop and comply with such minimum site security measures as the Secretary deems appropriate to protect oil or gas produced or stored on a lease site or on the Outer Contine</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for royalty payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability for royalty payments In order to increase receipts and achieve effective collections of royalty and other payments, a lessee who is required to make any royalty or other payment under a lease or under the mineral leasing laws, shall make such payments in the time and manner as may be specified by the Secretary or the applicable delegated State. A lessee may designate a person to make all or part of the payments due under a lease on the lessee’s behalf and shall notify the Secretary or the applicable delegated State in writing of such designation, in which event said designated person may, in its own name, pay, offset or credit monies, make adjustments, request and receive refunds and submit reports with respect to payments required by the lessee. Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter to the contrary, a designee shall not be liable for any payment obligation under the lease. The person owning operating rights in a lease shall be primarily liable for its pro r</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of and compliance with site security plan and minimum site security measures by operators; notification to Secretary of well production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of and compliance with site security plan and minimum site security measures by operators; notification to Secretary of well production An operator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Possession of documentation by transporters of oil or gas by motor vehicle or pipeline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Possession of documentation by transporters of oil or gas by motor vehicle or pipeline</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>