<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1721"><akn:num>1721</akn:num><akn:heading>Royalty terms and conditions, interest, and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1721. Royalty terms and conditions, interest, and penalties(a) Charge on late royalty payment or royalty payment deficiencyIn the case of oil and gas leases where royalty payments are not received by the Secretary on the date that such payments are due, or are less than the amount due, the Secretary shall charge interest on such late payments or underpayments at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26. In the case of an underpayment or partial payment, interest shall be computed and charged only on the amount of the deficiency and not on the total amount due.


(b) Charge on late payment made by Secretary to StatesAny payment made by the Secretary to a State under section 191 of this title and any other payment made by the Secretary to a State from any oil or gas royalty received by the Secretary which is not paid on the date required under section 191 of this title shall include an interest charge computed at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26.


(c) Deposit in royalty accounts of charges on royalties due and owing IndiansAll interest charges collected under this chapter or under other applicable laws because of nonpayment, late payment or underpayment of royalties due and owing an Indian tribe or an Indian allottee shall be deposited to the same account as the royalty with respect to which such interest is paid.


(d) Charge on late deposit of royalty fund to an Indian accountAny deposit of royalty funds made by the Secretary to an Indian account which is not made by the date required under section 1714 of this title shall include an interest charge computed at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26.


(e) Nonliability of States for Secretary’s failure to comply with the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 or regulations thereunderNotwithstanding any other provision of law, no State will be assessed for any interest or penalties found to be due against the Secretary for failure to comply with the Emergency Petroleum </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge on late royalty payment or royalty payment deficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Charge on late royalty payment or royalty payment deficiency In the case of oil and gas leases where royalty payments are not received by the Secretary on the date that such payments are due, or are less than the amount due, the Secretary shall charge interest on such late payments or underpayments at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26. In the case of an underpayment or partial payment, interest shall be computed and charged only on the amount of the deficiency and not on the total amount due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge on late payment made by Secretary to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Charge on late payment made by Secretary to States Any payment made by the Secretary to a State under section 191 of this title and any other payment made by the Secretary to a State from any oil or gas royalty received by the Secretary which is not paid on the date required under section 191 of this title shall include an interest charge computed at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit in royalty accounts of charges on royalties due and owing Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deposit in royalty accounts of charges on royalties due and owing Indians All interest charges collected under this chapter or under other applicable laws because of nonpayment, late payment or underpayment of royalties due and owing an Indian tribe or an Indian allottee shall be deposited to the same account as the royalty with respect to which such interest is paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge on late deposit of royalty fund to an Indian account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Charge on late deposit of royalty fund to an Indian account Any deposit of royalty funds made by the Secretary to an Indian account which is not made by the date required under section 1714 of this title shall include an interest charge computed at the rate applicable under section 6621 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonliability of States for Secretary’s failure to comply with the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 or regulations thereunder</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonliability of States for Secretary’s failure to comply with the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 or regulations thereunder Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no State will be assessed for any interest or penalties found to be due against the Secretary for failure to comply with the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 [15 U.S.C. 751 et seq.] or regulation of the Secretary of Energy thereunder concerning crude oil certification or pricing with respect to crude oil taken by the Secretary in kind as royalty. Any State share of an overcharge, resulting from such failure to comply, shall be assessed against moneys found to be due and owing to such State as a result of audits of royalty accounts for transactions which took place prior to January 12, 1983, except that if after the completion of such audits, sufficient moneys have not been found due and owing to any State, the State shall be assessed the balance of that State’s share of the overcharge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on interest charged</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on interest charged Interest shall be charged under this section only for the number of days a payment is late.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Estimated payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Estimated payment A lessee or its designee may make a payment for the approximate amount of royalties (hereinafter in this subsection “estimated payment”) that would otherwise be due for such lease by the date royalties are due for that lease. When an estimated payment is made, actual royalties are payable at the end of the month following the month in which the estimated payment is made. If the estimated payment was less than the amount of actual royalties due, interest is owed on the underpaid amount. If the lessee or its designee makes a payment for such actual royalties, the lessee or its designee may apply the estimated payment to future royalties. Any estimated payment may be adjusted, recouped, or reinstated at any time by the lessee or its designee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volume allocation of oil and gas production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Volume allocation of oil and gas production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1721_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Production allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Production allocation The Secretary shall issue all determinations of allocations of production for units and communitization agreements within 120 days of a request for determination. Until the Secretary issues the determination, the lessee or its designee of a lease in a unit or communitization agreement shall report and pay royalties on oil and gas production for each production month in accordance with the terms of the proposed allocation of production for the unit or communitization agreement. After the Secretary issues the determination, the lessee or its designee shall, as necessary, correct such reports and the amount of royalties paid on oil and gas production under the unit or communitization agreement by not later than the end of the third month following the month in which the lessee or its designee receives the determination from the Secretary. Subject to the full and timely monthly payment of royalties to all parties in accordance with the terms of the proposed alloca</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>