<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1724" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1724/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1724/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1724"><akn:num>1724</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial and delegated States’ actions and limitation periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1724. Secretarial and delegated States’ actions and limitation periods(a) In generalThe respective duties, responsibilities, and activities with respect to a lease shall be performed by the Secretary, delegated States, and lessees or their designees in a timely manner.


(b) Limitation period(1) In generalA judicial proceeding or demand which arises from, or relates to an obligation, shall be commenced within seven years from the date on which the obligation becomes due and if not so commenced shall be barred. If commencement of a judicial proceeding or demand for an obligation is barred by this section, the Secretary, a delegated State, or a lessee or its designee (A) shall not take any other or further action regarding that obligation, including (but not limited to) the issuance of any order, request, demand or other communication seeking any document, accounting, determination, calculation, recalculation, payment, principal, interest, assessment, or penalty or the initiation, pursuit or completion of an audit with respect to that obligation; and (B) shall not pursue any other equitable or legal remedy, whether under statute or common law, with respect to an action on or an enforcement of said obligation.


(2) Rule of constructionA judicial proceeding or demand that is timely commenced under paragraph (1) against a designee shall be considered timely commenced as to any lessee who is liable pursuant to section 1712(a) of this title for the obligation that is the subject of the judicial proceeding or demand.


(3) Application of certain limitationsThe limitations set forth in sections 2401, 2415, 2416, and 2462 of title 28 and section 226–2 of this title shall not apply to any obligation to which this chapter applies. Section 3716 of title 31 may be applied to an obligation the enforcement of which is not barred by this chapter, but may not be applied to any obligation the enforcement of which is barred by this chapter.



(c) Obligation becomes due(1) In genera</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The respective duties, responsibilities, and activities with respect to a lease shall be performed by the Secretary, delegated States, and lessees or their designees in a timely manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation becomes due</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Obligation becomes due</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tolling of limitation period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tolling of limitation period The running of the limitation period under subsection (b) shall not be suspended, tolled, extended, or enlarged for any obligation for any reason by any action, including an action by the Secretary or a delegated State, other than the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of limitations period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of limitations period An action or an enforcement of an obligation by the Secretary or delegated State or a lessee or its designee shall be barred under this section prior to the running of the seven-year period provided in subsection (b) in the event— For purposes of this subsection, notice to, or an agreement by, the designee shall be binding on any lessee who is liable pursuant to section 1712(a) of this title for obligations that are the subject of the notice or agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records required for determining collections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Records required for determining collections Records required pursuant to section 1713 of this title by the Secretary or any delegated State for the purpose of determining obligations due and compliance with any applicable mineral leasing law, lease provision, regulation or order with respect to oil and gas leases from Federal lands or the Outer Continental Shelf shall be maintained for the same period of time during which a judicial proceeding or demand may be commenced under subsection (b). If a judicial proceeding or demand is timely commenced, the record holder shall maintain such records until the final nonappealable decision in such judicial proceeding is made, or with respect to that demand is rendered, unless the Secretary or the applicable delegated State authorizes in writing an earlier release of the requirement to maintain such records. Notwithstanding anything herein to the contrary, under no circumstance shall a record holder be required to maintain or produce any rec</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely collections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Timely collections In order to most effectively utilize resources available to the Secretary to maximize the collection of oil and gas receipts from lease obligations to the Treasury within the seven-year period of limitations, and consequently to maximize the State share of such receipts, the Secretary should not perform or require accounting, reporting, or audit activities if the Secretary and the State concerned determine that the cost of conducting or requiring the activity exceeds the expected amount to be collected by the activity, based on the most current 12 months of activity. This subsection shall not provide a defense to a demand or an order to perform a restructured accounting. To the maximum extent possible, the Secretary and delegated States shall reduce costs to the United States Treasury and the States by discontinuing requirements for unnecessary or duplicative data and other information, such as separate allowances and payor information, relating to obligations du</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals and final agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appeals and final agency action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collections of disputed amounts due</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Collections of disputed amounts due To expedite collections relating to disputed obligations due within the seven-year period beginning on the date the obligation became due, the parties shall hold not less than one settlement consultation and the Secretary and the State concerned may take such action as is appropriate to compromise and settle a disputed obligation, including waiving or reducing interest and allowing offsetting of obligations among leases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1724_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of claim for judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Enforcement of claim for judicial review In the event a demand subject to this section is properly and timely commenced, the obligation which is the subject of the demand may be enforced beyond the seven-year limitations period without being barred by this statute of limitations. In the event a demand subject to this section is properly and timely commenced, a judicial proceeding challenging the final agency action with respect to such demand shall be deemed timely so long as such judicial proceeding is commenced within 180 days from receipt of notice by the lessee or its designee of the final agency action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>