<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1732" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1732/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/1732/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1732"><akn:num>1732</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1732. Cooperative agreements(a) Authorization of Secretary; permission of Indian tribe required for activities on Indian landsThe Secretary is authorized to enter into a cooperative agreement or agreements with any State or Indian tribe to share oil or gas royalty management information, to carry out inspection, auditing, investigation or enforcement (not including the collection of royalties, civil or criminal penalties or other payments) activities under this chapter in cooperation with the Secretary, and to carry out any other activity described in section 1718 of this title. The Secretary shall not enter into any such cooperative agreement with a State with respect to any such activities on Indian lands, except with the permission of the Indian tribe involved.


(b) Access to royalty accounting informationExcept as provided in section 1733 of this title, and pursuant to a cooperative agreement—(1) each State shall, upon request, have access to all royalty accounting information in the possession of the Secretary respecting the production, removal, or sale of oil or gas from leases on Federal lands within the State; and

(2) each Indian tribe shall, upon request, have access to all royalty accounting information in the possession of the Secretary respecting the production, removal, or sale of oil or gas from leases on Indian lands under the jurisdiction of such tribe.


Information shall be made available under paragraphs (1) and (2) as soon as practicable after it comes into the possession of the Secretary. Effective October 1, 1983, such information shall be made available under paragraphs (1) and (2) not later than 30 days after such information comes into the possession of the Secretary.

(c) Agreements in accordance with chapter 63 of title 31; terms and conditionsAny cooperative agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall be in accordance with the provisions of chapter 63 of title 31, and shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1732_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Secretary; permission of Indian tribe required for activities on Indian lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of Secretary; permission of Indian tribe required for activities on Indian lands The Secretary is authorized to enter into a cooperative agreement or agreements with any State or Indian tribe to share oil or gas royalty management information, to carry out inspection, auditing, investigation or enforcement (not including the collection of royalties, civil or criminal penalties or other payments) activities under this chapter in cooperation with the Secretary, and to carry out any other activity described in section 1718 of this title. The Secretary shall not enter into any such cooperative agreement with a State with respect to any such activities on Indian lands, except with the permission of the Indian tribe involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1732_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to royalty accounting information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access to royalty accounting information Except as provided in section 1733 of this title, and pursuant to a cooperative agreement— Information shall be made available under paragraphs (1) and (2) as soon as practicable after it comes into the possession of the Secretary. Effective October 1, 1983, such information shall be made available under paragraphs (1) and (2) not later than 30 days after such information comes into the possession of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1732_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements in accordance with chapter 63 of title 31; terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements in accordance with chapter 63 of title 31; terms and conditions Any cooperative agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall be in accordance with the provisions of chapter 63 of title 31, and shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary deems appropriate and consistent with the purposes of this chapter, including, but not limited to, a limitation on the use of Federal assistance to those costs which are directly required to carry out the agreed upon activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>