<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/195" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/195/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/195/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_195"><akn:num>195</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 195. Enforcement(a) ViolationsIt shall be unlawful for any person:(1) to organize or participate in any scheme, arrangement, plan, or agreement to circumvent or defeat the provisions of this chapter or its implementing regulations, or

(2) to seek to obtain or to obtain any money or property by means of false statements of material facts or by failing to state material facts concerning:(A) the value of any lease or portion thereof issued or to be issued under this chapter;

(B) the availability of any land for leasing under this chapter;

(C) the ability of any person to obtain leases under this chapter; or

(D) the provisions of this chapter and its implementing regulations.



(b) PenaltyAny person who knowingly violates the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500,000, imprisonment for not more than five years, or both.


(c) Civil actionsWhenever it shall appear that any person is engaged, or is about to engage, in any act which constitutes or will constitute a violation of subsection (a) of this section, the Attorney General may institute a civil action in the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the defendant resides or in which the violation occurred or in which the lease or land involved is located, for a temporary restraining order, injunction, civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation, or other appropriate remedy, including but not limited to, a prohibition from participation in exploration, leasing, or development of any Federal mineral, or any combination of the foregoing.


(d) Corporations(1) Whenever a corporation or other entity is subject to civil or criminal action under this section, any officer, employee, or agent of such corporation or entity who knowingly authorized, ordered, or carried out the proscribed activity shall be subject to the same action.

(2) Whenever any officer, employee, or agent of a corporation or other entity is subject </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations It shall be unlawful for any person:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalty Any person who knowingly violates the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be punished by a fine of not more than $500,000, imprisonment for not more than five years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil actions Whenever it shall appear that any person is engaged, or is about to engage, in any act which constitutes or will constitute a violation of subsection (a) of this section, the Attorney General may institute a civil action in the district court of the United States for the judicial district in which the defendant resides or in which the violation occurred or in which the lease or land involved is located, for a temporary restraining order, injunction, civil penalty of not more than $100,000 for each violation, or other appropriate remedy, including but not limited to, a prohibition from participation in exploration, leasing, or development of any Federal mineral, or any combination of the foregoing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Corporations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies, fines, and imprisonment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Remedies, fines, and imprisonment The remedies, penalties, fines, and imprisonment prescribed in this section shall be concurrent and cumulative and the exercise of one shall not preclude the exercise of the others. Further, the remedies, penalties, fines, and imprisonment prescribed in this section shall be in addition to any other remedies, penalties, fines, and imprisonment afforded by any other law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_195_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State civil actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>