<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/2003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/2003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/2003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2003"><akn:num>2003</akn:num><akn:heading>Methane hydrate research and development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2003. Methane hydrate research and development program(a) In general(1) Commencement of programNot later than 90 days after August 8, 2005, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Director, shall commence a program of methane hydrate research and development in accordance with this section.


(2) DesignationsThe Secretary, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Director shall designate individuals to carry out this section.


(3) CoordinationThe individual designated by the Secretary shall coordinate all activities within the Department of Energy relating to methane hydrate research and development.


(4) MeetingsThe individuals designated under paragraph (2) shall meet not later than 180 days after August 8, 2005, and not less frequently than every 180 days thereafter to—(A) review the progress of the program under paragraph (1); and

(B) coordinate interagency research and partnership efforts in carrying out the program.



(b) Grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, interagency funds transfer agreements, and field work proposals(1) Assistance and coordinationIn carrying out the program of methane hydrate research and development authorized by this section, the Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, institutions of higher education, oceanographic institutions, and industrial enterprises to—(A) conduct basic and applied research to identify, explore, assess, and develop methane hydrate as a commercially viable source of energy;

(B) identify methane hydrate resources through remote sensing;

(C) acquire and reprocess seismic data suitable for characterizing methane hydrate accumulations;

(D) assist in developing technologies required for efficient and environmentally sound development of methane hydrate resources;

(E) promote education and training in methane hydrate resou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, interagency funds transfer agreements, and field work proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, interagency funds transfer agreements, and field work proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methane hydrates advisory panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Methane hydrates advisory panel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction costs None of the funds made available to carry out this section may be used for the construction of a new building or the acquisition, expansion, remodeling, or alteration of an existing building (including site grading and improvement and architect fees).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Responsibilities of the Secretary In carrying out subsection (b)(1), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>