<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/207" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/207/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/207/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_207"><akn:num>207</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 207. Conditions of lease(a) Term of lease; annual rentals; royalties; readjustment of conditionsA coal lease shall be for a term of twenty years and for so long thereafter as coal is produced annually in commercial quantities from that lease. Any lease which is not producing in commercial quantities at the end of ten years shall be terminated. The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe annual rentals on leases. A lease shall require payment of a royalty in such amount as the Secretary shall determine of not less than 12½ percent, except such amount shall be not more than 7 percent during the period that begins on July 4, 2025, and ends September 30, 2034, of the value of coal as defined by regulation, except the Secretary may determine a lesser amount in the case of coal recovered by underground mining operations. The lease shall include such other terms and conditions as the Secretary shall determine. Such rentals and royalties and other terms and conditions of the lease will be subject to readjustment at the end of its primary term of twenty years and at the end of each ten-year period thereafter if the lease is extended.


(b) Diligent development and continued operation; suspension of condition on payment of advance royalties(1) Each lease shall be subject to the conditions of diligent development and continued operation of the mine or mines, except where operations under the lease are interrupted by strikes, the elements, or casualties not attributable to the lessee.

(2) The Secretary of the Interior, upon determining that the public interest will be served thereby, may suspend the condition of continued operation upon the payment of advance royalties.

(3) Advance royalties described in paragraph (2) shall be no less than the production royalty which would otherwise be paid and shall be computed on a fixed reserve to production ratio (determined by the Secretary).

(4) Advance royalties described in paragraph (2) shall be computed—(A) based on—(i) the aver</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of lease; annual rentals; royalties; readjustment of conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Term of lease; annual rentals; royalties; readjustment of conditions A coal lease shall be for a term of twenty years and for so long thereafter as coal is produced annually in commercial quantities from that lease. Any lease which is not producing in commercial quantities at the end of ten years shall be terminated. The Secretary shall by regulation prescribe annual rentals on leases. A lease shall require payment of a royalty in such amount as the Secretary shall determine of not less than 12½ percent, except such amount shall be not more than 7 percent during the period that begins on July 4, 2025, and ends September 30, 2034, of the value of coal as defined by regulation, except the Secretary may determine a lesser amount in the case of coal recovered by underground mining operations. The lease shall include such other terms and conditions as the Secretary shall determine. Such rentals and royalties and other terms and conditions of the lease will be subject to readjustment at </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diligent development and continued operation; suspension of condition on payment of advance royalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Diligent development and continued operation; suspension of condition on payment of advance royalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_207_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation and reclamation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation and reclamation plan Prior to taking any action on a leasehold which might cause a significant disturbance of the environment, the lessee shall submit for the Secretary’s approval an operation and reclamation plan. The Secretary shall approve or disapprove the plan or require that it be modified. Where the land involved is under the surface jurisdiction of another Federal agency, that other agency must consent to the terms of such approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>