<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/226" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/226/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/226/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_226"><akn:num>226</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing of oil and gas parcels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 226. Leasing of oil and gas parcels(a) Leasing authorized(1) In generalAny parcel of land subject to disposition under this chapter that is known or believed to contain oil or gas deposits shall be made available for leasing, subject to paragraph (2), by the Secretary of the Interior, not later than 18 months after the date of receipt by the Secretary of an expression of interest in leasing the applicable parcel of land available for disposition under this section, if the Secretary determines that the parcel of land is open to oil or gas leasing under the approved resource management plan applicable to the planning area in which the parcel of land is located that is in effect on the date on which the expression of interest was submitted to the Secretary (referred to in this subsection as the “approved resource management plan”).


(2) Resource management plans(A) Lease terms and conditionsA lease issued by the Secretary under this section with respect to an applicable parcel of land made available for leasing under paragraph (1)—(i) shall be subject to the terms and conditions of the approved resource management plan; and

(ii) may not require any stipulations or mitigation requirements not included in the approved resource management plan.


(B) Effect of amendmentThe initiation of an amendment to an approved resource management plan shall not prevent or delay the Secretary from making the applicable parcel of land available for leasing in accordance with that approved resource management plan if the other requirements of this section have been met, as determined by the Secretary.




(b) Lands within known geologic structure of a producing oil or gas field; lands within special tar sand areas; competitive bidding; royalties(1)(A) All lands to be leased which are not subject to leasing under paragraphs (2) and (3) of this subsection shall be leased as provided in this paragraph to the highest responsible qualified bidder by competitive bidding under general regul</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Leasing authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands within known geologic structure of a producing oil or gas field; lands within special tar sand areas; competitive bidding; royalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Lands within known geologic structure of a producing oil or gas field; lands within special tar sand areas; competitive bidding; royalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lands subject to leasing under subsection (b); first qualified applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lands subject to leasing under subsection (b); first qualified applicant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual rentals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual rentals All leases issued under this section, as amended by the Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Reform Act of 1987, shall be conditioned upon payment by the lessee of a rental of not less than $3 per acre per year during the 2-year period beginning on the date the lease begins for new leases, and after the end of that 2-year period, $5 per acre per year for the following 6-year period, and not less than $15 per acre per year thereafter, or, in the case of a lease issued during the 10-year period beginning on August 16, 2022, $3 per acre per year during the 2-year period beginning on the date the lease begins, and after the end of that 2-year period, $5 per acre per year for the following 6-year period, and $15 per acre per year thereafter. A minimum royalty in lieu of rental of not less than the rental which otherwise would be required for that lease year shall be payable at the expiration of each lease year beginning on or after a discovery of oil or gas in paying quant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Primary terms Competitive and noncompetitive leases issued under this section shall be for a primary term of 10 years: Provided, however, That competitive leases issued in special tar sand areas shall also be for a primary term of ten years. Each such lease shall continue so long after its primary term as oil or gas is produced in paying quantities. Any lease issued under this section for land on which, or for which under an approved cooperative or unit plan of development or operation, actual drilling operations were commenced prior to the end of its primary term and are being diligently prosecuted at that time shall be extended for two years and so long thereafter as oil or gas is produced in paying quantities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proposed action; posting of notice; terms and maps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice of proposed action; posting of notice; terms and maps At least 45 days before offering lands for lease under this section, and at least 30 days before approving applications for permits to drill under the provisions of a lease or substantially modifying the terms of any lease issued under this section, the Secretary shall provide notice of the proposed action. Such notice shall be posted in the appropriate local office of the leasing and land management agencies. Such notice shall include the terms or modified lease terms and maps or a narrative description of the affected lands. Where the inclusion of maps in such notice is not practicable, maps of the affected lands shall be made available to the public for review. Such maps shall show the location of all tracts to be leased, and of all leases already issued in the general area. The requirements of this subsection are in addition to any public notice required by other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of surface-disturbing activities; approval of plan of operations; bond or surety; failure to comply with reclamation requirements as barring lease; opportunity to comply with requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulation of surface-disturbing activities; approval of plan of operations; bond or surety; failure to comply with reclamation requirements as barring lease; opportunity to comply with requirements The Secretary of the Interior, or for National Forest lands, the Secretary of Agriculture, shall regulate all surface-disturbing activities conducted pursuant to any lease issued under this chapter, and shall determine reclamation and other actions as required in the interest of conservation of surface resources. No permit to drill on an oil and gas lease issued under this chapter may be granted without the analysis and approval by the Secretary concerned of a plan of operations covering proposed surface-disturbing activities within the lease area. The Secretary concerned shall, by rule or regulation, establish such standards as may be necessary to ensure that an adequate bond, surety, or other financial arrangement will be established prior to the commencement of surface-disturbing act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Forest System Lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) National Forest System Lands The Secretary of the Interior may not issue any lease on National Forest System Lands reserved from the public domain over the objection of the Secretary of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination No lease issued under this section which is subject to termination because of cessation of production shall be terminated for this cause so long as reworking or drilling operations which were commenced on the land prior to or within sixty days after cessation of production are conducted thereon with reasonable diligence, or so long as oil or gas is produced in paying quantities as a result of such operations. No lease issued under this section shall expire because operations or production is suspended under any order, or with the consent, of the Secretary. No lease issued under this section covering lands on which there is a well capable of producing oil or gas in paying quantities shall expire because the lessee fails to produce the same unless the lessee is allowed a reasonable time, which shall be not less than sixty days after notice by registered or certified mail, within which to place such well in producing status or unless, after such status is established, prod</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_226_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drainage agreements; primary term of lease, extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Drainage agreements; primary term of lease, extension Whenever it appears to the Secretary that lands owned by the United States are being drained of oil or gas by wells drilled on adjacent lands, he may negotiate agreements whereby the United States, or the United States and its lessees, shall be compensated for such drainage. Such agreements shall be made with the consent of the lessees, if any, affected thereby. If such agreement is entered into, the primary term of any lease for which compensatory royalty is being paid, or any extension of such primary term, shall be extended for the period during which such compensatory royalty is paid and for a period of one year from discontinuance of such payment and so long thereafter as oil or gas is produced in paying quantities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>