<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/523" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/523/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/523/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_523"><akn:num>523</akn:num><akn:heading>Uranium leases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 523. Uranium leases(a) Right to locate mining claimsSubject to the conditions and provisions of this chapter and to any valid prior rights acquired under the laws of the United States, the owner of any pending uranium lease application or of any uranium lease shall have, for a period of one hundred and twenty days after August 13, 1954, as limited in subsection (b) of this section, the right to locate mining claims upon the lands covered by said application or lease.


(b) Priorities and conflicting rights; termination of rightsAny rights under any such mining claim so hereafter located pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to any rights of the owner of any mining claim which was located prior to February 10, 1954, and which was valid on August 13, 1954 or which may acquire validity under the provisions of this chapter. As to any lands covered by a uranium lease and also by a pending uranium lease application, the right of mining location under this section, as between the owner of said lease and the owner of said application, shall be deemed as to such conflict area to be vested in the owner of said lease. As to any lands embraced in more than one such pending uranium lease application, such right of mining location, as between the owners of such conflicting applications, shall be deemed to be vested in the owner of the prior application. Priority of such an application shall be determined by the time of posting on a tract then available for such leasing of a notice of lease application in accordance with paragraph (c) of the Atomic Energy Commission’s Domestic Uranium Program Circular 7 (10 C.F.R. 60.7 (c)) provided there shall have been timely compliance with the other provisions of said paragraph (c) or, if there shall not have been such timely compliance, then by the time of the filing of the uranium lease application with the Atomic Energy Commission. Any rights under any mining claim located under the provisions of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_523_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to locate mining claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Right to locate mining claims Subject to the conditions and provisions of this chapter and to any valid prior rights acquired under the laws of the United States, the owner of any pending uranium lease application or of any uranium lease shall have, for a period of one hundred and twenty days after August 13, 1954, as limited in subsection (b) of this section, the right to locate mining claims upon the lands covered by said application or lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_523_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities and conflicting rights; termination of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priorities and conflicting rights; termination of rights Any rights under any such mining claim so hereafter located pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a) of this section shall be subject to any rights of the owner of any mining claim which was located prior to February 10, 1954, and which was valid on August 13, 1954 or which may acquire validity under the provisions of this chapter. As to any lands covered by a uranium lease and also by a pending uranium lease application, the right of mining location under this section, as between the owner of said lease and the owner of said application, shall be deemed as to such conflict area to be vested in the owner of said lease. As to any lands embraced in more than one such pending uranium lease application, such right of mining location, as between the owners of such conflicting applications, shall be deemed to be vested in the owner of the prior application. Priority of such an application shall be determined by the time of post</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_523_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Future claims on lands covered by application or lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Future claims on lands covered by application or lease Except as otherwise provided in subsections (a) and (b) of this section, no mining claim hereafter located shall be valid as to any lands which at the time of such location were covered by a uranium lease application or a uranium lease. Any tract upon which a notice of lease application has been posted in accordance with said paragraph (c) of said Circular 7 shall be deemed to have been included in a uranium lease application from and after the time of the posting of such notice of lease application: Provided, That there shall have been timely compliance with the other provisions of said paragraph (c) or, if there shall not have been such timely compliance, then from and after the time of the filing of a uranium lease application with the Atomic Energy Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>