<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/804" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/804/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/804/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_804"><akn:num>804</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim Compliance Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 804. Interim Compliance Panel(a) Establishment; compositionThere is hereby established the Interim Compliance Panel, which shall be composed of five members as follows:(1) Assistant Secretary of Labor for Labor Standards, Department of Labor, or his delegate;

(2) Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, Department of Commerce, or his delegate;

(3) Administrator of Consumer Protection and Environmental Health Service, Department of Health and Human Services, or his delegate;

(4) Director of the United States Bureau of Mines, Department of the Interior, or his delegate; and

(5) Director of the National Science Foundation, or his delegate.


(b) Compensation; travel and subsistence expensesMembers of the Panel shall serve without compensation in addition to that received in their regular employment, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of duties vested in the Panel.


(c) Cooperation of Federal agenciesNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary shall, upon request of the Panel, provide the Panel such personnel and other assistance as the Panel determines necessary to enable it to carry out its functions under this chapter.


(d) Quorum; voting; selection of chairmanThree members of the Panel shall constitute a quorum for doing business. All decisions of the Panel shall be by majority vote. The chairman of the Panel shall be selected by the members from among the membership thereof.


(e) Appointment of administrative law judges; provisions applicableThe Panel is authorized to appoint as many administrative law judges as are necessary for proceedings required to be conducted in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The provisions applicable to administrative law judges appointed under section 3105 of title 5 shall be appli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; composition There is hereby established the Interim Compliance Panel, which shall be composed of five members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation; travel and subsistence expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation; travel and subsistence expenses Members of the Panel shall serve without compensation in addition to that received in their regular employment, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of duties vested in the Panel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation of Federal agencies Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary shall, upon request of the Panel, provide the Panel such personnel and other assistance as the Panel determines necessary to enable it to carry out its functions under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum; voting; selection of chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Quorum; voting; selection of chairman Three members of the Panel shall constitute a quorum for doing business. All decisions of the Panel shall be by majority vote. The chairman of the Panel shall be selected by the members from among the membership thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of administrative law judges; provisions applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appointment of administrative law judges; provisions applicable The Panel is authorized to appoint as many administrative law judges as are necessary for proceedings required to be conducted in accordance with the provisions of this chapter. The provisions applicable to administrative law judges appointed under section 3105 of title 5 shall be applicable to administrative law judges appointed pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_804_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions; hearings; notice and review; termination; annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Functions; hearings; notice and review; termination; annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>