<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/817" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/817/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/817/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_817"><akn:num>817</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures to counteract dangerous conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 817. Procedures to counteract dangerous conditions(a) Withdrawal ordersIf, upon any inspection or investigation of a coal or other mine which is subject to this chapter, an authorized representative of the Secretary finds that an imminent danger exists, such representative shall determine the extent of the area of such mine throughout which the danger exists, and issue an order requiring the operator of such mine to cause all persons, except those referred to in section 814(c) of this title, to be withdrawn from, and to be prohibited from entering, such area until an authorized representative of the Secretary determines that such imminent danger and the conditions or practices which caused such imminent danger no longer exist. The issuance of an order under this subsection shall not preclude the issuance of a citation under section 814 of this title or the proposing of a penalty under section 820 of this title.


(b) Notice to mine operators; further investigation; findings and decision by Secretary(1) If, upon any inspection of a coal or other mine, an authorized representative of the Secretary finds (A) that conditions exist therein which have not yet resulted in an imminent danger, (B) that such conditions cannot be effectively abated through the use of existing technology, and (C) that reasonable assurance cannot be provided that the continuance of mining operations under such conditions will not result in an imminent danger, he shall determine the area throughout which such conditions exist, and thereupon issue a notice to the operator of the mine or his agent of such conditions, and shall file a copy thereof, incorporating his findings therein, with the Secretary and with the representative of the miners of such mine. Upon receipt of such copy, the Secretary shall cause such further investigation to be made as he deems appropriate, including an opportunity for the operator or a representative of the miners to present information relating to such notice.

(2)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_817_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Withdrawal orders If, upon any inspection or investigation of a coal or other mine which is subject to this chapter, an authorized representative of the Secretary finds that an imminent danger exists, such representative shall determine the extent of the area of such mine throughout which the danger exists, and issue an order requiring the operator of such mine to cause all persons, except those referred to in section 814(c) of this title, to be withdrawn from, and to be prohibited from entering, such area until an authorized representative of the Secretary determines that such imminent danger and the conditions or practices which caused such imminent danger no longer exist. The issuance of an order under this subsection shall not preclude the issuance of a citation under section 814 of this title or the proposing of a penalty under section 820 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_817_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to mine operators; further investigation; findings and decision by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice to mine operators; further investigation; findings and decision by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_817_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form and content of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form and content of orders Orders issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall contain a detailed description of the conditions or practices which cause and constitute an imminent danger and a description of the area of the coal or other mine from which persons must be withdrawn and prohibited from entering.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_817_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; duration of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Findings; duration of orders Each finding made and order issued under this section shall be given promptly to the operator of the coal or other mine to which it pertains by the person making such finding or order, and all of such findings and orders shall be in writing, and shall be signed by the person making them. Any order issued pursuant to subsection (a) may be modified or terminated by an authorized representative of the Secretary. Any order issued under subsection (a) or (b) shall remain in effect until vacated, modified, or terminated by the Secretary, or modified or vacated by the Commission pursuant to subsection (e), or by the courts pursuant to section 816(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_817_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reinstatement, modification, and vacatur of orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reinstatement, modification, and vacatur of orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>