<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/863" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/863/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/863/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_863"><akn:num>863</akn:num><akn:heading>Ventilation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 863. Ventilation(a) Equipment; approval; daily examinationsAll coal mines shall be ventilated by mechanical ventilation equipment installed and operated in a manner approved by an authorized representative of the Secretary and such equipment shall be examined daily and a record shall be kept of such examination.


(b) Standards for air in work areasAll active workings shall be ventilated by a current of air containing not less than 19.5 volume per centum of oxygen, not more than 0.5 volume per centum of carbon dioxide, and no harmful quantities of other noxious or poisonous gases; and the volume and velocity of the current of air shall be sufficient to dilute, render harmless, and to carry away, flammable, explosive, noxious, and harmful gases, and dust, and smoke and explosive fumes. The minimum quantity of air reaching the last open crosscut in any pair or set of developing entries and the last open crosscut in any pair or set of rooms shall be nine thousand cubic feet a minute, and the minimum quantity of air reaching the intake end of a pillar line shall be nine thousand cubic feet a minute. The minimum quantity of air in any coal mine reaching each working face shall be three thousand cubic feet a minute. Within three months after the operative date of this subchapter, the Secretary shall prescribe the minimum velocity and quantity of air reaching each working face of each coal mine in order to render harmless and carry away methane and other explosive gases and to reduce the level of respirable dust to the lowest attainable level. The authorized representative of the Secretary may require in any coal mine a greater quantity and velocity of air when he finds it necessary to protect the health or safety of miners. Within one year after the operative date of this subchapter, the Secretary or his authorized representative shall prescribe the maximum respirable dust level in the intake aircourses in each coal mine in order to reduce such level to the lowest attai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment; approval; daily examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Equipment; approval; daily examinations All coal mines shall be ventilated by mechanical ventilation equipment installed and operated in a manner approved by an authorized representative of the Secretary and such equipment shall be examined daily and a record shall be kept of such examination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for air in work areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards for air in work areas All active workings shall be ventilated by a current of air containing not less than 19.5 volume per centum of oxygen, not more than 0.5 volume per centum of carbon dioxide, and no harmful quantities of other noxious or poisonous gases; and the volume and velocity of the current of air shall be sufficient to dilute, render harmless, and to carry away, flammable, explosive, noxious, and harmful gases, and dust, and smoke and explosive fumes. The minimum quantity of air reaching the last open crosscut in any pair or set of developing entries and the last open crosscut in any pair or set of rooms shall be nine thousand cubic feet a minute, and the minimum quantity of air reaching the intake end of a pillar line shall be nine thousand cubic feet a minute. The minimum quantity of air in any coal mine reaching each working face shall be three thousand cubic feet a minute. Within three months after the operative date of this subchapter, the Secretary shall </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Line brattice; functions; exceptions; repairs; flame resistant material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Line brattice; functions; exceptions; repairs; flame resistant material</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-shift examinations and tests; scope; violations of mandatory standards; notification; posting of “DANGER” signs; restriction of entry; records; re-entry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pre-shift examinations and tests; scope; violations of mandatory standards; notification; posting of “DANGER” signs; restriction of entry; records; re-entry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Daily examinations and tests; scope; imminent danger; withdrawal of persons; abatement of danger</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Daily examinations and tests; scope; imminent danger; withdrawal of persons; abatement of danger At least once during each coal-producing shift, or more often if necessary for safety, each working section shall be examined for hazardous conditions by certified persons designated by the operator to do so. Any such condition shall be corrected immediately. If such condition creates an imminent danger, the operator shall withdraw all persons from the area affected by such condition to a safe area, except those persons referred to in section 814(d) of this title, until the danger is abated. Such examination shall include tests for methane with a means approved by the Secretary for detecting methane and for oxygen deficiency with a permissible flame safety lamp or other means approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weekly examination for hazardous conditions; scope; notification; repairs; imminent danger; withdrawal of persons; abatement; records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Weekly examination for hazardous conditions; scope; notification; repairs; imminent danger; withdrawal of persons; abatement; records In addition to the pre-shift and daily examinations required by this section, examinations for hazardous conditions, including tests for methane, and for compliance with the mandatory health or safety standards, shall be made at least once each week by a certified person designated by the operator in the return of each split of air where it enters the main return, on pillar falls, at seals, in the main return, at least one entry of each intake and return aircourse in its entirety, idle workings, and, insofar as safety considerations permit, abandoned areas. Such weekly examination need not be made during any week in which the mine is idle for the entire week, except that such examination shall be made before any other miner returns to the mine. The person making such examinations and tests shall place his initials and the date and time at the places </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Weekly ventilation examinations; scope; records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Weekly ventilation examinations; scope; records At least once each week, a qualified person shall measure the volume of air entering the main intakes and leaving the main returns, the volume passing through the last open crosscut in any pair or set of developing entries and the last open crosscut in any pair or set of rooms, the volume and, when the Secretary so prescribes, the velocity reaching each working face, the volume being delivered to the intake end of each pillar line, and the volume at the intake and return of each split of air. A record of such measurements shall be recorded in ink or indelible pencil in a book approved by the Secretary kept for such purpose in an area on the surface of the coal mine chosen by the operator to minimize the danger of destruction by fire or other hazard, and the record shall be open for inspection by interested persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methane examinations at working place; periodic intervals; standards; procedures for different air contents of methane</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Methane examinations at working place; periodic intervals; standards; procedures for different air contents of methane</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methane examination of air returning from working section; periodic intervals; standards; procedures for different air contents; virgin territory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Methane examination of air returning from working section; periodic intervals; standards; procedures for different air contents; virgin territory</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_863_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abandoned area air; pre-shift examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Abandoned area air; pre-shift examination Air which has passed by an opening of any abandoned area shall not be used to ventilate any working place in the coal mine if such air contains 0.25 volume per centum or more of methane. Examinations of such air shall be made during the pre-shift examination required by subsection (d) of this section. In making such tests, a certified person designated by the operator shall use means approved by the Secretary for detecting methane. For the purposes of this subsection, an area within a panel shall not be deemed to be abandoned until such panel is abandoned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>