<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/868" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/868/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/868/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_868"><akn:num>868</akn:num><akn:heading>Underground high-voltage distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 868. Underground high-voltage distribution(a) Circuits entering underground areas of mines; circuit breakersHigh-voltage circuits entering the underground area of any coal mine shall be protected by suitable circuit breakers of adequate interrupting capacity which are properly tested and maintained as prescribed by the Secretary. Such breakers shall be equipped with devices to provide protection against under-voltage, grounded phase, short circuit, and overcurrent.


(b) Circuits extending underground and supplying equipment; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames, exceptions; location of disconnection devices, exceptionsHigh-voltage circuits extending underground and supplying portable, mobile, or stationary high-voltage equipment shall contain either a direct or derived neutral which shall be grounded through a suitable resistor at the source transformers, and a grounding circuit, originating at the grounded side of the grounding resistor, shall extend along with the power conductors and serve as a grounding conductor for the frames of all high-voltage equipment supplied power from that circuit, except that the Secretary or his authorized representative may permit ungrounded high-voltage circuits to be extended underground to feed stationary electrical equipment if such circuits are either steel armored or installed in grounded, rigid steel conduit throughout their entire length, and upon his finding that such exception does not pose a hazard to the miners. Within one hundred feet of the point on the surface where high-voltage circuits enter the underground portion of the mine, disconnecting devices shall be installed and so equipped or designed in such a manner that it can be determined by visual observation that the power is disconnected, except that the Secretary or his authorized representative may permit such devices to be installed at a greater distance from such area of the mine if he determines, based on existing physical conditions, that s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuits entering underground areas of mines; circuit breakers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Circuits entering underground areas of mines; circuit breakers High-voltage circuits entering the underground area of any coal mine shall be protected by suitable circuit breakers of adequate interrupting capacity which are properly tested and maintained as prescribed by the Secretary. Such breakers shall be equipped with devices to provide protection against under-voltage, grounded phase, short circuit, and overcurrent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuits extending underground and supplying equipment; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames, exceptions; location of disconnection devices, exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Circuits extending underground and supplying equipment; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames, exceptions; location of disconnection devices, exceptions High-voltage circuits extending underground and supplying portable, mobile, or stationary high-voltage equipment shall contain either a direct or derived neutral which shall be grounded through a suitable resistor at the source transformers, and a grounding circuit, originating at the grounded side of the grounding resistor, shall extend along with the power conductors and serve as a grounding conductor for the frames of all high-voltage equipment supplied power from that circuit, except that the Secretary or his authorized representative may permit ungrounded high-voltage circuits to be extended underground to feed stationary electrical equipment if such circuits are either steel armored or installed in grounded, rigid steel conduit throughout their entire length, and upon his finding that such exception does not po</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grounding resistors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grounding resistors The grounding resistor, where required, shall be of the proper ohmic value to limit the voltage drop in the grounding circuit external to the resistor to not more than 100 volts under fault conditions. The grounding resistor shall be rated for maximum fault current continuously and insulated from ground for a voltage equal to the phase-to-phase voltage of the system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of fail safe ground check circuits in resistance grounded systems; operative functions; time extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusion of fail safe ground check circuits in resistance grounded systems; operative functions; time extension Six months after the operative date of this subchapter, high-voltage, resistance grounded systems shall include a fail safe ground check circuit to monitor continuously the grounding circuit to assure continuity and the fail safe ground check circuit shall cause the circuit breaker to open when either the ground or pilot check wire is broken, or other no less effective device approved by the Secretary or his authorized representative to assure such continuity, except that an extension of time, not in excess of twelve months, may be permitted by the Secretary on a mine-by-mine basis if he determines that such equipment is not available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Underground cables used in resistance grounded systems; metallic shields for power conductors; standards; splices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Underground cables used in resistance grounded systems; metallic shields for power conductors; standards; splices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Couplers for power circuits; guidelines for construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Couplers for power circuits; guidelines for construction Couplers that are used with medium-voltage or high-voltage power circuits shall be of the three-phase type with a full metallic shell, except that the Secretary may permit, under such guidelines as he may prescribe, no less effective couplers constructed of materials other than metal. Couplers shall be adequate for the voltage and current expected. All exposed metal on the metallic couplers shall be grounded to the ground conductor in the cable. The coupler shall be constructed so that the ground check continuity conductor shall be broken first and the ground conductors shall be broken last when the coupler is being uncoupled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Connections of single-phase loads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Connections of single-phase loads Single-phase loads, such as transformer primaries, shall be connected phase to phase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Installation of underground transmission cables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Installation of underground transmission cables All underground high-voltage transmission cables shall be installed only in regularly inspected air courses and haulageways, and shall be covered, buried, or placed so as to afford protection against damage, guarded where men regularly work or pass under them unless they are six and one-half feet or more above the floor or rail, securely anchored, properly insulated, and guarded at ends, and covered, insulated, or placed to prevent contact with trolley wires and other low-voltage circuits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disconnection devices; location; visual observation of position of switch</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disconnection devices; location; visual observation of position of switch Disconnecting devices shall be installed at the beginning of branch lines in high-voltage circuits and equipped or designed in such a manner that it can be determined by visual observation that the circuit is deenergized when the switches are open.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_868_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuit breakers and disconnection devices; markings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Circuit breakers and disconnection devices; markings Circuit breakers and disconnecting switches underground shall be marked for identification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>