<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/869" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/869/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/869/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_869"><akn:num>869</akn:num><akn:heading>Underground low- and medium-voltage alternating current circuits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 869. Underground low- and medium-voltage alternating current circuits(a) Circuits providing power for three-phase equipment; circuit breakersLow- and medium-voltage power circuits serving three-phase alternating current equipment shall be protected by suitable circuit breakers of adequate interrupting capacity which are properly tested and maintained as prescribed by the Secretary. Such breakers shall be equipped with devices to provide protection against under-voltage, grounded phase, short circuit, and over-current.


(b) Circuits used underground; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames; exceptions; grounding resistorsLow- and medium-voltage three-phase alternating-current circuits used underground shall contain either a direct or derived neutral which shall be grounded through a suitable resistor at the power center, and a grounding circuit, originating at the grounded side of the grounding resistor, shall extend along with the power conductors and serve as a grounding conductor for the frames of all the electrical equipment supplied power from that circuit, except that the Secretary or his authorized representative may permit ungrounded low- and medium-voltage circuits to be used underground to feed such stationary electrical equipment if such circuits are either steel armored or installed in grounded rigid steel conduit throughout their entire length. The grounding resistor, where required, shall be of the proper ohmic value to limit the ground fault current to 25 amperes. The grounding resistor shall be rated for maximum fault current continuously and insulated from ground for a voltage equal to the phase-to-phase voltage of the system.


(c) Inclusion of fail safe ground check circuits in resistance ground systems; operative functions; time extension; couplers for power circuits; guidelines for constructionSix months after the operative date of this subchapter, low- and medium-voltage resistance grounded systems shall include a fail safe groun</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuits providing power for three-phase equipment; circuit breakers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Circuits providing power for three-phase equipment; circuit breakers Low- and medium-voltage power circuits serving three-phase alternating current equipment shall be protected by suitable circuit breakers of adequate interrupting capacity which are properly tested and maintained as prescribed by the Secretary. Such breakers shall be equipped with devices to provide protection against under-voltage, grounded phase, short circuit, and over-current.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuits used underground; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames; exceptions; grounding resistors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Circuits used underground; direct neutral grounds; ground conductors for frames; exceptions; grounding resistors Low- and medium-voltage three-phase alternating-current circuits used underground shall contain either a direct or derived neutral which shall be grounded through a suitable resistor at the power center, and a grounding circuit, originating at the grounded side of the grounding resistor, shall extend along with the power conductors and serve as a grounding conductor for the frames of all the electrical equipment supplied power from that circuit, except that the Secretary or his authorized representative may permit ungrounded low- and medium-voltage circuits to be used underground to feed such stationary electrical equipment if such circuits are either steel armored or installed in grounded rigid steel conduit throughout their entire length. The grounding resistor, where required, shall be of the proper ohmic value to limit the ground fault current to 25 amperes. The grou</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of fail safe ground check circuits in resistance ground systems; operative functions; time extension; couplers for power circuits; guidelines for construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inclusion of fail safe ground check circuits in resistance ground systems; operative functions; time extension; couplers for power circuits; guidelines for construction Six months after the operative date of this subchapter, low- and medium-voltage resistance grounded systems shall include a fail safe ground check circuit to monitor continuously the grounding circuit to assure continuity which ground check circuit shall cause the circuit breaker to open when either the ground or pilot check wire is broken, or other no less effective device approved by the Secretary or his authorized representative to assure such continuity, except that an extension of time, not in excess of twelve months, may be permitted by the Secretary on a mine-by-mine basis if he determines that such equipment is not available. Cable couplers shall be constructed so that the ground check continuity conductor shall be broken first and the ground conductors shall be broken last when the coupler is being uncouple</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disconnecting devices installed in conjunction with circuit breakers; purpose; trailing cables for mobile equipment; guidelines for construction; time extension; splices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disconnecting devices installed in conjunction with circuit breakers; purpose; trailing cables for mobile equipment; guidelines for construction; time extension; splices Disconnecting devices shall be installed in conjunction with the circuit breaker to provide visual evidence that the power is disconnected. Trailing cables for mobile equipment shall contain one or more ground conductors having a cross sectional area of not less than one-half the power conductor, and, six months after the operative date of this subchapter, an insulated conductor for the ground continuity check circuit or other no less effective device approved by the Secretary or his authorized representative to assure such continuity, except that an extension of time, not in excess of twelve months may be permitted by the Secretary on a mine-by-mine basis if he determines that such equipment is not available. Splices made in the cables shall provide continuity of all components.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Connections of single phase loads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Connections of single phase loads Single phase loads shall be connected phase to phase.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Circuit breakers; markings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Circuit breakers; markings Circuit breakers shall be marked for identification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_869_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trailing cables for medium voltage circuits; guidelines for construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Trailing cables for medium voltage circuits; guidelines for construction Trailing cables for medium voltage circuits shall include grounding conductors, a ground check conductor, and ground metallic shields around each power conductor or a grounded metallic shield over the assembly, except that on equipment employing cable reels, cables without shields may be used if the insulation is rated 2,000 volts or more.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>