<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/877" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/877/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/877/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_877"><akn:num>877</akn:num><akn:heading>General safety provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 877. General safety provisions(a) Location of oil and gas wells; establishment and maintenance of barriers; minimum requisites; exceptionsEach operator of a coal mine shall take reasonable measures to locate oil and gas wells penetrating coalbeds or any underground area of a coal mine. When located, such operator shall establish and maintain barriers around such oil and gas wells in accordance with State laws and regulations, except that such barriers shall not be less than three hundred feet in diameter, unless the Secretary or his authorized representative permits a lesser barrier consistent with the applicable State laws and regulations where such lesser barrier will be adequate to protect against hazards from such wells to the miners in such mine, or unless the Secretary or his authorized representative requires a greater barrier where the depth of the mine, other geologic conditions, or other factors warrant such a greater barrier.


(b) Boreholes in advance of work face; distance in advance of work face; distance between boreholesWhenever any working place approaches within fifty feet of abandoned areas in the mine as shown by surveys made and certified by a registered engineer or surveyor, or within two hundred feet of any other abandoned areas of the mine which cannot be inspected and which may contain dangerous accumulations of water or gas, or within two hundred feet of any workings of an adjacent mine, a borehole or boreholes shall be drilled to a distance of at least twenty feet in advance of the working face of such working place and shall be continually maintained to a distance of at least ten feet in advance of the advancing working face. When there is more than one borehole, they shall be drilled sufficiently close to each other to insure that the advancing working face will not accidentally hole through into abandoned areas or adjacent mines. Boreholes shall also be drilled not more than eight feet apart in the rib of such working place to a dista</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of oil and gas wells; establishment and maintenance of barriers; minimum requisites; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Location of oil and gas wells; establishment and maintenance of barriers; minimum requisites; exceptions Each operator of a coal mine shall take reasonable measures to locate oil and gas wells penetrating coalbeds or any underground area of a coal mine. When located, such operator shall establish and maintain barriers around such oil and gas wells in accordance with State laws and regulations, except that such barriers shall not be less than three hundred feet in diameter, unless the Secretary or his authorized representative permits a lesser barrier consistent with the applicable State laws and regulations where such lesser barrier will be adequate to protect against hazards from such wells to the miners in such mine, or unless the Secretary or his authorized representative requires a greater barrier where the depth of the mine, other geologic conditions, or other factors warrant such a greater barrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Boreholes in advance of work face; distance in advance of work face; distance between boreholes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Boreholes in advance of work face; distance in advance of work face; distance between boreholes Whenever any working place approaches within fifty feet of abandoned areas in the mine as shown by surveys made and certified by a registered engineer or surveyor, or within two hundred feet of any other abandoned areas of the mine which cannot be inspected and which may contain dangerous accumulations of water or gas, or within two hundred feet of any workings of an adjacent mine, a borehole or boreholes shall be drilled to a distance of at least twenty feet in advance of the working face of such working place and shall be continually maintained to a distance of at least ten feet in advance of the advancing working face. When there is more than one borehole, they shall be drilled sufficiently close to each other to insure that the advancing working face will not accidentally hole through into abandoned areas or adjacent mines. Boreholes shall also be drilled not more than eight feet apa</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against smoking; implementation programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition against smoking; implementation programs No person shall smoke, carry smoking materials, matches, or lighters underground, or smoke in or around oil houses, explosives magazines, or other surface areas where such practice may cause a fire or explosion. The operator shall institute a program, approved by the Secretary, to insure that any person entering the underground area of the mine does not carry smoking materials, matches, or lighters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portable electric lamps; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Portable electric lamps; exceptions Persons underground shall use only permissible electric lamps approved by the Secretary for portable illumination. No open flame shall be permitted in the underground area of any coal mine, except as permitted under section 871(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of lighting standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Promulgation of lighting standards Within nine months after the operative date of this subchapter, the Secretary shall propose the standards under which all working places in a mine shall be illuminated by permissible lighting, within eighteen months after the promulgation of such standards, while persons are working in such places.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Escapeways; ventilation; maintenance; tests of passageways; protection of entrance; connection between mine openings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Escapeways; ventilation; maintenance; tests of passageways; protection of entrance; connection between mine openings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Erection of fireproof structures; prior existing structures; fire doors; monthly tests; records; availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Erection of fireproof structures; prior existing structures; fire doors; monthly tests; records; availability After the operative date of this subchapter, all structures erected on the surface within one hundred feet of any mine opening shall be of fireproof construction. Unless structures existing on or prior to such date which are located within one hundred feet of any mine opening are of such construction, fire doors shall be erected at effective points in mine openings to prevent smoke or fire from outside sources endangering miners underground. These doors shall be tested at least monthly to insure effective operation. A record of such tests shall be kept in an area on the surface of the mine chosen by the operator to minimize the danger of destruction by fire or other hazard and shall be available for inspection by interested persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of accumulations of coal dust and methane gas; surface coal-handling facilities; air-intake openings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prevention of accumulations of coal dust and methane gas; surface coal-handling facilities; air-intake openings Adequate measures shall be taken to prevent methane and coal dust from accumulating in excessive concentrations in or on surface coal-handling facilities, but in no event shall methane be permitted to accumulate in concentrations in or on surface coal-handling facilities in excess of limits established for methane by the Secretary within one year after the operative date of this subchapter. Where coal is dumped at or near air-intake openings, provisions shall be made to avoid dust from entering the mine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Training programs Every operator of a coal mine shall provide a program, approved by the Secretary, of training and retraining of both qualified and certified persons needed to carry out functions prescribed in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_877_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electric face equipment; installation of canopies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Electric face equipment; installation of canopies An authorized representative of the Secretary may require in any coal mine where the height of the coalbed permits that electric face equipment, including shuttle cars, be provided with substantially constructed canopies or cabs to protect the miners operating such equipment from roof falls and from rib and face rolls.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>