<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/931" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/931/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/931/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_931"><akn:num>931</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits under State workmen’s compensation laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 931. Benefits under State workmen’s compensation laws(a) FilingOn and after January 1, 1974, any claim for benefits for death or total disability due to pneumoconiosis shall be filed pursuant to the applicable State workmen’s compensation law, except that during any period when miners or their surviving widows, children, parents, brothers, or sisters, as the case may be, are not covered by a State workmen’s compensation law which provides adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis, and in any case in which benefits based upon eligibility under paragraph (5) of section 921(c) of this title are involved.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma. they shall be entitled to claim benefits under this part.


(b) Adequacy of compensation; listing of States providing adequate compensation; requisites for listing(1) For purposes of this section, a State workmen’s compensation law shall not be deemed to provide adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis during any period unless it is included in the list of State laws found by the Secretary to provide such adequate coverage during such period. The Secretary shall, no later than October 1, 1972, publish in the Federal Register a list of State workmen’s compensation laws which provide adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis and shall revise and republish in the Federal Register such list from time to time, as may be appropriate to reflect changes in such State laws due to legislation or judicial or administrative interpretation.

(2) The Secretary shall include a State workmen’s compensation law on such list during any period only if he finds that during such period under such law—(A) benefits must be paid for total disability or death of a miner due to pneumoconiosis, except that (i) such law shall not be required to provide such benefits where the miner’s last employment in a coal mine terminated before the Secretary’s approval of the State law pursuant to this section; and (ii) each operator of a coal mine shall secure the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_931_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Filing On and after January 1, 1974, any claim for benefits for death or total disability due to pneumoconiosis shall be filed pursuant to the applicable State workmen’s compensation law, except that during any period when miners or their surviving widows, children, parents, brothers, or sisters, as the case may be, are not covered by a State workmen’s compensation law which provides adequate coverage for pneumoconiosis, and in any case in which benefits based upon eligibility under paragraph (5) of section 921(c) of this title are involved.11 So in original. The period probably should be a comma. they shall be entitled to claim benefits under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_931_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adequacy of compensation; listing of States providing adequate compensation; requisites for listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adequacy of compensation; listing of States providing adequate compensation; requisites for listing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_931_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register; review of listings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication in Federal Register; review of listings Final regulations required for implementation of any amendments to this part shall be promulgated and published in the Federal Register at the earliest practicable date after the date of enactment of such amendments, and in no event later than the end of the sixth month following the month in which such amendments are enacted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>