<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/936" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/936/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/936/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_936"><akn:num>936</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 936. Regulations and reports(a) Promulgation; applicability of section 553 of title 5The Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Health and Human Services are authorized to issue such regulations as each deems appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subchapter. Such regulations shall be issued in conformity with section 553 of title 5, notwithstanding subsection (a) thereof.


(b) Annual reports to CongressAt the end of fiscal year 2003 and each succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the subject matter of this part and part B of this subchapter. Each such report shall be prepared and submitted to Congress in accordance with the requirement with respect to submission under section 942 of title 33.


(c) Compliance with State workmen’s compensation laws; conflicts between State and Federal provisionsNothing in this subchapter shall relieve any operator of the duty to comply with any State workmen’s compensation law, except insofar as such State law is in conflict with the provisions of this subchapter and the Secretary by regulation, so prescribes. The provisions of any State workmen’s compensation law which provide greater benefits than the benefits payable under this subchapter shall not thereby be construed or held to be in conflict with the provisions of this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 91–173, title IV, § 426, Dec. 30, 1969, 83 Stat. 798; Pub. L. 92–303, § 5(3), May 19, 1972, 86 Stat. 155; Pub. L. 103–296, title I, § 108(i)(3), Aug. 15, 1994, 108 Stat. 1488; Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1102(b)(2), Dec. 21, 1995, 109 Stat. 723; Pub. L. 107–275, § 2(b)(4), Nov. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 1926.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 942 of title 33, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “section 42 of the Longshore Harbor Worker’s Compensation Act” and was translated as reading “section 42 of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act” to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation; applicability of section 553 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Promulgation; applicability of section 553 of title 5 The Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Health and Human Services are authorized to issue such regulations as each deems appropriate to carry out the provisions of this subchapter. Such regulations shall be issued in conformity with section 553 of title 5, notwithstanding subsection (a) thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Annual reports to Congress At the end of fiscal year 2003 and each succeeding fiscal year, the Secretary of Labor shall submit to the Congress an annual report on the subject matter of this part and part B of this subchapter. Each such report shall be prepared and submitted to Congress in accordance with the requirement with respect to submission under section 942 of title 33.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_936_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with State workmen’s compensation laws; conflicts between State and Federal provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance with State workmen’s compensation laws; conflicts between State and Federal provisions Nothing in this subchapter shall relieve any operator of the duty to comply with any State workmen’s compensation law, except insofar as such State law is in conflict with the provisions of this subchapter and the Secretary by regulation, so prescribes. The provisions of any State workmen’s compensation law which provide greater benefits than the benefits payable under this subchapter shall not thereby be construed or held to be in conflict with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>