<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/943" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/943/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/943/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_943"><akn:num>943</akn:num><akn:heading>Black lung insurance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 943. Black lung insurance program(a) Authorization to establish and carry outThe Secretary is authorized to establish and carry out a black lung insurance program which will enable operators of coal mines to purchase insurance covering their obligations under section 932 of this title.


(b) Non-availability of other insurance coverageThe Secretary may exercise his or her authority under this section only if, and to the extent that, insurance coverage is not otherwise available, at reasonable cost, to operators of coal mines.


(c) Agreements with coal mine operators; reinsurance agreements(1) The Secretary may enter into agreements with operators of coal mines who may be liable for the payment of benefits under section 932 of this title, under which the Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund established under subsection (a) (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “insurance fund”) shall assume all or part of the liability of such operator in return for the payment of premiums to the insurance fund, and on such terms and conditions as will fully protect the financial solvency of the insurance fund. During any period in which such agreement is in effect the operator shall be deemed in compliance with the requirements of section 933 of this title with respect to the risks covered by such agreement.

(2) The Secretary may also enter into reinsurance agreements with one or more insurers or pools of insurers under which, in return for the payment of premiums to the insurance fund, and on such terms and conditions as will fully protect the financial solvency of the insurance fund, the insurance fund shall provide reinsurance coverage for benefits required to be paid under section 932 of this title.


(d) Terms and conditions of insurabilityThe Secretary may by regulation provide for general terms and conditions of insurability as applicable to operators of coal mines or insurers eligible for insurance or reinsurance under this section, including—(1) the types, c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to establish and carry out</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization to establish and carry out The Secretary is authorized to establish and carry out a black lung insurance program which will enable operators of coal mines to purchase insurance covering their obligations under section 932 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-availability of other insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Non-availability of other insurance coverage The Secretary may exercise his or her authority under this section only if, and to the extent that, insurance coverage is not otherwise available, at reasonable cost, to operators of coal mines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with coal mine operators; reinsurance agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements with coal mine operators; reinsurance agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of insurability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions of insurability The Secretary may by regulation provide for general terms and conditions of insurability as applicable to operators of coal mines or insurers eligible for insurance or reinsurance under this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Premium schedule studies and investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Premium schedule studies and investigations The Secretary may undertake and carry out such studies and investigations, and receive or exchange such information, as may be necessary to formulate a premium schedule which will enable the insurance and reinsurance authorized by this section to be provided on a basis which is (1) in accordance with accepted actuarial principles; and (2) fair and equitable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations relating to premium rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations relating to premium rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Black Lung Compensation Insurance Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_943_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the insurance fund, as repayable advances, such sums as may be necessary to meet obligations incurred under subsection (g). All such sums shall remain available without fiscal year limitation. Advances made pursuant to this subsection shall be repaid, with interest, to the general fund of the Treasury when the Secretary determines that moneys are available in the insurance fund for such repayments. Interest on such advances shall be computed in the same manner as provided in subsection (b)(2) of section 934a 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>