<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/951" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/951/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/30/951/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_951"><akn:num>951</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 951. Studies and research(a) Appropriate projectsThe Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, shall conduct such studies, research, experiments, and demonstrations as may be appropriate—(1) to improve working conditions and practices in coal or other mines, and to prevent accidents and occupational diseases originating in the coal or other mining industry;

(2) to develop new or improved methods of recovering persons in coal or other mines after an accident;

(3) to develop new or improved means and methods of communication from the surface to the underground area of a coal or other mine;

(4) to develop new or improved means and methods of reducing concentrations of respirable dust in the mine atmosphere of active workings of the coal or other mine;

(5) to develop epidemiological information to (A) identify and define positive factors involved in occupational diseases of miners, (B) provide information on the incidence and prevalence of pneumoconiosis and other respiratory ailments of miners, and (C) improve mandatory health standards;

(6) to develop techniques for the prevention and control of occupational diseases of miners, including tests for hypersusceptibility and early detection;

(7) to evaluate the effect on bodily impairment and occupational disability of miners afflicted with an occupational disease;

(8) to prepare and publish from time to time, reports on all significant aspects of occupational diseases of miners as well as on the medical aspects of injuries, other than diseases, which are revealed by the research carried on pursuant to this subsection;

(9) to study the relationship between coal or other mine environments and occupational diseases of miners;

(10) to develop new and improved underground equipment and other sources of power for such equipment which will provide greater safety;

(11) to determine, upon the written request by any operator or authorized representative of miners, specify</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriate projects The Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate, shall conduct such studies, research, experiments, and demonstrations as may be appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibility for carrying out prescribed activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibility for carrying out prescribed activities Activities under this section in the field of coal or other mine health shall be carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services through the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health established under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.], and activities under this section in the field of coal or other mine safety shall be carried out by the Secretary of the Interior in coordination with the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting with and grants to public and private agencies; availability of information; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contracting with and grants to public and private agencies; availability of information; exceptions In carrying out the provisions for research, demonstrations, experiments, studies, training, and education under this section and sections 861(b) and 952(a) of this title, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Health and Human Services in coordination with the Secretary may enter into contracts with, and make grants to, public and private agencies and organizations and individuals. No research, demonstrations, or experiments shall be carried out, contracted for, sponsored, cosponsored, or authorized under authority of this chapter, unless all information, uses, products, processes, patents, and other developments resulting from such research, demonstrations, or experiments will (with such exception and limitation, if any, as the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Health and Human Services in coordination with the Secretary may find to be necessary in the publi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention of diseases affecting persons working with mine products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prevention of diseases affecting persons working with mine products The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall also conduct studies and research into matters involving the protection of life and the prevention of diseases in connection with persons, who although not miners, work with, or around the products of, coal or other mines in areas outside of such mines and under conditions which may adversely affect the health and well-being of such persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior such sums as may be necessary to carry out his responsibilities under this section and section 861(b) of this title at an annual rate of not to exceed $20,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1970, $25,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1971, and $60,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1972, and for each succeeding fiscal year thereafter. There is authorized to be appropriated annually to the Secretary of Health and Human Services such sums as may be necessary to carry out his responsibilities under this chapter. Such sums shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions to mandatory health and safety standards for improving techniques and equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exceptions to mandatory health and safety standards for improving techniques and equipment The Secretary is authorized to grant on a mine-by-mine basis an exception to any mandatory health or safety standard under this chapter for the purpose of permitting, under such terms and conditions as he may prescribe, accredited educational institutions the opportunity for experimenting with new and improved techniques and equipment to improve the health and safety of miners. No such exception shall be granted unless the Secretary finds that the granting of the exception will not adversely affect the health and safety of miners and publishes his findings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_951_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for research and development of respiratory equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grants for research and development of respiratory equipment The Secretary of Health and Human Services is authorized to make grants to any public or private agency, institution, or organization, and operators or individuals for research and experiments to develop effective respiratory equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>