<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1003"><akn:num>1003</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1003. Additional definitions
In this chapter:(1) Authorizing committeesThe term “authorizing committees” means the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives.


(2) Combination of institutions of higher educationThe term “combination of institutions of higher education” means a group of institutions of higher education that have entered into a cooperative arrangement for the purpose of carrying out a common objective, or a public or private nonprofit agency, organization, or institution designated or created by a group of institutions of higher education for the purpose of carrying out a common objective on the group’s behalf.


(3) Critical foreign languageExcept as otherwise provided, the term “critical foreign language” means each of the languages contained in the list of critical languages designated by the Secretary in the Federal Register on August 2, 1985 (50 Fed. Reg. 31412; promulgated under the authority of section 212(d) of the Education for Economic Security Act (repealed by section 2303 of the Augustus F. Hawkins-Robert T. Stafford Elementary and Secondary School Improvement Amendments of 1988)), as updated by the Secretary from time to time and published in the Federal Register, except that in the implementation of this definition with respect to a specific title, the Secretary may set priorities according to the purposes of such title and the national security, economic competitiveness, and educational needs of the United States.


(4) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Education.


(5) Diploma millThe term “diploma mill” means an entity that—(A)(i) offers, for a fee, degrees, diplomas, or certificates, that may be used to represent to the general public that the individual possessing such a degree, diploma, or certificate has completed a program of postsecondary education or training; and

(ii) requires such individual to complete li</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizing committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Authorizing committees The term “authorizing committees” means the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combination of institutions of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Combination of institutions of higher education The term “combination of institutions of higher education” means a group of institutions of higher education that have entered into a cooperative arrangement for the purpose of carrying out a common objective, or a public or private nonprofit agency, organization, or institution designated or created by a group of institutions of higher education for the purpose of carrying out a common objective on the group’s behalf.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Critical foreign language</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Critical foreign language Except as otherwise provided, the term “critical foreign language” means each of the languages contained in the list of critical languages designated by the Secretary in the Federal Register on August 2, 1985 (50 Fed. Reg. 31412; promulgated under the authority of section 212(d) of the Education for Economic Security Act (repealed by section 2303 of the Augustus F. Hawkins-Robert T. Stafford Elementary and Secondary School Improvement Amendments of 1988)), as updated by the Secretary from time to time and published in the Federal Register, except that in the implementation of this definition with respect to a specific title, the Secretary may set priorities according to the purposes of such title and the national security, economic competitiveness, and educational needs of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diploma mill</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Diploma mill The term “diploma mill” means an entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Disability The term “disability” has the same meaning given that term under section 12102(2) of title 42.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distance education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Distance education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early childhood education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Early childhood education program The term “early childhood education program” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elementary school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Elementary school The term “elementary school” has the same meaning given that term under section 7801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1003_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifted and talented</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Gifted and talented The term “gifted and talented” has the same meaning given that term under section 7801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>