<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1011b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1011b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1011b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1011b"><akn:num>1011b</akn:num><akn:heading>Territorial waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1011b. Territorial waiver authority
The Secretary is required to waive the eligibility criteria of any postsecondary education program administered by the Department where such criteria do not take into account the unique circumstances in Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Freely Associated States.
(Pub. L. 89–329, title I, § 113, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title I, § 101(a), Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1591; amended Pub. L. 110–315, title I, § 105, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3090.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to this section were contained in section 1144a of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–244.
A prior section 1011b, Pub. L. 89–329, title I, § 123, as added Pub. L. 102–325, title I, § 101, July 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 462, related to State applications for grants, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 105–244.

Amendments2008—Pub. L. 110–315 substituted “Territorial waiver authority” for “Treatment of territories and territorial student assistance” in section catchline and struck out subsec. (a) designation and heading and subsec. (b). Text of former subsec. (b) read as follows: “Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an institution of higher education that is located in any of the Freely Associated States, rather than in another State, shall be eligible, if otherwise qualified, for assistance under division 1 of subpart 2 of part A of subchapter IV of this chapter. This subsection shall cease to be effective on September 30, 2004.”</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>