<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1015e"><akn:num>1015e</akn:num><akn:heading>State higher education information system pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1015e. State higher education information system pilot program(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to carry out a pilot program to assist not more than five States to develop State-level postsecondary student data systems to—(1) improve the capacity of States and institutions of higher education to generate more comprehensive and comparable data, in order to develop better-informed educational policy at the State level and to evaluate the effectiveness of institutional performance while protecting the confidentiality of students’ personally identifiable information; and

(2) identify how to best minimize the data-reporting burden placed on institutions of higher education, particularly smaller institutions, and to maximize and improve the information institutions receive from the data systems, in order to assist institutions in improving educational practice and postsecondary outcomes.


(b) Definition of eligible entityIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(1) a State higher education system; or

(2) a consortium of State higher education systems, or a consortium of individual institutions of higher education, that is broadly representative of institutions in different sectors and geographic locations.


(c) Competitive grants(1) Grants authorizedThe Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to not more than five eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to—(A) design, test, and implement systems of postsecondary student data that provide the maximum benefits to States, institutions of higher education, and State policymakers; and

(B) examine the costs and burdens involved in implementing a State-level postsecondary student data system.


(2) DurationA grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than three years.



(d) Application requirementsAn eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such informati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to carry out a pilot program to assist not more than five States to develop State-level postsecondary student data systems to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of eligible entity In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Competitive grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application requirements An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds A grant awarded under this section shall be used to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation; reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluation; reports Not later than six months after the end of the projects funded by grants awarded under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>