<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1015"><akn:num>1015</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvements in market information and public accountability in higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1015. Improvements in market information and public accountability in higher education(a) Improved data collection(1) Development of uniform methodologyThe Secretary shall direct the Commissioner of Education Statistics to convene a series of forums to develop nationally consistent methodologies for reporting costs incurred by postsecondary institutions in providing postsecondary education.


(2) Redesign of data systemsOn the basis of the methodologies developed pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary shall redesign relevant parts of the postsecondary education data systems to improve the usefulness and timeliness of the data collected by such systems.


(3) Information to institutionsThe Commissioner of Education Statistics shall—(A) develop a standard definition for the following data elements:(i) tuition and fees for a full-time undergraduate student;

(ii) cost of attendance for a full-time undergraduate student, consistent with the provisions of section 1087ll of this title;

(iii) average amount of financial assistance received by an undergraduate student who attends an institution of higher education, including—(I) each type of assistance or benefit described in section 1078(a)(2)(C)(ii) of this title;

(II) fellowships; and

(III) institutional and other assistance; and


(iv) number of students receiving financial assistance described in each of subclauses (I), (II), and (III) of clause (iii);


(B) not later than 90 days after October 7, 1998, report the definitions to each institution of higher education and within a reasonable period of time thereafter inform the authorizing committees of those definitions; and

(C) collect information regarding the data elements described in subparagraph (A) with respect to at least all institutions of higher education participating in programs under subchapter IV, beginning with the information from academic year 2000–2001 and annually thereafter.



(b) Data disseminationThe Secretary shall make available the data</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Improved data collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data dissemination The Secretary shall make available the data collected pursuant to subsection (a). Such data shall be available in a form that permits the review and comparison of the data submissions of individual institutions of higher education. Such data shall be presented in a form that is easily understandable and allows parents and students to make informed decisions based on the costs for typical full-time undergraduate students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of the Department of Education Federal student financial aid website</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Promotion of the Department of Education Federal student financial aid website The Secretary shall display a link to the Federal student financial aid website of the Department in a prominent place on the homepage of the Department’s website.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced student financial aid information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enhanced student financial aid information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved availability and coordination of information concerning student financial aid programs for military members and veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Improved availability and coordination of information concerning student financial aid programs for military members and veterans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of availability of information concerning other student financial aid programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Promotion of availability of information concerning other student financial aid programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>No user fees for Department financial aid websites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No user fees for Department financial aid websites No fee shall be charged to any individual to access—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>