<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1015b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1015b"><akn:num>1015b</akn:num><akn:heading>Textbook information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1015b. Textbook information(a) Purpose and intentThe purpose of this section is to ensure that students have access to affordable course materials by decreasing costs to students and enhancing transparency and disclosure with respect to the selection, purchase, sale, and use of course materials. It is the intent of this section to encourage all of the involved parties, including faculty, students, administrators, institutions of higher education, bookstores, distributors, and publishers, to work together to identify ways to decrease the cost of college textbooks and supplemental materials for students while supporting the academic freedom of faculty members to select high quality course materials for students.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BundleThe term “bundle” means one or more college textbooks or other supplemental materials that may be packaged together to be sold as course materials for one price.


(2) College textbookThe term “college textbook” means a textbook or a set of textbooks, used for, or in conjunction with, a course in postsecondary education at an institution of higher education.


(3) Course scheduleThe term “course schedule” means a listing of the courses or classes offered by an institution of higher education for an academic period, as defined by the institution.


(4) Custom textbookThe term “custom textbook”—(A) means a college textbook that is compiled by a publisher at the direction of a faculty member or other person or adopting entity in charge of selecting course materials at an institution of higher education; and

(B) may include, alone or in combination, items such as selections from original instructor materials, previously copyrighted publisher materials, copyrighted third-party works, and elements unique to a specific institution, such as commemorative editions.


(5) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1002 of this title.


(6) Integrated te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and intent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose and intent The purpose of this section is to ensure that students have access to affordable course materials by decreasing costs to students and enhancing transparency and disclosure with respect to the selection, purchase, sale, and use of course materials. It is the intent of this section to encourage all of the involved parties, including faculty, students, administrators, institutions of higher education, bookstores, distributors, and publishers, to work together to identify ways to decrease the cost of college textbooks and supplemental materials for students while supporting the academic freedom of faculty members to select high quality course materials for students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publisher requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publisher requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of ISBN college textbook information in course schedules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of ISBN college textbook information in course schedules To the maximum extent practicable, each institution of higher education receiving Federal financial assistance shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of information for college bookstores</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of information for college bookstores An institution of higher education receiving Federal financial assistance shall make available to a college bookstore that is operated by, or in a contractual relationship or otherwise affiliated with, the institution, as soon as is practicable upon the request of such college bookstore, the most accurate information available regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional information An institution disclosing the information required by subsection (d)(1) is encouraged to disseminate to students information regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) GAO report Not later than July 1, 2013, the Comptroller General of the United States shall report to the authorizing committees on the implementation of this section by institutions of higher education, college bookstores, and publishers. The report shall particularly examine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to supercede the institutional autonomy or academic freedom of instructors involved in the selection of college textbooks, supplemental materials, and other classroom materials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1015b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>No regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) No regulatory authority The Secretary shall not promulgate regulations with respect to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>