<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1018a"><akn:num>1018a</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1018a. Procurement flexibility(a) Procurement authoritySubject to the authority of the Secretary, the Chief Operating Officer of a PBO may exercise the authority of the Secretary to procure property and services in the performance of functions managed by the PBO. For the purposes of this section, the term “PBO” includes the Chief Operating Officer of the PBO and any employee of the PBO exercising procurement authority under the preceding sentence.


(b) In generalExcept as provided in this section, the PBO shall abide by all applicable Federal procurement laws and regulations when procuring property and services. The PBO shall—(1) enter into contracts to carry out the functions set forth in section 1018(b)(2) of this title;

(2) obtain the services of experts and consultants without regard to section 3109 of title 5 and set pay in accordance with such section; and

(3) through the Chief Operating Officer—(A) to the maximum extent practicable, utilize procurement systems that streamline operations, improve internal controls, and enhance management; and

(B) assess the efficiency of such systems and assess such systems’ ability to meet PBO requirements.



(c) Service contracts(1) Performance-based servicing contractsThe Chief Operating Officer shall, to the extent practicable, maximize the use of performance-based servicing contracts, consistent with guidelines for such contracts published by the Office of Federal Procurement Policy, to achieve cost savings and improve service.


(2) Fee for service arrangementsThe Chief Operating Officer shall, when appropriate and consistent with the purposes of the PBO, acquire services related to the functions set forth in section 1018(b)(2) of this title from any entity that has the capability and capacity to meet the requirements set by the PBO. The Chief Operating Officer is authorized to pay fees that are equivalent to those paid by other entities to an organization that provides services that meet the requirements of the P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Procurement authority Subject to the authority of the Secretary, the Chief Operating Officer of a PBO may exercise the authority of the Secretary to procure property and services in the performance of functions managed by the PBO. For the purposes of this section, the term “PBO” includes the Chief Operating Officer of the PBO and any employee of the PBO exercising procurement authority under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general Except as provided in this section, the PBO shall abide by all applicable Federal procurement laws and regulations when procuring property and services. The PBO shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Service contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Two-phase source-selection procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Two-phase source-selection procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of simplified procedures for commercial products and commercial services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of simplified procedures for commercial products and commercial services Whenever the PBO anticipates that commercial products or commercial services will be offered for a procurement, the PBO may use (consistent with the special rules for commercial products and commercial services) the special simplified procedures for the procurement without regard to any dollar limitation otherwise applicable to the use of those procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexible wait periods and deadlines for submission of offers of noncommercial products and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Flexible wait periods and deadlines for submission of offers of noncommercial products and services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modular contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Modular contracting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of simplified procedures for small business set-asides for services other than commercial services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of simplified procedures for small business set-asides for services other than commercial services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance for use of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Guidance for use of authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on multiagency contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitation on multiagency contracting No department or agency of the Federal Government may purchase property or services under contracts entered into or administered by a PBO under this section unless the purchase is approved in advance by the senior procurement official of that department or agency who is responsible for purchasing by the department or agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>