<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1018/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1018"><akn:num>1018</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance-Based Organization for delivery of Federal student financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1018. Performance-Based Organization for delivery of Federal student financial assistance(a) Establishment and purpose(1) EstablishmentThere is established in the Department a Performance-Based Organization (hereafter referred to as the “PBO”) which shall be a discrete management unit responsible for managing the administrative and oversight functions supporting the programs authorized under subchapter IV of this chapter, as specified in subsection (b).


(2) PurposesThe purposes of the PBO are—(A) to improve service to students and other participants in the student financial assistance programs authorized under subchapter IV, including making those programs more understandable to students and their parents;

(B) to reduce the costs of administering those programs;

(C) to increase the accountability of the officials responsible for administering the operational aspects of these programs;

(D) to provide greater flexibility in the management and administration of the Federal student financial assistance programs;

(E) to integrate the information systems supporting the Federal student financial assistance programs;

(F) to implement an open, common, integrated system for the delivery of student financial assistance under subchapter IV; and

(G) to develop and maintain a student financial assistance system that contains complete, accurate, and timely data to ensure program integrity.



(b) General authority(1) Authority of SecretaryNotwithstanding any other provision of this part, the Secretary shall maintain responsibility for the development and promulgation of policy and regulations relating to the programs of student financial assistance under subchapter IV. In the exercise of its functions, the PBO shall be subject to the direction of the Secretary. The Secretary shall—(A) request the advice of, and work in cooperation with, the Chief Operating Officer in developing regulations, policies, administrative guidance, or procedures affecting the Federal student fi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment and purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance plan, report, and briefing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Performance plan, report, and briefing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Operating Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chief Operating Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Senior management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student Loan Ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Student Loan Ombudsman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Personnel flexibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fair and equitable system for measuring staff performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Establishment of fair and equitable system for measuring staff performance The PBO shall establish an annual performance management system, subject to compliance with title 5, and consistent with applicable provisions of law and regulations, which strengthens the effectiveness of the PBO by providing for establishing goals or objectives for individual, group, or organizational performance (or any combination thereof), consistent with the performance plan of the PBO and its performance planning procedures, including those established under the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993, and communicating such goals or objectives to employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1018_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations The Secretary shall allocate from funds made available under section 1087h of this title such funds as are appropriate to the functions assumed by the PBO. In addition, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the purposes of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>