<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_102"><akn:num>102</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 102. Application of appropriations
The Secretary of Education is authorized to pay over semiannually, to the trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind, located in Louisville, Kentucky, and chartered in 1858 by the Legislature of Kentucky, upon requisition of their president, countersigned by their treasurer, one-half of such annual appropriation upon the following conditions:(1) Purposes and methods of expendituresFirst. (A) Such appropriation shall be expended by the trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind each year in manufacturing and furnishing books and other materials specially adapted for instruction of the blind; and the total amount of such books and other materials so manufactured and furnished by such appropriation shall each year be distributed among all the public and private nonprofit institutions in the States, Territories, and possessions of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia, in which blind pupils are educated. Each public and private nonprofit institution for the education of the blind shall receive, in books and other materials, upon requisition of its superintendent, that portion of the appropriation as is shown by the ratio between the number of blind pupils in that institution and the total number of blind pupils in all of the public and private nonprofit institutions in which blind pupils are educated. Each chief State school officer shall receive, in books and other materials, upon requisition, that portion of the appropriation as is shown by the ratio between the number of blind pupils in public and private nonprofit institutions (in the State) in which blind pupils are educated, other than institutions to which the preceding sentence is applicable, and the total number of blind pupils in the public and private nonprofit institutions in which blind pupils are educated in all of the States, Territories, and possessions of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Ri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes and methods of expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Purposes and methods of expenditures First. (A) Such appropriation shall be expended by the trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind each year in manufacturing and furnishing books and other materials specially adapted for instruction of the blind; and the total amount of such books and other materials so manufactured and furnished by such appropriation shall each year be distributed among all the public and private nonprofit institutions in the States, Territories, and possessions of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia, in which blind pupils are educated. Each public and private nonprofit institution for the education of the blind shall receive, in books and other materials, upon requisition of its superintendent, that portion of the appropriation as is shown by the ratio between the number of blind pupils in that institution and the total number of blind pupils in all of the public and private nonprofit institutions in whi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Buildings Second. No part of the appropriation shall be expended in the erection or leasing of buildings; but the trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind may use each year a reasonable sum of the annual appropriation for salaries and other expenses of experts and other staff to assist special committees which may be appointed in performance of their functions, and for expenses of such special committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales of books and apparatus at cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Sales of books and apparatus at cost Third. No profit shall be put on any books or tangible apparatus for the instruction of the blind manufactured or furnished by the trustees of said American Printing House for the Blind, located in Louisville, Kentucky; and the price put upon each article so manufactured or furnished shall only be its actual cost.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income withheld when not properly used</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Income withheld when not properly used Fourth. The Secretary of the Treasury of the United States shall have the authority to withhold the appropriation whenever he shall receive satisfactory proof that the trustees of said American Printing House for the Blind, located in Louisville, Kentucky, are not using the appropriation for the benefit of the blind in the public and private nonprofit institutions for the education of the blind in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bond of treasurer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Bond of treasurer Fifth. Before any money be paid to the treasurer of the American Printing House for the Blind by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, the treasurer of the American Printing House for the Blind shall execute a bond, with two approved sureties, to the amount of $20,000, conditioned that the money so received shall be expended according to this law and all amendments thereto, which shall be held by the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, and shall be renewed every two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_102_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ex officio trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Ex officio trustees Sixth. The superintendent of each public institution for the education of the blind (or his designee) and the chief State school officer (or his designee), of each State and possession of the United States, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the District of Columbia, shall each, ex officio, be a member of the Board of Trustees of the American Printing House for the Blind only for purposes of administering sections 101, 102 and 104 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>