<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1035" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1035/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1035/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1035"><akn:num>1035</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjunct teacher corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1035. Adjunct teacher corps(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to create opportunities for professionals and other individuals with subject matter expertise in mathematics, science, or critical foreign languages to provide such subject matter expertise to secondary school students on an adjunct basis.


(b) Program authorizedThe Secretary is authorized to award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to identify, recruit, and train qualified individuals with subject matter expertise in mathematics, science, or critical foreign languages to serve as adjunct content specialists.


(c) Duration of grantsThe Secretary may award grants under this section for a period of not more than five years.


(d) Eligible entityIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(1) a local educational agency; or

(2) a partnership consisting of a local educational agency, serving as a fiscal agent, and a public or private educational organization or business.


(e) Uses of fundsAn eligible entity that receives a grant under this section is authorized to use such grant to carry out one or both of the following activities:(1) To develop the capacity of the eligible entity to identify, recruit, and train individuals with subject matter expertise in mathematics, science, or critical foreign languages who are not employed in the elementary and secondary education system (including individuals in business and government, and individuals who would participate through distance-learning arrangements) to become adjunct content specialists.

(2) To provide preservice training and on-going professional development to adjunct content specialists.


(f) Applications(1) Application requiredAn eligible entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(2) ContentsAn application submitted under paragraph (1) shall include—(A) a description of—(i) t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to create opportunities for professionals and other individuals with subject matter expertise in mathematics, science, or critical foreign languages to provide such subject matter expertise to secondary school students on an adjunct basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program authorized The Secretary is authorized to award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to identify, recruit, and train qualified individuals with subject matter expertise in mathematics, science, or critical foreign languages to serve as adjunct content specialists.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duration of grants The Secretary may award grants under this section for a period of not more than five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible entity In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Uses of funds An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section is authorized to use such grant to carry out one or both of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priorities In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that demonstrate in the application for such a grant a plan to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Matching requirement Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 100 percent of the amount of such grant (in cash or in kind) to carry out the activities supported by such grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Performance report Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a final report on the results of the activities supported by such grant, which shall contain such information as the Secretary may require, including any improvements in student academic achievement as a result of the use of adjunct content specialists.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1035_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Evaluation The Secretary shall evaluate the activities supported by grants under this section, including the impact of such activities on student academic achievement, and shall report the results of such evaluation to the authorizing committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>