<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1057" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1057/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1057/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1057"><akn:num>1057</akn:num><akn:heading>Program purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1057. Program purpose(a) General authorizationThe Secretary shall carry out a program, in accordance with this part, to improve the academic quality, institutional management, and fiscal stability of eligible institutions, in order to increase their self-sufficiency and strengthen their capacity to make a substantial contribution to the higher education resources of the Nation.


(b) Grants awarded; special consideration(1) From the sums available for this part under section 1068h(a)(1) of this title, the Secretary may award grants to any eligible institution with an application approved under section 1068 of this title in order to assist such an institution to plan, develop, or implement activities that promise to strengthen the institution.

(2) Special consideration shall be given to any eligible institution—(A) which has endowment funds (other than any endowment fund built under section 1065 of this title as in effect on September 30, 1986, and under part B) the market value of which, per full-time equivalent student, is less than the average current market value of the endowment funds, per full-time equivalent student (other than any endowment fund built under section 1065 of this title as in effect on September 30, 1986, and under part B) at similar institutions; or

(B) which has expenditures per full-time equivalent student for library materials which is less than the average of the expenditures for library materials per full-time equivalent student by other similarly situated institutions.


(3) Special consideration shall be given to applications which propose, pursuant to the institution’s plan, to engage in—(A) faculty development;

(B) funds and administrative management;

(C) development and improvement of academic programs;

(D) acquisition of equipment for use in strengthening funds management and academic programs;

(E) joint use of facilities such as libraries and laboratories; and

(F) student services, including services that will assist in the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1057_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authorization The Secretary shall carry out a program, in accordance with this part, to improve the academic quality, institutional management, and fiscal stability of eligible institutions, in order to increase their self-sufficiency and strengthen their capacity to make a substantial contribution to the higher education resources of the Nation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1057_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants awarded; special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants awarded; special consideration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1057_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities Grants awarded under this section shall be used for 1 or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1057_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Endowment fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Endowment fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>