<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1059c"><akn:num>1059c</akn:num><akn:heading>American Indian tribally controlled colleges and universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1059c. American Indian tribally controlled colleges and universities(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary shall provide grants and related assistance to Tribal Colleges and Universities to enable such institutions to improve and expand their capacity to serve Indian students.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) IndianThe term “Indian” has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 1801].


(2) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 [25 U.S.C. 1801].


(3) Tribal College or UniversityThe term “Tribal College or University” means an institution that—(A) qualifies for funding under the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (25 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.) or the Navajo Community College Act (25 U.S.C. 640a note); 11 See References in Text note below. or

(B) is cited in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (7 U.S.C. 301 note).


(4) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” means an institution of higher education as defined in section 1001(a) of this title, except that paragraph (2) of such section shall not apply.



(c) Authorized activities(1) In generalGrants awarded under this section shall be used by Tribal Colleges or Universities to assist such institutions to plan, develop, undertake, and carry out activities to improve and expand such institutions’ capacity to serve Indian students.


(2) Examples of authorized activitiesThe activities described in paragraph (1) may include—(A) purchase, rental, or lease of scientific or laboratory equipment for educational purposes, including instructional and research purposes;

(B) construction, maintenance, renovation, and improvement in classrooms, libraries, laboratories, and other instructional facilities, including purchase or rent</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary shall provide grants and related assistance to Tribal Colleges and Universities to enable such institutions to improve and expand their capacity to serve Indian students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application, plan, and allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application, plan, and allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>