<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1059g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1059g"><akn:num>1059g</akn:num><akn:heading>Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1059g. Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary shall provide grants and related assistance to Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions to enable such institutions to improve and expand their capacity to serve Asian Americans and Native American Pacific Islanders and low-income individuals.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Asian AmericanThe term “Asian American” has the meaning given the term “Asian” in the Office of Management and Budget’s Standards for Maintaining, Collecting, and Presenting Federal Data on Race and Ethnicity as published on October 30, 1997 (62 Fed. Reg. 58789).


(2) Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutionThe term “Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution” means an institution of higher education that—(A) is an eligible institution under section 1058(b) of this title; and

(B) at the time of application, has an enrollment of undergraduate students that is not less than 10 percent students who are Asian American or Native American Pacific Islander.


(3) Native American Pacific IslanderThe term “Native American Pacific Islander” means any descendant of the aboriginal people of any island in the Pacific Ocean that is a territory or possession of the United States.



(c) Authorized activities(1) Types of activities authorizedGrants awarded under this section shall be used by Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions to assist such institutions to plan, develop, undertake, and carry out activities to improve and expand such institutions’ capacity to serve Asian Americans and Native American Pacific Islanders and low-income individuals.


(2) Examples of authorized activitiesSuch programs may include—(A) purchase, rental, or lease of scientific or laboratory equipment for educational purposes, including instructional and research purposes;

(B) renovatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary shall provide grants and related assistance to Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions to enable such institutions to improve and expand their capacity to serve Asian Americans and Native American Pacific Islanders and low-income individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1059g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>