<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1063e"><akn:num>1063e</akn:num><akn:heading>President’s Board of Advisors on HBCUs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1063e. President’s Board of Advisors on HBCUs(a) Administration(1) In generalThere is established the President’s Board of Advisors on historically Black colleges and universities in the Department of Education or, if the President so elects, within the Executive Office of the President.


(2) Funding from ED 11 So in original.Except as provided in paragraph (3), the Secretary shall provide funding and administrative support for the President’s Board of Advisors, subject to the availability of appropriations.


(3) Funding from the Executive Office of the PresidentIf the President elects to locate the President’s Board of Advisors within the Executive Office of the President, the Executive Office of the President shall provide funding and administrative support for the President’s Board of Advisors, subject to the availability of appropriations.



(b) Membership(1) In generalThe President shall appoint not more than 23 members to the President’s Board of Advisors, and the Secretary and Executive Director or their designees shall serve as ex officio members.


(2) Chair(A) DesignationThe President shall designate one member of the President’s Board of Advisors to serve as its Chair, who shall help direct the Board’s work in coordination with the Secretary and in consultation with the Executive Director.


(B) ConsultationThe Chair shall also consult with the Executive Director regarding the time and location of meetings of the President’s Board of Advisors, which shall take place not less frequently than once every 6 months.


(C) PerformanceInsofar as the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) 22 See References in Text note below. may apply to the President’s Board of Advisors, any functions of the President under such Act, except for those of reporting to the Congress, shall be performed by the Chair, in accordance with guidelines issued by the Administrator of General Services.



(3) CompensationMembers of the President’s Board of Advisors shall serve </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission and functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mission and functions The President’s Board of Advisors shall advise the President, through the White House Initiative, on all matters pertaining to strengthening the educational capacity of HBCUs, which shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report The President’s Board of Advisors shall report annually to the President on the Board’s progress in carrying out its duties under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>