<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1063d"><akn:num>1063d</akn:num><akn:heading>Strengthening HBCUs through Federal agency plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1063d. Strengthening HBCUs through Federal agency plans(a) Designating applicable agenciesThe Secretary, in consultation with the Executive Director, shall—(1) identify each Federal agency with which an HBCU—(A) has entered into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; or

(B) is eligible to participate in the programs and initiatives under the jurisdiction of such Federal agency; and


(2) designate each Federal agency so identified as an applicable agency.


(b) Submitting agency plansNot later than February 1 of each year, the head of each applicable agency shall submit to the Secretary, the Executive Director, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, and the President’s Board of Advisors an annual Agency Plan describing efforts to strengthen the capacity of HBCUs to participate or be eligible to participate in the programs and initiatives under the jurisdiction of such applicable agency as described in subsection (a)(1)(B).


(c) Further requirements for submission and accessibilityThe Executive Director shall make all annual Agency Plan submissions publicly available online in a user-friendly format.


(d) Agency plan contentWhere appropriate, each Agency Plan shall include—(1) a description of how the applicable agency intends to increase the capacity of HBCUs to compete effectively for grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements;

(2) an identification of Federal programs and initiatives under the jurisdiction of the applicable agency in which HBCUs are underrepresented;

(3) an outline of proposed efforts to improve HBCUs’ participation in such programs and initiatives;

(4) a description of any progress made towards advancing or achieving goals and efforts from previous Agency Plans submitted under this section by such applicable agency;

(5) a description of how the applicable agency plans to encourage public-sector, private-sector, and community invo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designating applicable agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designating applicable agencies The Secretary, in consultation with the Executive Director, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submitting agency plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submitting agency plans Not later than February 1 of each year, the head of each applicable agency shall submit to the Secretary, the Executive Director, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, and the President’s Board of Advisors an annual Agency Plan describing efforts to strengthen the capacity of HBCUs to participate or be eligible to participate in the programs and initiatives under the jurisdiction of such applicable agency as described in subsection (a)(1)(B).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Further requirements for submission and accessibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Further requirements for submission and accessibility The Executive Director shall make all annual Agency Plan submissions publicly available online in a user-friendly format.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency plan content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agency plan content Where appropriate, each Agency Plan shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency engagement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Agency engagement To help fulfill the objectives of the Agency Plans, the head of each applicable agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>