<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1063/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1063"><akn:num>1063</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments to institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1063. Allotments to institutions(a) Allotment; Pell Grant basisFrom the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-half that amount as the number of Pell Grant recipients in attendance at such institution at the end of the school year preceding the beginning of that fiscal year bears to the total number of Pell Grant recipients at all part B institutions.


(b) Allotment; graduates basisFrom the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-fourth that amount as the number of graduates for such school year at such institution bears to the total number of graduates for such school year at all part B institutions.


(c) Allotment; graduate and professional student basisFrom the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-fourth of that amount as the percentage of graduates per institution, who are admitted to and in attendance at, within 5 years of graduation with a baccalaureate degree, a graduate or professional school in a degree program in disciplines in which Blacks are underrepresented, bears to the percentage of such graduates per institution for all part B institutions.


(d) Minimum allotment(1) Notwithstanding subsections (a) through (c), and subject to subsection (h), if the amount of an award under this section for a part B institution, based on the data provided by the part B institution and the formula under subsections (a) through (c), would be—(A) an amount that is greater than $250,000 but less than $500,000, the Secretary shall award the part B institution an allotment in the amount of $500,000; and

(B) an amount that is equal to or less than $250,000, the Secretary shall award the part B institution an allotment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment; Pell Grant basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allotment; Pell Grant basis From the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-half that amount as the number of Pell Grant recipients in attendance at such institution at the end of the school year preceding the beginning of that fiscal year bears to the total number of Pell Grant recipients at all part B institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment; graduates basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allotment; graduates basis From the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-fourth that amount as the number of graduates for such school year at such institution bears to the total number of graduates for such school year at all part B institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment; graduate and professional student basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allotment; graduate and professional student basis From the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each part B institution a sum which bears the same ratio to one-fourth of that amount as the percentage of graduates per institution, who are admitted to and in attendance at, within 5 years of graduation with a baccalaureate degree, a graduate or professional school in a degree program in disciplines in which Blacks are underrepresented, bears to the percentage of such graduates per institution for all part B institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Minimum allotment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reallotment The amount of any part B institution’s allotment under subsection (a), (b), (c), or (d) for any fiscal year which the Secretary determines will not be required for such institution for the period such allotment is available shall be available for reallotment from time to time on such date during such period as the Secretary may determine to other part B institutions in proportion to the original allotment to such other institutions under this section for such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special merger rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special merger rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for certain District of Columbia eligible institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rule for certain District of Columbia eligible institutions In any fiscal year that the Secretary determines that Howard University or the University of the District of Columbia will receive an allotment under subsections (b) and (c) of this section which is not in excess of amounts received by Howard University under the Act of March 2, 1867 (14 Stat. 438; 20 U.S.C. 123), relating to annual authorization of appropriations for Howard University, or by the University of the District of Columbia under the District of Columbia Home Rule Act (87 Stat. 774) for such fiscal year, then Howard University and the University of the District of Columbia, as the case may be, shall be ineligible to receive an allotment under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1063_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Conditions for allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>