<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1065" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1065/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1065/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1065"><akn:num>1065</akn:num><akn:heading>Endowment challenge grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1065. Endowment challenge grants(a) Purpose; definitions(1) The purpose of this section is to establish a program to provide matching grants to eligible institutions in order to establish or increase endowment funds at such institutions, to provide additional incentives to promote fund raising activities by such institutions, and to foster increased independence and self-sufficiency at such institutions.

(2) For the purpose of this section:(A) The term “endowment fund” means a fund established by State law, by an institution of higher education, or by a foundation which is exempt from taxation and is maintained for the purpose of generating income for the support of the institution, but which shall not include real estate.

(B) The term “endowment fund corpus” means an amount equal to the grant or grants awarded under this section plus an amount equal to such grant or grants provided by the institution.

(C) The term “endowment fund income” means an amount equal to the total value of the endowment fund established under this section minus the endowment fund corpus.

(D)(i) The term “eligible institution” means an institution that is an—(I) eligible institution under part A or would be considered to be such an institution if section 1058(b)(1)(C) of this title referred to a postgraduate degree rather than a bachelor’s degree;

(II) institution eligible for assistance under part B or would be considered to be such an institution if section 1063 of this title referred to a postgraduate degree rather than a baccalaureate degree; or

(III) institution of higher education that makes a substantial contribution to postgraduate medical educational opportunities for minorities and the economically disadvantaged.


(ii) The Secretary may waive the requirements of subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i) with respect to a postgraduate degree in the case of any institution otherwise eligible under clause (i) for an endowment challenge grant upon determining that the institution </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant agreement; endowment fund provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant agreement; endowment fund provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repayment provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Audit information An institution receiving a grant under this section shall provide to the Secretary (or a designee thereof) such information (or access thereto) as may be necessary to audit or examine expenditures made from the endowment fund corpus or income in order to determine compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Selection criteria In selecting eligible institutions for grants under this section for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application Any institution which is eligible for assistance under this section may submit to the Secretary a grant application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Secretary may prescribe, including a description of the long- and short-term plans for raising and using the funds under this part. Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this section and consistent with the requirement of subsection (f), the Secretary may approve an application for a grant if an institution, in its application, provides adequate assurances that it will comply with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination and recovery provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Termination and recovery provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1065_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Technical assistance The Secretary, directly or by grant or contract, may provide technical assistance to eligible institutions to prepare the institutions to qualify, apply for, and maintain a grant, under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>