<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1066c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1066c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1066c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1066c"><akn:num>1066c</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Federal insurance for bonds issued by designated bonding authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1066c. Limitations on Federal insurance for bonds issued by designated bonding authority(a) Limit on amountAt no time shall the aggregate principal amount of outstanding bonds insured under this part together with any accrued unpaid interest thereon exceed $1,100,000,000, of which—(1) not more than $733,333,333 shall be used for loans to eligible institutions that are private historically Black colleges and universities; and

(2) not more than $366,666,667 shall be used for loans to eligible institutions which are historically Black public colleges and universities.


For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2), Lincoln University of Pennsylvania is an historically Black public institution. No institution of higher education that has received assistance under section 123 of this title shall be eligible to receive assistance under this part.

(b) Limitation on credit authorityThe authority of the Secretary to issue letters of credit and insurance under this part is effective only to the extent provided in advance by appropriations Acts.


(c) Religious activity prohibitionNo loan may be made under this part for any educational program, activity or service related to sectarian instruction or religious worship or provided by a school or department of divinity or to an institution in which a substantial portion of its functions is subsumed in a religious mission.


(d) Discrimination prohibitionNo loan may be made to an institution under this part if the institution discriminates on account of race, color, religion, national origin, sex (to the extent provided in title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.]), or disabling condition; except that the prohibition with respect to religion shall not apply to an institution which is controlled by or which is closely identified with the tenets of a particular religious organization if the application of this section would not be consistent with the religious tenets of such organization.


(Pub. L. 89–329,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limit on amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limit on amount At no time shall the aggregate principal amount of outstanding bonds insured under this part together with any accrued unpaid interest thereon exceed $1,100,000,000, of which— For purposes of paragraphs (1) and (2), Lincoln University of Pennsylvania is an historically Black public institution. No institution of higher education that has received assistance under section 123 of this title shall be eligible to receive assistance under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on credit authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on credit authority The authority of the Secretary to issue letters of credit and insurance under this part is effective only to the extent provided in advance by appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious activity prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Religious activity prohibition No loan may be made under this part for any educational program, activity or service related to sectarian instruction or religious worship or provided by a school or department of divinity or to an institution in which a substantial portion of its functions is subsumed in a religious mission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1066c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Discrimination prohibition No loan may be made to an institution under this part if the institution discriminates on account of race, color, religion, national origin, sex (to the extent provided in title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.]), or disabling condition; except that the prohibition with respect to religion shall not apply to an institution which is controlled by or which is closely identified with the tenets of a particular religious organization if the application of this section would not be consistent with the religious tenets of such organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>