<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1067e"><akn:num>1067e</akn:num><akn:heading>YES partnerships grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1067e. YES partnerships grant program(a) Grant program authorizedSubject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subpart, the Secretary shall make grants to eligible partnerships (as described in subsection (f)) to support the engagement of underrepresented minority youth and youth who are low-income individuals (as such term is defined in section 1058 of this title) in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics through outreach and hands-on, experiential-based learning projects that encourage students in kindergarten through grade 12 who are underrepresented minority youth or low-income individuals to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.


(b) Minimum grant amountA grant awarded to a partnership under this subpart shall be for an amount that is not less than $500,000.


(c) DurationA grant awarded under this subpart shall be for a period of five years.


(d) Non-Federal matching share requiredA partnership receiving a grant under this subpart shall provide, from non-Federal sources, in cash or in-kind, an amount equal to 50 percent of the costs of the project supported by such grant.


(e) Distribution of grantsIn awarding grants under this subpart, the Secretary shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the projects funded under this subpart are located in diverse geographic regions of the United States.


(f) Eligible partnershipsNotwithstanding the general eligibility provision in section 1067g of this title, eligibility to receive grants under this subpart is limited to partnerships described in paragraph (5) of such section.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title III, § 355, as added Pub. L. 110–315, title III, § 315(a)(2), Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3182; amended Pub. L. 111–39, title III, § 301(6), July 1, 2009, 123 Stat. 1937.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 355 of Pub. L. 89–329 was classified to section 1069a of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 102–325.

Amendments2009—Subsec. (a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant program authorized Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subpart, the Secretary shall make grants to eligible partnerships (as described in subsection (f)) to support the engagement of underrepresented minority youth and youth who are low-income individuals (as such term is defined in section 1058 of this title) in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics through outreach and hands-on, experiential-based learning projects that encourage students in kindergarten through grade 12 who are underrepresented minority youth or low-income individuals to pursue careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum grant amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimum grant amount A grant awarded to a partnership under this subpart shall be for an amount that is not less than $500,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duration A grant awarded under this subpart shall be for a period of five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal matching share required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Non-Federal matching share required A partnership receiving a grant under this subpart shall provide, from non-Federal sources, in cash or in-kind, an amount equal to 50 percent of the costs of the project supported by such grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of grants In awarding grants under this subpart, the Secretary shall ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, the projects funded under this subpart are located in diverse geographic regions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible partnerships Notwithstanding the general eligibility provision in section 1067g of this title, eligibility to receive grants under this subpart is limited to partnerships described in paragraph (5) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>