<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1067c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1067c"><akn:num>1067c</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1067c. Use of funds(a) Types of grantsFunds appropriated to carry out this subpart may be made available as—(1) institutional grants (as defined in section 1067k(6) of this title);

(2) cooperative grants (as defined in section 1067k(7) of this title);

(3) design projects (as defined in section 1067k(8) of this title); or

(4) special projects (as defined in section 1067k(9) of this title).


(b) Authorized uses for each type of grant(1) The authorized uses of funds made available as institutional grants include (but are not limited to)—(A) faculty development programs; or

(B) development of curriculum materials.


(2) The authorized uses of funds made available as cooperative grants include (but are not limited to)—(A) assisting institutions in sharing facilities and personnel;

(B) disseminating information about established programs in science and engineering;

(C) supporting cooperative efforts to strengthen the institutions’ science and engineering programs; or

(D) carrying out a combination of any of the activities in subparagraphs (A) through (C).


(3) The authorized uses of funds made available as design projects include (but are not limited to)—(A) developing planning, management, and evaluation systems; or

(B) developing plans for initiating scientific research and for improving institutions’ capabilities for such activities.


Funds used for design project grants may not be used to pay more than 50 percent of the salaries during any academic year of faculty members involved in the project.

(4) The authorized uses of funds made available as special projects include (but are not limited to)—(A) advanced science seminars;

(B) science faculty workshops and conferences;

(C) faculty training to develop specific science research or education skills;

(D) research in science education;

(E) programs for visiting scientists;

(F) preparation of films or audio-visual materials in science;

(G) development of learning experiences in science beyond those no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of grants Funds appropriated to carry out this subpart may be made available as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1067c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized uses for each type of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorized uses for each type of grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>