<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1068b"><akn:num>1068b</akn:num><akn:heading>Application review process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1068b. Application review process(a) Review panel(1) All applications submitted under this subchapter by institutions of higher education shall be read by a panel of readers composed of individuals selected by the Secretary. The Secretary shall assure that no individual assigned under this section to review any application has any conflict of interest with regard to the application which might impair the impartiality with which the individual conducts the review under this section.

(2) The Secretary shall take care to assure that representatives of historically and predominantly Black colleges, Hispanic institutions, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and institutions with substantial numbers of Hispanics, Native Americans, Asian Americans, and Native American Pacific Islanders (including Native Hawaiians) are included as readers.

(3) All readers selected by the Secretary shall receive thorough instruction from the Secretary regarding the evaluation process for applications submitted under this subchapter and consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, including—(A) explanations and examples of the types of activities referred to in section 1057(b) of this title that should receive special consideration for grants awarded under part A and of the types of activities referred to in section 1062 of this title that should receive special consideration for grants awarded under part B;

(B) an enumeration of the factors to be used to determine the quality of applications submitted under this subchapter; and

(C) an enumeration of the factors to be used to determine whether a grant should be awarded for a project under this subchapter, the amount of any such grant, and the duration of any such grant.



(b) Recommendations of panelIn awarding grants under this subchapter, the Secretary shall take into consideration the recommendations of the panel made under subsection (a).


(c) NotificationNot later than June 30 of each year, the Secretary shall notify each ins</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Review panel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations of panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recommendations of panel In awarding grants under this subchapter, the Secretary shall take into consideration the recommendations of the panel made under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification Not later than June 30 of each year, the Secretary shall notify each institution of higher education making an application under this subchapter of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusion The provisions of this section shall not apply to applications submitted under part D.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>