<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1068/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1068"><akn:num>1068</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1068. Applications for assistance(a) Applications(1) Applications requiredAny institution which is eligible for assistance under this subchapter shall submit to the Secretary an application for assistance at such time, in such form, and containing such information, as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to evaluate the institution’s need for the assistance. Subject to the availability of appropriations to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary may approve an application for assistance under this subchapter only if the Secretary determines that—(A) the application meets the requirements of subsection (b);

(B) the applicant is eligible for assistance in accordance with the part of this subchapter under which the assistance is sought; and

(C) the applicant’s performance goals are sufficiently rigorous as to meet the purposes of this subchapter and the performance objectives and indicators for this subchapter established by the Secretary pursuant to the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 and the amendments made by such Act.


(2) Preliminary applicationsIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary may develop a preliminary application for use by eligible institutions applying under part A prior to the submission of the principal application.



(b) ContentsAn institution, in its application for a grant, shall—(1) set forth, or describe how the institution (other than an institution applying under part C, D or E) will develop, a comprehensive development plan to strengthen the institution’s academic quality and institutional management, and otherwise provide for institutional self-sufficiency and growth (including measurable objectives for the institution and the Secretary to use in monitoring the effectiveness of activities under this subchapter);

(2) set forth policies and procedures to ensure that Federal funds made available under this subchapter for any fiscal year will be used to supplement and, to the extent practical, increase the funds th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents An institution, in its application for a grant, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority criteria publication required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority criteria publication required The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register, pursuant to chapter 5 of title 5, all policies and procedures required to exercise the authority set forth in subsection (a). No other criteria, policies, or procedures shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility data The Secretary shall use the most recent and relevant data concerning the number and percentage of students receiving need-based assistance under subchapter IV of this chapter in making eligibility determinations under section 1058 of this title and shall advance the base-year forward following each annual grant cycle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1068_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance The Secretary, directly or by grant or contract, may provide technical assistance to eligible institutions to prepare the institutions to qualify, apply for, and maintain a grant, under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>