<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–18" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–18/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–18/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070a_18"><akn:num>1070a–18</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports, evaluations, and grants for project improvement and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070a–18. Reports, evaluations, and grants for project improvement and dissemination(a) Reports to the authorizing committees(1) In generalThe Secretary shall submit annually, to the authorizing committees, a report that documents the performance of all programs funded under this division. Such report shall—(A) be submitted not later than 12 months after the eligible entities receiving funds under this division are required to report their performance to the Secretary;

(B) focus on the programs’ performance on the relevant outcome criteria determined under section 1070a–11(f)(4) of this title;

(C) aggregate individual project performance data on the outcome criteria in order to provide national performance data for each program;

(D) include, when appropriate, descriptive data, multi-year data, and multi-cohort data; and

(E) include comparable data on the performance nationally of low-income students, first-generation students, and students with disabilities.


(2) InformationThe Secretary shall provide, with each report submitted under paragraph (1), information on the impact of the secondary review process described in section 1070a–11(c)(8)(C)(iv) of this title, including the number and type of secondary reviews, the disposition of the secondary reviews, the effect on timing of awards, and any other information the Secretary determines is necessary.



(b) Evaluations(1) In general(A) Authorization of grants and contractsFor the purpose of improving the effectiveness of the programs and projects assisted under this division, the Secretary shall make grants to, or enter into contracts with, institutions of higher education and other public and private institutions and organizations to rigorously evaluate the effectiveness of the programs and projects assisted under this division, including a rigorous evaluation of the programs and projects assisted under section 1070a–13 of this title. The evaluation of the programs and projects assisted under section 1070a–1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_18_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to the authorizing committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports to the authorizing committees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_18_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_18_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants The Secretary may award grants to institutions of higher education or other private and public institutions and organizations, that are carrying out a program or project assisted under this division prior to October 7, 1998, to enable the institutions and organizations to expand and leverage the success of such programs or projects by working in partnership with other institutions, community-based organizations, or combinations of such institutions and organizations, that are not receiving assistance under this division and are serving low-income students and first generation college students, in order to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_18_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Results</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Results In order to improve overall program or project effectiveness, the results of evaluations and grants described in this section shall be disseminated by the Secretary to similar programs or projects assisted under this subpart, as well as other individuals concerned with postsecondary access for and retention of low-income individuals and first-generation college students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>