<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070c_3"><akn:num>1070c–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of State programs; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070c–3. Administration of State programs; judicial review(a) Disapproval of applications; suspension of eligibility(1) The Secretary shall not finally disapprove any application for a State program submitted under section 1070c–2 of this title, or any modification thereof, without first affording the State agency submitting the program reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing.

(2) Whenever the Secretary, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State agency administering a State program approved under this subpart, finds—(A) that the State program has been so changed that it no longer complies with the provisions of this subpart, or

(B) that in the administration of the program there is a failure to comply substantially with any such provisions,


the Secretary shall notify such State agency that the State will not be regarded as eligible to participate in the program under this subpart until he is satisfied that there is no longer any such failure to comply.


(b) Review of decisions(1) If any State is dissatisfied with the Secretary’s final action with respect to the approval of its State program submitted under this subpart or with his final action under subsection (a), such State may appeal to the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which such State is located. The summons and notice of appeal may be served at any place in the United States. The Commissioner shall forthwith certify and file in the court the transcript of the proceedings and the record on which he based his action.

(2) The findings of fact by the Secretary, if supported by substantial evidence, shall be conclusive; but the court, for good cause shown, may remand the case to the Secretary to take further evidence, and the Secretary may thereupon make new or modified findings of fact and may modify his previous action, and shall certify to the court the transcript and record of further proceedings. Such new or modified findings of fact shall likewise be </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070c_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval of applications; suspension of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disapproval of applications; suspension of eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070c_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review of decisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>