<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070a"><akn:num>1070a</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Pell Grants: amount and determinations; applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070a. Federal Pell Grants: amount and determinations; applications(a) Purpose; definitions(1) PurposeThe purpose of this subpart is to provide a Federal Pell Grant to low-income students.


(2) DefinitionsIn this section—(A) the term “adjusted gross income” means—(i) in the case of a dependent student, for the second tax year preceding the academic year—(I) the adjusted gross income (as defined in section 62 of title 26) of the student’s parents; plus

(II) for Federal Pell Grant determinations made for academic years beginning on or after July 1, 2026, the foreign income (as described in section 1087vv(b)(5) of this title) of the student’s parents; and


(ii) in the case of an independent student, for the second tax year preceding the academic year—(I) the adjusted gross income (as defined in section 62 of title 26) of the student (and the student’s spouse, if applicable); plus

(II) for Federal Pell Grant determinations made for academic years beginning on or after July 1, 2026, the foreign income (as described in section 1087vv(b)(5) of this title) of the student (and the student’s spouse, if applicable);



(B) the term “family size” has the meaning given the term in section 1087vv(k) of this title;

(C) the term “poverty line” means the poverty line (as determined under the poverty guidelines updated periodically in the Federal Register by the Department of Health and Human Services under the authority of section 9902(2) of title 42) applicable to the student’s family size and applicable to the second tax year preceding the academic year;

(D) the term “single parent” means—(i) a parent of a dependent student who was a head of household (as defined in section 2(b) of title 26) or a surviving spouse (as defined in section 2(a) of title 26) or was an eligible individual for purposes of the credit under section 32 of such title, in the second tax year preceding the academic year; or

(ii) an independent student who is a parent and was a head of household (as de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and distribution of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount and distribution of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of eligibility for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of eligibility for grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applications for grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of grants to students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Distribution of grants to students Payments under this section shall be made in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Secretary for such purpose, in such manner as will best accomplish the purpose of this section. Any disbursement allowed to be made by crediting the student’s account shall be limited to tuition and fees, and food and housing if that food and housing is institutionally owned or operated. The student may elect to have the institution provide other such goods and services by crediting the student’s account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insufficient appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Insufficient appropriations If, for any fiscal year, the funds appropriated for payments under this subpart are insufficient to satisfy fully all entitlements, as calculated under subsections (b) and (c) (but at the maximum grant level specified in such appropriation), the Secretary shall promptly transmit a notice of such insufficiency to each House of the Congress, and identify in such notice the additional amount that would be required to be appropriated to satisfy fully all entitlements (as so calculated at such maximum grant level).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of excess funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of excess funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of institutions and students under other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Treatment of institutions and students under other laws Any institution of higher education which enters into an agreement with the Secretary to disburse to students attending that institution the amounts those students are eligible to receive under this subpart shall not be deemed, by virtue of such agreement, a contractor maintaining a system of records to accomplish a function of the Secretary. Recipients of Pell Grants shall not be considered to be individual grantees for purposes of chapter 81 of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional ineligibility based on default rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Institutional ineligibility based on default rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>