<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070d_2"><akn:num>1070d–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance and expansion of existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070d–2. Maintenance and expansion of existing programs(a) Program authorityThe Secretary shall maintain and expand existing secondary and postsecondary high school equivalency program and college assistance migrant program projects located at institutions of higher education or at private nonprofit organizations working in cooperation with institutions of higher education.


(b) Services provided by high school equivalency programThe services authorized by this subpart for the high school equivalency program include—(1) recruitment services to reach persons—(A)(i) who are 16 years of age and over; or

(ii) who are beyond the age of compulsory school attendance in the State in which such persons reside and are not enrolled in school;


(B)(i) who themselves, or whose immediate family, have spent a minimum of 75 days during the past 24 months in migrant and seasonal farmwork; or

(ii) who are eligible to participate, or have participated within the preceding 2 years, in programs under part C of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6391 et seq.] or section 3222 of title 29; and


(C) who lack a high school diploma or its equivalent;


(2) educational services which provide instruction designed to help students obtain a general education diploma which meets the guidelines established by the State in which the project is located for high school equivalency;

(3) supportive services which include the following:(A) personal, vocational, and academic counseling;

(B) placement services designed to place students in a university, college, or junior college program (including preparation for college entrance examinations), or in military service or career positions; and

(C) health services;


(4) information concerning, and assistance in obtaining, available student financial aid;

(5) stipends for high school equivalency program participants;

(6) housing for those enrolled in residential programs;

(7) exposure to cultural events, aca</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authority The Secretary shall maintain and expand existing secondary and postsecondary high school equivalency program and college assistance migrant program projects located at institutions of higher education or at private nonprofit organizations working in cooperation with institutions of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services provided by high school equivalency program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Services provided by high school equivalency program The services authorized by this subpart for the high school equivalency program include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services provided by college assistance migrant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services provided by college assistance migrant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management plan required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management plan required Each project application shall include a management plan which contains assurances that the grant recipient will coordinate the project, to the extent feasible, with other local, State, and Federal programs to maximize the resources available for migrant students, and that staff shall have a demonstrated knowledge and be sensitive to the unique characteristics and needs of the migrant and seasonal farmworker population, and provisions for:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Five-year grant period; consideration of prior experience</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Five-year grant period; consideration of prior experience Except under extraordinary circumstances, the Secretary shall award grants for a 5-year period. For the purpose of making grants under this subpart, the Secretary shall consider the prior experience of service delivery under the particular project for which funds are sought by each applicant. Such prior experience shall be awarded the same level of consideration given this factor for applicants for programs in accordance with section 1070a–11(c)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minimum allocations The Secretary shall not allocate an amount less than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation and allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reservation and allocation of funds From the amounts made available under subsection (i), the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Data collection The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of making grants and contracts under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $75,000,000 for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as may be necessary for the each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>