<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070b_1"><akn:num>1070b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and duration of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070b–1. Amount and duration of grants(a) Amount of grant(1) Except as provided in paragraph (3), from the funds received by it for such purpose under this subpart, an institution which awards a supplemental grant to a student for an academic year under this subpart shall, for each year, pay to that student an amount not to exceed the lesser of (A) the amount determined by the institution, in accordance with the provisions of part F of this subchapter, to be needed by that student to enable the student to pursue a course of study at the institution or in a program of study abroad that is approved for credit by the institution at which the student is enrolled, or (B) $4,000.

(2) If the amount determined under paragraph (1) with respect to a student for any academic year is less than $100, no payment shall be made to that student for that year. For a student enrolled for less than a full academic year, the minimum payment required shall be reduced proportionately.

(3) For students participating in study abroad programs, the institution shall consider all reasonable costs associated with such study abroad when determining student eligibility. The amount of grant to be awarded in such cases may exceed the maximum amount of $4,000 by as much as $400 if reasonable study abroad costs exceed the cost of attendance at the home institution.


(b) Period for receipt of grants; continuing eligibility(1) The period during which a student may receive supplemental grants shall be the period required for the completion of the first undergraduate baccalaureate course of study being pursued by that student.

(2) A supplemental grant awarded under this subpart shall entitle the student (to whom it is awarded) to payments pursuant to such grant only if the student meets the requirements of section 1091 of this title, except as provided in section 1070b–2(c) of this title.


(c) Distribution of grant during academic yearNothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an insti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period for receipt of grants; continuing eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Period for receipt of grants; continuing eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070b_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of grant during academic year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution of grant during academic year Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit an institution from making payments of varying amounts from a supplemental grant to a student during an academic year to cover costs for a period which are not applicable to other periods of such academic year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>