<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070"><akn:num>1070</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose; program authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070. Statement of purpose; program authorization(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this part, to assist in making available the benefits of postsecondary education to eligible students (defined in accordance with section 1091 of this title) in institutions of higher education by—(1) providing Federal Pell Grants to all eligible students;

(2) providing supplemental educational opportunity grants to those students who demonstrate financial need;

(3) providing for payments to the States to assist them in making financial aid available to such students;

(4) providing for special programs and projects designed (A) to identify and encourage qualified youths with financial or cultural need with a potential for postsecondary education, (B) to prepare students from low-income families for postsecondary education, and (C) to provide remedial (including remedial language study) and other services to students; and

(5) providing assistance to institutions of higher education.


(b) Secretary required to carry out purposesThe Secretary shall, in accordance with subparts 1 through 9 of this part, carry out programs to achieve the purposes of this part.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 400, formerly § 401, as added Pub. L. 99–498, title IV, § 401(a), Oct. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 1308; renumbered § 400, Pub. L. 102–325, title IV, § 402(a)(3), July 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 482; amended Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 401(g)(1), Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1652; Pub. L. 111–39, title IV, § 401(a)(1), July 1, 2009, 123 Stat. 1938.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1070, Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 401, as added and amended Pub. L. 92–318, title I, § 131(b)(1), title X, § 1001(c)(1), (2), June 23, 1972, 86 Stat. 247, 381; Pub. L. 94–482, title I, § 125, Oct. 12, 1976, 90 Stat. 2096; Pub. L. 96–374, title IV, § 401, title XIII, § 1391(a)(1), Oct. 3, 1980, 94 Stat. 1401, 1503, stated purpose of program of grants to students in attendance at institutions of higher education, prior to the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this part, to assist in making available the benefits of postsecondary education to eligible students (defined in accordance with section 1091 of this title) in institutions of higher education by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary required to carry out purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretary required to carry out purposes The Secretary shall, in accordance with subparts 1 through 9 of this part, carry out programs to achieve the purposes of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>