<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–25" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–25/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–25/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070a_25"><akn:num>1070a–25</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship component</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070a–25. Scholarship component(a) In general(1) StatesIn order to receive a grant under this division, an eligible entity described in section 1070a–21(c)(1) of this title shall establish or maintain a financial assistance program that awards scholarships to students in accordance with the requirements of this section. The Secretary shall encourage the eligible entity to ensure that a scholarship provided pursuant to this section is available to an eligible student for use at any institution of higher education.


(2) PartnershipsAn eligible entity described in section 1070a–21(c)(2) of this title may award scholarships to eligible students in accordance with the requirements of this section.



(b) Limitation(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), each eligible entity described in section 1070a–21(c)(1) of this title that receives a grant under this division shall use not less than 25 percent and not more than 50 percent of the grant funds for activities described in section 1070a–24 of this title (except for the activity described in subsection (a)(4) of such section), with the remainder of such funds to be used for a scholarship program under this section in accordance with such subsection.


(2) ExceptionNotwithstanding paragraph (1), the Secretary may allow an eligible entity to use more than 50 percent of grant funds received under this division for such activities, if the eligible entity demonstrates that the eligible entity has another means of providing the students with the financial assistance described in this section and describes such means in the application submitted under section 1070a–23 of this title.



(c) Notification of eligibilityEach eligible entity providing scholarships under this section shall provide information on the eligibility requirements for the scholarships to all participating students upon the students’ entry into the programs assisted under this division.


(d) Grant amountsThe maximum amount of a scholarship that an eligibl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of eligibility Each eligible entity providing scholarships under this section shall provide information on the eligibility requirements for the scholarships to all participating students upon the students’ entry into the programs assisted under this division.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant amounts The maximum amount of a scholarship that an eligible student shall be eligible to receive under this section shall be established by the eligible entity. The minimum amount of the scholarship for each fiscal year shall not be less than the minimum Federal Pell Grant award under section 1070a of this title for such award year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portability of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Portability of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Relation to other assistance Scholarships provided under this section shall not be considered for the purpose of awarding Federal grant assistance under this subchapter, except that in no case shall the total amount of student financial assistance awarded to a student under this subchapter exceed such student’s total cost of attendance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_25_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Eligible students A student eligible for assistance under this section is a student who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>