<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–36" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–36/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070d–36/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070d_36"><akn:num>1070d–36</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of scholars</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070d–36. Eligibility of scholars(a) High school graduation or equivalent and admission to institution requiredEach student awarded a scholarship under this subpart shall be a graduate of a public or private secondary school (or a home school, whether treated as a home school or a private school under State law) or have the equivalent of a certificate of graduation as recognized by the State in which the student resides and must have been admitted for enrollment at an institution of higher education.


(b) Selection based on promise of academic achievementEach student awarded a scholarship under this subpart must demonstrate outstanding academic achievement and show promise of continued academic achievement.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 419F, as added Pub. L. 99–498, title IV, § 401(a), Oct. 17, 1986, 100 Stat. 1344; amended Pub. L. 110–315, title IV, § 409(a), Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3225.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1070d–36, Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 419F, as added Pub. L. 98–558, title VIII, § 801(a), Oct. 30, 1984, 98 Stat. 2901, related to eligibility of students for scholarships under Robert C. Byrd Honors Scholarship Program, prior to the general revision of this part by Pub. L. 99–498.

Amendments2008—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 110–315 inserted “(or a home school, whether treated as a home school or a private school under State law)” after “public or private secondary school”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_36_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>High school graduation or equivalent and admission to institution required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) High school graduation or equivalent and admission to institution required Each student awarded a scholarship under this subpart shall be a graduate of a public or private secondary school (or a home school, whether treated as a home school or a private school under State law) or have the equivalent of a certificate of graduation as recognized by the State in which the student resides and must have been admitted for enrollment at an institution of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070d_36_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection based on promise of academic achievement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection based on promise of academic achievement Each student awarded a scholarship under this subpart must demonstrate outstanding academic achievement and show promise of continued academic achievement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>