<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070c–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070c_2"><akn:num>1070c–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for leveraging educational assistance partnership programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070c–2. Applications for leveraging educational assistance partnership programs(a) Submission and contents of applicationsA State which desires to obtain a payment under this subpart for any fiscal year shall submit annually an application therefor through the State agency administering its program under this subpart as of July 1, 1985, unless the Governor of that State so designates, in writing, a different agency to administer the program. The application shall contain such information as may be required by, or pursuant to, regulation for the purpose of enabling the Secretary to make the determinations required under this subpart.


(b) Payment of Federal share of grants made by qualified programFrom a State’s allotment under this subpart for any fiscal year the Secretary is authorized to make payments to such State for paying up to 50 percent of the amount of student grants pursuant to a State program which—(1) is administered by a single State agency;

(2) provides that such grants will be in amounts not to exceed the lesser of $12,500 or the student’s cost of attendance per academic year (A) for attendance on a full-time basis at an institution of higher education, and (B) for campus-based community service work learning study jobs;

(3) provides that—(A) not more than 20 percent of the allotment to the State for each fiscal year may be used for the purpose described in paragraph (2)(B);

(B) grants for the campus-based community work learning study jobs may be made only to students who are otherwise eligible for assistance under this subpart; and

(C) grants for such jobs be made in accordance with the provisions of section 1087–53(b)(1) of this title;


(4) provides for the selection of recipients of such grants or of such State work-study jobs on the basis of substantial financial need determined annually on the basis of criteria established by the State and approved by the Secretary, except that for the purpose of collecting data to make such determinati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070c_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission and contents of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission and contents of applications A State which desires to obtain a payment under this subpart for any fiscal year shall submit annually an application therefor through the State agency administering its program under this subpart as of July 1, 1985, unless the Governor of that State so designates, in writing, a different agency to administer the program. The application shall contain such information as may be required by, or pursuant to, regulation for the purpose of enabling the Secretary to make the determinations required under this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070c_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of Federal share of grants made by qualified program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of Federal share of grants made by qualified program From a State’s allotment under this subpart for any fiscal year the Secretary is authorized to make payments to such State for paying up to 50 percent of the amount of student grants pursuant to a State program which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070c_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation and disbursement of allotments and reallotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reservation and disbursement of allotments and reallotments Upon his approval of any application for a payment under this subpart, the Secretary shall reserve from the applicable allotment (including any applicable reallotment) available therefor, the amount of such payment, which (subject to the limits of such allotment or reallotment) shall be equal to the Federal share of the cost of the students’ incentive grants or work-study jobs covered by such application. The Secretary shall pay such reserved amount, in advance or by way of reimbursement, and in such installments as the Secretary may determine. The Secretary may amend the reservation of any amount under this section, either upon approval of an amendment of the application or upon revision of the estimated cost of the student grants or work-study jobs with respect to which such reservation was made. If the Secretary approves an upward revision of such estimated cost, the Secretary may reserve the Federal share of the added </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>