<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–27" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–27/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1070a–27/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1070a_27"><akn:num>1070a–27</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1070a–27. Evaluation and report(a) EvaluationEach eligible entity receiving a grant under this division shall biennially evaluate the activities assisted under this division in accordance with the standards described in subsection (b) and shall submit to the Secretary a copy of such evaluation. The evaluation shall permit service providers to track eligible student progress during the period such students are participating in the activities and shall be consistent with the standards developed by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (b).


(b) Evaluation standardsThe Secretary shall prescribe standards for the evaluation described in subsection (a). Such standards shall—(1) provide for input from eligible entities and service providers; and

(2) ensure that data protocols and procedures are consistent and uniform.


(c) Federal evaluationIn order to evaluate and improve the impact of the activities assisted under this division, the Secretary shall, from not more than 0.75 percent of the funds appropriated under section 1070a–28 of this title for a fiscal year, award one or more grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to or with public and private institutions and organizations, to enable the institutions and organizations to evaluate the effectiveness of the program and, as appropriate, disseminate the results of the evaluation. Such evaluation shall include a separate analysis of—(1) the implementation of the scholarship component described in section 1070a–25 of this title; and

(2) the use of methods for complying with matching requirements described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1070a–23(c) of this title.


(d) ReportThe Secretary shall biennially report to Congress regarding the activities assisted under this division and the evaluations conducted pursuant to this section.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 404G, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 403, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1662; amended Pub. L. 110–315, title IV, § 404(g), Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_27_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluation Each eligible entity receiving a grant under this division shall biennially evaluate the activities assisted under this division in accordance with the standards described in subsection (b) and shall submit to the Secretary a copy of such evaluation. The evaluation shall permit service providers to track eligible student progress during the period such students are participating in the activities and shall be consistent with the standards developed by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_27_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation standards The Secretary shall prescribe standards for the evaluation described in subsection (a). Such standards shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_27_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal evaluation In order to evaluate and improve the impact of the activities assisted under this division, the Secretary shall, from not more than 0.75 percent of the funds appropriated under section 1070a–28 of this title for a fiscal year, award one or more grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to or with public and private institutions and organizations, to enable the institutions and organizations to evaluate the effectiveness of the program and, as appropriate, disseminate the results of the evaluation. Such evaluation shall include a separate analysis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1070a_27_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report The Secretary shall biennially report to Congress regarding the activities assisted under this division and the evaluations conducted pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>