<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1072b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1072b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1072b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1072b"><akn:num>1072b</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency Operating Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1072b. Agency Operating Fund(a) EstablishmentEach guaranty agency shall, not later than 60 days after October 7, 1998, establish a fund designated as the Operating Fund.


(b) Investment of fundsFunds deposited into the Operating Fund shall be invested at the discretion of the guaranty agency in accordance with prudent investor standards.


(c) Additional depositsAfter the establishment of the Operating Fund, the guaranty agency shall deposit into the Operating Fund—(1) the loan processing and issuance fee paid by the Secretary pursuant to section 1078(f) of this title;

(2) 30 percent of amounts received after October 7, 1998, from the Secretary as payment for administrative cost allowances for loans upon which insurance was issued prior to October 7, 1998;

(3) the account maintenance fee paid by the Secretary in accordance with section 1087h of this title;

(4) the default aversion fee paid in accordance with section 1078(l) of this title;

(5) amounts remaining pursuant to section 1078(c)(6)(B) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title from collection on defaulted loans held by the agency, after payment of the Secretary’s equitable share, excluding amounts deposited in the Federal Fund pursuant to section 1072a(c)(2) of this title; and

(6) other receipts as specified in regulations of the Secretary.


(d) Uses of funds(1) In generalFunds in the Operating Fund shall be used for application processing, loan disbursement, enrollment and repayment status management, default aversion activities (including those described in section 1072(h)(8) of this title), default collection activities, school and lender training, financial aid awareness and related outreach activities, compliance monitoring, and other student financial aid related activities, as selected by the guaranty agency.


(2) Special ruleThe guaranty agency may, in the agency’s discretion, transfer funds from the Operating Fund to the Federal Fund for use pursuant to section 1072a of this titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Each guaranty agency shall, not later than 60 days after October 7, 1998, establish a fund designated as the Operating Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investment of funds Funds deposited into the Operating Fund shall be invested at the discretion of the guaranty agency in accordance with prudent investor standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional deposits After the establishment of the Operating Fund, the guaranty agency shall deposit into the Operating Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uses of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1072b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership and regulation of Operating Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ownership and regulation of Operating Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>