<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_1"><akn:num>1078–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary flexible agreements with guaranty agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–1. Voluntary flexible agreements with guaranty agencies(a) Voluntary agreements(1) AuthoritySubject to paragraph (2),11 See References in Text note below. the Secretary may enter into a voluntary, flexible agreement with a guaranty agency under this section, in lieu of agreements with a guaranty agency under subsections (b) and (c) of section 1078 of this title. The Secretary may waive or modify any requirement under such subsections, except that the Secretary may not waive—(A) any statutory requirement pertaining to the terms and conditions attached to student loans or default claim payments made to lenders;

(B) the prohibitions on inducements contained in section 1078(b)(3) of this title; or

(C) the Federal default fee required by section 1078(b)(1)(H) of this title and the second sentence of section 1078–8(h) of this title.


(2) EligibilityDuring fiscal years 1999, 2000, and 2001, the Secretary may enter into a voluntary, flexible agreement with not more than 6 guaranty agencies that had 1 or more agreements with the Secretary under subsections (b) and (c) of section 1078 of this title as of the day before October 7, 1998. Beginning in fiscal year 2002, any guaranty agency or consortium thereof may enter into a voluntary flexible agreement with the Secretary.


(3) Report required(A) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the guaranty agencies operating under voluntary flexible agreements, shall report on an annual basis to the authorizing committees regarding the program outcomes that the voluntary flexible agreements have had with respect to—(i) program integrity and program and cost efficiencies, delinquency prevention, and default aversion, including a comparison of such outcomes to such outcomes for each guaranty agency operating under an agreement under subsection (b) or (c) of section 1078 of this title;

(ii) consumer education programs described in section 1083a of this title; and

(iii) the availability and delivery of student financial</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Voluntary agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of agreement An agreement between the Secretary and a guaranty agency under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination At the expiration or early termination of an agreement under this section, the Secretary shall reinstate the guaranty agency’s prior agreements under subsections (b) and (c) of section 1078 of this title, subject only to such additional requirements as the Secretary determines to be necessary in order to ensure the efficient transfer of responsibilities between the agreement under this section and the agreements under subsections (b) and (c) of section 1078 of this title, and including the guaranty agency’s compliance with reserve requirements under sections 1072 and 1078 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>