<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_2"><akn:num>1078–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal PLUS loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–2. Federal PLUS loans(a) Authority to borrow(1) Authority and eligibilityPrior to July 1, 2010, a graduate or professional student or the parents of a dependent student shall be eligible to borrow funds under this section in amounts specified in subsection (b), if—(A) the graduate or professional student or the parents do not have an adverse credit history as determined pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Secretary;

(B) in the case of a graduate or professional student or parent who has been convicted of, or has pled nolo contendere or guilty to, a crime involving fraud in obtaining funds under this subchapter, such graduate or professional student or parent has completed the repayment of such funds to the Secretary, or to the holder in the case of a loan under this subchapter obtained by fraud; and

(C) the graduate or professional student or the parents meet such other eligibility criteria as the Secretary may establish by regulation, after consultation with guaranty agencies, eligible lenders, and other organizations involved in student financial assistance.


(2) Terms, conditions, and benefitsExcept as provided in subsections (c), (d), and (e), loans made under this section shall have the same terms, conditions, and benefits as all other loans made under this part.


(3) Special rules(A) Parent borrowersWhenever necessary to carry out the provisions of this section, the terms “student” and “borrower” as used in this part shall include a parent borrower under this section.


(B)(i) Extenuating circumstancesAn eligible lender may determine that extenuating circumstances exist under the regulations promulgated pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) if, during the period beginning January 1, 2007, and ending December 31, 2009, an applicant for a loan under this section—(I) is or has been delinquent for 180 days or fewer on mortgage loan payments or on medical bill payments during such period; and

(II) does not otherwise have an adverse credit history, as dete</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to borrow</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to borrow</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation based on need</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation based on need Any loan under this section may be counted as part of the student aid index in the determination of need under this subchapter, but no loan may be made to any graduate or professional student or any parent under this section for any academic year in excess of (A) the student’s estimated cost of attendance, minus (B) other financial aid as certified by the eligible institution under section 1078(a)(2)(A) of this title. The annual insurable limit on account of any student shall not be deemed to be exceeded by a line of credit under which actual payments to the borrower will not be made in any year in excess of the annual limit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>PLUS loan disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) PLUS loan disbursement All loans made under this section shall be disbursed in accordance with the requirements of section 1078–7 of this title and shall be disbursed by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of principal and interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of principal and interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refinancing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Refinancing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification of immigration status and social security number</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Verification of immigration status and social security number A parent who wishes to borrow funds under this section shall be subject to verification of the parent’s—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>