<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_3"><akn:num>1078–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal consolidation loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–3. Federal consolidation loans(a) Agreements with eligible lenders(1) Agreement required for insurance coverageFor the purpose of providing loans to eligible borrowers for consolidation of their obligations with respect to eligible student loans, the Secretary or a guaranty agency shall enter into agreements in accordance with subsection (b) with the following eligible lenders:(A) the Student Loan Marketing Association or the Holding Company of the Student Loan Marketing Association, including any subsidiary of the Holding Company, created pursuant to section 1087–3 of this title;

(B) State agencies described in subparagraphs (D) and (F) of section 1085(d)(1) of this title; and

(C) other eligible lenders described in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), (E), and (J) of such section.


(2) Insurance coverage of consolidation loansExcept as provided in section 1079(e) of this title, no contract of insurance under this part shall apply to a consolidation loan unless such loan is made under an agreement pursuant to this section and is covered by a certificate issued in accordance with subsection (b)(2). Loans covered by such a certificate that is issued by a guaranty agency shall be considered to be insured loans for the purposes of reimbursements under section 1078(c) of this title, but no payment shall be made with respect to such loans under section 1078(f) of this title to any such agency.


(3) Definition of eligible borrower(A) For the purpose of this section, the term “eligible borrower” means a borrower who—(i) is not subject to a judgment secured through litigation with respect to a loan under this subchapter or to an order for wage garnishment under section 1095a of this title; and

(ii) at the time of application for a consolidation loan—(I) is in repayment status as determined under section 1078(b)(7)(A) of this title;

(II) is in a grace period preceding repayment; or

(III) is a defaulted borrower who has made arrangements to repay the obligation on the d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with eligible lenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreements with eligible lenders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of agreements, certificates of insurance, and loan notes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of agreements, certificates of insurance, and loan notes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of principal and interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of principal and interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special program authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of authority The authority to make loans under this section expires at the close of June 30, 2010. No loan may be made under this section for which the disbursement is on or after July 1, 2010. Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to promulgate rules or regulations governing the terms or conditions of the agreements and certificates under subsection (b). Loans made under this section which are insured by the Secretary shall be considered to be new loans made to students for the purpose of section 1074(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest payment rebate fee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Interest payment rebate fee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>