<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_12"><akn:num>1078–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan repayment for civil legal assistance attorneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–12. Loan repayment for civil legal assistance attorneys(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to encourage qualified individuals to enter and continue employment as civil legal assistance attorneys.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Civil legal assistance attorneyThe term “civil legal assistance attorney” means an attorney who—(A) is a full-time employee of—(i) a nonprofit organization that provides legal assistance with respect to civil matters to low-income individuals without a fee; or

(ii) a protection and advocacy system or client assistance program that provides legal assistance with respect to civil matters and receives funding under—(I) subtitle C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 (42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.);

(II) section 732 or 794e of title 29;

(III) part A of title I of the Protection and Advocacy for Individuals with Mental Illness Act (42 U.S.C. 10801 et seq.);

(IV) section 3004 of title 29;

(V) section 1320b–21 of title 42;

(VI) section 300d–53 of title 42; or

(VII) section 21061 of title 52;



(B) as such employee, provides civil legal assistance as described in subparagraph (A) on a full-time basis; and

(C) is continually licensed to practice law.


(2) Student loan(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the term “student loan” means—(i) subject to clause (ii), a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part, part D, or part E; and

(ii) a loan made under section 1078–3 or 1087e(g) of this title, to the extent that such loan was used to repay—(I) a Federal Direct Stafford Loan, a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or a Federal Direct PLUS Loan;

(II) a loan made under section 1078, 1078–2, or 1078–8 of this title; or

(III) a loan made under part E.



(B) Exclusion of parent plus loansThe term “student loan” does not include any of the following loans:(i) A loan made to the parents of a dependent student under section 1078–2 of this title.

(ii) A Fede</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to encourage qualified individuals to enter and continue employment as civil legal assistance attorneys.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program authorized From amounts appropriated under subsection (i) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall carry out a program of assuming the obligation to repay a student loan, by direct payments on behalf of a borrower to the holder of such loan, in accordance with subsection (d), for any borrower who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award basis; priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Award basis; priority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility for double benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Ineligibility for double benefits No borrower may, for the same service, receive a reduction of loan obligations under both this section and section 1078–11 or 1087e(m) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations The Secretary is authorized to issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_12_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>