<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_7"><akn:num>1078–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for disbursement of student loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–7. Requirements for disbursement of student loans(a) Multiple disbursement required(1) Two disbursements requiredThe proceeds of any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part that is made for any period of enrollment shall be disbursed in 2 or more installments, none of which exceeds one-half of the loan.


(2) Minimum interval requiredThe interval between the first and second such installments shall be not less than one-half of such period of enrollment, except as necessary to permit the second installment to be disbursed at the beginning of the second semester, quarter, or similar division of such period of enrollment.


(3) Special ruleAn institution whose cohort default rate (as determined under section 1085(m) of this title) for each of the 3 most recent fiscal years for which data are available is less than 10 percent may disburse any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part in a single installment for any period of enrollment that is not more than 1 semester, 1 trimester, 1 quarter, or 4 months. Notwithstanding section 422(d) of the Higher Education Amendments of 1998, this paragraph shall be effective beginning on February 8, 2006.


(4) Amendment to special ruleBeginning on October 1, 2011, the special rule under paragraph (3) shall be applied by substituting “15 percent” for “10 percent”.



(b) Disbursement and endorsement requirements(1) First year studentsThe first installment of the proceeds of any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part that is made to a student borrower who is entering the first year of a program of undergraduate education, and who has not previously obtained a loan under this part, shall not (regardless of the amount of such loan or the duration of the period of enrollment) be presented by the institution to the student for endorsement until 30 days after the borrower begins a course of study, but may be delivered to the eligible institution prior to the end of that 30-day period. An institution who</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multiple disbursement required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Multiple disbursement required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement and endorsement requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disbursement and endorsement requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method of multiple disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Method of multiple disbursement Disbursements under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of second disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Withholding of second disbursement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of consolidation and foreign study loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of consolidation and foreign study loans The provisions of this section shall not apply in the case of a loan made under section 1078–3 of this title, or made to a student to cover the cost of attendance in a program of study abroad approved by the home eligible institution if the home eligible institution has a cohort default rate (as calculated under section 1085(m) of this title) of less than 5 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beginning of period of enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Beginning of period of enrollment For purposes of this section, a period of enrollment begins on the first day that classes begin for the applicable period of enrollment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales prior to disbursement prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sales prior to disbursement prohibited An eligible lender shall not sell or transfer a promissory note for any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part until the final disbursement of such loan has been made, except that the prohibition of this subsection shall not apply if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>