<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1078–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1078_8"><akn:num>1078–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsubsidized Stafford loans for middle-income borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1078–8. Unsubsidized Stafford loans for middle-income borrowers(a) In generalIt is the purpose of this section to authorize insured loans under this part that are first disbursed before July 1, 2010, for borrowers who do not qualify for Federal interest subsidy payments under section 1078 of this title. Except as provided in this section, all terms and conditions for Federal Stafford loans established under section 1078 of this title shall apply to loans made pursuant to this section.


(b) Eligible borrowersPrior to July 1, 2010, any student meeting the requirements for student eligibility under section 1091 of this title (including graduate and professional students as defined in regulations promulgated by the Secretary) shall be entitled to borrow an unsubsidized Federal Stafford Loan for which the first disbursement is made before such date if the eligible institution at which the student has been accepted for enrollment, or at which the student is in attendance, has—(1) determined and documented the student’s need for the loan based on the student’s estimated cost of attendance (as determined under section 1087ll of this title) and the student’s estimated financial assistance, including a loan which qualifies for interest subsidy payments under section 1078 of this title; and

(2) provided the lender a statement—(A) certifying the eligibility of the student to receive a loan under this section and the amount of the loan for which such student is eligible, in accordance with subsection (c); and

(B) setting forth a schedule for disbursement of the proceeds of the loan in installments, consistent with the requirements of section 1078–7 of this title.



(c) Determination of amount of loanThe determination of the amount of a loan by an eligible institution under subsection (b) shall be calculated by subtracting from the estimated cost of attendance at the eligible institution any estimated financial assistance reasonably available to such student. An eligible in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general It is the purpose of this section to authorize insured loans under this part that are first disbursed before July 1, 2010, for borrowers who do not qualify for Federal interest subsidy payments under section 1078 of this title. Except as provided in this section, all terms and conditions for Federal Stafford loans established under section 1078 of this title shall apply to loans made pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible borrowers Prior to July 1, 2010, any student meeting the requirements for student eligibility under section 1091 of this title (including graduate and professional students as defined in regulations promulgated by the Secretary) shall be entitled to borrow an unsubsidized Federal Stafford Loan for which the first disbursement is made before such date if the eligible institution at which the student has been accepted for enrollment, or at which the student is in attendance, has—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount of loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of amount of loan The determination of the amount of a loan by an eligible institution under subsection (b) shall be calculated by subtracting from the estimated cost of attendance at the eligible institution any estimated financial assistance reasonably available to such student. An eligible institution may not, in carrying out the provisions of subsection (b) of this section, provide a statement which certifies the eligibility of any student to receive any loan under this section in excess of the amount calculated under the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Loan limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of principal and interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment of principal and interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 423(f), Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1698</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single application form and loan repayment schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Single application form and loan repayment schedule A guaranty agency shall use a single application form and a single repayment schedule for subsidized Federal Stafford loans made pursuant to section 1078 of this title and for unsubsidized Federal Stafford loans made pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1078_8_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance premium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Insurance premium Each State or nonprofit private institution or organization having an agreement with the Secretary under section 1078(b)(1) of this title may charge a borrower under this section an insurance premium equal to not more than 1.0 percent of the principal amount of the loan, if such premium will not be used for incentive payments to lenders. Effective for loans for which the date of guarantee of principal is on or after July 1, 2006, and that are first disbursed before July 1, 2010, in lieu of the insurance premium authorized under the preceding sentence, each State or nonprofit private institution or organization having an agreement with the Secretary under section 1078(b)(1) of this title shall collect and deposit into the Federal Student Loan Reserve Fund under section 1072a of this title, a Federal default fee of an amount equal to 1.0 percent of the principal amount of the loan, which fee shall be collected either by deduction from the proceeds of the loan or by </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>