<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_107a"><akn:num>107a</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal and State responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 107a. Federal and State responsibilities(a) Functions of Secretary; surveys; designation of State licensing agencies; qualifications for license; evaluation of programsThe Secretary of Education shall—(1) Insure that the Rehabilitation Services Administration is the principal agency for carrying out this chapter; and the Commissioner shall, within one hundred and eighty days after enactment of the Randolph-Sheppard Act Amendments of 1974, establish requirements for the uniform application of this chapter by each State agency designated under paragraph (5) of this subsection, including appropriate accounting procedures, policies on the selection and establishment of new vending facilities, distribution of income to blind vendors, and the use and control of set-aside funds under section 107b(3) of this title;

(2) Through the Commissioner, make annual surveys of concession vending opportunities for blind persons on Federal and other property in the United States, particularly with respect to Federal property under the control of the General Services Administration, the Department of Defense, and the United States Postal Service;

(3) Make surveys throughout the United States of industries with a view to obtaining information that will assist blind persons to obtain employment;

(4) Make available to the public, and especially to persons and organizations engaged in work for the blind, information obtained as a result of such surveys;

(5) Designate as provided in section 107b of this title the State agency for the blind in each State, or, in any State in which there is no such agency, some other public agency to issue licenses to blind persons who are citizens of the United States for the operating of vending facilities on Federal and other property in such State for the vending of newspapers, periodicals, confections, tobacco products, foods, beverages, and other articles or services dispensed automatically or manually and prepared on or off the premises in accorda</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Secretary; surveys; designation of State licensing agencies; qualifications for license; evaluation of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Functions of Secretary; surveys; designation of State licensing agencies; qualifications for license; evaluation of programs The Secretary of Education shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of State licensing agencies to prefer blind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty of State licensing agencies to prefer blind The State licensing agency shall, in issuing each such license for the operation of a vending facility, give preference to blind persons who are in need of employment. Each such license shall be issued for an indefinite period but may be terminated by the State licensing agency if it is satisfied that the facility is not being operated in accordance with the rules and regulations prescribed by such licensing agency. Such licenses shall be issued only to applicants who are blind within the meaning of section 107e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of location and type of facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection of location and type of facility The State licensing agency designated by the Secretary is authorized, with the approval of the head of the department or agency in control of the maintenance, operation, and protection of the Federal property on which the facility is to be located but subject to regulations prescribed pursuant to section 107 of this title, to select a location for such facility and the type of facility to be provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buildings occupied by United States departments, agencies, and instrumentalities required to provide sites for facilities; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Buildings occupied by United States departments, agencies, and instrumentalities required to provide sites for facilities; exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State licensing agency in States having vocational rehabilitation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State licensing agency in States having vocational rehabilitation plans In any State having an approved plan for vocational rehabilitation pursuant to the Vocational Rehabilitation Act or the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.], the State licensing agency designated under paragraph (5) of subsection (a) of this section shall be the State agency designated under section 101(a)(2)(A) of such Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 721(a)(2)(A)].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>