<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_107b_1"><akn:num>107b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to information with State licensing agencies; election and responsibilities of Committee of B</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 107b–1. Access to information with State licensing agencies; election and responsibilities of Committee of Blind Vendors
In addition to other requirements imposed in this title 11 See References in Text note below. and in the Randolph-Sheppard Act [20 U.S.C. 107 et seq.] upon State licensing agencies, such agencies shall—(1) provide to each blind licensee access to all relevant financial data, including quarterly and annual financial reports, on the operation of the State vending facility program;

(2) conduct the biennial election of a Committee of Blind Vendors who shall be fully representative of all blind licensees in the State program,22 So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon. and

(3) insure that such committee’s responsibilities include (A) participation, with the State agency, in major administrative decisions and policy and program development, (B) receiving grievances of blind licensees and serving as advocates for such licensees, (C) participation, with the State agency, in the development and administration of a transfer and promotion system for blind licensees, (D) participation, with the State agency, in developing training and retraining programs, and (E) sponsorship, with the assistance of the State agency, of meetings and instructional conferences for blind licensees.

(Pub. L. 93–516, title II, § 209, Dec. 7, 1974, 88 Stat. 1630; Pub. L. 93–651, title II, § 209, Nov. 21, 1974, 89 Stat. 2–15.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis title, referred to in text, is title II of Pub. L. 93–516, Dec. 7, 1974, 88 Stat. 1617, known as the “Randolph-Sheppard Act Amendments of 1974”. For complete classification of such title to the Code, see Short Title of 1974 Amendment note set out under section 107 of this title and Tables.
The Randolph-Sheppard Act, referred to in text, is act June 20, 1936, ch. 638, 49 Stat. 1559, also popularly known as the Randolph-Sheppard Vending Stand Act, which is classified generally to this chapter. For comp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107b_1_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) provide to each blind licensee access to all relevant financial data, including quarterly and annual financial reports, on the operation of the State vending facility program;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107b_1_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) conduct the biennial election of a Committee of Blind Vendors who shall be fully representative of all blind licensees in the State program,22 So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon. and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107b_1_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) insure that such committee’s responsibilities include (A) participation, with the State agency, in major administrative decisions and policy and program development, (B) receiving grievances of blind licensees and serving as advocates for such licensees, (C) participation, with the State agency, in the development and administration of a transfer and promotion system for blind licensees, (D) participation, with the State agency, in developing training and retraining programs, and (E) sponsorship, with the assistance of the State agency, of meetings and instructional conferences for blind licensees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>