<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_107d_2"><akn:num>107d–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Arbitration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 107d–2. Arbitration(a) Notice and hearingUpon receipt of a complaint filed under section 107d–1 of this title, the Secretary shall convene an ad hoc arbitration panel as provided in subsection (b). Such panel shall, in accordance with the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5, give notice, conduct a hearing, and render its decision which shall be subject to appeal and review as a final agency action for purposes of chapter 7 of such title 5.


(b) Composition of panel; designation of chairman; termination of violations(1) The arbitration panel convened by the Secretary to hear grievances of blind licensees shall be composed of three members appointed as follows:(A) one individual designated by the State licensing agency;

(B) one individual designated by the blind licensee; and

(C) one individual, not employed by the State licensing agency or, where appropriate, its parent agency, who shall serve as chairman, jointly designated by the members appointed under subparagraphs (A) and (B).


If any party fails to designate a member under subparagraph (1)(A), (B), or (C), the Secretary shall designate such member on behalf of such party.

(2) The arbitration panel convened by the Secretary to hear complaints filed by a State licensing agency shall be composed of three members appointed as follows:(A) one individual, designated by the State licensing agency;

(B) one individual, designated by the head of the Federal department, agency, or instrumentality controlling the Federal property over which the dispute arose; and

(C) one individual, not employed by the Federal department, agency, or instrumentality controlling the Federal property over which the dispute arose, who shall serve as chairman, jointly designated by the members appointed under subparagraphs (A) and (B).


If any party fails to designate a member under subparagraph (2)(A), (B), or (C), the Secretary shall designate such member on behalf of such party. If the panel appointed pursuant to pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice and hearing Upon receipt of a complaint filed under section 107d–1 of this title, the Secretary shall convene an ad hoc arbitration panel as provided in subsection (b). Such panel shall, in accordance with the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5, give notice, conduct a hearing, and render its decision which shall be subject to appeal and review as a final agency action for purposes of chapter 7 of such title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of panel; designation of chairman; termination of violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition of panel; designation of chairman; termination of violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of decisions in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Publication of decisions in Federal Register The decisions of a panel convened by the Secretary pursuant to this section shall be matters of public record and shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of costs by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of costs by the Secretary The Secretary shall pay all reasonable costs of arbitration under this section in accordance with a schedule of fees and expenses he shall publish in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>