<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/107d–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_107d_1"><akn:num>107d–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Grievances of blind licensees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 107d–1. Grievances of blind licensees(a) Hearing and arbitrationAny blind licensee who is dissatisfied with any action arising from the operation or administration of the vending facility program may submit to a State licensing agency a request for a full evidentiary hearing, which shall be provided by such agency in accordance with section 107b(6) of this title. If such blind licensee is dissatisfied with any action taken or decision rendered as a result of such hearing, he may file a complaint with the Secretary who shall convene a panel to arbitrate the dispute pursuant to section 107d–2 of this title, and the decision of such panel shall be final and binding on the parties except as otherwise provided in this chapter.


(b) Noncompliance by Federal departments and agencies; complaints by State licensing agencies; arbitrationWhenever any State licensing agency determines that any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States that has control of the maintenance, operation, and protection of Federal property is failing to comply with the provisions of this chapter or any regulations issued thereunder (including a limitation on the placement or operation of a vending facility as described in section 107(b) of this title and the Secretary’s determination thereon) such licensing agency may file a complaint with the Secretary who shall convene a panel to arbitrate the dispute pursuant to section 107d–2 of this title, and the decision of such panel shall be final and binding on the parties except as otherwise provided in this chapter.


(June 20, 1936, ch. 638, § 5, as added Pub. L. 93–516, title II, § 206, Dec. 7, 1974, 88 Stat. 1626; Pub. L. 93–651, title II, § 206, Nov. 21, 1974, 89 Stat. 2–11.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
The content of Pub. L. 93–516, including provisions of section 206 thereof which enacted this section, were originally contained in H.R. 14225, 93rd Congress, Second Session, which was pocket-vetoed during the 31-day intrasession </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing and arbitration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hearing and arbitration Any blind licensee who is dissatisfied with any action arising from the operation or administration of the vending facility program may submit to a State licensing agency a request for a full evidentiary hearing, which shall be provided by such agency in accordance with section 107b(6) of this title. If such blind licensee is dissatisfied with any action taken or decision rendered as a result of such hearing, he may file a complaint with the Secretary who shall convene a panel to arbitrate the dispute pursuant to section 107d–2 of this title, and the decision of such panel shall be final and binding on the parties except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_107d_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance by Federal departments and agencies; complaints by State licensing agencies; arbitration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Noncompliance by Federal departments and agencies; complaints by State licensing agencies; arbitration Whenever any State licensing agency determines that any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States that has control of the maintenance, operation, and protection of Federal property is failing to comply with the provisions of this chapter or any regulations issued thereunder (including a limitation on the placement or operation of a vending facility as described in section 107(b) of this title and the Secretary’s determination thereon) such licensing agency may file a complaint with the Secretary who shall convene a panel to arbitrate the dispute pursuant to section 107d–2 of this title, and the decision of such panel shall be final and binding on the parties except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>