<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1083" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1083/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1083/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1083"><akn:num>1083</akn:num><akn:heading>Student loan information by eligible lenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1083. Student loan information by eligible lenders(a) Required disclosure before disbursementEach eligible lender, at or prior to the time such lender disburses a loan that is insured or guaranteed under this part (other than a loan made under section 1078–3 of this title), shall provide thorough and accurate loan information on such loan to the borrower in simple and understandable terms. Any disclosure required by this subsection may be made by an eligible lender by written or electronic means, including as part of the application material provided to the borrower, as part of the promissory note evidencing the loan, or on a separate written form provided to the borrower. Each lender shall provide to each borrower a telephone number, and may provide an electronic address, through which additional loan information can be obtained. The disclosure shall include—(1) a statement prominently and clearly displayed and in bold print that the borrower is receiving a loan that must be repaid;

(2) the name of the eligible lender, and the address to which communications and payments should be sent;

(3) the principal amount of the loan;

(4) the amount of any charges, such as the origination fee and Federal default fee, and whether those fees will be—(A) collected by the lender at or prior to the disbursal of the loan;

(B) deducted from the proceeds of the loan;

(C) paid separately by the borrower; or

(D) paid by the lender;


(5) the stated interest rate on the loan;

(6) for loans made under section 1078–8 of this title or to a student borrower under section 1078–2 of this title, an explanation—(A) that the borrower has the option to pay the interest that accrues on the loan while the borrower is a student at an institution of higher education; and

(B) if the borrower does not pay such interest while attending an institution, when and how often interest on the loan will be capitalized;


(7) for loans made to a parent borrower on behalf of a student under section 1078</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosure before disbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required disclosure before disbursement Each eligible lender, at or prior to the time such lender disburses a loan that is insured or guaranteed under this part (other than a loan made under section 1078–3 of this title), shall provide thorough and accurate loan information on such loan to the borrower in simple and understandable terms. Any disclosure required by this subsection may be made by an eligible lender by written or electronic means, including as part of the application material provided to the borrower, as part of the promissory note evidencing the loan, or on a separate written form provided to the borrower. Each lender shall provide to each borrower a telephone number, and may provide an electronic address, through which additional loan information can be obtained. The disclosure shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosure before repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required disclosure before repayment Each eligible lender shall, at or prior to the start of the repayment period on a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under section 1078, 1078–2, or 1078–8 of this title, disclose to the borrower by written or electronic means the information required under this subsection in simple and understandable terms. Each eligible lender shall provide to each borrower a telephone number, and may provide an electronic address, through which additional loan information can be obtained. The disclosure required by this subsection shall be made not less than 30 days nor more than 150 days before the first payment on the loan is due from the borrower. The disclosure shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separate notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Separate notification Each eligible lender shall, at the time such lender notifies a borrower of approval of a loan which is insured or guaranteed under this part, provide the borrower with a separate notification which summarizes, in simple and understandable terms, the rights and responsibilities of the borrower with respect to the loan, including a statement of the consequences of defaulting on the loan and a statement that each borrower who defaults will be reported to a consumer reporting agency. The requirement of this subsection shall be in addition to the information required by subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special disclosure rules on PLUS loans, and unsubsidized loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special disclosure rules on PLUS loans, and unsubsidized loans Loans made under sections 1078–2 and 1078–8 of this title shall not be subject to the disclosure of projected monthly payment amounts required under subsection (b)(7) if the lender, in lieu of such disclosure, provides the borrower with sample projections of monthly repayment amounts, assuming different levels of borrowing and interest accruals resulting from capitalization of interest while the borrower, or the student on whose behalf the loan is made, is in school, in simple and understandable terms. Such sample projections shall disclose the cost to the borrower of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required disclosures during repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Required disclosures during repayment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1083_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost of disclosure and consequences of nondisclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cost of disclosure and consequences of nondisclosure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>