<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–58" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–58/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–58/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087_58"><akn:num>1087–58</akn:num><akn:heading>Work colleges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087–58. Work colleges(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to recognize, encourage, and promote the use of comprehensive work-learning-service programs as a valuable educational approach when it is an integral part of the institution’s educational program and a part of a financial plan which decreases reliance on grants and loans.


(b) Source and use of funds(1) Source of fundsIn addition to the sums appropriated under subsection (f) of this section, funds allocated to the institution under this part and part E of this subchapter may be transferred for use under this section to provide flexibility in strengthening the self-help-through-work element in financial aid packaging.


(2) Activities authorizedFrom the sums appropriated pursuant to subsection (f) of this section, and from the funds available under paragraph (1), eligible institutions may, following approval of an application under subsection (c) of this section by the Secretary—(A) support the educational costs of qualified students through self-help payments or credits provided under the work-learning-service program of the institution within the limits of part F of this subchapter;

(B) promote the work-learning-service experience as a tool of postsecondary education, financial self-help and community service-learning opportunities;

(C) carry out activities described in section 1087–53 or 1087–56 of this title;

(D) be used for the administration, development and assessment of comprehensive work-learning-service programs, including—(i) community-based work-learning-service alternatives that expand opportunities for community service and career-related work; and

(ii) alternatives that develop sound citizenship, encourage student persistence, and make optimum use of assistance under this part in education and student development;


(E) coordinate and carry out joint projects and activities to promote work service learning; and

(F) carry out a comprehensive, longitudinal study of student academic </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to recognize, encourage, and promote the use of comprehensive work-learning-service programs as a valuable educational approach when it is an integral part of the institution’s educational program and a part of a financial plan which decreases reliance on grants and loans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source and use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Source and use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application Each eligible institution may submit an application for funds authorized by subsection (f) of this section to use funds under subsection (b)(1) of this section at such time and in such manner as the Secretary, by regulation, may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Match required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Match required Funds made available to work-colleges pursuant to this section shall be matched on a dollar-for-dollar basis from non-Federal sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_58_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>