<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087h"><akn:num>1087h</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087h. Funds for administrative expenses(a) Administrative expenses(1) Additional mandatory funds for servicingThere shall be available to the Secretary (in addition to any other amounts appropriated under any appropriations Act for administrative costs under this part and part B and out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated) $1,000,000,000 to be obligated for administrative costs under this part and part B, including the costs of servicing the direct student loan programs under this part, which shall remain available until expended.


(2) Repealed. Pub. L. 113–67, div. A, title V, § 502(2), Dec. 26, 2013, 127 Stat. 1187

(3) Authorization for administrative costs beginning in fiscal years 2007 through 2014For each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2014, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for administrative costs under this part and part B, including the costs of the direct student loan programs under this part.


(4) Continuing mandatory funds for account maintenance feesFor each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2021,11 See Funds for Account Maintenance Fees note below. there shall be available to the Secretary, from funds not otherwise appropriated, funds to be obligated for account maintenance fees payable to guaranty agencies under part B and calculated in accordance with subsection (b).


(5) Account maintenance feesAccount maintenance fees under paragraph (3) 22 See References in Text note below. shall be paid quarterly and deposited in the Agency Operating Fund established under section 1072b of this title.


(6) Technical assistance to institutions of higher education(A) Provision of assistanceThe Secretary shall provide institutions of higher education participating, or seeking to participate, in the loan programs under this part with technical assistance in establishing and administering such programs.


(B) FundsThere are authorized to be appropriated, and there are appropriated, to carry out this para</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Calculation basis Account maintenance fees payable to guaranty agencies under subsection (a)(4) shall be calculated on the basis of 0.06 percent of the original principal amount of outstanding loans on which insurance was issued under part B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget justification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Budget justification No funds may be expended under this section unless the Secretary includes in the Department of Education’s annual budget justification to Congress a detailed description of the specific activities for which the funds made available by this section have been used in the prior and current years (if applicable), the activities and costs planned for the budget year, and the projection of activities and costs for each remaining year for which administrative expenses under this section are made available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>