<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–53" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–53/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–53/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087_53"><akn:num>1087–53</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for Federal work-study programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087–53. Grants for Federal work-study programs(a) Agreements requiredThe Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements with institutions of higher education under which the Secretary will make grants to such institutions to assist in the operation of work-study programs as provided in this part.


(b) Contents of agreementsAn agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall—(1) provide for the operation by the institution of a program for the part-time employment, including internships, practica, or research assistantships as determined by the Secretary, of its students in work for the institution itself, work in community service or work in the public interest for a Federal, State, or local public agency or private nonprofit organization under an arrangement between the institution and such agency or organization, and such work—(A) will not result in the displacement of employed workers or impair existing contracts for services;

(B) will be governed by such conditions of employment as will be appropriate and reasonable in light of such factors as type of work performed, geographical region, and proficiency of the employee;

(C) does not involve the construction, operation, or maintenance of so much of any facility as is used or is to be used for sectarian instruction or as a place for religious worship; and

(D) will not pay any wage to students employed under this subpart 11 So in original. Probably should be “part”. that is less than the current Federal minimum wage as mandated by section 206 of title 29;


(2) provide that funds granted an institution of higher education, pursuant to this section, may be used only to make payments to students participating in work-study programs, except that—(A) for fiscal year 2000 and succeeding fiscal years, an institution shall use at least 7 percent of the total amount of funds granted to such institution under this section for such fiscal year to compensate students employed in community service, and shall ensu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_53_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreements required The Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements with institutions of higher education under which the Secretary will make grants to such institutions to assist in the operation of work-study programs as provided in this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_53_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of agreements An agreement entered into pursuant to this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_53_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private sector employment agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Private sector employment agreement As part of its agreement agreement 22 So in original. described in subsection (b) of this section, an institution of higher education may, at its option, enter into an additional agreement with the Secretary which shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_53_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tutoring and literacy activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tutoring and literacy activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_53_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civic education and participation activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Civic education and participation activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>