<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087f"><akn:num>1087f</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087f. Contracts(a) Contracts for supplies and services(1) In generalThe Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, award contracts for origination, servicing, and collection described in subsection (b). In awarding such contracts, the Secretary shall ensure that such services and supplies are provided at competitive prices.


(2) EntitiesThe entities with which the Secretary may enter into contracts shall include only entities which the Secretary determines are qualified to provide such services and supplies and will comply with the procedures applicable to the award of such contracts. In the case of awarding contracts for the origination, servicing, and collection of loans under this part, the Secretary shall enter into contracts only with entities that have extensive and relevant experience and demonstrated effectiveness. The entities with which the Secretary may enter into such contracts shall include, where practicable, agencies with agreements with the Secretary under sections 1078(b) and (c) of this title, if such agencies meet the qualifications as determined by the Secretary under this subsection and if those agencies have such experience and demonstrated effectiveness. In awarding contracts to such State agencies, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable and consistent with the purposes of this part, give special consideration to State agencies with a history of high quality performance to perform services for institutions of higher education within their State.


(3) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed as a limitation of the authority of any State agency to enter into an agreement for the purposes of this section as a member of a consortium of State agencies.



(b) Contracts for origination, servicing, and data systemsThe Secretary may enter into contracts for—(1) the alternative origination of loans to students attending institutions of higher education with agreements to participate in the program under this part (or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for supplies and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts for supplies and services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts for origination, servicing, and data systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contracts for origination, servicing, and data systems The Secretary may enter into contracts for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>