<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087"><akn:num>1087</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment by Secretary of loans of bankrupt, deceased, or disabled borrowers; treatment of borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087. Repayment by Secretary of loans of bankrupt, deceased, or disabled borrowers; treatment of borrowers attending schools that fail to provide a refund, attending closed schools, or falsely certified as eligible to borrow(a) Repayment in full for death and disability(1) In generalIf a student borrower who has received a loan described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1078(a)(1) of this title dies or becomes permanently and totally disabled (as determined in accordance with regulations of the Secretary), or if a student borrower who has received such a loan is unable to engage in any substantial gainful activity by reason of any medically determinable physical or mental impairment that can be expected to result in death, has lasted for a continuous period of not less than 60 months, or can be expected to last for a continuous period of not less than 60 months then the Secretary shall discharge the borrower’s liability on the loan by repaying the amount owed on the loan. The Secretary may develop such safeguards as the Secretary determines necessary to prevent fraud and abuse in the discharge of liability under this subsection. Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the Secretary may promulgate regulations to reinstate the obligation of, and resume collection on, loans discharged under this subsection in any case in which—(A) a borrower received a discharge of liability under this subsection and after the discharge the borrower—(i) receives a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this subchapter; or

(ii) has earned income in excess of the poverty line; or


(B) the Secretary determines the reinstatement and resumption to be necessary.


(2) Disability determinationsA borrower who has been determined by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to be unemployable due to a service-connected condition and who provides documentation of such determination to the Secretary of Education, shall be considered permanently and totally disabled for the purpo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment in full for death and disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repayment in full for death and disability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of claims on loans in bankruptcy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of claims on loans in bankruptcy The Secretary shall pay to the holder of a loan described in section 1078(a)(1)(A) or (B), 1078–1,11 See References in Text note below. 1078–2, 1078–3, or 1078–8 of this title, the amount of the unpaid balance of principal and interest owed on such loan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Discharge</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of loans to parents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repayment of loans to parents If a student on whose behalf a parent has received a loan described in section 1078–2 of this title dies, then the Secretary shall discharge the borrower’s liability on the loan by repaying the amount owed on the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>