<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087vv" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087vv/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087vv/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087vv"><akn:num>1087vv</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087vv. Definitions
In this part:(a) Total incomeThe term “total income” means the amount equal to adjusted gross income for the second preceding tax year plus untaxed income and benefits for the second preceding tax year minus excludable income for the second preceding tax year. The factors used to determine total income shall be derived from the Federal income tax return, if available, except for the applicant’s ability to indicate a qualified rollover in the second preceding tax year as outlined in section 1090 of this title or foreign income described in subsection (b)(5).


(b) Untaxed income and benefitsThe term “untaxed income and benefits” means—(1) deductions and payments to self-employed SEP, SIMPLE, Keogh, and other qualified individual retirement accounts excluded from income for Federal tax purposes, except such term shall not include payments made to tax-deferred pension and retirement plans, paid directly or withheld from earnings, that are not delineated on the Federal tax return;

(2) tax-exempt interest income;

(3) untaxed portion of individual retirement account distributions;

(4) untaxed portion of pensions; and

(5) foreign income of permanent residents of the United States or United States citizens exempt from Federal taxation, or the foreign income for which such a permanent resident or citizen receives a foreign tax credit.


(c) Veterans and veterans’ education benefits(1) The term “veteran” has the meaning given the term in section 101(2) of title 38 and includes individuals who served in the United States Armed Forces as described in sections 101(21), 101(22), and 101(23) of title 38.

(2) The term “veterans’ education benefits” means veterans’ benefits under the following provisions of law:(A) Chapter 103 of title 10 (Senior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps).

(B) Chapter 106A of title 10 (Educational Assistance for Persons Enlisting for Active Duty).

(C) Chapter 1606 of title 10 (Selected Reserve Educational Assistance Program).

(D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Total income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Total income The term “total income” means the amount equal to adjusted gross income for the second preceding tax year plus untaxed income and benefits for the second preceding tax year minus excludable income for the second preceding tax year. The factors used to determine total income shall be derived from the Federal income tax return, if available, except for the applicant’s ability to indicate a qualified rollover in the second preceding tax year as outlined in section 1090 of this title or foreign income described in subsection (b)(5).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Untaxed income and benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Untaxed income and benefits The term “untaxed income and benefits” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans and veterans’ education benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Veterans and veterans’ education benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent students and determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Independent students and determinations The term “independent”, when used with respect to a student, means any individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excludable income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Excludable income The term “excludable income” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Net value The term “net value” means the market value at the time of application of the assets (as defined in subsection (f)), minus the outstanding liabilities or indebtedness against the assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of income taxes paid to other jurisdictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Treatment of income taxes paid to other jurisdictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Other financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087vv_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Dependents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>