<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087cc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087cc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087cc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087cc"><akn:num>1087cc</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with institutions of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087cc. Agreements with institutions of higher education(a) Contents of agreementsAn agreement with any institution of higher education for the payment of Federal capital contributions under this part shall—(1) provide for the establishment and maintenance of a student loan fund for the purpose of this part;

(2) provide for the deposit in such fund of—(A) Federal capital contributions from funds appropriated under section 1087aa of this title;

(B) a capital contribution by an institution in an amount equal to one-third of the Federal capital contributions described in subparagraph (A);

(C) collections of principal and interest on student loans made from deposited funds;

(D) charges collected pursuant to regulations under section 1087dd(c)(1)(H) of this title; and

(E) any other earnings of the funds;


(3) provide that such student loan fund shall be used only for—(A) loans to students, in accordance with the provisions of this part;

(B) administrative expenses, as provided in subsection (b);

(C) capital distributions, as provided in section 1087ff of this title; and

(D) costs of litigation, and other collection costs agreed to by the Secretary in connection with the collection of a loan from the fund (and interest thereon) or a charge assessed pursuant to regulations under section 1087dd(c)(1)(H) of this title;


(4) provide that where a note or written agreement evidencing a loan has been in default despite due diligence on the part of the institution in attempting collection thereon—(A) if the institution has knowingly failed to maintain an acceptable collection record with respect to such loan, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with criteria established by regulation, the Secretary may—(i) require the institution to assign such note or agreement to the Secretary, without recompense; and

(ii) apportion any sums collected on such a loan, less an amount not to exceed 30 percent of any sums collected to cover the Secretary’s collection costs, am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087cc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contents of agreements An agreement with any institution of higher education for the payment of Federal capital contributions under this part shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087cc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative expenses An institution which has entered into an agreement under subsection (a) shall be entitled, for each fiscal year during which it makes student loans from a student loan fund established under such agreement, to a payment in lieu of reimbursement for its expenses in administering its student loan program under this part during such year. Such payment shall be made in accordance with section 1096 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087cc_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements with consumer reporting agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperative agreements with consumer reporting agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087cc_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of interest bearing accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on use of interest bearing accounts In carrying out the provisions of subsection (a)(9), the Secretary may not require that any collection agency, collection attorney, or loan servicer collecting loans made under this part deposit amounts collected on such loans in interest bearing accounts, unless such agency, attorney, or servicer holds such amounts for more than 45 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087cc_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special due diligence rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special due diligence rule In carrying out the provisions of subsection (a)(5) 11 See References in Text note below. relating to due diligence, the Secretary shall make every effort to ensure that institutions of higher education may use Internal Revenue Service skip-tracing collection procedures on loans made under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>