<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087_2"><akn:num>1087–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Student Loan Marketing Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087–2. Student Loan Marketing Association(a) PurposeThe Congress hereby declares that it is the purpose of this section (1) to establish a private corporation which will be financed by private capital and which will serve as a secondary market and warehousing facility for student loans, including loans which are insured by the Secretary under this part or by a guaranty agency, and which will provide liquidity for student loan investments; (2) in order to facilitate secured transactions involving student loans, to provide for perfection of security interests in student loans either through the taking of possession or by notice filing; and (3) to assure nationwide the establishment of adequate loan insurance programs for students, to provide for an additional program of loan insurance to be covered by agreements with the Secretary.


(b) Establishment(1) In generalThere is hereby created a body corporate to be known as the Student Loan Marketing Association (hereinafter referred to as the “Association”). The Association shall have succession until dissolved. It shall maintain its principal office in the District of Columbia and shall be deemed, for purposes of venue and jurisdiction in civil actions, to be a resident and citizen thereof. Offices may be established by the Association in such other place or places as it may deem necessary or appropriate for the conduct of its business.


(2) Exemption from State and local taxesThe Association, including its franchise, capital, reserves, surplus, mortgages, or other security holdings, and income shall be exempt from all taxation now or hereafter imposed by any State, territory, possession, Commonwealth, or dependency of the United States, or by the District of Columbia, or by any county, municipality, or local taxing authority, except that any real property of the Association shall be subject to State, territorial, county, municipal, or local taxation to the same extent according to its value as other real property is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The Congress hereby declares that it is the purpose of this section (1) to establish a private corporation which will be financed by private capital and which will serve as a secondary market and warehousing facility for student loans, including loans which are insured by the Secretary under this part or by a guaranty agency, and which will provide liquidity for student loan investments; (2) in order to facilitate secured transactions involving student loans, to provide for perfection of security interests in student loans either through the taking of possession or by notice filing; and (3) to assure nationwide the establishment of adequate loan insurance programs for students, to provide for an additional program of loan insurance to be covered by agreements with the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board of Directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority of Association</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advances to lenders that do not discriminate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advances to lenders that do not discriminate The Association, pursuant to such criteria as the Board of Directors may prescribe, shall make advances on security or purchase student loans pursuant to subsection (d) only after the Association is assured that the lender (1) does not discriminate by pattern or practice against any particular class or category of students by requiring that, as a condition to the receipt of a loan, the student or his family maintain a business relationship with the lender, except that this clause shall not apply in the case of a loan made by a credit union, savings and loan association, mutual savings bank, institution of higher education, or any other lender with less than $75,000,000 in deposits, and (2) does not discriminate on the basis of race, sex, color, creed, or national origin.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stock of the Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Stock of the Association</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferred stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preferred stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debt obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Debt obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>General corporate powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) General corporate powers The Association shall have power—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_2_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting, auditing, and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Accounting, auditing, and reporting The accounts of the Association shall be audited annually. Such audits shall be conducted in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants or by independent licensed public accountants, licensed on or before December 31, 1970, who are certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State or other political subdivision of the United States, except that independent public accountants licensed to practice by such regulatory authority after December 31, 1970, and persons who, although not so certified or licensed, meet, in the opinion of the Secretary, standards of education and experience representative of the highest standards prescribed by the licensing authorities of the several States which provide for the continuing licensing of public accountants and which are prescribed by the Secretary in appropriate regulations may perform such audits until December 31, 1975. A report of each such aud</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>