<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087_1"><akn:num>1087–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Special allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087–1. Special allowances(a) FindingsIn order to assure (1) that the limitation on interest payments or other conditions (or both) on loans made or insured under this part, do not impede or threaten to impede the carrying out of the purposes of this part or do not cause the return to holders of loans to be less than equitable, (2) that incentive payments on such loans are paid promptly to eligible lenders, and (3) that appropriate consideration of relative administrative costs and money market conditions is made in setting the quarterly rate of such payments, the Congress finds it necessary to establish an improved method for the determination of the quarterly rate of the special allowances on such loans, and to provide for a thorough, expeditious, and objective examination of alternative methods for the determination of the quarterly rate of such allowances.


(b) Computation and payment(1) Quarterly payment based on unpaid balanceA special allowance shall be paid for each of the 3-month periods ending March 31, June 30, September 30, and December 31 of every year and the amount of such allowance paid to any holder with respect to any 3-month period shall be a percentage of the average unpaid balance of principal (not including unearned interest added to principal) of all eligible loans held by such holder during such period.


(2) Rate of special allowance(A) Subject to subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), and (I) and paragraph (4), the special allowance paid pursuant to this subsection on loans shall be computed (i) by determining the average of the bond equivalent rates of 91-day Treasury bills auctioned for such 3-month period, (ii) by subtracting the applicable interest rate on such loans from such average, (iii) by adding 3.10 percent to the resultant percent, and (iv) by dividing the resultant percent by 4. If such computation produces a number less than zero, such loans shall be subject to section 1077a(i) of this title.

(B)(i) The quarterly</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings In order to assure (1) that the limitation on interest payments or other conditions (or both) on loans made or insured under this part, do not impede or threaten to impede the carrying out of the purposes of this part or do not cause the return to holders of loans to be less than equitable, (2) that incentive payments on such loans are paid promptly to eligible lenders, and (3) that appropriate consideration of relative administrative costs and money market conditions is made in setting the quarterly rate of such payments, the Congress finds it necessary to establish an improved method for the determination of the quarterly rate of the special allowances on such loans, and to provide for a thorough, expeditious, and objective examination of alternative methods for the determination of the quarterly rate of such allowances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation and payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation and payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Origination fees from students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Origination fees from students</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan fees from lenders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Loan fees from lenders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nondiscrimination In order for the holders of loans which were made or purchased with funds obtained by the holder from an Authority issuing obligations, the income from which is exempt from taxation under title 26, to be eligible to receive a special allowance under subsection (b)(2) on any such loans, the Authority shall not engage in any pattern or practice which results in a denial of a borrower’s access to loans under this part because of the borrower’s race, sex, color, religion, national origin, age, disability status, income, attendance at a particular eligible institution within the area served by the Authority, length of the borrower’s educational program, or the borrower’s academic year in school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to prevent denial of loans to eligible students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations to prevent denial of loans to eligible students The Secretary shall adopt or amend appropriate regulations pertaining to programs carried out under this part to prevent, where practicable, any practices which the Secretary finds have denied loans to a substantial number of eligible students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special Rule With respect to any loan made under this part for which the interest rate is determined under the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act (50 U.S.C. App. 527) [now 50 U.S.C. 3937],1 the applicable interest rate to be subtracted in calculating the special allowance for such loan under this section shall be the interest rate determined under that Act for such loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>