<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1087–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1087_3"><akn:num>1087–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Reorganization of Student Loan Marketing Association through formation of Holding Company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1087–3. Reorganization of Student Loan Marketing Association through formation of Holding Company(a) Actions by Association’s Board of DirectorsThe Board of Directors of the Association shall take or cause to be taken all such action as the Board of Directors deems necessary or appropriate to effect, upon the shareholder approval described in subsection (b), a restructuring of the common stock ownership of the Association, as set forth in a plan of reorganization adopted by the Board of Directors (the terms of which shall be consistent with this section) so that all of the outstanding common shares of the Association shall be directly owned by a Holding Company. Such actions may include, in the Board of Director’s discretion, a merger of a wholly owned subsidiary of the Holding Company with and into the Association, which would have the effect provided in the plan of reorganization and the law of the jurisdiction in which such subsidiary is incorporated. As part of the restructuring, the Board of Directors may cause—(1) the common shares of the Association to be converted, on the reorganization effective date, to common shares of the Holding Company on a one for one basis, consistent with applicable State or District of Columbia law; and

(2) Holding Company common shares to be registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission.


(b) Shareholder approvalThe plan of reorganization adopted by the Board of Directors pursuant to subsection (a) shall be submitted to common shareholders of the Association for their approval. The reorganization shall occur on the reorganization effective date, provided that the plan of reorganization has been approved by the affirmative votes, cast in person or by proxy, of the holders of a majority of the issued and outstanding shares of the Association common stock.


(c) TransitionIn the event the shareholders of the Association approve the plan of reorganization under subsection (b), the following provisions shall apply beginnin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by Association’s Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Actions by Association’s Board of Directors The Board of Directors of the Association shall take or cause to be taken all such action as the Board of Directors deems necessary or appropriate to effect, upon the shareholder approval described in subsection (b), a restructuring of the common stock ownership of the Association, as set forth in a plan of reorganization adopted by the Board of Directors (the terms of which shall be consistent with this section) so that all of the outstanding common shares of the Association shall be directly owned by a Holding Company. Such actions may include, in the Board of Director’s discretion, a merger of a wholly owned subsidiary of the Holding Company with and into the Association, which would have the effect provided in the plan of reorganization and the law of the jurisdiction in which such subsidiary is incorporated. As part of the restructuring, the Board of Directors may cause—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Shareholder approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Shareholder approval The plan of reorganization adopted by the Board of Directors pursuant to subsection (a) shall be submitted to common shareholders of the Association for their approval. The reorganization shall occur on the reorganization effective date, provided that the plan of reorganization has been approved by the affirmative votes, cast in person or by proxy, of the holders of a majority of the issued and outstanding shares of the Association common stock.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transition In the event the shareholders of the Association approve the plan of reorganization under subsection (b), the following provisions shall apply beginning on the reorganization effective date:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination of Association In the event the shareholders of the Association approve a plan of reorganization under subsection (b), the Association shall dissolve, and the Association’s separate existence shall terminate on September 30, 2008, after discharge of all outstanding debt obligations and liquidation pursuant to this subsection. The Association may dissolve pursuant to this subsection prior to such date by notifying the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of the Treasury of the Association’s intention to dissolve, unless within 60 days after receipt of such notice the Secretary of Education notifies the Association that the Association continues to be needed to serve as a lender of last resort pursuant to section 1087–2(q) of this title or continues to be needed to purchase loans under an agreement with the Secretary described in subsection (c)(6). On the dissolution date, the Association shall take the following actions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of Holding Company</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Operation of Holding Company In the event the shareholders of the Association approve the plan of reorganization under subsection (b), the following provisions shall apply beginning on the reorganization effective date:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strict construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Strict construction Except as specifically set forth in this section, nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the Association as a federally chartered corporation, or of the Holding Company as a State or District of Columbia chartered corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to enforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Right to enforce The Secretary of Education or the Secretary of the Treasury, as appropriate, may request that the Attorney General bring an action in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for the enforcement of any provision of this section, or may, under the direction or control of the Attorney General, bring such an action. Such court shall have jurisdiction and power to order and require compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for reorganization effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Deadline for reorganization effective date This section shall be of no further force and effect in the event that the reorganization effective date does not occur on or before 18 months after September 30, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1087_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>