<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1091b"><akn:num>1091b</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1091b. Institutional refunds(a) Return of subchapter IV funds(1) In generalIf a recipient of assistance under this subchapter withdraws from an institution during a payment period or period of enrollment in which the recipient began attendance, the amount of grant or loan assistance (other than assistance received under part C) to be returned to the subchapter IV programs is calculated according to paragraph (3) and returned in accordance with subsection (b).


(2) Leave of absence(A) Leave not treated as withdrawalIn the case of a student who takes 1 or more leaves of absence from an institution for not more than a total of 180 days in any 12-month period, the institution may consider the student as not having withdrawn from the institution during the leave of absence, and not calculate the amount of grant and loan assistance provided under this subchapter that is to be returned in accordance with this section if—(i) the institution has a formal policy regarding leaves of absence;

(ii) the student followed the institution’s policy in requesting a leave of absence; and

(iii) the institution approved the student’s request in accordance with the institution’s policy.


(B) Consequences of failure to returnIf a student does not return to the institution at the expiration of an approved leave of absence that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A), the institution shall calculate the amount of grant and loan assistance provided under this subchapter that is to be returned in accordance with this section based on the day the student withdrew (as determined under subsection (c)).



(3) Calculation of amount of subchapter IV assistance earned(A) In generalThe amount of grant or loan assistance under this subchapter that is earned by the recipient for purposes of this section is calculated by—(i) determining the percentage of grant and loan assistance under this subchapter that has been earned by the student, as described in subparagraph (B); and

(ii) applying such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of subchapter IV funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Return of subchapter IV funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return of subchapter IV program funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Return of subchapter IV program funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withdrawal date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Percentage of the payment period or period of enrollment completed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Percentage of the payment period or period of enrollment completed For purposes of subsection (a)(3)(B), the percentage of the payment period or period of enrollment for which assistance was awarded that was completed, is determined—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date The provisions of this section shall take effect 2 years after October 7, 1998. An institution of higher education may choose to implement such provisions prior to that date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>