<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1091/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1091"><akn:num>1091</akn:num><akn:heading>Student eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1091. Student eligibility(a) In generalIn order to receive any grant, loan, or work assistance under this subchapter, a student must—(1) be enrolled or accepted for enrollment in a degree, certificate, or other program (including a program of study abroad approved for credit by the eligible institution at which such student is enrolled) leading to a recognized educational credential at an institution of higher education that is an eligible institution in accordance with the provisions of section 1094 of this title, except as provided in subsections (b)(3) and (b)(4), and not be enrolled in an elementary or secondary school;

(2) if the student is presently enrolled at an institution, be maintaining satisfactory progress in the course of study the student is pursuing in accordance with the provisions of subsection (c);(q)

(3) not owe a refund on grants previously received at any institution under this subchapter, or be in default on any loan from a student loan fund at any institution provided for in part E, or a loan made, insured, or guaranteed by the Secretary under this subchapter for attendance at any institution;

(4) file with the Secretary, as part of the original financial aid application process, a certification, which need not be notarized, but which shall include—(A) a statement of educational purpose stating that the money attributable to such grant, loan, or loan guarantee will be used solely for expenses related to attendance or continued attendance at such institution; and

(B) such student’s social security number;


(5) be a citizen or national of the United States, a permanent resident of the United States, or able to provide evidence from the Immigration and Naturalization Service that he or she is in the United States for other than a temporary purpose with the intention of becoming a citizen or permanent resident; and

(6) if the student has been convicted of, or has pled nolo contendere or guilty to, a crime involving fraud in obtaining fund</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to receive any grant, loan, or work assistance under this subchapter, a student must—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for student loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility for student loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfactory progress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Satisfactory progress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Students who are not high school graduates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Students who are not high school graduates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification for GSL eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification for GSL eligibility Each eligible institution may certify student eligibility for a loan by an eligible lender under part B of this subchapter prior to completing the review for accuracy of the information submitted by the applicant required by regulations issued under this subchapter, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loss of eligibility for violation of loan limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Loss of eligibility for violation of loan limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification of immigration status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Verification of immigration status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations of enforcement actions against institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations of enforcement actions against institutions The Secretary shall not take any compliance, disallowance, penalty, or other regulatory action against an institution of higher education with respect to any error in the institution’s determination to make a student eligible for a grant, loan, or work assistance based on citizenship or immigration status—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Validity of loan guarantees for loan payments made before immigration status verification completed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Validity of loan guarantees for loan payments made before immigration status verification completed Notwithstanding subsection (h),1 if— the official of the institution making the determination shall notify and instruct the entity making the loan to cease further payments under the loan, but such guaranty shall not be voided or otherwise nullified with respect to such payments made before the date the entity receives the notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1091_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 110–315, title IV, § 485(a)(4), Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3288</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>