<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1092a"><akn:num>1092a</akn:num><akn:heading>Combined payment plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1092a. Combined payment plan(a) Eligibility for planUpon the request of the borrower, a lender described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 1078–3(a)(1) of this title, or an eligible lender as defined in section 719 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292o) may, with respect to a consolidation loan made under section 1078–3 of this title (and section 1087–2(o) of this title as in effect prior to the enactment of section 1078–3 of this title) and loans guaranteed under part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.), offer a combined payment plan under which the lender shall submit one bill to the borrower for the repayment of all such loans for the monthly or other similar period of repayment.


(b) Applicability of other requirementsA lender offering a combined payment plan shall comply with all provisions of section 1078–3 of this title applicable to loans consolidated or to be consolidated and shall comply with all provisions of part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.) applicable to loans under that subpart which are made part of the combined payment plan, except that a lender offering a combined payment plan under this section may offer consolidation loans pursuant to section 1078–3(b)(1)(A) of this title if such lender holds any outstanding loan of a borrower which is selected for inclusion in a combined payment plan.


(c) Lender eligibilitySuch lender may offer a combined payment plan only if—(1) the lender holds an outstanding loan of that borrower which is selected by the borrower for incorporation into a combined payment plan pursuant to this section (including loans which are selected by the borrower for consolidation under this section); or

(2) the borrower certifies that the borrower has sought and has been unable to obtain a combined payment plan from the holders of the outstanding loans of that borrower.


(d) Borrower selection of competing offersIn the case of multi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility for plan Upon the request of the borrower, a lender described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of section 1078–3(a)(1) of this title, or an eligible lender as defined in section 719 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292o) may, with respect to a consolidation loan made under section 1078–3 of this title (and section 1087–2(o) of this title as in effect prior to the enactment of section 1078–3 of this title) and loans guaranteed under part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.), offer a combined payment plan under which the lender shall submit one bill to the borrower for the repayment of all such loans for the monthly or other similar period of repayment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applicability of other requirements A lender offering a combined payment plan shall comply with all provisions of section 1078–3 of this title applicable to loans consolidated or to be consolidated and shall comply with all provisions of part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.) applicable to loans under that subpart which are made part of the combined payment plan, except that a lender offering a combined payment plan under this section may offer consolidation loans pursuant to section 1078–3(b)(1)(A) of this title if such lender holds any outstanding loan of a borrower which is selected for inclusion in a combined payment plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lender eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Lender eligibility Such lender may offer a combined payment plan only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Borrower selection of competing offers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Borrower selection of competing offers In the case of multiple offers by lenders to administer a combined payment plan for a borrower, the borrower shall select from among them the lender to administer the combined payment plan including its loan consolidation component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect of plan Upon selection of a lender to administer the combined payment plan, the lender may reissue any loan under part A of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.) selected by the borrower for incorporation in the combined payment plan which is not held by such lender and the proceeds of such reissued loan shall be paid by the lender to the holder or holders of the loans so selected to discharge the liability on such loans, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notes and insurance certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notes and insurance certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of borrower eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination of borrower eligibility The status of an individual as an eligible combined payment plan borrower terminates upon receipt of a combined payment plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fees and premiums No origination fee or insurance premium shall be charged to the borrower on any combined payment plan, and no origination fee or insurance premium shall be payable by the lender to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Commencement of repayment Repayment of a combined payment plan shall commence within 60 days after the later of the date of acceptance of the lender’s offer to administer a combined payment plan, the making of the consolidation loan or the reissuance of any Health Education Assistance Loans pursuant to subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>