<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1092f"><akn:num>1092f</akn:num><akn:heading>Early awareness and outreach of financial aid eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1092f. Early awareness and outreach of financial aid eligibility(a) In generalThe Secretary shall implement early outreach activities in order to provide prospective students and their families with information about financial aid and estimates of financial aid. Such early outreach activities shall include the activities described in subsections (b), (c), and (d).


(b) Pell Grant early awareness estimates(1) In generalThe Secretary shall produce a consumer-tested method of estimating student eligibility for Federal Pell Grants under section 1070a(b) of this title utilizing the variables of family size and adjusted gross income, presented in electronic format. There shall be a method for students to indicate whether they are, or will be in—(A) a single-parent household;

(B) a household with two parents; or

(C) a household with no children or dependents.


(2) Consumer testing(A) In generalThe method of estimating eligibility described in paragraph (1) shall be consumer tested with prospective first-generation students and families as well as low-income individuals and families.


(B) UpdatesFor award year 2024–2025 and each fourth succeeding award year thereafter, the design of the method of estimating eligibility shall be updated based on additional consumer testing with the populations described in subparagraph (A).



(3) DistributionThe method of estimating eligibility described in paragraph (1) shall be—(A) made publicly and prominently available on the Department’s website; and

(B) actively shared by the Secretary with—(i) institutions of higher education participating in programs under this subchapter;

(ii) all middle and secondary schools eligible for funds under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.];

(iii) local educational agencies and middle schools and high schools that serve students not less than 25 percent of whom meet a measure of poverty as described in section 1113(a)(5) of the Eleme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall implement early outreach activities in order to provide prospective students and their families with information about financial aid and estimates of financial aid. Such early outreach activities shall include the activities described in subsections (b), (c), and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pell Grant early awareness estimates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pell Grant early awareness estimates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early awareness plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Early awareness plans The Secretary shall establish and implement early awareness and outreach plans to provide early information about the availability of Federal financial aid and estimates of prospective students’ eligibility for Federal financial aid as well as to promote the attainment of postsecondary education specifically among prospective first-generation students and families as well as low-income individuals and families, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public awareness campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public awareness campaign</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>