<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1092"><akn:num>1092</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional and financial assistance information for students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1092. Institutional and financial assistance information for students(a) Information dissemination activities(1) Each eligible institution participating in any program under this subchapter shall carry out information dissemination activities for prospective and enrolled students (including those attending or planning to attend less than full time) regarding the institution and all financial assistance under this subchapter. The information required by this section shall be produced and be made readily available upon request, through appropriate publications, mailings, and electronic media, to an enrolled student and to any prospective student. Each eligible institution shall, on an annual basis, provide to all enrolled students a list of the information that is required to be provided by institutions to students by this section and section 444 of the General Education Provisions Act [20 U.S.C. 1232g] (commonly known as the “Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974”), together with a statement of the procedures required to obtain such information. The information required by this section shall accurately describe—(A) the student financial assistance programs available to students who enroll at such institution;

(B) the methods by which such assistance is distributed among student recipients who enroll at such institution;

(C) any means, including forms, by which application for student financial assistance is made and requirements for accurately preparing such application;

(D) the rights and responsibilities of students receiving financial assistance under this subchapter;

(E) the cost of attending the institution, including (i) tuition and fees, (ii) books and supplies, (iii) estimates of typical student room and board costs or typical commuting costs, and (iv) any additional cost of the program in which the student is enrolled or expresses a specific interest;

(F) a statement of—(i) the requirements of any refund policy with which the institution i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information dissemination activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information dissemination activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exit counseling for borrowers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exit counseling for borrowers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance information personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial assistance information personnel Each eligible institution shall designate an employee or group of employees who shall be available on a full-time basis to assist students or potential students in obtaining information as specified in subsection (a). The Secretary may, by regulation, waive the requirement that an employee or employees be available on a full-time basis for carrying out responsibilities required under this section whenever an institution in which the total enrollment, or the portion of the enrollment participating in programs under this subchapter at that institution, is too small to necessitate such employee or employees being available on a full-time basis. No such waiver may include permission to exempt any such institution from designating a specific individual or a group of individuals to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Departmental publication of descriptions of assistance programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Departmental publication of descriptions of assistance programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures required with respect to athletically related student aid</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosures required with respect to athletically related student aid</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of campus security policy and campus crime statistics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disclosure of campus security policy and campus crime statistics</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Data required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of credit policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transfer of credit policies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of fire safety standards and measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Disclosure of fire safety standards and measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missing person procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Missing person procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>