<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1092b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1092b"><akn:num>1092b</akn:num><akn:heading>National Student Loan Data System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1092b. National Student Loan Data System(a) Development of SystemThe Secretary shall consult with a representative group of guaranty agencies, eligible lenders, and eligible institutions to develop a mutually agreeable proposal for the establishment of a National Student Loan Data System containing information regarding loans made, insured, or guaranteed under part B and loans made under parts D and E, and for allowing the electronic exchange of data between program participants and the system. In establishing such data system, the Secretary shall place a priority on providing for the monitoring of enrollment, student status, information about current loan holders and servicers, and internship and residency information. Such data system shall also permit borrowers to use the system to identify the current loan holders and servicers of such borrower’s loan not later than one year after October 7, 1998. The information in the data system shall include (but is not limited to)—(1) the amount and type of each such loan made;

(2) the names and social security numbers of the borrowers;

(3) the guaranty agency responsible for the guarantee of the loan;

(4) the institution of higher education or organization responsible for loans made under parts D and E;

(5) the exact amount of loans partially or totally canceled or in deferment for service under the Peace Corps Act (22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.), for service under the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 [42 U.S.C. 4950 et seq.], and for comparable full-time service as a volunteer for a tax-exempt organization of demonstrated effectiveness;

(6) the eligible institution in which the student was enrolled or accepted for enrollment at the time the loan was made, and any additional institutions attended by the borrower;

(7) the total amount of loans made to any borrower and the remaining balance of the loans;

(8) the lender, holder, and servicer of such loans;

(9) information concerning the date of any default on the loa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development of System The Secretary shall consult with a representative group of guaranty agencies, eligible lenders, and eligible institutions to develop a mutually agreeable proposal for the establishment of a National Student Loan Data System containing information regarding loans made, insured, or guaranteed under part B and loans made under parts D and E, and for allowing the electronic exchange of data between program participants and the system. In establishing such data system, the Secretary shall place a priority on providing for the monitoring of enrollment, student status, information about current loan holders and servicers, and internship and residency information. Such data system shall also permit borrowers to use the system to identify the current loan holders and servicers of such borrower’s loan not later than one year after October 7, 1998. The information in the data system shall include (but is not limited to)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional information For the purposes of research and policy analysis, the proposal shall also contain provisions for obtaining additional data concerning the characteristics of borrowers and the extent of student loan indebtedness on a statistically valid sample of borrowers under part B. Such data shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Verification The Secretary may require lenders, guaranty agencies, or institutions of higher education to verify information or obtain eligibility or other information through the National Student Loan Data System prior to making, guaranteeing, or certifying a loan made under part B, D, or E.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principles for administering the data system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Principles for administering the data system In managing the National Student Loan Data System, the Secretary shall take actions necessary to maintain confidence in the data system, including, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for third-party data system access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements for third-party data system access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standardization of data reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Standardization of data reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common identifiers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Common identifiers The Secretary shall, not later than July 1, 1993—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1092b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of databases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Integration of databases The Secretary shall integrate the National Student Loan Data System with the Pell Grant applicant and recipient databases as of January 1, 1994, and any other databases containing information on participation in programs under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>