<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1094" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1094/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1094/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1094"><akn:num>1094</akn:num><akn:heading>Program participation agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1094. Program participation agreements(a) Required for programs of assistance; contentsIn order to be an eligible institution for the purposes of any program authorized under this subchapter, an institution must be an institution of higher education or an eligible institution (as that term is defined for the purpose of that program) and shall, except with respect to a program under subpart 4 of part A, enter into a program participation agreement with the Secretary. The agreement shall condition the initial and continuing eligibility of an institution to participate in a program upon compliance with the following requirements:(1) The institution will use funds received by it for any program under this subchapter and any interest or other earnings thereon solely for the purpose specified in and in accordance with the provision of that program.

(2) The institution shall not charge any student a fee for processing or handling any application, form, or data required to determine the student’s eligibility for assistance under this subchapter or the amount of such assistance.

(3) The institution will establish and maintain such administrative and fiscal procedures and records as may be necessary to ensure proper and efficient administration of funds received from the Secretary or from students under this subchapter, together with assurances that the institution will provide, upon request and in a timely fashion, information relating to the administrative capability and financial responsibility of the institution to—(A) the Secretary;

(B) the appropriate guaranty agency; and

(C) the appropriate accrediting agency or association.


(4) The institution will comply with the provisions of subsection (c) of this section and the regulations prescribed under that subsection, relating to fiscal eligibility.

(5) The institution will submit reports to the Secretary and, in the case of an institution participating in a program under part B or part E, to holders of loans made t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required for programs of assistance; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Required for programs of assistance; contents In order to be an eligible institution for the purposes of any program authorized under this subchapter, an institution must be an institution of higher education or an eligible institution (as that term is defined for the purpose of that program) and shall, except with respect to a program under subpart 4 of part A, enter into a program participation agreement with the Secretary. The agreement shall condition the initial and continuing eligibility of an institution to participate in a program upon compliance with the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits; financial responsibility; enforcement of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Audits; financial responsibility; enforcement of standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of non-Federal revenue requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation of non-Federal revenue requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Code of conduct requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Code of conduct requirements An institution of higher education’s code of conduct, as required under subsection (a)(25), shall include the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional requirements for teach-outs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Institutional requirements for teach-outs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General report on gift ban violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inspector General report on gift ban violations The Inspector General of the Department shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferred lender list requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Preferred lender list requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For the purpose of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1094_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Construction Nothing in the amendments made by the Higher Education Amendments of 1992 shall be construed to prohibit an institution from recording, at the cost of the institution, a hearing referred to in subsection (b)(2), subsection (c)(1)(D), or subparagraph (A) or (B)(i) of subsection (c)(2), of this section to create a record of the hearing, except the unavailability of a recording shall not serve to delay the completion of the proceeding. The Secretary shall allow the institution to use any reasonable means, including stenographers, of recording the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>