<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1097a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1097a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1097a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1097a"><akn:num>1097a</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative subpoenas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1097a. Administrative subpoenas(a) AuthorityTo assist the Secretary in the conduct of investigations of possible violations of the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized to require by subpoena the production of information, documents, reports, answers, records, accounts, papers, and other documentary evidence pertaining to participation in any program under this subchapter. The production of any such records may be required from any place in a State.


(b) EnforcementIn case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to invoke the aid of any court of the United States where such person resides or transacts business for a court order for the enforcement of this section.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title IV, § 490A, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title IV, § 490B, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1754.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1998, except as otherwise provided in Pub. L. 105–244, see section 3 of Pub. L. 105–244, set out as an Effective Date of 1998 Amendment note under section 1001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1097a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority To assist the Secretary in the conduct of investigations of possible violations of the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary is authorized to require by subpoena the production of information, documents, reports, answers, records, accounts, papers, and other documentary evidence pertaining to participation in any program under this subchapter. The production of any such records may be required from any place in a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1097a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any person, the Secretary may request the Attorney General to invoke the aid of any court of the United States where such person resides or transacts business for a court order for the enforcement of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>