<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1098bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1098bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1098bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1098bb"><akn:num>1098bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority for response to military contingencies and national emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1098bb. Waiver authority for response to military contingencies and national emergencies(a) Waivers and modifications(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, unless enacted with specific reference to this section, the Secretary of Education (referred to in this part as the “Secretary”) may waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to the student financial assistance programs under title IV of the Act [20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.] as the Secretary deems necessary in connection with a war or other military operation or national emergency to provide the waivers or modifications authorized by paragraph (2).


(2) Actions authorizedThe Secretary is authorized to waive or modify any provision described in paragraph (1) as may be necessary to ensure that—(A) recipients of student financial assistance under title IV of the Act who are affected individuals are not placed in a worse position financially in relation to that financial assistance because of their status as affected individuals;

(B) administrative requirements placed on affected individuals who are recipients of student financial assistance are minimized, to the extent possible without impairing the integrity of the student financial assistance programs, to ease the burden on such students and avoid inadvertent, technical violations or defaults;

(C) the calculation of “annual adjusted family income” and “available income”, as used in the determination of need for student financial assistance under title IV of the Act for any such affected individual (and the determination of such need for his or her spouse and dependents, if applicable), may be modified to mean the sums received in the first calendar year of the award year for which such determination is made, in order to reflect more accurately the financial condition of such affected individual and his or her family;

(D) the calculation under section 484B(b)(2) of the Act (20 U.S.C. 1091b(b)(2)) of the amount a student is</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1098bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers and modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Waivers and modifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1098bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of waivers or modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice of waivers or modifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1098bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Impact report The Secretary shall, not later than 15 months after first exercising any authority to issue a waiver or modification under subsection (a), report to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions of the Senate on the impact of any waivers or modifications issued pursuant to subsection (a) on affected individuals and the programs under title IV of the Act [20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.], and the basis for such determination, and include in such report the Secretary’s recommendations for changes to the statutory or regulatory provisions that were the subject of such waiver or modification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1098bb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No delay in waivers and modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No delay in waivers and modifications Sections 482(c) and 492 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1089(c), 1098a) shall not apply to the waivers and modifications authorized or required by this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>