<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1099d"><akn:num>1099d</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive loan auction pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1099d. Competitive loan auction pilot program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible Federal PLUS LoanThe term “eligible Federal PLUS Loan” means a loan described in section 1078–2 of this title made to a parent of a dependent student who is a new borrower on or after July 1, 2009.


(2) Eligible lenderThe term “eligible lender” has the meaning given the term in section 1085 of this title.



(b) Pilot programThe Secretary shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary establishes a mechanism for an auction of eligible Federal PLUS Loans in accordance with this subsection. The pilot program shall meet the following requirements:(1) Planning and implementationDuring the period beginning on September 27, 2007, and ending on June 30, 2009, the Secretary shall plan and implement the pilot program under this subsection. During the planning and implementation, the Secretary shall consult with other Federal agencies with knowledge of, and experience with, auction programs, including the Federal Communication Commission and the Department of the Treasury.


(2) Origination and disbursement; applicability of section 1078–2Beginning on July 1, 2009, the Secretary shall arrange for the origination and disbursement of all eligible Federal PLUS Loans in accordance with the provisions of this subsection and the provisions of section 1078–2 of this title that are not inconsistent with this subsection.


(3) Loan origination mechanismThe Secretary shall establish a loan origination auction mechanism that meets the following requirements:(A) Auction for each StateThe Secretary administers an auction under this paragraph for each State, under which eligible lenders compete to originate eligible Federal PLUS Loans under this paragraph at all institutions of higher education within such State.


(B) Prequalification processThe Secretary establishes a prequalification process for eligible lenders desiring to participate in an auction under this paragraph that contains, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pilot program The Secretary shall carry out a pilot program under which the Secretary establishes a mechanism for an auction of eligible Federal PLUS Loans in accordance with this subsection. The pilot program shall meet the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required initial evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Required initial evaluation The Secretary and Secretary of the Treasury shall jointly conduct an evaluation, in consultation with the Office of Management and Budget, the Congressional Budget Office, and the Comptroller General, of the pilot program carried out by the Secretary under this section. The evaluation shall determine—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>