<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1099b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1099b"><akn:num>1099b</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of accrediting agency or association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1099b. Recognition of accrediting agency or association(a) Criteria requiredNo accrediting agency or association may be determined by the Secretary to be a reliable authority as to the quality of education or training offered for the purposes of this chapter or for other Federal purposes, unless the agency or association meets criteria established by the Secretary pursuant to this section. The Secretary shall, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, establish criteria for such determinations. Such criteria shall include an appropriate measure or measures of student achievement. Such criteria shall require that—(1) the accrediting agency or association shall be a State, regional, or national agency or association and shall demonstrate the ability and the experience to operate as an accrediting agency or association within the State, region, or nationally, as appropriate;

(2) such agency or association—(A)(i) for the purpose of participation in programs under this chapter, has a voluntary membership of institutions of higher education and has as a principal purpose the accrediting of institutions of higher education; or

(ii) for the purpose of participation in other programs administered by the Department of Education or other Federal agencies, has a voluntary membership and has as its principal purpose the accrediting of institutions of higher education or programs;


(B) is a State agency approved by the Secretary for the purpose described in subparagraph (A); or

(C) is an agency or association that, for the purpose of determining eligibility for student assistance under this subchapter, conducts accreditation through (i) a voluntary membership organization of individuals participating in a profession, or (ii) an agency or association which has as its principal purpose the accreditation of programs within institutions, which institutions are accredited by another agency or association recognized by the Secretary;


(3) if such agency or association is an ag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criteria required No accrediting agency or association may be determined by the Secretary to be a reliable authority as to the quality of education or training offered for the purposes of this chapter or for other Federal purposes, unless the agency or association meets criteria established by the Secretary pursuant to this section. The Secretary shall, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, establish criteria for such determinations. Such criteria shall include an appropriate measure or measures of student achievement. Such criteria shall require that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Separate and independent” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Separate and independent” defined For the purpose of subsection (a)(3), the term “separate and independent” means that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating procedures required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operating procedures required No accrediting agency or association may be recognized by the Secretary as a reliable authority as to the quality of education or training offered by an institution seeking to participate in the programs authorized under this subchapter, unless the agency or association—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Length of recognition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Length of recognition No accrediting agency or association may be recognized by the Secretary for the purpose of this chapter for a period of more than 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial arbitration rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Initial arbitration rule The Secretary may not recognize the accreditation of any institution of higher education unless the institution of higher education agrees to submit any dispute involving the final denial, withdrawal, or termination of accreditation to initial arbitration prior to any other legal action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Jurisdiction Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any civil action brought by an institution of higher education seeking accreditation from, or accredited by, an accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary for the purpose of this subchapter and involving the denial, withdrawal, or termination of accreditation of the institution of higher education, shall be brought in the appropriate United States district court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on scope of criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on scope of criteria Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to permit the Secretary to establish criteria for accrediting agencies or associations that are not required by this section. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to prohibit or limit any accrediting agency or association from adopting additional standards not provided for in this section. Nothing in this section shall be construed to permit the Secretary to establish any criteria that specifies, defines, or prescribes the standards that accrediting agencies or associations shall use to assess any institution’s success with respect to student achievement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Change of accrediting agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Change of accrediting agency The Secretary shall not recognize the accreditation of any otherwise eligible institution of higher education if the institution of higher education is in the process of changing its accrediting agency or association, unless the eligible institution submits to the Secretary all materials relating to the prior accreditation, including materials demonstrating reasonable cause for changing the accrediting agency or association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dual accreditation rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Dual accreditation rule The Secretary shall not recognize the accreditation of any otherwise eligible institution of higher education if the institution of higher education is accredited, as an institution, by more than one accrediting agency or association, unless the institution submits to each such agency and association and to the Secretary the reasons for accreditation by more than one such agency or association and demonstrates to the Secretary reasonable cause for its accreditation by more than one agency or association. If the institution is accredited, as an institution, by more than one accrediting agency or association, the institution shall designate which agency’s accreditation shall be utilized in determining the institution’s eligibility for programs under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1099b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact of loss of accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Impact of loss of accreditation An institution may not be certified or recertified as an institution of higher education under section 1002 of this title and subpart 3 of this part or participate in any of the other programs authorized by this chapter if such institution—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>