<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1101"><akn:num>1101</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; purpose; and program authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1101. Findings; purpose; and program authority(a) FindingsCongress makes the following findings:(1) Hispanic Americans are at high risk of not enrolling or graduating from institutions of higher education.

(2) Disparities between the enrollment of non-Hispanic white students and Hispanic students in postsecondary education are increasing. Between 1973 and 1994, enrollment of white secondary school graduates in 4-year institutions of higher education increased at a rate two times higher than that of Hispanic secondary school graduates.

(3) Despite significant limitations in resources, Hispanic-serving institutions provide a significant proportion of postsecondary opportunities for Hispanic students.

(4) Relative to other institutions of higher education, Hispanic-serving institutions are underfunded. Such institutions receive significantly less in State and local funding, per full-time equivalent student, than other institutions of higher education.

(5) Hispanic-serving institutions are succeeding in educating Hispanic students despite significant resource problems that—(A) limit the ability of such institutions to expand and improve the academic programs of such institutions; and

(B) could imperil the financial and administrative stability of such institutions.


(6) There is a national interest in remedying the disparities described in paragraphs (2) and (4) and ensuring that Hispanic students have an equal opportunity to pursue postsecondary opportunities.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of this subchapter is to—(1) expand educational opportunities for, and improve the academic attainment of, Hispanic students; and

(2) expand and enhance the academic offerings, program quality, and institutional stability of colleges and universities that are educating the majority of Hispanic college students and helping large numbers of Hispanic students and other low-income individuals complete postsecondary degrees.


(c) Program authorityThe Secretary shall provide grants an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1101_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress makes the following findings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1101_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of this subchapter is to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1101_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program authority The Secretary shall provide grants and related assistance to Hispanic-serving institutions to enable such institutions to improve and expand their capacity to serve Hispanic students and other low-income individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>