<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1128" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1128/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1128/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1128"><akn:num>1128</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable distribution of certain funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1128. Equitable distribution of certain funds(a) Selection criteriaThe Secretary shall make excellence the criterion for selection of grants awarded under section 1122 of this title.


(b) Equitable distributionTo the extent practicable and consistent with the criterion of excellence, the Secretary shall award grants under this part (other than section 1122 of this title) in such a manner as will achieve an equitable distribution of funds throughout the United States.


(c) Support for undergraduate educationThe Secretary shall also award grants under this part in such manner as to ensure that an appropriate portion of the funds appropriated for this part (as determined by the Secretary) are used to support undergraduate education.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title VI, § 608, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title VI, § 601, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1782.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 1128, Pub. L. 89–329, title VI, § 610A, as added Pub. L. 102–325, title VI, § 601, July 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 728, authorized appropriations for this part, prior to the general amendment of this part by Pub. L. 105–244.
Another prior section 1128, Pub. L. 89–329, title VI, § 608, Nov. 8, 1965, 79 Stat. 1265, provided the process of judicial review in event of State dissatisfaction in equipment grant program, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 96–374.
A prior section 608 of Pub. L. 89–329 was classified to section 1125b of this title, prior to the general amendment of this part by Pub. L. 105–244.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Selection criteria The Secretary shall make excellence the criterion for selection of grants awarded under section 1122 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Equitable distribution To the extent practicable and consistent with the criterion of excellence, the Secretary shall award grants under this part (other than section 1122 of this title) in such a manner as will achieve an equitable distribution of funds throughout the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1128_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for undergraduate education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support for undergraduate education The Secretary shall also award grants under this part in such manner as to ensure that an appropriate portion of the funds appropriated for this part (as determined by the Secretary) are used to support undergraduate education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>