<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1132_6"><akn:num>1132–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Science and technology advanced foreign language education grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1132–6. Science and technology advanced foreign language education grant program(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to support programs in institutions of higher education that—(1) encourage students to develop—(A) an understanding of science and technology; and

(B) foreign language proficiency;


(2) foster future international scientific collaboration;

(3) provide for professional development opportunities for elementary school and secondary school teachers of critical foreign languages to increase the number of highly qualified teachers in critical foreign languages; and

(4) increase the number of United States students who achieve the highest level of proficiency in foreign languages critical to the security and competitiveness of the Nation.


(b) DevelopmentThe Secretary shall develop a program for the awarding of grants to institutions of higher education that develop innovative programs for the teaching of foreign languages, which may include the preparation of teachers to teach foreign languages.


(c) Regulations and requirementsThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations for the awarding of grants under subsection (b). Such regulations may require institutions of higher education to use grant funds for, among other things—(1) the development of an on-campus cultural awareness program by which students attend classes taught in a foreign language and study the science and technology developments and practices in a non-English speaking country;

(2) immersion programs where students take science or technology related course work in a non-English speaking country;

(3) other programs, such as summer workshops, that emphasize the intense study of a foreign language and science technology;

(4) if applicable, recruiting highly qualified teachers in critical foreign languages, and providing professional development activities for such teachers at the elementary school and secondary school levels; and

(5) providing innovative opportunities for stude</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to support programs in institutions of higher education that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development The Secretary shall develop a program for the awarding of grants to institutions of higher education that develop innovative programs for the teaching of foreign languages, which may include the preparation of teachers to teach foreign languages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations and requirements The Secretary shall promulgate regulations for the awarding of grants under subsection (b). Such regulations may require institutions of higher education to use grant funds for, among other things—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant distribution In distributing grants to institutions of higher education under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on best practices Not later than one year after August 14, 2008, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appropriations authorized There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and for each subsequent fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>