<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1132–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1132_7"><akn:num>1132–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting by institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1132–7. Reporting by institutions(a) ApplicabilityThe data requirement in subsection (b) shall apply to an institution of higher education that receives funds for a center or program under this subchapter if—(1) the amount of the contribution (including cash and the fair market value of any property) received from any foreign government or from a foreign private sector corporation or foundation during any fiscal year exceeds $250,000 in the aggregate; and

(2) the aggregate contribution, or a significant part of the aggregate contribution, is to be used by a center or program receiving funds under this subchapter.


(b) Data requiredThe Secretary shall require an institution of higher education referred to in subsection (a) to report information listed in subsection (a) to the Secretary consistent with the requirements of section 1011f of this title.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title VI, § 638, as added Pub. L. 110–315, title VI, § 622, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3345.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability The data requirement in subsection (b) shall apply to an institution of higher education that receives funds for a center or program under this subchapter if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1132_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Data required The Secretary shall require an institution of higher education referred to in subsection (a) to report information listed in subsection (a) to the Secretary consistent with the requirements of section 1011f of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>