<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1134b"><akn:num>1134b</akn:num><akn:heading>Stipends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1134b. Stipends(a) Award by SecretaryThe Secretary shall pay to individuals awarded fellowships under this subpart such stipends as the Secretary may establish, reflecting the purpose of this program to encourage highly talented students to undertake graduate study as described in this subpart. In the case of an individual who receives such individual’s first stipend under this subpart in academic year 2009–2010 or any succeeding academic year, such stipend shall be set at a level of support equal to that provided by the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship Program for such academic year, except such amount shall be adjusted as necessary so as not to exceed the fellow’s demonstrated level of need determined in accordance with part F of subchapter IV.


(b) Institutional payments(1) In general(A) The Secretary shall (in addition to stipends paid to individuals under this subpart) pay to the institution of higher education, for each individual awarded a fellowship under this subpart at such institution, an institutional allowance. Except as provided in subparagraph (B), such allowance shall be, for academic year 2009–2010 and succeeding academic years, the same amount as the institutional payment made for academic year 2008–2009, adjusted for academic year 2009–2010 and annually thereafter in accordance with inflation as determined by the Department of Labor’s Consumer Price Index for the previous calendar year.

(B) The institutional allowance paid under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the amount the institution charges and collects from a fellowship recipient for tuition and other expenses as part of the recipient’s instructional program.


(2) Special rules(A) Beginning March 1, 1992, any applicant for a fellowship under this subpart who has been notified in writing by the Secretary that such applicant has been selected to receive such a fellowship and is subsequently notified that the fellowship award has been withdrawn, shall receive su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Award by Secretary The Secretary shall pay to individuals awarded fellowships under this subpart such stipends as the Secretary may establish, reflecting the purpose of this program to encourage highly talented students to undertake graduate study as described in this subpart. In the case of an individual who receives such individual’s first stipend under this subpart in academic year 2009–2010 or any succeeding academic year, such stipend shall be set at a level of support equal to that provided by the National Science Foundation Graduate Research Fellowship Program for such academic year, except such amount shall be adjusted as necessary so as not to exceed the fellow’s demonstrated level of need determined in accordance with part F of subchapter IV.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institutional payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Institutional payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>