<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1134c"><akn:num>1134c</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1134c. Fellowship conditions(a) Requirements for receiptAn individual awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subpart shall continue to receive payments provided in section 1134b of this title only during such periods as the Secretary finds that such individual is maintaining satisfactory proficiency in, and devoting essentially full time to, study or research in the field in which such fellowship was awarded, in an institution of higher education, and is not engaging in gainful employment other than part-time employment by such institution in teaching, research, or similar activities, approved by the Secretary.


(b) Reports from recipientsThe Secretary is authorized to require reports containing such information in such form and filed at such times as the Secretary determines necessary from any person awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subpart. The reports shall be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education, library, archive, or other research center approved by the Secretary, stating that such individual is making satisfactory progress in, and is devoting essentially full time to the program for which the fellowship was awarded.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title VII, § 704, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title VII, § 701, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1789.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to this section were contained in section 1134k of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–244.
A prior section 1134c, Pub. L. 89–329, title IX, § 913, as added Pub. L. 102–325, title IX, § 901, July 23, 1992, 106 Stat. 762, related to use of funds by grant recipients, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–244, § 3, title VII, § 702, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1585, 1803, effective Oct. 1, 1998.
Another prior section 1134c, Pub. L. 89–329, title IX, § 904, as added Pub. L. 92–318, title I, § 181(a), June 23, 1972, 86 Stat. 306; amended Pub. L. 96–374, title XIII, § 1391(a)(1), Oct. 3, 1980, 94 Stat. 1503,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for receipt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements for receipt An individual awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subpart shall continue to receive payments provided in section 1134b of this title only during such periods as the Secretary finds that such individual is maintaining satisfactory proficiency in, and devoting essentially full time to, study or research in the field in which such fellowship was awarded, in an institution of higher education, and is not engaging in gainful employment other than part-time employment by such institution in teaching, research, or similar activities, approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports from recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports from recipients The Secretary is authorized to require reports containing such information in such form and filed at such times as the Secretary determines necessary from any person awarded a fellowship under the provisions of this subpart. The reports shall be accompanied by a certificate from an appropriate official at the institution of higher education, library, archive, or other research center approved by the Secretary, stating that such individual is making satisfactory progress in, and is devoting essentially full time to the program for which the fellowship was awarded.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>