<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1134a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1134a"><akn:num>1134a</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1134a. Allocation of fellowships(a) Fellowship Board(1) Appointment(A) In generalThe Secretary shall appoint a Jacob K. Javits Fellows Program Fellowship Board (referred to in this subpart as the “Board”) consisting of 9 individuals representative of both public and private institutions of higher education who are especially qualified to serve on the Board.


(B) QualificationsIn making appointments under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall—(i) give due consideration to the appointment of individuals who are highly respected in the academic community;

(ii) appoint members who represent the various geographic regions of the United States;

(iii) ensure that individuals appointed to the Board are broadly representative of a range of disciplines in graduate education in arts, humanities, and social sciences; and

(iv) ensure that such individuals include representatives from institutions that are eligible for one or more of the grants under subchapter III or V.



(2) DutiesThe Board shall—(A) establish general policies for the program established by this subpart and oversee the program’s operation;

(B) establish general criteria for the award of fellowships in academic fields identified by the Board, or, in the event that the Secretary enters into a contract with a nongovernmental entity to administer the program assisted under this subpart, by such nongovernmental entity;

(C) appoint panels of academic scholars with distinguished backgrounds in the arts, humanities, and social sciences for the purpose of selecting fellows, except that, in the event that the Secretary enters into a contract with a nongovernmental entity to administer the program, such panels may be appointed by such nongovernmental entity; and

(D) prepare and submit to the Congress at least once in every 3-year period a report on any modifications in the program that the Board determines are appropriate.


(3) ConsultationsIn carrying out its responsibilities, the Board shall consult on a regu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fellowship Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of selection panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of selection panels The recipients of fellowships shall be selected in each designated field from among all applicants nationwide in each field by distinguished panels appointed by the Board to make such selections under criteria established by the Board, except that, in the event that the Secretary enters into a contract with a nongovernmental entity to administer the program, such panels may be appointed by such nongovernmental entity. The number of recipients in each field in each year shall not exceed the number of fellows allocated to that field for that year by the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1134a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship portability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fellowship portability Each recipient shall be entitled to use the fellowship in a graduate program at any accredited institution of higher education in which the recipient may decide to enroll.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>