<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1135"><akn:num>1135</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to academic departments and programs of institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1135. Grants to academic departments and programs of institutions(a) Grant authority(1) In generalThe Secretary shall make grants to academic departments, programs and other academic units of institutions of higher education that provide courses of study leading to a graduate degree, including a master’s or doctoral degree, in order to enable such institutions to provide assistance to graduate students in accordance with this subpart.


(2) Additional grantsThe Secretary may also make grants to such departments, programs and other academic units of institutions of higher education granting graduate degrees which submit joint proposals involving nondegree granting institutions which have formal arrangements for the support of doctoral dissertation research with degree-granting institutions. Nondegree granting institutions eligible for awards as part of such joint proposals include any organization which—(A) is described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26, and is exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such title;

(B) is organized and operated substantially to conduct scientific and cultural research and graduate training programs;

(C) is not a private foundation;

(D) has academic personnel for instruction and counseling who meet the standards of the institution of higher education in which the students are enrolled; and

(E) has necessary research resources not otherwise readily available in such institutions to such students.



(b) Award and duration of grants(1) AwardsThe principal criterion for the award of grants shall be the relative quality of the graduate programs presented in competing applications. Consistent with an allocation of awards based on quality of competing applications, the Secretary shall, in awarding such grants, promote an equitable geographic distribution among eligible public and private institutions of higher education.


(2) Duration and amount(A) DurationThe Secretary shall award a grant under this subpart for a period of 3 years.


(B</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award and duration of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Award and duration of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference to continuing grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preference to continuing grant recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>