<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1135b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1135b"><akn:num>1135b</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1135b. Criteria for applications(a) Selection of applicationsThe Secretary shall make grants to academic departments, programs and units of institutions of higher education on the basis of applications submitted in accordance with subsection (b). Applications shall be ranked on program quality by review panels of nationally recognized scholars and evaluated on the quality and effectiveness of the academic program and the achievement and promise of the students to be served. To the extent possible (consistent with other provisions of this section), the Secretary shall make awards that are consistent with recommendations of the review panels.


(b) Contents of applicationsAn academic department, program or unit of an institution of higher education, in the department, program or unit’s application for a grant, shall—(1) describe the current academic program of the applicant for which the grant is sought;

(2) provide assurances that the applicant will provide, from other non-Federal sources, for the purposes of the fellowship program under this subpart an amount equal to at least 25 percent of the amount of the grant received under this subpart, which contribution may be in cash or in kind, fairly valued;

(3) set forth policies and procedures to assure that, in making fellowship awards under this subpart, the institution will seek talented students from traditionally underrepresented backgrounds, as determined by the Secretary;

(4) describe the number, types, and amounts of the fellowships that the applicant intends to offer with grant funds provided under this part;

(5) set forth policies and procedures to assure that, in making fellowship awards under this subpart, the institution will make awards to individuals who—(A) have financial need, as determined under part F of subchapter IV;

(B) have excellent academic records in their previous programs of study; and

(C) plan to pursue the highest possible degree available in their course of study at the institution</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1135b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Selection of applications The Secretary shall make grants to academic departments, programs and units of institutions of higher education on the basis of applications submitted in accordance with subsection (b). Applications shall be ranked on program quality by review panels of nationally recognized scholars and evaluated on the quality and effectiveness of the academic program and the achievement and promise of the students to be served. To the extent possible (consistent with other provisions of this section), the Secretary shall make awards that are consistent with recommendations of the review panels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1135b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of applications An academic department, program or unit of an institution of higher education, in the department, program or unit’s application for a grant, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>