<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1137" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1137/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1137/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1137"><akn:num>1137</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions for subparts 1 through 4</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1137. Administrative provisions for subparts 1 through 4(a) Coordinated administrationIn carrying out the purpose described in section 1133(1) of this title, the Secretary shall provide for coordinated administration and regulation of graduate programs assisted under subparts 1 through 4 of this part with other Federal programs providing assistance for graduate education in order to minimize duplication and improve efficiency to ensure that the programs are carried out in a manner most compatible with academic practices and with the standard timetables for applications for, and notifications of acceptance to, graduate programs.


(b) Hiring authorityFor purposes of carrying out subparts 1 through 4 of this part, the Secretary shall appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5 that govern appointments in the competitive service, such administrative and technical employees, with the appropriate educational background, as shall be needed to assist in the administration of such parts 11 So in original. Probably should be “subparts”.. The employees shall be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.


(c) Use for religious purposes prohibitedNo institutional payment or allowance under section 1134b(b) or 1135d(a) of this title shall be paid to a school or department of divinity as a result of the award of a fellowship under subpart 1 or 2 of this part, respectively, to an individual who is studying for a religious vocation.


(d) EvaluationThe Secretary shall evaluate the success of assistance provided to individuals under subpart 1, 2, 3, or 4 of this part with respect to graduating from their degree programs, and placement in faculty and professional positions.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title VII, § 731, as added Pub. L. 105–244, title VII, § 701, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1795; amended Pub. L. 110–315, title VII, §§ 704(i), 706(a)(2), (3), Aug. 14, 2008,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinated administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordinated administration In carrying out the purpose described in section 1133(1) of this title, the Secretary shall provide for coordinated administration and regulation of graduate programs assisted under subparts 1 through 4 of this part with other Federal programs providing assistance for graduate education in order to minimize duplication and improve efficiency to ensure that the programs are carried out in a manner most compatible with academic practices and with the standard timetables for applications for, and notifications of acceptance to, graduate programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hiring authority For purposes of carrying out subparts 1 through 4 of this part, the Secretary shall appoint, without regard to the provisions of title 5 that govern appointments in the competitive service, such administrative and technical employees, with the appropriate educational background, as shall be needed to assist in the administration of such parts 11 So in original. Probably should be “subparts”.. The employees shall be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use for religious purposes prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use for religious purposes prohibited No institutional payment or allowance under section 1134b(b) or 1135d(a) of this title shall be paid to a school or department of divinity as a result of the award of a fellowship under subpart 1 or 2 of this part, respectively, to an individual who is studying for a religious vocation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1137_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation The Secretary shall evaluate the success of assistance provided to individuals under subpart 1, 2, 3, or 4 of this part with respect to graduating from their degree programs, and placement in faculty and professional positions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>