<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1140m"><akn:num>1140m</akn:num><akn:heading>Model demonstration programs to support improved access to postsecondary instructional materials for</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1140m. Model demonstration programs to support improved access to postsecondary instructional materials for students with print disabilities(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to support model demonstration programs for the purpose of encouraging the development of systems to improve the quality of postsecondary instructional materials in specialized formats and such materials’ timely delivery to postsecondary students with print disabilities, including systems to improve efficiency and reduce duplicative efforts across multiple institutions of higher education.


(b) Definition of eligible partnershipIn this section, the term “eligible partnership” means a partnership that—(1) shall include—(A) an institution of higher education with demonstrated expertise in meeting the needs of students with print disabilities, including the retention of such students in, and such students’ completion of, postsecondary education; and

(B) a public or private entity, other than an institution of higher education, with—(i) demonstrated expertise in developing accessible instructional materials in specialized formats for postsecondary students with print disabilities; and

(ii) the technical development expertise necessary for the efficient dissemination of such materials, including procedures to protect against copyright infringement with respect to the creation, use, and distribution of instructional materials in specialized formats; and



(2) may include representatives of the publishing industry.


(c) Program authorizedFrom amounts appropriated under section 1140o of this title, the Secretary shall award grants or contracts, on a competitive basis, to not less than one eligible partnership to enable the eligible partnership to support the activities described in subsection (f) and, as applicable, subsection (g).


(d) ApplicationAn eligible partnership that desires a grant or contract under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to support model demonstration programs for the purpose of encouraging the development of systems to improve the quality of postsecondary instructional materials in specialized formats and such materials’ timely delivery to postsecondary students with print disabilities, including systems to improve efficiency and reduce duplicative efforts across multiple institutions of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of eligible partnership In this section, the term “eligible partnership” means a partnership that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program authorized From amounts appropriated under section 1140o of this title, the Secretary shall award grants or contracts, on a competitive basis, to not less than one eligible partnership to enable the eligible partnership to support the activities described in subsection (f) and, as applicable, subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application An eligible partnership that desires a grant or contract under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and in such format as the Secretary may prescribe. The application shall include information on how the eligible partnership will implement activities under subsection (f) and, as applicable, subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In awarding grants or contracts under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any applications that include the development and implementation of the procedures and approaches described in paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Required activities An eligible partnership that receives a grant or contract under this section shall use the grant or contract funds to carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized approaches</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorized approaches An eligible partnership that receives a grant or contract under this section may use the grant or contract funds to support the development and implementation of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report Not later than three years after the date of the first grant or contract awarded under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the authorizing committees a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140m_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Model expansion The Secretary may, on the basis of the reports under subsection (h) and section 1140l(b)(2) of this title and any evaluations of the projects funded under this section, expand the program under this section to additional grant or contract recipients that use other programmatic approaches and serve different geographic regions, if the Secretary finds that the models used under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>