<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1140g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1140g"><akn:num>1140g</akn:num><akn:heading>Model comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilitie</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1140g. Model comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalFrom amounts appropriated under section 1140i(a) of this title, the Secretary shall annually award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education (or consortia of institutions of higher education), to enable the institutions or consortia to create or expand high quality, inclusive model comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities.


(2) AdministrationThe program under this section shall be administered by the office in the Department that administers other postsecondary education programs.


(3) Duration of grantsA grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.



(b) ApplicationAn institution of higher education (or a consortium) desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(c) Award basisIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—(1) provide for an equitable geographic distribution of such grants;

(2) provide grant funds for model comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities that will serve areas that are underserved by programs of this type; and

(3) give preference to applications submitted under subsection (b) that agree to incorporate into the model comprehensive transition and postsecondary program for students with intellectual disabilities carried out under the grant one or more of the following elements:(A) The formation of a partnership with any relevant agency serving students with intellectual disabilities, such as a vocational rehabilitation agency.

(B) In the case of an institution of higher education that provides institutionally owned or operated housing for students attending the institution, the integration of students</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application An institution of higher education (or a consortium) desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award basis In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds An institution of higher education (or consortium) receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to establish a model comprehensive transition and postsecondary program for students with intellectual disabilities that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching requirement An institution of higher education (or consortium) that receives a grant under this section shall provide matching funds toward the cost of the model comprehensive transition and postsecondary program for students with intellectual disabilities carried out under the grant. Such matching funds may be provided in cash or in-kind, and shall be in an amount of not less than 25 percent of the amount of such costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1140g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than five years after the date of the first grant awarded under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and disseminate a report to the authorizing committees and to the public that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>