<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1155"><akn:num>1155</akn:num><akn:heading>Connie Lee privatization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1155. Connie Lee privatization(a) Status of Corporation and corporate powers; obligations not federally guaranteed(1) Status of the CorporationThe Corporation shall not be an agency, instrumentality, or establishment of the United States Government, nor a Government corporation, nor a Government controlled corporation, as such terms are defined in section 103 of title 5. No action under section 1491 of title 28 (commonly known as the Tucker Act) shall be allowable against the United States based on the actions of the Corporation.


(2) Corporate powersThe Corporation shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and, to the extent not inconsistent with this section, to the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act (or the comparable law of another State, if applicable). The Corporation shall have the powers conferred upon a corporation by the District of Columbia Business Corporation Act (or such other applicable State law) as from time to time in effect in order to conduct the Corporation’s affairs as a private, for-profit corporation and to carry out the Corporation’s purposes and activities incidental thereto. The Corporation shall have the power to enter into contracts, to execute instruments, to incur liabilities, to provide products and services, and to do all things as are necessary or incidental to the proper management of the Corporation’s affairs and the efficient operation of a private, for-profit business.


(3) Limitation on ownership of stock(A) Student Loan Marketing AssociationThe Student Loan Marketing Association shall not increase its share of the ownership of the Corporation in excess of 42 percent of the shares of stock of the Corporation outstanding on September 30, 1996. The Student Loan Marketing Association shall not control the operation of the Corporation, except that the Student Loan Marketing Association may participate in the election of directors as a shareholder, and may continue to exercise the Student Loan Marketing Asso</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1155_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of Corporation and corporate powers; obligations not federally guaranteed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Status of Corporation and corporate powers; obligations not federally guaranteed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1155_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related privatization requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Related privatization requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1155_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of federally owned stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale of federally owned stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1155_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1155_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment of account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>