<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161g"><akn:num>1161g</akn:num><akn:heading>Patsy T. Mink fellowship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161g. Patsy T. Mink fellowship program(a) Purpose; designation(1) In generalIt is the purpose of this section to provide, through eligible institutions, a program of fellowship awards to assist highly qualified minorities and women to acquire the doctoral degree, or highest possible degree available, in academic areas in which such individuals are underrepresented for the purpose of enabling such individuals to enter the higher education professoriate.


(2) DesignationEach recipient of a fellowship award from an eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall be known as a “Patsy T. Mink Graduate Fellow”.



(b) Eligible institutionIn this section, the term “eligible institution” means an institution of higher education, or a consortium of such institutions, that offers a program of postbaccalaureate study leading to a graduate degree.


(c) Program authorized(1) Grants by Secretary(A) In generalFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (f), the Secretary shall award grants to eligible institutions to enable such institutions to make fellowship awards to individuals in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(B) Priority considerationIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider the eligible institution’s prior experience in producing doctoral degree, or highest possible degree available, holders who are minorities and women, and shall give priority consideration in making grants under this section to those eligible institutions with a demonstrated record of producing minorities and women who have earned such degrees.



(2) Applications(A) In generalAn eligible institution that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(B) Applications made on behalfThe following entities may submit an application on behalf of an eligible institution:(i) A graduate school or department of such in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible institution In this section, the term “eligible institution” means an institution of higher education, or a consortium of such institutions, that offers a program of postbaccalaureate study leading to a graduate degree.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fellowship recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to require an eligible institution that receives a grant under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>