<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161l"><akn:num>1161l</akn:num><akn:heading>Student safety and campus emergency management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161l. Student safety and campus emergency management(a) Grants authorized(1) In generalFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (f), the Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education or consortia of institutions of higher education to enable institutions of higher education or consortia to pay the Federal share of the cost of carrying out the authorized activities described in subsection (c).


(2) Consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland SecurityWhere appropriate, the Secretary shall award grants under this section in consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security.


(3) DurationThe Secretary shall award each grant under this section for a period of two years.


(4) Limitation on institutions and consortiaAn institution of higher education or consortium shall be eligible for only one grant under this section.



(b) Federal share; non-Federal share(1) In generalThe Federal share of the activities described in subsection (c) shall be 50 percent.


(2) Non-Federal shareAn institution of higher education or consortium that receives a grant under this section shall provide the non-Federal share, which may be provided from State and local resources dedicated to emergency preparedness and response.



(c) Authorized activitiesEach institution of higher education or consortium receiving a grant under this section may use the grant funds to carry out one or more of the following:(1) Developing and implementing a state-of-the-art emergency communications system for each campus of an institution of higher education or consortium, in order to contact students via cellular, text message, or other state-of-the-art communications methods when a significant emergency or dangerous situation occurs. An institution or consortium using grant funds to carry out this paragraph shall also, in coordination with the appropriate State and local emergency management aut</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share; non-Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal share; non-Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities Each institution of higher education or consortium receiving a grant under this section may use the grant funds to carry out one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application Each institution of higher education or consortium desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance The Secretary shall coordinate technical assistance provided by State and local emergency management agencies, the Department of Homeland Security, and other agencies as appropriate, to institutions of higher education or consortia that request assistance in developing and implementing the activities assisted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161l_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this part such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>