<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161o"><akn:num>1161o</akn:num><akn:heading>College partnership grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161o. College partnership grants authorized(a) Grants authorizedFrom the amount appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible partnerships for the purposes of developing and implementing articulation agreements.


(b) Eligible partnershipsFor purposes of this part, an eligible partnership shall include at least two institutions of higher education, or a system of institutions of higher education, and may include either or both of the following:(1) A consortia of institutions of higher education.

(2) A State higher education agency.


(c) PriorityThe Secretary shall give priority to eligible partnerships that—(1) are located in a State that has employed strategies described in section 1093a(b)(1) of this title; or

(2) include—(A) one or more junior or community colleges (as defined by section 1058(f) of this title) that award associate’s degrees; and

(B) one or more institutions of higher education that offer a baccalaureate or post-baccalaureate degree not awarded by the institutions described in subparagraph (A) with which it is partnered.



(d) Mandatory use of fundsGrants awarded under this part shall be used for—(1) the development of policies and programs to expand opportunities for students to earn bachelor’s degrees, by facilitating the transfer of academic credits between institutions and expanding articulation and guaranteed transfer agreements between institutions of higher education, including through common course numbering and general education core curriculum;

(2) academic program enhancements; and

(3) programs to identify and remove barriers that inhibit student transfers, including technological and informational programs.


(e) Optional use of fundsGrants awarded under this part may be used for—(1) support services to students participating in the program, such as tutoring, mentoring, and academic and personal counseling; and

(2) any service that facilitates the transition of students between the part</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized From the amount appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible partnerships for the purposes of developing and implementing articulation agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible partnerships For purposes of this part, an eligible partnership shall include at least two institutions of higher education, or a system of institutions of higher education, and may include either or both of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority The Secretary shall give priority to eligible partnerships that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mandatory use of funds Grants awarded under this part shall be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Optional use of funds Grants awarded under this part may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition No funds provided under this section shall be used to financially compensate an institution for the purposes of entering into an articulation agreement or for accepting students transferring into such institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications Any eligible partnership that desires to obtain a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information or assurances as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition For purposes of this section, the term “articulation agreement” means an agreement between institutions of higher education that specifies the acceptability of courses in transfer toward meeting specific degree requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>