<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161t"><akn:num>1161t</akn:num><akn:heading>Model programs for Centers of Excellence for Veteran Student Success</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161t. Model programs for Centers of Excellence for Veteran Student Success(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to encourage model programs to support veteran student success in postsecondary education by coordinating services to address the academic, financial, physical, and social needs of veteran students.


(b) Grants authorized(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations under subsection (f), the Secretary shall award grants to institutions of higher education to develop model programs to support veteran student success in postsecondary education.


(2) Grant periodA grant awarded under this section shall be awarded for a period of three years.



(c) Use of grants(1) Required activitiesAn institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section shall use such grant to carry out a model program that includes—(A) establishing a Center of Excellence for Veteran Student Success on the campus of the institution to provide a single point of contact to coordinate comprehensive support services for veteran students;

(B) establishing a veteran student support team, including representatives from the offices of the institution responsible for admissions, registration, financial aid, veterans benefits, academic advising, student health, personal or mental health counseling, career advising, disabilities services, and any other office of the institution that provides support to veteran students on campus;

(C) providing a coordinator whose primary responsibility is to coordinate the model program carried out under this section;

(D) monitoring the rates of veteran student enrollment, persistence, and completion; and

(E) developing a plan to sustain the Center of Excellence for Veteran Student Success after the grant period.


(2) Other authorized activitiesAn institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section may use such grant to carry out any of the following activities with respect to veteran students:(A) Outreac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to encourage model programs to support veteran student success in postsecondary education by coordinating services to address the academic, financial, physical, and social needs of veteran students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application; selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application; selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and accountability plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation and accountability plan The Secretary shall develop an evaluation and accountability plan for model programs funded under this section to objectively measure the impact of such programs, including a measure of whether postsecondary education enrollment, persistence, and completion for veterans increases as a result of such programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>