<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161s"><akn:num>1161s</akn:num><akn:heading>Program to promote training and job placement of realtime writers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161s. Program to promote training and job placement of realtime writers(a) Authorization of grant program(1) In generalFrom the amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities under paragraph (2) to promote training and placement of individuals, including individuals who have completed a court reporting training program, as realtime writers in order to meet the requirements for closed captioning of video programming set forth in section 613 of title 47 and the rules prescribed thereunder.


(2) Eligible entitiesFor purposes of this section, an eligible entity is a court reporting program that—(A) has a curriculum capable of training realtime writers qualified to provide captioning services;

(B) is accredited by an accrediting agency or association recognized by the Secretary; and

(C) is participating in student aid programs under subchapter IV.


(3) Priority in grantsIn determining whether to make grants under this section, the Secretary shall give a priority to eligible entities that, as determined by the Secretary—(A) possess the most substantial capability to increase their capacity to train realtime writers;

(B) demonstrate the most promising collaboration with educational institutions, businesses, labor organizations, or other community groups having the potential to train or provide job placement assistance to realtime writers; or

(C) propose the most promising and innovative approaches for initiating or expanding training or job placement assistance efforts with respect to realtime writers.


(4) Duration of grantA grant under this section shall be for a period of up to five years.


(5) Maximum amount of grantThe amount of a grant provided under this subsection to an eligible entity may not exceed $1,500,000 for the period of the grant.



(b) Application(1) In generalTo receive a grant under subsection (a), an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>