<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161c"><akn:num>1161c</akn:num><akn:heading>Business workforce partnerships for job skill training in high-growth occupations or industries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161c. Business workforce partnerships for job skill training in high-growth occupations or industries(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide grants to institutions of higher education partnering with employers to—(1) provide relevant job skill training in high-growth and high-wage industries or occupations to nontraditional students; and

(2) strengthen ties between degree credit offerings at institutions of higher education and business and industry workforce needs.


(b) Authorization(1) In generalFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (k), the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships for the purpose provided in subsection (a).


(2) DurationThe Secretary shall award grants under this section for a period of not less than 36 months and not more than 60 months.


(3) Supplement, not supplantFunds made available under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, and local funds available to the eligible partnership for carrying out the activities described in subsection (c).



(c) Use of fundsIn consultation with all of the members of an eligible partnership, grant funds provided under this section may be used to—(1) expand or create for-credit academic programs or programs of training that provide relevant job skill training for high-growth and high-wage occupations or industries, including offerings connected to registered apprenticeship programs and entrepreneurial training opportunities;

(2) in consultation with faculty in the appropriate departments of an institution of higher education, adapt college offerings to the schedules and needs of working students, such as the creation of evening, weekend, modular, compressed, or distance learning formats;

(3) purchase equipment that will facilitate the development of academic programs or programs of training that provide training for high-growth and high-wage occupations or industries;

(4) strengthen outreach effort</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide grants to institutions of higher education partnering with employers to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds In consultation with all of the members of an eligible partnership, grant funds provided under this section may be used to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Award basis In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs A grantee under this section may use not more than five percent of the grant amount to pay administrative costs associated with activities funded by the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to grantees under this section throughout the grant period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Evaluation The Secretary shall conduct an evaluation of the effectiveness of the program under this section based on performance standards developed in consultation with the Department of Labor, and shall disseminate to the public the findings of such evaluation and information related to promising practices developed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report to Congress Not later than 36 months after the first grant is awarded under this section, the Comptroller General shall report to the authorizing committees recommendations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>