<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161v"><akn:num>1161v</akn:num><akn:heading>Modeling and simulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161v. Modeling and simulation(a) Purpose; definition(1) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to promote the study of modeling and simulation at institutions of higher education, through the collaboration with new and existing programs, and specifically to promote the use of technology in such study through the creation of accurate models that can simulate processes or recreate real life, by—(A) establishing a task force at the Department of Education to raise awareness of and define the study of modeling and simulation;

(B) providing grants to institutions of higher education to develop new modeling and simulation degree programs; and

(C) providing grants for institutions of higher education to enhance existing modeling and simulation degree programs.


(2) DefinitionIn this section, the term “modeling and simulation” means a field of study related to the application of computer science and mathematics to develop a level of understanding of the interaction of the parts of a system and of a system as a whole.



(b) Establishment of task force(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Secretary shall establish a task force within the Department to study modeling and simulation and to support the development of the modeling and simulation field. The activities of such task force shall include—(A) helping to define the study of modeling and simulation (including the content of modeling and simulation classes and programs);

(B) identifying best practices for such study;

(C) identifying core knowledge and skills that individuals who participate in modeling and simulation programs should acquire; and

(D) providing recommendations to the Secretary with respect to—(i) the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (C); and

(ii) a system by which grants under this section will be distributed.



(2) Task force membershipThe membership of the task force under this subsection shall be composed of representatives from—(A) institutions of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; definition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of task force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of task force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing modeling and simulation at institutions of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enhancing modeling and simulation at institutions of higher education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161v_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishing modeling and simulation programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishing modeling and simulation programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161v_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years. Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>