<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161r"><akn:num>1161r</akn:num><akn:heading>Campus-based digital theft prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161r. Campus-based digital theft prevention(a) Program authorityFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (d), the Secretary may make grants to institutions of higher education, or consortia of such institutions, and enter into contracts with such institutions, consortia, and other organizations, to develop, implement, operate, improve, and disseminate programs of prevention, education, and cost-effective technological solutions, to reduce and eliminate the illegal downloading and distribution of intellectual property. Such grants or contracts may also be used for the support of higher education centers that will provide training, technical assistance, evaluation, dissemination, and associated services and assistance to the higher education community as determined by the Secretary and institutions of higher education.


(b) AwardsGrants and contracts shall be awarded under this section on a competitive basis.


(c) ApplicationsAn institution of higher education or a consortium of such institutions that desires to receive a grant or contract under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require by regulation.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.


(Pub. L. 89–329, title VIII, § 871, as added Pub. L. 110–315, title VIII, § 801, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3425.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authority From the amounts appropriated under subsection (d), the Secretary may make grants to institutions of higher education, or consortia of such institutions, and enter into contracts with such institutions, consortia, and other organizations, to develop, implement, operate, improve, and disseminate programs of prevention, education, and cost-effective technological solutions, to reduce and eliminate the illegal downloading and distribution of intellectual property. Such grants or contracts may also be used for the support of higher education centers that will provide training, technical assistance, evaluation, dissemination, and associated services and assistance to the higher education community as determined by the Secretary and institutions of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Awards Grants and contracts shall be awarded under this section on a competitive basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications An institution of higher education or a consortium of such institutions that desires to receive a grant or contract under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Secretary may reasonably require by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>