<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1161b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1161b"><akn:num>1161b</akn:num><akn:heading>Mathematics and science scholars program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1161b. Mathematics and science scholars program(a) Program authorizedFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (f), the Secretary is authorized to award grants to States, on a competitive basis, to enable the States to encourage students to pursue a rigorous course of study, beginning in secondary school and continuing through the students’ postsecondary education, in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or a health-related field.


(b) Applications(1) In generalA State that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. A State may submit an application to receive a grant under subsection (c) or (d), or both.


(2) Contents of applicationEach application shall include a description of—(A) the program or programs for which the State is applying;

(B) if applicable, the priority set by the Governor pursuant to subsection (c)(4) or (d)(3); and

(C) how the State will meet the requirements of subsection (e).



(c) Mathematics and science scholars program(1) Grant for scholarshipsThe Secretary shall award grants under this subsection to provide scholarship support to eligible students.


(2) Eligible studentsA student is eligible for a scholarship under this subsection if the student—(A) meets the requirements of section 1091(a) of this title;

(B) is a full-time student in the student’s first year of undergraduate study; and

(C) has completed a rigorous secondary school curriculum in mathematics and science.


(3) Rigorous curriculumEach participating State shall determine the requirements for a rigorous secondary school curriculum in mathematics and science described in paragraph (2)(C).


(4) Priority for scholarshipsThe Governor of a State may set a priority for awarding scholarships under this subsection for particular eligible students, such as students attending schools in high-need local educational agencies (as defined </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized From the amounts appropriated under subsection (f), the Secretary is authorized to award grants to States, on a competitive basis, to enable the States to encourage students to pursue a rigorous course of study, beginning in secondary school and continuing through the students’ postsecondary education, in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, or a health-related field.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mathematics and science scholars program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mathematics and science scholars program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>STEM or health-related scholars program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) STEM or health-related scholars program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching requirement In order to receive a grant under this section, a State shall provide matching funds for the scholarships awarded under this section in an amount equal to 50 percent of the Federal funds received.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1161b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition The term “Governor” means the chief executive officer of a State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>