<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1228a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1228a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1228a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1228a"><akn:num>1228a</akn:num><akn:heading>Equity for students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1228a. Equity for students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to assist the Department in implementing the Department’s mission to ensure equal access to education and to promote educational excellence throughout the Nation, by—(1) ensuring equal opportunities to participate for all eligible students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries in any project or activity carried out under an applicable program; and

(2) promoting the ability of such students, teachers, and beneficiaries to meet high standards.


(b) Requirement to develop steps to ensure equityThe Secretary shall require each applicant for assistance under an applicable program (other than an individual) to develop and describe in such applicant’s application the steps such applicant proposes to take to ensure equitable access to, and equitable participation in, the project or activity to be conducted with such assistance, by addressing the special needs of students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries in order to overcome barriers to equitable participation, including barriers based on gender, race, color, national origin, disability, and age.


(c) Establishment of criteriaThe Secretary may establish criteria and provide technical assistance for meeting the requirements of this section.


(d) Effect on other lawsNothing in this section shall be construed to alter in any way the rights or responsibilities established under the laws cited in section 1221(d) of this title.


(Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 427, as added Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 236, Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 3917.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 427 of Pub. L. 90–247 was renumbered section 434, and is classified to section 1231d of this title.
Another prior section 427 of Pub. L. 90–247 was renumbered section 429, and was classified to section 1231f of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–382.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1228a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to assist the Department in implementing the Department’s mission to ensure equal access to education and to promote educational excellence throughout the Nation, by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1228a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to develop steps to ensure equity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement to develop steps to ensure equity The Secretary shall require each applicant for assistance under an applicable program (other than an individual) to develop and describe in such applicant’s application the steps such applicant proposes to take to ensure equitable access to, and equitable participation in, the project or activity to be conducted with such assistance, by addressing the special needs of students, teachers, and other program beneficiaries in order to overcome barriers to equitable participation, including barriers based on gender, race, color, national origin, disability, and age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1228a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of criteria The Secretary may establish criteria and provide technical assistance for meeting the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1228a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect on other laws Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter in any way the rights or responsibilities established under the laws cited in section 1221(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>