<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1232i"><akn:num>1232i</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on withholding of Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1232i. Limitations on withholding of Federal assistance(a) Refusal to supply personal data on students or familiesExcept as provided in section 1232g(b)(1)(D) of this title, the refusal of a State or local educational agency or institution of higher education, community college, school, agency offering a preschool program, or other educational institution to provide personally identifiable data on students or their families, as a part of any applicable program, to any Federal office, agency, department, or other third party, on the grounds that it constitutes a violation of the right to privacy and confidentiality of students or their parents, shall not constitute sufficient grounds for the suspension or termination of Federal assistance. Such a refusal shall also not constitute sufficient grounds for a denial of, a refusal to consider, or a delay in the consideration of, funding for such a recipient in succeeding fiscal years. In the case of any dispute arising under this section, reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing shall be afforded the applicant.


(b) Noncompliance with nondiscrimination provisions of Federal lawThe extension of Federal financial assistance to a local educational agency may not be limited, deferred, or terminated by the Secretary on the ground of noncompliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.] or any other nondiscrimination provision of Federal law unless such agency is accorded the right of due process of law, which shall include—(1) at least 30 days prior written notice of deferral to the agency, setting forth the particular program or programs which the Secretary finds to be operated in noncompliance with a specific provision of Federal law;

(2) the opportunity for a hearing on the record before a duly appointed administrative law judge within a 60-day period (unless such period is extended by mutual consent of the Secretary and such agency) from the commencement of any deferral;

(3) the c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal to supply personal data on students or families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Refusal to supply personal data on students or families Except as provided in section 1232g(b)(1)(D) of this title, the refusal of a State or local educational agency or institution of higher education, community college, school, agency offering a preschool program, or other educational institution to provide personally identifiable data on students or their families, as a part of any applicable program, to any Federal office, agency, department, or other third party, on the grounds that it constitutes a violation of the right to privacy and confidentiality of students or their parents, shall not constitute sufficient grounds for the suspension or termination of Federal assistance. Such a refusal shall also not constitute sufficient grounds for a denial of, a refusal to consider, or a delay in the consideration of, funding for such a recipient in succeeding fiscal years. In the case of any dispute arising under this section, reasonable notice and opportunity for a hearing shall be </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance with nondiscrimination provisions of Federal law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Noncompliance with nondiscrimination provisions of Federal law The extension of Federal financial assistance to a local educational agency may not be limited, deferred, or terminated by the Secretary on the ground of noncompliance with title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.] or any other nondiscrimination provision of Federal law unless such agency is accorded the right of due process of law, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to comply with imposition of quotas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to comply with imposition of quotas It shall be unlawful for the Secretary to defer or limit any Federal financial assistance on the basis of any failure to comply with the imposition of quotas (or any other numerical requirements which have the effect of imposing quotas) on the student admission practices of an institution of higher education or community college receiving Federal financial assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>