<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1232g"><akn:num>1232g</akn:num><akn:heading>Family educational and privacy rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1232g. Family educational and privacy rights(a) Conditions for availability of funds to educational agencies or institutions; inspection and review of education records; specific information to be made available; procedure for access to education records; reasonableness of time for such access; hearings; written explanations by parents; definitions(1)(A) No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution which has a policy of denying, or which effectively prevents, the parents of students who are or have been in attendance at a school of such agency or at such institution, as the case may be, the right to inspect and review the education records of their children. If any material or document in the education record of a student includes information on more than one student, the parents of one of such students shall have the right to inspect and review only such part of such material or document as relates to such student or to be informed of the specific information contained in such part of such material. Each educational agency or institution shall establish appropriate procedures for the granting of a request by parents for access to the education records of their children within a reasonable period of time, but in no case more than forty-five days after the request has been made.

(B) No funds under any applicable program shall be made available to any State educational agency (whether or not that agency is an educational agency or institution under this section) that has a policy of denying, or effectively prevents, the parents of students the right to inspect and review the education records maintained by the State educational agency on their children who are or have been in attendance at any school of an educational agency or institution that is subject to the provisions of this section.

(C) The first sentence of subparagraph (A) shall not operate to make available to students in institutions of postsecon</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for availability of funds to educational agencies or institutions; inspection and review of education records; specific information to be made available; procedure for access to education records; reasonableness of time for such access; hearings; written explanations by parents; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions for availability of funds to educational agencies or institutions; inspection and review of education records; specific information to be made available; procedure for access to education records; reasonableness of time for such access; hearings; written explanations by parents; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of education records; parental consent requirement; exceptions; compliance with judicial orders and subpoenas; audit and evaluation of federally-supported education programs; recordkeeping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Release of education records; parental consent requirement; exceptions; compliance with judicial orders and subpoenas; audit and evaluation of federally-supported education programs; recordkeeping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveys or data-gathering activities; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Surveys or data-gathering activities; regulations Not later than 240 days after October 20, 1994, the Secretary shall adopt appropriate regulations or procedures, or identify existing regulations or procedures, which protect the rights of privacy of students and their families in connection with any surveys or data-gathering activities conducted, assisted, or authorized by the Secretary or an administrative head of an education agency. Regulations established under this subsection shall include provisions controlling the use, dissemination, and protection of such data. No survey or data-gathering activities shall be conducted by the Secretary, or an administrative head of an education agency under an applicable program, unless such activities are authorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Students’ rather than parents’ permission or consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Students’ rather than parents’ permission or consent For the purposes of this section, whenever a student has attained eighteen years of age, or is attending an institution of postsecondary education, the permission or consent required of and the rights accorded to the parents of the student shall thereafter only be required of and accorded to the student.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informing parents or students of rights under this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Informing parents or students of rights under this section No funds shall be made available under any applicable program to any educational agency or institution unless such agency or institution effectively informs the parents of students, or the students, if they are eighteen years of age or older, or are attending an institution of postsecondary education, of the rights accorded them by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement; termination of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enforcement; termination of assistance The Secretary shall take appropriate actions to enforce this section and to deal with violations of this section, in accordance with this chapter, except that action to terminate assistance may be taken only if the Secretary finds there has been a failure to comply with this section, and he has determined that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office and review board; creation; functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Office and review board; creation; functions The Secretary shall establish or designate an office and review board within the Department for the purpose of investigating, processing, reviewing, and adjudicating violations of this section and complaints which may be filed concerning alleged violations of this section. Except for the conduct of hearings, none of the functions of the Secretary under this section shall be carried out in any of the regional offices of such Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disciplinary records; disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disciplinary records; disclosure Nothing in this section shall prohibit an educational agency or institution from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drug and alcohol violation disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Drug and alcohol violation disclosures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232g_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigation and prosecution of terrorism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Investigation and prosecution of terrorism</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>