<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1232f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1232f"><akn:num>1232f</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1232f. Records(a) Records kept by recipient; full disclosure; maintenance periodEach recipient of Federal funds under any applicable program through any grant, subgrant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other arrangement shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by the recipient of those funds, the total cost of the activity for which the funds are used, the share of that cost provided from other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective financial or programmatic audit. The recipient shall maintain such rec­ords for three years after the completion of the activity for which the funds are used.


(b) Audit examinationThe Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for the purpose of audit examination, to any rec­ords maintained by a recipient that may be related, or pertinent to, grants, subgrants, cooperative agreements, loans, or other arrangements to which reference is made in subsection (a), or which may relate to the compliance of the recipient with any requirement of an applicable program.


(Pub. L. 90–247, title IV, § 443, formerly § 437, as added Pub. L. 95–561, title XII, § 1231(c), Nov. 1, 1978, 92 Stat. 2346; renumbered § 443 and amended Pub. L. 103–382, title II, §§ 212(b)(1), 248, Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 3913, 3924.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 443 of Pub. L. 90–247 was classified to section 1233b of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 103–382.

Amendments1994—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 103–382, § 248(1), substituted “grant, subgrant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other arrangement” for “grant, subgrant, contract, subcontract, loan, or other arrangement (other than procurement contracts awarded by an administrative head of an educational agency)”, inserted “financial or programmatic” before “audit.”, and substituted “three years” for “five years”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 103–382, § 248(2), substituted “to a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records kept by recipient; full disclosure; maintenance period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Records kept by recipient; full disclosure; maintenance period Each recipient of Federal funds under any applicable program through any grant, subgrant, cooperative agreement, loan, or other arrangement shall keep records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by the recipient of those funds, the total cost of the activity for which the funds are used, the share of that cost provided from other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective financial or programmatic audit. The recipient shall maintain such rec­ords for three years after the completion of the activity for which the funds are used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1232f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audit examination The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access, for the purpose of audit examination, to any rec­ords maintained by a recipient that may be related, or pertinent to, grants, subgrants, cooperative agreements, loans, or other arrangements to which reference is made in subsection (a), or which may relate to the compliance of the recipient with any requirement of an applicable program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>