<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1234a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1234a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1234a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1234a"><akn:num>1234a</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1234a. Recovery of funds(a) Preliminary departmental decision; grounds of determination; notice requirements; prima facie case; amount of funds recoverable(1) Whenever the Secretary determines that a recipient of a grant or cooperative agreement under an applicable program must return funds because the recipient has made an expenditure of funds that is not allowable under that grant or cooperative agreement, or has otherwise failed to discharge its obligation to account properly for funds under the grant or cooperative agreement, the Secretary shall give the recipient written notice of a preliminary departmental decision and notify the recipient of its right to have that decision reviewed by the Office and of its right to request mediation.

(2) In a preliminary departmental decision, the Secretary shall have the burden of establishing a prima facie case for the recovery of funds, including an analysis reflecting the value of the program services actually obtained in a determination of harm to the Federal interest. The facts to serve as the basis of the preliminary departmental decision may come from an audit report, an investigative report, a monitoring report, or other evidence. The amount of funds to be recovered shall be determined on the basis of section 1234b of this title.

(3) For the purpose of paragraph (2), failure by a recipient to maintain records required by law, or to allow the Secretary access to such records, shall constitute a prima facie case.


(b) Review of preliminary departmental decision; form and contents of application for review; inadequate preliminary decisions; duties of recipient to subrecipients after preliminary decision; burden of proof(1) A recipient that has received written notice of a preliminary departmental decision and that desires to have such decision reviewed by the Office shall submit to the Office an application for review not later than 60 days after receipt of notice of the preliminary departmental decision. The appli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary departmental decision; grounds of determination; notice requirements; prima facie case; amount of funds recoverable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preliminary departmental decision; grounds of determination; notice requirements; prima facie case; amount of funds recoverable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of preliminary departmental decision; form and contents of application for review; inadequate preliminary decisions; duties of recipient to subrecipients after preliminary decision; burden of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review of preliminary departmental decision; form and contents of application for review; inadequate preliminary decisions; duties of recipient to subrecipients after preliminary decision; burden of proof</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Time for hearing A hearing shall be set 90 days after receipt of a request for review of a preliminary departmental decision by the Office, except that such 90-day requirement may be waived at the discretion of the judge for good cause.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of findings of fact in preliminary decision; conclusiveness; remand; new or modified findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of findings of fact in preliminary decision; conclusiveness; remand; new or modified findings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for filing petition for review of preliminary decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Time for filing petition for review of preliminary decision Parties to the proceeding shall have 30 days to file a petition for review of a decision of the administrative law judges with the Office of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of collection or other adverse action by Secretary against recipient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Stay of collection or other adverse action by Secretary against recipient</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary decision as final agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preliminary decision as final agency action A decision of the Office regarding the review of a preliminary departmental decision shall become final agency action 60 days after the recipient receives written notice of the decision unless the Secretary either—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of decisions as final agency actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of decisions as final agency actions The Secretary shall publish decisions that have become final agency action under subsection (g) in the Federal Register or in another appropriate publication within 60 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection amounts and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Collection amounts and procedures The amount of a preliminary departmental decision under subsection (a) for which review has not been requested in accordance with subsection (b), and the amount sustained by a decision of the Office or the Secretary which becomes final agency action under subsection (g), may be collected by the Secretary in accordance with chapter 37 of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1234a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise of preliminary departmental decisions; preconditions; notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Compromise of preliminary departmental decisions; preconditions; notice requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>