<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_124"><akn:num>124</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of Freedmen’s Hospital to Howard University</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 124. Transfer of Freedmen’s Hospital to Howard University(a) Purpose; authorization; agreementFor the purpose of assisting in the provision of teaching hospital resources for Howard University, thereby assisting the university in the training of medical and allied personnel and in providing hospital services for the community, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall, pursuant to agreement with the board of trustees of Howard University, transfer to Howard University, without reimbursement, all right, title, and interest of the United States in certain lands in the District of Columbia, together with the buildings and improvements thereon and the personal property used in connection therewith (as determined by the Secretary), commonly known as Freedmen’s Hospital.


(b) Congressional intentIt is the intent of Congress (1) that the transfer of Freedmen’s Hospital to Howard University be effected as soon as practicable, (2) to assure the well-being of patients at Freedmen’s Hospital during the period of transition, and (3) that the transfer be effected with minimum dislocation of the present hospital staff and maximum consideration of their interests as employees.


(c) Report to CongressThe Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall report to the Congress the terms of the agreement for such transfer.


(Pub. L. 87–262, § 1, Sept. 21, 1961, 75 Stat. 542.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
Functions of Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under laws relating to relationship between Howard University and Department of Health, Education, and Welfare transferred to Secretary of Education by section 3441(a)(2)(M) of this title.

Repeal of Laws Applicable to Freedmen’s HospitalPub. L. 87–262, § 7, Sept. 21, 1961, 75 Stat. 544, provided that: “All laws heretofore applicable specifically to Freedmen’s Hospital are, to the extent of such applicability, repealed, effective with the transfer of Freedmen’s Hospital pursu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose; authorization; agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose; authorization; agreement For the purpose of assisting in the provision of teaching hospital resources for Howard University, thereby assisting the university in the training of medical and allied personnel and in providing hospital services for the community, the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall, pursuant to agreement with the board of trustees of Howard University, transfer to Howard University, without reimbursement, all right, title, and interest of the United States in certain lands in the District of Columbia, together with the buildings and improvements thereon and the personal property used in connection therewith (as determined by the Secretary), commonly known as Freedmen’s Hospital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional intent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional intent It is the intent of Congress (1) that the transfer of Freedmen’s Hospital to Howard University be effected as soon as practicable, (2) to assure the well-being of patients at Freedmen’s Hospital during the period of transition, and (3) that the transfer be effected with minimum dislocation of the present hospital staff and maximum consideration of their interests as employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress The Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare shall report to the Congress the terms of the agreement for such transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>