<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/131...152" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/131...152/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/131...152/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_131___152"><akn:num>131...152</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 131 to 152. Omitted
Editorial Notes
Codification
Sections provided for the National Training School for Boys which was governed and managed by a Board of Trustees until July 1, 1939, at which time 1939 Reorg. Plan No. 2 (4 F.R. 2731, 53 Stat. 1431) abolished the Board of Trustees and transferred the School and its functions (including the functions of the Board of Trustees) to the Department of Justice, to be administered by the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, under the direction and supervision of the Attorney General. The School was so operated until May 15, 1968, when it was closed pursuant to order of the Attorney General.
Section 131, act May 27, 1908, ch. 200, § 1, 35 Stat. 380, provided that District reform school for boys should be known as National Training School for Boys.
Section 132, acts May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 1, 19 Stat. 49; May 27, 1908, ch. 200, § 1, 35 Stat. 380, dealt with appointment of a board of trustees to govern and manage the school.
Section 133, act June 4, 1880, ch. 121, § 1, 21 Stat. 156, provided that one of the District commissioners should be a trustee of the school.
Section 134, act May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 16, 19 Stat. 52, provided for appointment of two consulting trustees of the school.
Section 135, acts May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 2, 19 Stat. 49; May 27, 1908, ch. 200, § 1, 35 Stat. 380, dealt with corporate capacity and powers of the board of trustees.
Section 136, acts May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 15, 19 Stat. 52; June 5, 1900, ch. 715, 31 Stat. 267, authorized board of trustees to make by-laws, rules, and regulations.
Section 137, act May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 14, 19 Stat. 51, dealt with contracts and purchases, the executive officer, and annual reports.
Section 138, act May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 3, 19 Stat. 49, dealt with appointment and compensation of a superintendent and other employees of the school.
Section 139, acts May 3, 1876, ch. 90, § 4, 19 Stat. 49; June 10, 1921, ch. 18, § 304, 42 Stat. 24, dealt with appointment, bonding, and d</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>