<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1401"><akn:num>1401</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1401. Definitions
Except as otherwise provided, in this chapter:(1) Assistive technology device(A) In generalThe term “assistive technology device” means any item, piece of equipment, or product system, whether acquired commercially off the shelf, modified, or customized, that is used to increase, maintain, or improve functional capabilities of a child with a disability.


(B) ExceptionThe term does not include a medical device that is surgically implanted, or the replacement of such device.



(2) Assistive technology serviceThe term “assistive technology service” means any service that directly assists a child with a disability in the selection, acquisition, or use of an assistive technology device. Such term includes—(A) the evaluation of the needs of such child, including a functional evaluation of the child in the child’s customary environment;

(B) purchasing, leasing, or otherwise providing for the acquisition of assistive technology devices by such child;

(C) selecting, designing, fitting, customizing, adapting, applying, maintaining, repairing, or replacing assistive technology devices;

(D) coordinating and using other therapies, interventions, or services with assistive technology devices, such as those associated with existing education and rehabilitation plans and programs;

(E) training or technical assistance for such child, or, where appropriate, the family of such child; and

(F) training or technical assistance for professionals (including individuals providing education and rehabilitation services), employers, or other individuals who provide services to, employ, or are otherwise substantially involved in the major life functions of such child.


(3) Child with a disability(A) In generalThe term “child with a disability” means a child—(i) with intellectual disabilities, hearing impairments (including deafness), speech or language impairments, visual impairments (including blindness), serious emotional disturbance (referred to in this chapter as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistive technology device</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Assistive technology device</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistive technology service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Assistive technology service The term “assistive technology service” means any service that directly assists a child with a disability in the selection, acquisition, or use of an assistive technology device. Such term includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child with a disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Child with a disability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(ss)(1)(A), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2181</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational service agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Educational service agency The term “educational service agency”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elementary school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Elementary school The term “elementary school” means a nonprofit institutional day or residential school, including a public elementary charter school, that provides elementary education, as determined under State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Equipment The term “equipment” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Excess costs The term “excess costs” means those costs that are in excess of the average annual per-student expenditure in a local educational agency during the preceding school year for an elementary school or secondary school student, as may be appropriate, and which shall be computed after deducting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free appropriate public education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Free appropriate public education The term “free appropriate public education” means special education and related services that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1401_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9214(d)(1), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2164</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>