<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1412"><akn:num>1412</akn:num><akn:heading>State eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1412. State eligibility(a) In generalA State is eligible for assistance under this subchapter for a fiscal year if the State submits a plan that provides assurances to the Secretary that the State has in effect policies and procedures to ensure that the State meets each of the following conditions:(1) Free appropriate public education(A) In generalA free appropriate public education is available to all children with disabilities residing in the State between the ages of 3 and 21, inclusive, including children with disabilities who have been suspended or expelled from school.


(B) LimitationThe obligation to make a free appropriate public education available to all children with disabilities does not apply with respect to children—(i) aged 3 through 5 and 18 through 21 in a State to the extent that its application to those children would be inconsistent with State law or practice, or the order of any court, respecting the provision of public education to children in those age ranges; and

(ii) aged 18 through 21 to the extent that State law does not require that special education and related services under this subchapter be provided to children with disabilities who, in the educational placement prior to their incarceration in an adult correctional facility—(I) were not actually identified as being a child with a disability under section 1401 of this title; or

(II) did not have an individualized education program under this subchapter.



(C) State flexibilityA State that provides early intervention services in accordance with subchapter III to a child who is eligible for services under section 1419 of this title, is not required to provide such child with a free appropriate public education.



(2) Full educational opportunity goalThe State has established a goal of providing full educational opportunity to all children with disabilities and a detailed timetable for accomplishing that goal.


(3) Child find(A) In generalAll children with disabilities residing i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State is eligible for assistance under this subchapter for a fiscal year if the State submits a plan that provides assurances to the Secretary that the State has in effect policies and procedures to ensure that the State meets each of the following conditions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State educational agency as provider of free appropriate public education or direct services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State educational agency as provider of free appropriate public education or direct services If the State educational agency provides free appropriate public education to children with disabilities, or provides direct services to such children, such agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for prior State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for prior State plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Approval by the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance under other Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance under other Federal programs Nothing in this chapter permits a State to reduce medical and other assistance available, or to alter eligibility, under titles V and XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 701 et seq., 1396 et seq.] with respect to the provision of a free appropriate public education for children with disabilities in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1412_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>By-pass for children in private schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) By-pass for children in private schools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>