<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1415" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1415/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1415/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1415"><akn:num>1415</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1415. Procedural safeguards(a) Establishment of proceduresAny State educational agency, State agency, or local educational agency that receives assistance under this subchapter shall establish and maintain procedures in accordance with this section to ensure that children with disabilities and their parents are guaranteed procedural safeguards with respect to the provision of a free appropriate public education by such agencies.


(b) Types of proceduresThe procedures required by this section shall include the following:(1) An opportunity for the parents of a child with a disability to examine all records relating to such child and to participate in meetings with respect to the identification, evaluation, and educational placement of the child, and the provision of a free appropriate public education to such child, and to obtain an independent educational evaluation of the child.

(2)(A) Procedures to protect the rights of the child whenever the parents of the child are not known, the agency cannot, after reasonable efforts, locate the parents, or the child is a ward of the State, including the assignment of an individual to act as a surrogate for the parents, which surrogate shall not be an employee of the State educational agency, the local educational agency, or any other agency that is involved in the education or care of the child. In the case of—(i) a child who is a ward of the State, such surrogate may alternatively be appointed by the judge overseeing the child’s care provided that the surrogate meets the requirements of this paragraph; and

(ii) an unaccompanied homeless youth as defined in section 11434a(6) of title 42, the local educational agency shall appoint a surrogate in accordance with this paragraph.


(B) The State shall make reasonable efforts to ensure the assignment of a surrogate not more than 30 days after there is a determination by the agency that the child needs a surrogate.


(3) Written prior notice to the parents of the child, in acco</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of procedures Any State educational agency, State agency, or local educational agency that receives assistance under this subchapter shall establish and maintain procedures in accordance with this section to ensure that children with disabilities and their parents are guaranteed procedural safeguards with respect to the provision of a free appropriate public education by such agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Types of procedures The procedures required by this section shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural safeguards notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Procedural safeguards notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mediation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Mediation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impartial due process hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Impartial due process hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appeal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Safeguards Any party to a hearing conducted pursuant to subsection (f) or (k), or an appeal conducted pursuant to subsection (g), shall be accorded—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administrative procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1415_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of current educational placement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Maintenance of current educational placement Except as provided in subsection (k)(4), during the pendency of any proceedings conducted pursuant to this section, unless the State or local educational agency and the parents otherwise agree, the child shall remain in the then-current educational placement of the child, or, if applying for initial admission to a public school, shall, with the consent of the parents, be placed in the public school program until all such proceedings have been completed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>