<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1416" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1416/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1416/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1416"><akn:num>1416</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring, technical assistance, and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1416. Monitoring, technical assistance, and enforcement(a) Federal and State monitoring(1) In generalThe Secretary shall—(A) monitor implementation of this subchapter through—(i) oversight of the exercise of general supervision by the States, as required in section 1412(a)(11) of this title; and

(ii) the State performance plans, described in subsection (b);


(B) enforce this subchapter in accordance with subsection (e); and

(C) require States to—(i) monitor implementation of this subchapter by local educational agencies; and

(ii) enforce this subchapter in accordance with paragraph (3) and subsection (e).



(2) Focused monitoringThe primary focus of Federal and State monitoring activities described in paragraph (1) shall be on—(A) improving educational results and functional outcomes for all children with disabilities; and

(B) ensuring that States meet the program requirements under this subchapter, with a particular emphasis on those requirements that are most closely related to improving educational results for children with disabilities.


(3) Monitoring prioritiesThe Secretary shall monitor the States, and shall require each State to monitor the local educational agencies located in the State (except the State exercise of general supervisory responsibility), using quantifiable indicators in each of the following priority areas, and using such qualitative indicators as are needed to adequately measure performance in the following priority areas:(A) Provision of a free appropriate public education in the least restrictive environment.

(B) State exercise of general supervisory authority, including child find, effective monitoring, the use of resolution sessions, mediation, voluntary binding arbitration, and a system of transition services as defined in sections 1401(34) and 1437(a)(9) of this title.

(C) Disproportionate representation of racial and ethnic groups in special education and related services, to the extent the representation is the result of i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal and State monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal and State monitoring</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State performance plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State performance plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary’s review and determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Secretary’s review and determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State enforcement If a State educational agency determines that a local educational agency is not meeting the requirements of this subchapter, including the targets in the State’s performance plan, the State educational agency shall prohibit the local educational agency from reducing the local educational agency’s maintenance of effort under section 1413(a)(2)(C) of this title for any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict the Secretary from utilizing any authority under the General Education Provisions Act [20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.] to monitor and enforce the requirements of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Divided State agency responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Divided State agency responsibility For purposes of this section, where responsibility for ensuring that the requirements of this subchapter are met with respect to children with disabilities who are convicted as adults under State law and incarcerated in adult prisons is assigned to a public agency other than the State educational agency pursuant to section 1412(a)(11)(C) of this title, the Secretary, in instances where the Secretary finds that the failure to comply substantially with the provisions of this subchapter are related to a failure by the public agency, shall take appropriate corrective action to ensure compliance with this subchapter, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1416_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data capacity and technical assistance review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Data capacity and technical assistance review The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>