<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1419" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1419/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1419/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1419"><akn:num>1419</akn:num><akn:heading>Preschool grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1419. Preschool grants(a) In generalThe Secretary shall provide grants under this section to assist States to provide special education and related services, in accordance with this subchapter—(1) to children with disabilities aged 3 through 5, inclusive; and

(2) at the State’s discretion, to 2-year-old children with disabilities who will turn 3 during the school year.


(b) EligibilityA State shall be eligible for a grant under this section if such State—(1) is eligible under section 1412 of this title to receive a grant under this subchapter; and

(2) makes a free appropriate public education available to all children with disabilities, aged 3 through 5, residing in the State.


(c) Allocations to States(1) In generalThe Secretary shall allocate the amount made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year among the States in accordance with paragraph (2) or (3), as the case may be.


(2) Increase in fundsIf the amount available for allocations to States under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year is equal to or greater than the amount allocated to the States under this section for the preceding fiscal year, those allocations shall be calculated as follows:(A) Allocation(i) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall—(I) allocate to each State the amount the State received under this section for fiscal year 1997;

(II) allocate 85 percent of any remaining funds to States on the basis of the States’ relative populations of children aged 3 through 5; and

(III) allocate 15 percent of those remaining funds to States on the basis of the States’ relative populations of all children aged 3 through 5 who are living in poverty.


(ii) DataFor the purpose of making grants under this paragraph, the Secretary shall use the most recent population data, including data on children living in poverty, that are available and satisfactory to the Secretary.



(B) LimitationsNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), allocations under this paragraph shall be su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall provide grants under this section to assist States to provide special education and related services, in accordance with this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility A State shall be eligible for a grant under this section if such State—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocations to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation for State activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reservation for State activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other State-level activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Other State-level activities Each State shall use any funds the State reserves under subsection (d) and does not use for administration under subsection (e)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to local educational agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subgrants to local educational agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subchapter III inapplicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Subchapter III inapplicable Subchapter III does not apply to any child with a disability receiving a free appropriate public education, in accordance with this subchapter, with funds received under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>State defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) State defined In this section, the term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1419_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>