<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1436" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1436/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1436/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1436"><akn:num>1436</akn:num><akn:heading>Individualized family service plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1436. Individualized family service plan(a) Assessment and program developmentA statewide system described in section 1433 of this title shall provide, at a minimum, for each infant or toddler with a disability, and the infant’s or toddler’s family, to receive—(1) a multidisciplinary assessment of the unique strengths and needs of the infant or toddler and the identification of services appropriate to meet such needs;

(2) a family-directed assessment of the resources, priorities, and concerns of the family and the identification of the supports and services necessary to enhance the family’s capacity to meet the developmental needs of the infant or toddler; and

(3) a written individualized family service plan developed by a multidisciplinary team, including the parents, as required by subsection (e), including a description of the appropriate transition services for the infant or toddler.


(b) Periodic reviewThe individualized family service plan shall be evaluated once a year and the family shall be provided a review of the plan at 6-month intervals (or more often where appropriate based on infant or toddler and family needs).


(c) Promptness after assessmentThe individualized family service plan shall be developed within a reasonable time after the assessment required by subsection (a)(1) is completed. With the parents’ consent, early intervention services may commence prior to the completion of the assessment.


(d) Content of planThe individualized family service plan shall be in writing and contain—(1) a statement of the infant’s or toddler’s present levels of physical development, cognitive development, communication development, social or emotional development, and adaptive development, based on objective criteria;

(2) a statement of the family’s resources, priorities, and concerns relating to enhancing the development of the family’s infant or toddler with a disability;

(3) a statement of the measurable results or outcomes expected to be achieved for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1436_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment and program development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment and program development A statewide system described in section 1433 of this title shall provide, at a minimum, for each infant or toddler with a disability, and the infant’s or toddler’s family, to receive—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1436_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic review The individualized family service plan shall be evaluated once a year and the family shall be provided a review of the plan at 6-month intervals (or more often where appropriate based on infant or toddler and family needs).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1436_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promptness after assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Promptness after assessment The individualized family service plan shall be developed within a reasonable time after the assessment required by subsection (a)(1) is completed. With the parents’ consent, early intervention services may commence prior to the completion of the assessment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1436_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Content of plan The individualized family service plan shall be in writing and contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1436_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parental consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Parental consent The contents of the individualized family service plan shall be fully explained to the parents and informed written consent from the parents shall be obtained prior to the provision of early intervention services described in such plan. If the parents do not provide consent with respect to a particular early intervention service, then only the early intervention services to which consent is obtained shall be provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>