<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1443" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1443/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1443/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1443"><akn:num>1443</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1443. Allocation of funds(a) Reservation of funds for outlying areas(1) In generalFrom the sums appropriated to carry out this subchapter for any fiscal year, the Secretary may reserve not more than 1 percent for payments to Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands in accordance with their respective needs for assistance under this subchapter.


(2) Consolidation of fundsThe provisions of Public Law 95–134, permitting the consolidation of grants to the outlying areas, shall not apply to funds those areas receive under this subchapter.



(b) Payments to Indians(1) In generalThe Secretary shall, subject to this subsection, make payments to the Secretary of the Interior to be distributed to tribes, tribal organizations (as defined under section 5304 of title 25), or consortia of the above entities for the coordination of assistance in the provision of early intervention services by the States to infants and toddlers with disabilities and their families on reservations served by elementary schools and secondary schools for Indian children operated or funded by the Department of the Interior. The amount of such payment for any fiscal year shall be 1.25 percent of the aggregate of the amount available to all States under this subchapter for such fiscal year.


(2) AllocationFor each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Interior shall distribute the entire payment received under paragraph (1) by providing to each tribe, tribal organization, or consortium an amount based on the number of infants and toddlers residing on the reservation, as determined annually, divided by the total of such children served by all tribes, tribal organizations, or consortia.


(3) InformationTo receive a payment under this subsection, the tribe, tribal organization, or consortium shall submit such information to the Secretary of the Interior as is needed to determine the amounts to be distributed under paragraph (2).


(4) Use </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of funds for outlying areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reservation of funds for outlying areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments to Indians</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State allotments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallotment of funds If a State elects not to receive its allotment under subsection (c), the Secretary shall reallot, among the remaining States, amounts from such State in accordance with such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1443_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation for State incentive grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reservation for State incentive grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>