<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1462" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1462/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1462/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1462"><akn:num>1462</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel development to improve services and results for children with disabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1462. Personnel development to improve services and results for children with disabilities(a) In generalThe Secretary, on a competitive basis, shall award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to carry out 1 or more of the following objectives:(1) To help address the needs identified in the State plan described in section 1453(a)(2) of this title for personnel, as defined in section 1451(b) of this title, who meet the applicable requirements described in section 1412(a)(14) of this title, to work with infants or toddlers with disabilities, or children with disabilities, consistent with the qualifications described in section 1412(a)(14) of this title.

(2) To ensure that those personnel have the necessary skills and knowledge, derived from practices that have been determined, through scientifically based research, to be successful in serving those children.

(3) To encourage increased focus on academics and core content areas in special education personnel preparation programs.

(4) To ensure that regular education teachers have the necessary skills and knowledge to provide instruction to students with disabilities in the regular education classroom.

(5) To ensure that all special education teachers meet the qualifications described in section 1412(a)(14)(C) of this title.

(6) To ensure that preservice and in-service personnel preparation programs include training in—(A) the use of new technologies;

(B) the area of early intervention, educational, and transition services;

(C) effectively involving parents; and

(D) positive behavioral supports.


(7) To provide high-quality professional development for principals, superintendents, and other administrators, including training in—(A) instructional leadership;

(B) behavioral supports in the school and classroom;

(C) paperwork reduction;

(D) promoting improved collaboration between special education and general education teachers;

(E) assessment and accountability</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, on a competitive basis, shall award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to carry out 1 or more of the following objectives:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel development; enhanced support for beginning special educators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Personnel development; enhanced support for beginning special educators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low incidence disabilities; authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Low incidence disabilities; authorized activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leadership preparation; authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Leadership preparation; authorized activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Selection of recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Scholarships The Secretary may include funds for scholarships, with necessary stipends and allowances, in awards under subsections (b), (c), and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Service obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1462_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>