<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1481" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1481/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1481/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1481"><akn:num>1481</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive plan for parts B and C</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1481. Comprehensive plan for parts B and C(a) Comprehensive plan(1) In generalAfter receiving input from interested individuals with relevant expertise, the Secretary shall develop and implement a comprehensive plan for activities carried out under parts B and C in order to enhance the provision of early intervention services, educational services, related services, and transitional services to children with disabilities under subchapters II and III. To the extent practicable, the plan shall be coordinated with the plan developed pursuant to section 9567b(c) of this title 11 See References in Text note below. and shall include mechanisms to address early intervention, educational, related service and transitional needs identified by State educational agencies in applications submitted for State personnel development grants under part A and for grants under parts B and C.


(2) Public commentThe Secretary shall provide a public comment period of not less than 45 days on the plan.


(3) Distribution of fundsIn implementing the plan, the Secretary shall, to the extent appropriate, ensure that funds awarded under parts B and C are used to carry out activities that benefit, directly or indirectly, children with the full range of disabilities and of all ages.


(4) Reports to CongressThe Secretary shall annually report to Congress on the Secretary’s activities under parts B and C, including an initial report not later than 12 months after December 3, 2004.



(b) Assistance authorizedThe Secretary is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the purposes of such parts in accordance with the comprehensive plan described in subsection (a).


(c) Special populations(1) Application requirementIn making an award of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under part B or C, the Secretary shall, as appropriate, require an eligible entity to demonstrate how the eligib</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1481_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Comprehensive plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1481_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance authorized The Secretary is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the purposes of such parts in accordance with the comprehensive plan described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1481_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special populations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1481_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priorities The Secretary, in making an award of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under part B or C, may, without regard to the rulemaking procedures under section 553 of title 5, limit competitions to, or otherwise give priority to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1481_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility for financial assistance No State or local educational agency, or other public institution or agency, may receive a grant or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement under part B or C that relates exclusively to programs, projects, and activities pertaining to children aged 3 through 5, inclusive, unless the State is eligible to receive a grant under section 1419(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>