<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1757" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1757/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/1757/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1757"><akn:num>1757</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of forced busing during school year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1757. Prohibition of forced busing during school year(a) Congressional findingsThe Congress finds that—(1) the forced transportation of elementary and secondary school students in implementation of the constitutional requirement for the desegregation of such schools is controversial and difficult under the best planning and administration; and

(2) the forced transportation of elementary and secondary school students after the commencement of an academic school year is educationally unsound and administratively inefficient.


(b) Student transportation orders incidental to student transfers pursuant to school desegregation plans effective beginning with academic school yearNotwithstanding any other provisions of law, no order of a court, department, or agency of the United States, requiring the transportation of any student incident to the transfer of that student from one elementary or secondary school to another such school in a local educational agency pursuant to a plan requiring such transportation for the racial desegregation of any school in that agency, shall be effective until the beginning of an academic school year.


(c) “Academic school year” definedFor the purpose of this section, the term “academic school year” means, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the customary beginning of classes for the school year at an elementary or secondary school of a local educational agency for a school year that occurs not more often than once in any twelve-month period.


(d) Orders subject to provisions of sectionThe provisions of this section apply to any order which was not implemented at the beginning of the 1974–1975 academic year.


(Pub. L. 93–380, title II, § 258, Aug. 21, 1974, 88 Stat. 520; Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1), title V, § 507, Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 677, 692.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on and after sixtieth day after Aug. 21, 1974, see section 2(c) of Pub. L. 93–380, set </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student transportation orders incidental to student transfers pursuant to school desegregation plans effective beginning with academic school year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Student transportation orders incidental to student transfers pursuant to school desegregation plans effective beginning with academic school year Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, no order of a court, department, or agency of the United States, requiring the transportation of any student incident to the transfer of that student from one elementary or secondary school to another such school in a local educational agency pursuant to a plan requiring such transportation for the racial desegregation of any school in that agency, shall be effective until the beginning of an academic school year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Academic school year” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Academic school year” defined For the purpose of this section, the term “academic school year” means, pursuant to regulations promulgated by the Secretary, the customary beginning of classes for the school year at an elementary or secondary school of a local educational agency for a school year that occurs not more often than once in any twelve-month period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1757_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Orders subject to provisions of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Orders subject to provisions of section The provisions of this section apply to any order which was not implemented at the beginning of the 1974–1975 academic year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>