<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/191" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/191/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/191/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_191"><akn:num>191</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; site; acquisition of land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 191. Establishment; site; acquisition of land
The Secretary of Agriculture is authorized and directed to establish and maintain a national arboretum for purposes of research and education concerning tree and plant life. For the purposes of this chapter, (1) the President is authorized to transfer to the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture by Executive order any land which now belongs to the United States within or adjacent to the District of Columbia located along the Anacostia River north of Benning Bridge, and (2) the Secretary of Agriculture is authorized in his discretion to acquire, within the limits of the appropriation authorized by this chapter by private purchase, condemnation proceedings, or gift, land so located or other land within or adjacent to the District of Columbia: Provided, That the purchase price of any part of said land shall not exceed the full value assessment of such property last made before purchase thereof plus 25 per centum of such assessed value.
(Mar. 4, 1927, ch. 505, § 1, 44 Stat. 1422.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Facilities To House Bonsai CollectionsPub. L. 103–111, title I, Oct. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 1051, provided in part: “That hereafter, facilities to house bonsai collections at the National Arboretum may be constructed with funds accepted under the provisions of Public Law 94–129 (20 U.S.C. 195) and the limitation on construction contained in the Act of August 24, 1912 (40 U.S.C. 68) [now 40 U.S.C. 8106] shall not apply to the construction of such facilities”.

Similar provisions were contained in the following prior appropriations acts:
Pub. L. 102–341, title I, Aug. 14, 1992, 106 Stat. 878.
Pub. L. 102–142, title I, Oct. 28, 1991, 105 Stat. 883.
Pub. L. 101–506, title I, Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 1320.
Pub. L. 101–161, title I, Nov. 21, 1989, 103 Stat. 956.
Pub. L. 100–460, title I, Oct. 1, 1988, 102 Stat. 2234.
Pub. L. 100–202, § 101(k) [title I], Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1329–322, 1329–327.
Pub. L. 99</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>