<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2105"><akn:num>2105</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2105. Limitations on contracts(a) TimeNo payment shall be made pursuant to this subchapter to carry out any research or training over a period in excess of two years, except that with the concurrence of at least two-thirds of the members of the Board of the Center such research or training may be carried out over a period of not to exceed five years.


(b) Items excludedAssistance pursuant to this subchapter shall not cover the cost of land acquisition, construction, building acquisitions, or acquisition of major equipment.


(c) Former Government employeesNo individual formerly in the employment of the Federal Government shall be eligible to receive any assistance pursuant to this subchapter, or to serve as a trustee of the Center in the two-year period following the termination of such employment.


(Pub. L. 94–201, § 6, Jan. 2, 1976, 89 Stat. 1132.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Time No payment shall be made pursuant to this subchapter to carry out any research or training over a period in excess of two years, except that with the concurrence of at least two-thirds of the members of the Board of the Center such research or training may be carried out over a period of not to exceed five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Items excluded</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Items excluded Assistance pursuant to this subchapter shall not cover the cost of land acquisition, construction, building acquisitions, or acquisition of major equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Former Government employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Former Government employees No individual formerly in the employment of the Federal Government shall be eligible to receive any assistance pursuant to this subchapter, or to serve as a trustee of the Center in the two-year period following the termination of such employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>