<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2143" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2143/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2143/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2143"><akn:num>2143</akn:num><akn:heading>Private support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2143. Private support(a) Acceptance of donationsThe Librarian of Congress may solicit and accept donations of funds and in-kind contributions to carry out the oral history program under section 2142 of this title.


(b) Establishment of separate gift accountThere is established in the Treasury (among the accounts of the Library of Congress) a gift account for the oral history program under section 2142 of this title.


(c) Dedication of fundsNotwithstanding any other provision of law—(1) any funds donated to the Librarian of Congress to carry out the oral history program under section 2142 of this title shall be deposited entirely into the gift account established under subsection (b);

(2) the funds contained in such account shall be used solely to carry out the oral history program under section 2142 of this title; and

(3) the Librarian of Congress may not deposit into such account any funds donated to the Librarian which are not donated for the exclusive purpose of carrying out the oral history program under section 2142 of this title.


(Pub. L. 106–380, § 4, Oct. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 1448.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acceptance of donations The Librarian of Congress may solicit and accept donations of funds and in-kind contributions to carry out the oral history program under section 2142 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of separate gift account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of separate gift account There is established in the Treasury (among the accounts of the Library of Congress) a gift account for the oral history program under section 2142 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2143_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dedication of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dedication of funds Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>