<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2302"><akn:num>2302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2302. Definitions
Unless otherwise specified, in this chapter:(1) AdministrationThe term “administration”, when used with respect to an eligible agency or eligible recipient, means activities necessary for the proper and efficient performance of the eligible agency or eligible recipient’s duties under this chapter, including the supervision of such activities. Such term does not include curriculum development activities, personnel development, or research activities.


(2) All aspects of an industryThe term “all aspects of an industry” means strong experience in, and comprehensive understanding of, the industry that the individual is preparing to enter.


(3) Area career and technical education schoolThe term “area career and technical education school” means—(A) a specialized public secondary school used exclusively or principally for the provision of career and technical education to individuals who are available for study in preparation for entering the labor market;

(B) the department of a public secondary school exclusively or principally used for providing career and technical education in not fewer than 3 different fields that are available to all students, especially in high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations;

(C) a public or nonprofit technical institution or career and technical education school used exclusively or principally for the provision of career and technical education to individuals who have completed or left secondary school and who are available for study in preparation for entering the labor market, if the institution or school admits, as regular students, individuals who have completed secondary school and individuals who have left secondary school; or

(D) the department or division of an institution of higher education, that operates under the policies of the eligible agency and that provides career and technical education in not fewer than 3 different occupational fields leading to immediate employment but n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administration The term “administration”, when used with respect to an eligible agency or eligible recipient, means activities necessary for the proper and efficient performance of the eligible agency or eligible recipient’s duties under this chapter, including the supervision of such activities. Such term does not include curriculum development activities, personnel development, or research activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>All aspects of an industry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) All aspects of an industry The term “all aspects of an industry” means strong experience in, and comprehensive understanding of, the industry that the individual is preparing to enter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Area career and technical education school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Area career and technical education school The term “area career and technical education school” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Articulation agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Articulation agreement The term “articulation agreement” means a written commitment—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Career and technical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Career and technical education The term “career and technical education” means organized educational activities that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Career and technical student organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Career and technical student organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Career guidance and academic counseling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Career guidance and academic counseling The term “career guidance and academic counseling” means guidance and counseling that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Career pathways</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Career pathways The term “career pathways” has the meaning given the term in section 3102 of title 29.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Charter school The term “charter school” has the meaning given the term in section 7221i of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2302_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Cooperative education The term “cooperative education” means a method of education for individuals who, through written cooperative arrangements between a school and employers, receive instruction, including required rigorous and challenging academic courses and related career and technical education instruction, by alternation of study in school with a job in any occupational field, which alternation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>