<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2306a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2306a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2306a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2306a"><akn:num>2306a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2306a. Prohibitions(a) Local controlNothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government—(1) to condition or incentivize the receipt of any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, or the receipt of any priority or preference under such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, upon a State, local educational agency, eligible agency, eligible recipient, eligible entity, or school’s adoption or implementation of specific instructional content, academic standards and assessments, curricula, or program of instruction (including any condition, priority, or preference to adopt the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative, any other academic standards common to a significant number of States, or any assessment, instructional content, or curriculum aligned to such standards);

(2) through grants, contracts, or other cooperative agreements, to mandate, direct, or control a State, local educational agency, eligible agency, eligible recipient, eligible entity, or school’s specific instructional content, academic standards and assessments, curricula, or program of instruction (including any requirement, direction, or mandate to adopt the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative, any other academic standards common to a significant number of States, or any assessment, instructional content, or curriculum aligned to such standards); or

(3) except as required under sections 2322(b), 2391(b), and 2413 of this title—(A) to mandate, direct, or control the allocation of State or local resources; or

(B) to mandate that a State or a political subdivision of a State spend any funds or incur any costs not paid for under this chapter.



(b) No preclusion of other assistanceAny State that declines to submit an application to the Secretary for assistance under this chapter shall not be precluded from applying for assistance under any other p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Local control Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No preclusion of other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No preclusion of other assistance Any State that declines to submit an application to the Secretary for assistance under this chapter shall not be precluded from applying for assistance under any other program administered by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on requiring Federal approval or certification of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on requiring Federal approval or certification of standards Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, no State shall be required to have academic and career and technical content standards or student academic and career and technical achievement standards approved or certified by the Federal Government, in order to receive assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section affects the applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”) or chapter 8 of title 5, commonly 11 So in original. Probably should be “title 5 (commonly”. known as the “Congressional Review Act”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coherent and rigorous content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coherent and rigorous content For the purposes of this chapter, coherent and rigorous content shall be determined by the State consistent with section 6311(b)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2306a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional notice and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Congressional notice and comment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>