<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2308"><akn:num>2308</akn:num><akn:heading>Interdepartmental Task Force on Vocational Education and Related Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2308. Interdepartmental Task Force on Vocational Education and Related Programs(a) EstablishmentThere is established the Interdepartmental Task Force on Vocational Education and Related Programs (in this section referred to as the “Task Force”).


(b) MembershipThe Task Force shall consist of the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and such other personnel of the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Health and Human Services as the Secretaries consider appropriate.


(c) DutiesThe Task Force shall—(1) examine principal data required for programs under the Adult Education Act, the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act, the Job Training Partnership Act, the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.], and the Wagner-Peyser Act [29 U.S.C. 49 et seq.];

(2) examine possible common objectives, definitions, measures, and standards for such programs; and

(3) consider integration of research and development conducted with Federal assistance in the area of vocational education and related areas, including areas of emerging technologies.


(Pub. L. 101–392, § 4, Sept. 25, 1990, 104 Stat. 758; Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1041(f), Dec. 21, 1995, 109 Stat. 715.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Adult Education Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), was title III of Pub. L. 89–750, Nov. 3, 1966, 80 Stat. 1216, which was classified generally to chapter 30 (§ 1201 et seq.) of this title, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–220, title II, § 251(a)(1), Aug. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1079. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Applied Technology Education Act, referred to in subsec. (c)(1), was Pub. L. 88–210, Dec. 18, 1963, 77 Stat. 403, which was classified generally to this chapter, prior to being amended generally and renamed the Carl D. Perkins Vocational and Technical Education Act of 1998 by Pub. L. 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established the Interdepartmental Task Force on Vocational Education and Related Programs (in this section referred to as the “Task Force”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Task Force shall consist of the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and such other personnel of the Department of Education, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Health and Human Services as the Secretaries consider appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Task Force shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>