<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2321"><akn:num>2321</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservations and State allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2321. Reservations and State allotment(a) Reservations and State allotment(1) ReservationsFrom the amount appropriated under section 2307 of this title for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—(A) 0.13 percent to carry out section 2325 of this title; and

(B) 1.50 percent to carry out section 2326 of this title, of which—(i) 1.25 percent of the sum shall be available to carry out section 2326(b) of this title; and

(ii) 0.25 percent of the sum shall be available to carry out section 2326(h) of this title.



(2) Foundational grant(A) In generalFrom the remainder of the amount appropriated under section 2307 of this title and not reserved under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to a State for the fiscal year an amount equal to the amount the State received in fiscal year 2018.


(B) Ratable reductionIf for any fiscal year the amount appropriated for allotments under this section is insufficient to satisfy the provisions of subparagraph (A), the payments to all States under such subparagraph shall be ratably reduced.



(3) Additional fundsSubject to paragraph (4), from the additional funds remaining from the amount appropriated under section 2307 of this title and not expended under paragraphs (1) and (2) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to a State for the fiscal year—(A) an amount that bears the same ratio to 50 percent of the sum being allotted as the product of the population aged 15 to 19, inclusive, in the State in the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made and the State’s allotment ratio bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all the States;

(B) an amount that bears the same ratio to 20 percent of the sum being allotted as the product of the population aged 20 to 24, inclusive, in the State in the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the determination is made and the State’s allotment ratio bears to the sum of the corresponding products for all the States;</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservations and State allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reservations and State allotment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reallotment If the Secretary determines that any amount of any State’s allotment under subsection (a) for any fiscal year will not be required for such fiscal year for carrying out the activities for which such amount has been allotted, the Secretary shall make such amount available for reallotment. Any such reallotment among other States shall occur on such dates during the same year as the Secretary shall fix, and shall be made on the basis of criteria established by regulation. No funds may be reallotted for any use other than the use for which the funds were appropriated. Any amount reallotted to a State under this subsection for any fiscal year shall remain available for obligation during the succeeding fiscal year and shall be deemed to be part of the State’s allotment for the year in which the amount is obligated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment ratio</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allotment ratio</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition of State For the purpose of this section, the term “State” means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>