<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2323"><akn:num>2323</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2323. Accountability(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to establish and support State and local performance accountability systems, comprised of the activities described in this section, to assess the effectiveness of the State and the eligible recipients of the State in achieving statewide progress in career and technical education, and to optimize the return of investment of Federal funds in career and technical education activities.


(b) State determined performance measures(1) In generalEach eligible agency, with input from eligible recipients, shall establish State determined performance measures for a State that consist of—(A) the core indicators of performance described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (2); and

(B) a State determined level of performance described in paragraph (3)(A) for each core indicator of performance.


(2) Indicators of performance(A) Core indicators of performance for CTE concentrators at the secondary levelEach eligible agency shall identify in the State plan core indicators of performance for CTE concentrators at the secondary level that are valid and reliable, and that include, at a minimum, measures of each of the following:(i) The percentage of CTE concentrators who graduate high school, as measured by—(I) the four-year adjusted cohort graduation rate (defined in section 7801 of this title); and

(II) at the State’s discretion, the extended-year adjusted cohort graduation rate defined in such section 7801.


(ii) CTE concentrator proficiency in the challenging State academic standards adopted by the State under section 6311(b)(1) of this title, as measured by the academic assessments described in section 6311(b)(2) of this title.

(iii) The percentage of CTE concentrators who, in the second quarter after exiting from secondary education, are in postsecondary education or advanced training, military service or a service program that receives assistance under title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to establish and support State and local performance accountability systems, comprised of the activities described in this section, to assess the effectiveness of the State and the eligible recipients of the State in achieving statewide progress in career and technical education, and to optimize the return of investment of Federal funds in career and technical education activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State determined performance measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State determined performance measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>