<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2351"><akn:num>2351</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of funds to secondary education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2351. Distribution of funds to secondary education programs(a) Distribution rulesExcept as provided in section 2353 of this title and as otherwise provided in this section, each eligible agency shall distribute the portion of funds made available under section 2322(a)(1) of this title to carry out this section to local educational agencies within the State as follows:(1) Thirty percentThirty percent shall be allocated to such local educational agencies in proportion to the number of individuals aged 5 through 17, inclusive, who reside in the school district served by such local educational agency for the preceding fiscal year compared to the total number of such individuals who reside in the school districts served by all local educational agencies in the State for such preceding fiscal year, as determined on the basis of the most recent satisfactory—(A) data provided to the Secretary by the Bureau of the Census for the purpose of determining eligibility under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.]; or

(B) student membership data collected by the National Center for Education Statistics through the Common Core of Data survey system.


(2) Seventy percentSeventy percent shall be allocated to such local educational agencies in proportion to the number of individuals aged 5 through 17, inclusive, who reside in the school district served by such local educational agency and are from families below the poverty level for the preceding fiscal year, as determined on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data used under section 1124(c)(1)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6333(c)(1)(A)], compared to the total number of such individuals who reside in the school districts served by all the local educational agencies in the State for such preceding fiscal year.


(3) AdjustmentsEach eligible agency, in making the allocations under paragraphs (1) and (2), shall adjust the data used to make t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distribution rules Except as provided in section 2353 of this title and as otherwise provided in this section, each eligible agency shall distribute the portion of funds made available under section 2322(a)(1) of this title to carry out this section to local educational agencies within the State as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver for more equitable distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver for more equitable distribution The Secretary may waive the application of subsection (a) in the case of any eligible agency that submits to the Secretary an application for such a waiver that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Minimum allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited jurisdiction agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limited jurisdiction agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations to area career and technical education schools and educational service agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocations to area career and technical education schools and educational service agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortium requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consortium requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Data The Secretary shall collect information from eligible agencies regarding the specific dollar allocations made available by the eligible agency for career and technical education programs and programs of study under subsections (a), (b), (c), (d), and (e) and how these allocations are distributed to local educational agencies, area career and technical education schools, and educational service agencies, within the State in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special rule Each eligible agency distributing funds under this section shall treat a secondary school funded by the Bureau of Indian Education within the State as if such school were a local educational agency within the State for the purpose of receiving a distribution under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>