<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2353" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2353/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2353/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2353"><akn:num>2353</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for career and technical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2353. Special rules for career and technical education(a) Special rule for minimal allocation(1) General authorityNotwithstanding the provisions of sections 2351 and 2352 of this title and in order to make a more equitable distribution of funds for programs serving the areas of greatest economic need, for any program year for which a minimal amount is made available by an eligible agency for distribution under section 2351 or 2352 of this title, such eligible agency may distribute such minimal amount for such year—(A) on a competitive basis; or

(B) through any alternative method determined by the eligible agency.


(2) Minimal amountFor purposes of this section, the term “minimal amount” means not more than 15 percent of the total amount made available for distribution under section 2322(a)(1) of this title.



(b) Redistribution(1) In generalIn any academic year that an eligible recipient does not expend all of the amounts the eligible recipient is allocated for such year under section 2351 or 2352 of this title, such eligible recipient shall return any unexpended amounts to the eligible agency to be reallocated under section 2351 or 2352 of this title, as appropriate.


(2) Redistribution of amounts returned late in an academic yearIn any academic year in which amounts are returned to the eligible agency under section 2351 or 2352 of this title and the eligible agency is unable to reallocate such amounts according to such sections in time for such amounts to be expended in such academic year, the eligible agency shall retain such amounts for distribution in combination with amounts provided under section 2322(a)(1) of this title for the following academic year.



(c) ConstructionNothing in section 2351 or 2352 of this title shall be construed—(1) to prohibit a local educational agency or a consortium thereof that receives assistance under section 2351 of this title, from working with an eligible institution or consortium thereof that receives assistance under </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2353_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for minimal allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Special rule for minimal allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2353_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Redistribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Redistribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2353_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Construction Nothing in section 2351 or 2352 of this title shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2353_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistent application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consistent application For purposes of this section, the eligible agency shall provide funds to charter schools offering career and technical education programs or programs of study in the same manner as the eligible agency provides those funds to other schools. Such career and technical education programs or programs of study within a charter school shall be of sufficient size, scope, and quality to be effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>