<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2399" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2399/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2399/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2399"><akn:num>2399</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on programs of study aligned to high-skill, high-wage occupations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2399. Study on programs of study aligned to high-skill, high-wage occupations(a) Scope of studyThe Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to evaluate—(1) the strategies, components, policies, and practices used by eligible agencies or eligible recipients receiving funding under this chapter to successfully assist—(A) all students in pursuing and completing programs of study aligned to high-skill, high-wage occupations; and

(B) any special population or specific subgroup of students identified in section 6311(h)(1)(C)(ii) of this title in pursuing and completing programs of study aligned to high-skill, high-wage occupations in fields in which such special population or subgroup is underrepresented; and


(2) any challenges associated with replication of such strategies, components, policies, and practices.


(b) ConsultationIn carrying out the study conducted under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall consult with a geographically diverse (including urban, suburban, and rural) representation of—(1) students and parents;

(2) eligible agencies and eligible recipients;

(3) teachers, faculty, specialized instructional support personnel, and paraprofessionals, including those with expertise in preparing career and technical education students for non-traditional fields;

(4) Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations;

(5) special populations; and

(6) representatives of business and industry.


(c) SubmissionUpon completion, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit the study conducted under subsection (a) to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.


(Pub. L. 88–210, title II, § 219, as added Pub. L. 115–224, title II, § 201(a)(8), July 31, 2018, 132 Stat. 1621.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsPrior sections 2401 to 2404 were omitted in the general amendment of this chapter by Pub. L. 105–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2399_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scope of study The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to evaluate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2399_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In carrying out the study conducted under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall consult with a geographically diverse (including urban, suburban, and rural) representation of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2399_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission Upon completion, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit the study conducted under subsection (a) to the Committee on Education and the Workforce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>