<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2502" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2502/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/2502/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2502"><akn:num>2502</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2502. Funding requirements(a) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of this subchapter $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1978. The provisions of section 1226a 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall not apply to the authorization made by this subsection.


(b) Availability of amounts appropriated; allotments to States, etc.(1) From the sums appropriated under this subchapter, the Secretary of Education shall reserve an amount not to exceed $2,000,000, for the purpose of carrying out section 2505 of this title.

(2) From the remainder of the sums appropriated under this subchapter, the Secretary of Education shall reserve such amount, not to exceed 1 per centum thereof, as he may determine necessary and shall allot such amount among the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, according to their relative need for assistance under this subchapter.

(3)(A) Of the remainder of the sums appropriated, the Secretary of Education shall allot to each State $100,000, and of the remainder of the sums appropriated the Secretary of Education shall allot to each State an amount which bears the same ratio to such sums for such year as the population of the State bears to the population of all States, for purposes of carrying out section 2501 of this title.

(B) For purposes of this paragraph, the term “State” means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.



(c) Federal shareThe Federal share of funds allotted to States under this subchapter shall not exceed 80 per centum of the total cost of the planning undertaken pursuant to this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 94–482, title III, § 332, Oct. 12, 1976, 90 Stat. 2222; Pub. L. 95–207, § 16, Dec. 13, 1977, 91 Stat. 1474; Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 301(a)(1), title V, § 507, Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 677, 692.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1226a of this title, referred to i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2502_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for the purpose of this subchapter $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1978. The provisions of section 1226a 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall not apply to the authorization made by this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2502_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of amounts appropriated; allotments to States, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of amounts appropriated; allotments to States, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2502_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal share The Federal share of funds allotted to States under this subchapter shall not exceed 80 per centum of the total cost of the planning undertaken pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>