<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3441"><akn:num>3441</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers from Department of Health, Education, and Welfare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3441. Transfers from Department of Health, Education, and Welfare(a) Functions transferred to SecretaryThere are transferred to the Secretary—(1) all functions of the Assistant Secretary for Education and of the Commissioner of Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, and all functions of the Office of such Assistant Secretary and of the Education Division of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare and of any officer or component of such Office or Division;

(2) all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare and of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare under—(A) the General Education Provisions Act [20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.];

(B) the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;

(C) the Higher Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.];

(D) the Education Amendments of 1978;

(E) the Act of August 30, 1890 (7 U.S.C. 321–328);

(F) the National Defense Education Act of 1958;

(G) the International Education Act of 1966;

(H) the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.];

(I) part B of title V of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2929 et seq.];

(J) the National Commission on Libraries and Information Science Act;

(K) the Vocational Education Act of 1963;

(L) the Career Education Incentive Act;

(M) laws relating to the relationship between (i) Gallaudet College, Howard University, the American Printing House for the Blind, and the National Technical Institute for the Deaf, and (ii) the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare;

(N) the Model Secondary School for the Deaf Act;

(O) subpart A[C] of part IV of title III of the Communications Act of 1934 [47 U.S.C. 395 et seq.] with respect to the telecommunications demonstration program;

(P) section 550 of title 40 with respect to donations of surplus property for educational purposes; and

(Q) the Alcohol and Drug Abuse Education Act;


(3) all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions transferred to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Functions transferred to Secretary There are transferred to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offices, etc., transferred to Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Offices, etc., transferred to Department There are transferred to the Department—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative functions transferred to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative functions transferred to Secretary There are transferred to the Secretary all functions of the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare, the Assistant Secretary for Education, or the Commissioner of Education of the Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, as the case may be, with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of functions relating to Project Head Start</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reservation of functions relating to Project Head Start Nothing in the provisions of this section or in the provisions of this chapter shall authorize the transfer of functions under part A of title V of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2928 et seq.], relating to Project Head Start, from the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>