<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3445" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3445/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3445/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3445"><akn:num>3445</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers from Department of Justice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3445. Transfers from Department of Justice
There are transferred to the Secretary all functions of the Attorney General and of the Law Enforcement Assistance Administration with regard to the student loan and grant programs known as the law enforcement education program and the law enforcement intern program authorized by subsections (b), (c), and (f) of section 406 11 See References in Text note below. of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.
(Pub. L. 96–88, title III, § 304, formerly § 305, Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 680; renumbered § 304, Pub. L. 103–382, title II, § 271(a)(2), Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 3929.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 406 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, referred to in text, is section 406 of title I of Pub. L. 90–351, June 19, 1968, 82 Stat. 204, which was classified to section 3746 of Title 42, The Public Health and Welfare. Title I of the Act was amended generally by Pub. L. 96–157, § 2, Dec. 27, 1979, 93 Stat. 1167, and provisions formerly contained in section 406 of the Act were contained in section 705 of part G of title I of the Act, which was classified to section 3775 of Title 42. Subsequently, part G of title I of the Act was amended generally by Pub. L. 98–473, title II, § 609A(a), Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 2090, and, as so amended, did not contain a section 705 or similar provisions.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 304 of Pub. L. 96–88 was renumbered section 303 and is classified to section 3444 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>