<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3479" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3479/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3479/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3479"><akn:num>3479</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3479. Use of facilities(a) Federal, State, local and foreign government facilitiesWith their consent, the Secretary may, with or without reimbursement, use the research, equipment, services, and facilities of any agency or instrumentality of the United States, of any State or political subdivision thereof, or of any foreign government, in carrying out any function of the Secretary or the Department.


(b) Public and private permitteesThe Secretary is authorized to permit public and private agencies, corporations, associations, organizations, or individuals to use any real property, or any facilities, structures, or other improvements thereon, under the custody and control of the Secretary for Department purposes. The Secretary shall permit the use of such property, facilities, structures, or improvements under such terms and rates and for such period as may be in the public interest, except that the periods of such uses may not exceed five years. The Secretary may require permittees under this section to recondition and maintain, at their own expense, the real property, facilities, structures, and improvements used by such permittees to a standard satisfactory to the Secretary. This subsection shall not apply to excess property as defined in section 102(3) of title 40.


(c) Appropriation credits and refundsProceeds from reimbursements under this section may be credited to the appropriation of funds that bear or will bear all or part of the cost of such equipment or facilities provided or to refund excess sums when necessary.


(d) Interests in real propertyAny interest in real property acquired pursuant to this chapter shall be acquired in the name of the United States Government.


(Pub. L. 96–88, title IV, § 419, Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 686; Pub. L. 99–145, title XII, § 1204(a)(2), Nov. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 720.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
“Section 102(3) of title 40” substituted in subsec. (b) for “section 3(e) of the Federal Property and Administrative Servic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3479_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal, State, local and foreign government facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal, State, local and foreign government facilities With their consent, the Secretary may, with or without reimbursement, use the research, equipment, services, and facilities of any agency or instrumentality of the United States, of any State or political subdivision thereof, or of any foreign government, in carrying out any function of the Secretary or the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3479_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public and private permittees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public and private permittees The Secretary is authorized to permit public and private agencies, corporations, associations, organizations, or individuals to use any real property, or any facilities, structures, or other improvements thereon, under the custody and control of the Secretary for Department purposes. The Secretary shall permit the use of such property, facilities, structures, or improvements under such terms and rates and for such period as may be in the public interest, except that the periods of such uses may not exceed five years. The Secretary may require permittees under this section to recondition and maintain, at their own expense, the real property, facilities, structures, and improvements used by such permittees to a standard satisfactory to the Secretary. This subsection shall not apply to excess property as defined in section 102(3) of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3479_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation credits and refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriation credits and refunds Proceeds from reimbursements under this section may be credited to the appropriation of funds that bear or will bear all or part of the cost of such equipment or facilities provided or to refund excess sums when necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3479_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interests in real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Interests in real property Any interest in real property acquired pursuant to this chapter shall be acquired in the name of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>