<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3602"><akn:num>3602</akn:num><akn:heading>Asbestos Hazards School Safety Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3602. Asbestos Hazards School Safety Task Force(a) Establishment; composition; membership; chairman; appointment; vacancies(1) There is established a task force to be known as the Asbestos Hazards School Safety Task Force (hereinafter in this chapter referred to as “Task Force”). The Task Force shall be composed of ten members, who shall be appointed by the Secretary within 30 days after June 14, 1980, as follows:(A) One representative of the Department of Education, recommended by the Secretary of Education.

(B) One representative of the Department of Health and Human Services.

(C) One representative of the National Cancer Institute.

(D) One representative of the Environmental Protection Agency, recommended by the Administrator of such agency.

(E) One representative of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences.

(F) One representative of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration, recommended by the Secretary of Labor.

(G) Four representatives from among organizations concerned with education and health.


Members of the Task Force shall be individuals who have knowledge of the medical problems associated with exposure to asbestos, or individuals who are familiar with procedures for the following activities: the containment or removal of asbestos from buildings; the replacement of asbestos materials removed from school buildings with other appropriate building materials; and the restoration of such buildings to conditions comparable to those existing before such containment or removal was carried out.

(2) The Secretary shall designate a chairman of the Task Force from among its members.

(3) Members shall be appointed for the life of the Task Force. Any vacancy in the Task Force shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.


(b) Meetings; quorum; hearings(1) The Task Force shall meet, no later than 30 days after the appointment of its members, at the call of the chairman of the Task Force.

(2) Five mem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; composition; membership; chairman; appointment; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; composition; membership; chairman; appointment; vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings; quorum; hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Meetings; quorum; hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation; travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation; travel expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of Department of Education personnel; use of mails</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of Department of Education personnel; use of mails</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties The duties of the Task Force shall include— In carrying out its duties under this subsection, the Task Force shall avoid, to the maximum extent practicable, duplicating similar activities undertaken by the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3602_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination The Task Force shall cease to exist at the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date that the authority of the Secretary to make loans under section 3605 of this title has expired.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>