<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/3912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3912"><akn:num>3912</akn:num><akn:heading>Functional objectives; uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3912. Functional objectives; uses of funds(a) In carrying out its science and engineering education responsibilities, the Foundation shall have the following functional objectives: public understanding of science and technology, faculty enhancement, student education and training, instructional development and instrumentation, and materials development and dissemination.

(b) Funds under this subchapter shall, consistent with such functional objectives, be used for—(1) enhancement of public understanding of science and engineering through informal education activities using a variety of mediums such as broadcasting, museums, clubs, and amateur science societies;

(2) development of new science and engineering faculty resources and talents;

(3) enhancement of the quality of science and engineering instruction in colleges of teacher education;

(4) development of four-year college faculty and instructors in high technology fields;

(5) development of two-year community college faculty and instructors especially in high technology fields;

(6) development of precollege mathematics, science and engineering education and training;

(7) encouragement of potential students, including underrepresented and underserved populations, to pursue careers in mathematics, science, engineering, and critical foreign languages;

(8) development of instructional instrumentation and systems for postsecondary technical, engineering, and scientific education; and

(9) development of science, engineering, and education networks to aid in the development and dissemination of successful curricula, methods, and materials.


(Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 102, as added Pub. L. 99–159, title II, § 201, Nov. 22, 1985, 99 Stat. 894.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 3912, Pub. L. 98–377, title I, § 102, Aug. 11, 1984, 98 Stat. 1268, related to submission, contents, etc., of applications, prior to the general revision of this subchapter by section 201 of Pub. L. 99–159.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In carrying out its science and engineering education responsibilities, the Foundation shall have the following functional objectives: public understanding of science and technology, faculty enhancement, student education and training, instructional development and instrumentation, and materials development and dissemination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funds under this subchapter shall, consistent with such functional objectives, be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>