<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4071"><akn:num>4071</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of equal access prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4071. Denial of equal access prohibited(a) Restriction of limited open forum on basis of religious, political, philosophical, or other speech content prohibitedIt shall be unlawful for any public secondary school which receives Federal financial assistance and which has a limited open forum to deny equal access or a fair opportunity to, or discriminate against, any students who wish to conduct a meeting within that limited open forum on the basis of the religious, political, philosophical, or other content of the speech at such meetings.


(b) “Limited open forum” definedA public secondary school has a limited open forum whenever such school grants an offering to or opportunity for one or more noncurriculum related student groups to meet on school premises during noninstructional time.


(c) Fair opportunity criteriaSchools shall be deemed to offer a fair opportunity to students who wish to conduct a meeting within its limited open forum if such school uniformly provides that—(1) the meeting is voluntary and student-initiated;

(2) there is no sponsorship of the meeting by the school, the government, or its agents or employees;

(3) employees or agents of the school or government are present at religious meetings only in a nonparticipatory capacity;

(4) the meeting does not materially and substantially interfere with the orderly conduct of educational activities within the school; and

(5) nonschool persons may not direct, conduct, control, or regularly attend activities of student groups.


(d) Construction of subchapter with respect to certain rightsNothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof—(1) to influence the form or content of any prayer or other religious activity;

(2) to require any person to participate in prayer or other religious activity;

(3) to expend public funds beyond the incidental cost of providing the space for student-initiated meetings;

(4) to compel any school</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction of limited open forum on basis of religious, political, philosophical, or other speech content prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Restriction of limited open forum on basis of religious, political, philosophical, or other speech content prohibited It shall be unlawful for any public secondary school which receives Federal financial assistance and which has a limited open forum to deny equal access or a fair opportunity to, or discriminate against, any students who wish to conduct a meeting within that limited open forum on the basis of the religious, political, philosophical, or other content of the speech at such meetings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Limited open forum” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Limited open forum” defined A public secondary school has a limited open forum whenever such school grants an offering to or opportunity for one or more noncurriculum related student groups to meet on school premises during noninstructional time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fair opportunity criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Fair opportunity criteria Schools shall be deemed to offer a fair opportunity to students who wish to conduct a meeting within its limited open forum if such school uniformly provides that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of subchapter with respect to certain rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction of subchapter with respect to certain rights Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize the United States or any State or political subdivision thereof—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal financial assistance to schools unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal financial assistance to schools unaffected Notwithstanding the availability of any other remedy under the Constitution or the laws of the United States, nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to authorize the United States to deny or withhold Federal financial assistance to any school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of schools with respect to order, discipline, well-being, and attendance concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority of schools with respect to order, discipline, well-being, and attendance concerns Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed to limit the authority of the school, its agents or employees, to maintain order and discipline on school premises, to protect the well-being of students and faculty, and to assure that attendance of students at meetings is voluntary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>