<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4355" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4355/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4355/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4355"><akn:num>4355</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring, evaluation, and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4355. Monitoring, evaluation, and reporting(a) ActivitiesThe Secretary shall conduct monitoring and evaluation activities of the education programs and activities and the administrative operations of the University (including the elementary, secondary, undergraduate, and graduate programs) and of NTID. The Secretary may also conduct studies related to the provision of preschool, elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education and other related services to individuals who are deaf or hard of hearing. In carrying out the responsibilities described in this section, the Secretary is authorized to employ such consultants as may be necessary pursuant to section 3109 of title 5.


(b) ReportThe Secretary shall annually transmit information to Congress on the monitoring and evaluation activities pursuant to subsection (a), together with such recommendations, including recommendations for legislation, as the Secretary may consider necessary.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014 to carry out the monitoring and evaluation activities authorized under this section.


(Pub. L. 99–371, title II, § 205, formerly title IV, § 405, Aug. 4, 1986, 100 Stat. 790; renumbered title II, § 205, and amended Pub. L. 102–421, title I, §§ 101(b)(5), (6), 135(a), Oct. 16, 1992, 106 Stat. 2151, 2158; Pub. L. 103–73, title II, § 204(d), Aug. 11, 1993, 107 Stat. 735; Pub. L. 105–244, title IX, § 918, Oct. 7, 1998, 112 Stat. 1831; Pub. L. 110–315, title IX, § 907, Aug. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 3453.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2008—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 110–315, § 907(1), struck out “preparatory,” before “undergraduate”.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 110–315, § 907(2), substituted “The Secretary shall annually transmit information to Congress on” for “The Secretary, as part of the annual report required under section 3486 of this title, shall include a description of”.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 110–3</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4355_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Activities The Secretary shall conduct monitoring and evaluation activities of the education programs and activities and the administrative operations of the University (including the elementary, secondary, undergraduate, and graduate programs) and of NTID. The Secretary may also conduct studies related to the provision of preschool, elementary, secondary, and postsecondary education and other related services to individuals who are deaf or hard of hearing. In carrying out the responsibilities described in this section, the Secretary is authorized to employ such consultants as may be necessary pursuant to section 3109 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4355_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report The Secretary shall annually transmit information to Congress on the monitoring and evaluation activities pursuant to subsection (a), together with such recommendations, including recommendations for legislation, as the Secretary may consider necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4355_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2014 to carry out the monitoring and evaluation activities authorized under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>