<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4414" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4414/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4414/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4414"><akn:num>4414</akn:num><akn:heading>General powers of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4414. General powers of Board(a) In generalIn carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Board shall have the power, consistent with the provisions of this chapter—(1) to adopt, use, and alter a corporate seal;

(2) to make agreements and contracts with persons, Indian tribes, and private or governmental entities and to make payments or advance payments under such agreements or contract 11 So in original. Probably should be “contracts”. without regard to section 3324 of title 31;

(3) any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, to enter into joint development ventures with public or private commercial or noncommercial entities for development of facilities to meet the plan required under section 4426 of this title, if the ventures are related to and further the mission of the Institute;

(4) to sue and be sued in its corporate name and to complain and defend in any court of competent jurisdiction;

(5) to represent itself, or to contract for representation, in all judicial, legal, and other proceedings;

(6) with the approval of the agency concerned, to make use of services, facilities, and property of any board, commission, independent establishment, or executive agency or department of the executive branch in carrying out the provisions of this chapter and to pay for such use (such payments to be credited to the applicable appropriation that incurred the expense);

(7) to use the United States mails on the same terms and conditions as the executive departments of the United States Government;

(8) to obtain the services of experts and consultants in accordance with the provisions of section 3109 of title 5 and to accept and utilize the services of voluntary and noncompensated personnel and reimburse them for travel expenses, including per diem, as authorized by section 5703 of title 5;

(9) to solicit, accept, and dispose of gifts, bequests, devises of money, securities, and other properties of whatever character, for the benefit of the Ins</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4414_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Board shall have the power, consistent with the provisions of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4414_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounting for non-Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accounting for non-Federal funds Any funds received by, or under the control of, the Institute that are not Federal funds shall be accounted for separately from Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4414_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest and investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interest and investments Interest and earnings on amounts received by the Institute pursuant to section 4451 of this title invested under subsection (a)(12) 22 See References in Text note below. shall be the property of the Institute and shall be expended to carry out this chapter. The Board shall be held to a reasonable and prudent standard of care, given such information and circumstances as existed when the decision is made, in decisions involving investment of funds under subsection (a)(12).2</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>