<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4421"><akn:num>4421</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4421. Transfer of functions(a) Institute of American Indian ArtsThere are hereby transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Art Development, and such Institute shall perform, the functions of the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962.


(b) Certain matters relating to transferred functions(1) Subject to subsection (d), all personnel, liabilities, contracts, real property (including the collections of the museum located on the site known as the “Santa Fe Indian School” but not the museum building), personal property, assets, and records as are determined by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to be employed, held, or used primarily in connection with any function transferred under the provisions of this chapter (regardless of the administrative entity providing the services on the date before the transfer) shall be transferred to the Institute.

(2) Personnel engaged in functions transferred by this chapter shall be transferred in accordance with applicable laws and regulations relating to the transfer of functions, except that such transfer shall be without reduction in classification or compensation for one year after such transfer.


(c) References in other lawsAll laws and regulations relating to the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962 shall, insofar as such laws and regulations are appropriate, and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, remain in full force and effect and apply with respect to the Institute. All references in any other Federal law to the Institute of American Indian Arts, or any officer transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development under subsection (b), shall be deemed to refer to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development or an officer of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development.


(d) Fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institute of American Indian Arts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Institute of American Indian Arts There are hereby transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Art Development, and such Institute shall perform, the functions of the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain matters relating to transferred functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain matters relating to transferred functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4421_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>References in other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) References in other laws All laws and regulations relating to the Institute of American Indian Arts established by the Secretary in 1962 shall, insofar as such laws and regulations are appropriate, and not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, remain in full force and effect and apply with respect to the Institute. All references in any other Federal law to the Institute of American Indian Arts, or any officer transferred to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development under subsection (b), shall be deemed to refer to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development or an officer of the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4421_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forgiveness of amounts owed; hold harmless</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Forgiveness of amounts owed; hold harmless</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>