<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4425" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4425/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4425/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4425"><akn:num>4425</akn:num><akn:heading>Endowment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4425. Endowment programs(a) Program enhancement endowment(1)(A) From the total amount appropriated for this subsection pursuant to section 4451(a) of this title, funds may be deposited into a trust fund maintained by the Institute at a federally insured banking or savings institution.

(B) The President of the Institute shall provide—(i) for the deposit into the trust fund referred to in subparagraph (A)—(I) of a capital contribution by the Institute in an amount equal to the amount of each Federal contribution; and

(II) any earnings on the funds deposited under this paragraph; or


(ii) for the reservation for the sole use of the Institute of any noncash, in-kind contributions of real or personal property, which property may at any time be converted to cash, which shall be deposited as a capital contribution into the trust fund referred to in subparagraph (A).


(C) If at any time the Institute withdraws any capital contribution (as described in subparagraph (B)(i)) made by the Institute to the trust fund referred to in subparagraph (A) or puts any property (as described in subparagraph (B)(ii)) to a use which is not for the sole benefit of the Institute, an amount equal to the value of the Federal contribution shall be withdrawn from such trust fund and returned to the Treasury as miscellaneous receipts.


(2) Interest deposited into the trust fund pursuant to paragraph (1)(B)(ii) may be periodically withdrawn and used, at the direction of the Board or its designee, to defray any expense associated with the operation of the Institute, including the expense of operations and maintenance, administration, academic and support personnel, community and student services programs, and technical assistance.

(3) For the purpose of complying with the contribution requirement of paragraph (1)(B), the Institute may use funds or in-kind contributions of real or personal property fairly valued which are made available from any private or tribal source, including interest ea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4425_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program enhancement endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program enhancement endowment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4425_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital improvement endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Capital improvement endowment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4425_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General administrative provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>