<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4441"><akn:num>4441</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for Native Hawaiian and Alaska Native culture and arts development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4441. Program for Native Hawaiian and Alaska Native culture and arts development(a) In generalThe Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make grants for the purpose of supporting programs for Native Hawaiian or Alaska Native culture and arts development to any private, nonprofit organization or institution which—(1) primarily serves and represents Native Hawaiians or Alaska Natives, and

(2) has been recognized by the Governor of the State of Hawaii or the Governor of the State of Alaska, as appropriate, for the purpose of making such organization or institution eligible to receive such grants.


(b) Purpose of grantsGrants made under subsection (a) shall, to the extent deemed possible by the Secretary and the recipient of the grant, be used—(1) to provide scholarly study of, and instruction in, Native Hawaiian or Alaska Native art and culture,

(2) to establish programs which culminate in the awarding of degrees in the various fields of Native Hawaiian or Alaska Native art and culture, or

(3) to establish centers and programs with respect to Native Hawaiian or Alaska Native art and culture that are similar in purpose to the centers and programs described in subsections (b) and (c) of section 4417 of this title.


(c) Management of grants(1) Any organization or institution which is the recipient of a grant made under subsection (a) shall establish a governing board to manage and control the program with respect to which such grant is made.

(2) For any grants made with respect to Native Hawaiian art and culture, the members of the governing board which is required to be established under paragraph (1) shall—(A) be Native Hawaiians or individuals widely recognized in the field of Native Hawaiian art and culture,

(B) include a representative of the Office of Hawaiian Affairs of the State of Hawaii,

(C) include the president of the University of Hawaii,

(D) include the president of the Bishop Museum, and

(E) serve for a fixed term of office.


(3) For any gr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of the Interior is authorized to make grants for the purpose of supporting programs for Native Hawaiian or Alaska Native culture and arts development to any private, nonprofit organization or institution which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of grants Grants made under subsection (a) shall, to the extent deemed possible by the Secretary and the recipient of the grant, be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Management of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>