<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4704" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4704/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/4704/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4704"><akn:num>4704</akn:num><akn:heading>Barry Goldwater scholarship and excellence in education awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4704. Barry Goldwater scholarship and excellence in education awards(a) Award of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships(1) The Foundation may award scholarships, fellowships, and research internships to eligible persons for study in the fields of the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics. Such scholarships, fellowships, and research internships shall be awarded to persons as provided in this chapter who meet the minimum criteria established by the Foundation.

(2) Scholarships shall be awarded to outstanding undergraduate students who intend to pursue careers in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics, which shall be prioritized for students attending community colleges and minority-serving institutions specified in section 1067q(a) of this title.

(3) Fellowships shall be awarded to outstanding graduate students who intend to pursue advanced degrees in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics.

(4) Research internships shall be awarded to outstanding undergraduate students who intend to pursue careers in the natural sciences, engineering, and mathematics, which shall be prioritized for students attending community colleges and minority-serving institutions specified in section 1067q(a) of this title.

(5) The Foundation may provide, directly or by contract, for the conduct of nationwide competition for the purpose of selecting recipients of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships awarded under this chapter.


(b) Barry Goldwater Scholars and Research InternsRecipients of scholarships and fellowships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Scholars”. Recipients of research internships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Interns”.


(c) Award of honoraria to volunteers(1) The Foundation may award honoraria to outstanding educators, teachers, and persons who have volunteered to assist in secondary schools who have made significant contributions to improve the quality of instructio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4704_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Award of scholarships, fellowships, and research internships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4704_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Barry Goldwater Scholars and Research Interns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Barry Goldwater Scholars and Research Interns Recipients of scholarships and fellowships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Scholars”. Recipients of research internships under this chapter shall be known as “Barry Goldwater Interns”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4704_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of honoraria to volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award of honoraria to volunteers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>