<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/50" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/50/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/50/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50"><akn:num>50</akn:num><akn:heading>Reception and arrangement of specimens and objects of art</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50. Reception and arrangement of specimens and objects of art
Whenever suitable arrangements can be made from time to time for their reception, all objects of art and of foreign and curious research, and all objects of natural history, plants, and geological and mineralogical specimens belonging to the United States, which may be in the city of Washington, in whosesoever custody they may be, shall be delivered to such persons as may be authorized by the Board of Regents to receive them, and shall be so arranged and classified in the building erected for the institution as best to facilitate the examination and study of them; and whenever new specimens in natural history, geology, or mineralogy are obtained for the museum of the institution, by exchanges of duplicate specimens, which the Regents may in their discretion make, or by donation, which they may receive, or otherwise, the Regents shall cause such new specimens to be appropriately classed and arranged. The minerals, books, manuscripts, and other property of James Smithson, which have been received by the Government of the United States, shall be preserved separate and apart from other property of the institution.
(R.S. § 5586.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
R.S. § 5586 derived from act Aug. 10, 1846, ch. 178, § 6, 9 Stat. 105.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Laboratory Space, Gamboa, PanamaPub. L. 111–11, title XV, § 15102, Mar. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 1456, provided that:
“(a) Authority To Construct.—The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution is authorized to construct laboratory space to accommodate the terrestrial research program of the Smithsonian tropical research institute in Gamboa, Panama.

“(b) Authorization of Appropriations.—There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section a total of $14,000,000 for fiscal years 2009 and 2010. Such sums shall remain available until expended.”




Veritas Astrophysical Observatory Project; Authorization of Construction and Appropri</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>