<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5205" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5205/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5205/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5205"><akn:num>5205</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of income on endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5205. Use of income on endowment(a), (b) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)] [title IV, § 407], Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321, 1321–45; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a), May 2, 1996, 110 Stat. 1327

(c) Agricultural exchange programFor any fiscal year, as may be determined by Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, a portion of the amounts made available to Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, pursuant to section 5203(a) of this title shall be used to provide fellowships for agricultural exchange programs for farmers from the United States and foreign countries.


(d) Participation by United States minority populationsIn order to ensure that the United States fellows participating in programs of the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, are representative of the cultural, ethnic, and racial diversity of the American people, of the amounts made available to Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, pursuant to section 5203(a) of this title which are obligated and expended for United States fellowship programs, not less than 10 percent shall be available only for participation by individuals who are representative of United States minority populations.


(Pub. L. 101–454, § 6, Oct. 24, 1990, 104 Stat. 1065; Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)] [title IV, § 407], Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321, 1321–45; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a), May 2, 1996, 110 Stat. 1327.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 104–134 struck out heading and text of subsec. (a). Text read as follows: “For any fiscal year, not less than 50 percent of the amounts made available to Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, pursuant to section 5203(a) of this title shall be available only to assist United States fellows in traveling to and studying in emerging European democracies.”
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 104–134 struck out heading and text of subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “For any fiscal year, not more than 50</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5205_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (b) Repealed. Pub. L. 104–134, title I, § 101[(a)] [title IV, § 407], Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321, 1321–45; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 104–140, § 1(a), May 2, 1996, 110 Stat. 1327</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) , (b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5205_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural exchange program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agricultural exchange program For any fiscal year, as may be determined by Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, a portion of the amounts made available to Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, pursuant to section 5203(a) of this title shall be used to provide fellowships for agricultural exchange programs for farmers from the United States and foreign countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5205_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by United States minority populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Participation by United States minority populations In order to ensure that the United States fellows participating in programs of the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, are representative of the cultural, ethnic, and racial diversity of the American people, of the amounts made available to Eisenhower Exchange Fellowships, Incorporated, pursuant to section 5203(a) of this title which are obligated and expended for United States fellowship programs, not less than 10 percent shall be available only for participation by individuals who are representative of United States minority populations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>