<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5601"><akn:num>5601</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5601. Findings
The Congress finds that—(1) for three decades, Congressman Morris K. Udall has served his country with distinction and honor;

(2) Congressman Morris K. Udall has had a lasting impact on this Nation’s environment, public lands, and natural resources, and has instilled in this Nation’s youth a love of the air, land, and water;

(3) Congressman Morris K. Udall has been a champion of the rights of Native Americans and Alaska Natives and has used his leadership in the Congress to strengthen tribal self-governance;

(4) it is a fitting tribute to the leadership, courage, and vision Congressman Morris K. Udall exemplifies to establish in his name programs to encourage the continued use, enjoyment, education, and exploration of our Nation’s rich and bountiful natural resources;

(5) the Foundation—(A) since 1995, has operated exceptional scholarship, internship, and fellowship programs for areas of study related to the environment and Native American tribal policy and health care;

(B) since 1999, has provided valuable environmental conflict resolution services and leadership through the National Center (previously known as the United States Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution); and

(C) is committed to continue making a substantial contribution toward public policy in the future by—(i) playing a significant role in developing the next generation of environmental and Native American leaders; and

(ii) working with current leaders to improve decisionmaking on—(I) challenging environmental, energy, and related economic problems; and

(II) tribal governance and economic issues;




(6) Stewart L. Udall, as a member of Congress, Secretary of the Interior, environmental lawyer, and author, has provided distinguished national leadership in environmental and Native American policy for more than 50 years;

(7) as Secretary of the Interior from 1961 to 1969, Stewart L. Udall oversaw the creation of 4 national parks, 6 national monuments, 8 national seas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) for three decades, Congressman Morris K. Udall has served his country with distinction and honor;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Congressman Morris K. Udall has had a lasting impact on this Nation’s environment, public lands, and natural resources, and has instilled in this Nation’s youth a love of the air, land, and water;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Congressman Morris K. Udall has been a champion of the rights of Native Americans and Alaska Natives and has used his leadership in the Congress to strengthen tribal self-governance;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) it is a fitting tribute to the leadership, courage, and vision Congressman Morris K. Udall exemplifies to establish in his name programs to encourage the continued use, enjoyment, education, and exploration of our Nation’s rich and bountiful natural resources;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) the Foundation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Stewart L. Udall, as a member of Congress, Secretary of the Interior, environmental lawyer, and author, has provided distinguished national leadership in environmental and Native American policy for more than 50 years;</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) as Secretary of the Interior from 1961 to 1969, Stewart L. Udall oversaw the creation of 4 national parks, 6 national monuments, 8 national seashores and lakeshores, 9 recreation areas, 20 historic sites, and 56 wildlife refuges; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5601_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) it is fitting that the leadership and vision of Stewart L. Udall in the areas of environmental and Native American policy be jointly honored with that of Morris K. Udall through the foundation bearing the Udall name.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>