<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5603" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5603/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5603/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5603"><akn:num>5603</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5603. Establishment of Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation(a) EstablishmentThere is established as an independent entity of the executive branch of the United States Government, the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation.


(b) Board of TrusteesThe Foundation shall be subject to the supervision and direction of the Board of Trustees. The Board shall be comprised of thirteen trustees, eleven of whom shall be voting members of the Board, as follows:(1) Two Trustees, shall be appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, after considering the recommendation of the Speaker of the House of Representatives, in consultation with the Minority Leader of the House of Representatives.

(2) Two Trustees, shall be appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, after considering the recommendation of the President pro tempore of the Senate, in consultation with the Majority and Minority Leaders of the Senate.

(3) Five Trustees, not more than three of whom shall be of the same political party, shall be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate, who have shown leadership and interest in—(A) the continued use, enjoyment, education, and exploration of our Nation’s rich and bountiful natural resources, such as presidents of major foundations involved with the environment; or

(B) in the improvement of the health status of Native Americans and Alaska Natives and in strengthening tribal self-governance, such as tribal leaders involved in health and public policy development affecting Native American and Alaska Native communities.


(4) The Secretary of the Interior, or the Secretary’s designee, who shall serve as a voting ex officio member of the Board but shall not be eligible to serve as Chairperson.

(5) The Secretary of Education, or the Secretary’s designee, who shall serve as a voting ex officio member of the Board but shall not be eligible to serve as Chairperson.

(6) The Presiden</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established as an independent entity of the executive branch of the United States Government, the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board of Trustees The Foundation shall be subject to the supervision and direction of the Board of Trustees. The Board shall be comprised of thirteen trustees, eleven of whom shall be voting members of the Board, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term of office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel and subsistence pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Travel and subsistence pay Trustees shall serve without pay, but shall be entitled to reimbursement for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred in the performance of their duties as members of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Location of Foundation The Foundation shall be located in Tucson, Arizona and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5603_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Executive Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>