<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5605"><akn:num>5605</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5605. Authority of Foundation(a) Authority of Foundation(1) In general(A) General programming authorityThe Foundation is authorized to identify and conduct, directly or by contract, such programs, activities, and services as the Foundation considers appropriate to carry out the purposes described in section 5604 of this title, which may include—(i) awarding scholarships, fellowships, internships, and grants, by national competition, to eligible individuals, as determined by the Foundation and in accordance with paragraphs (2), (3), and (4), for study in fields related to the environment or Native American and Alaska Native health care and tribal policy;

(ii) funding the Center to carry out and manage other programs, activities, and services; and

(iii) other education programs that the Board determines are consistent with the purposes for which the Foundation is established.


(B) John S. McCain III National Center for Environmental Conflict Resolution(i) In generalThe Foundation shall—(I) establish the John S. McCain III National Center for Environmental Conflict Resolution as part of the Foundation; and

(II) identify and conduct such programs, activities, and services as the Foundation determines appropriate to permit the Foundation to provide assessment, mediation, collaboration, training, and other related services to resolve—(aa) environmental disputes; and

(bb) Federal, State, or tribal environmental or natural resource decision-making processes or procedures that may result in a dispute or conflict that may cause or result in disputes.



(ii) Geographic proximity of conflict resolution provisionIn providing assessment, mediation, collaboration, training, and other related services under clause (i)(II) to resolve environmental disputes, the Foundation shall consider, to the maximum extent practicable, conflict resolution providers within the geographic proximity of the conflict.




(2) Scholarships(A) Scholarships shall be awarded to outstanding undergr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Foundation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Udall Scholars</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Udall Scholars Recipients of scholarships, fellowships, and internships under this chapter shall be known as “Udall Scholars”, “Udall Fellows”, and “Udall Interns”, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Donations Any funds received by the Foundation in the form of donations or grants, as well as any unexpended earnings on interest from the Trust Fund that is carried forward from prior years—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>