<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5607a"><akn:num>5607a</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5607a. Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Treasury of the United States an Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund to be administered by the Foundation. The Fund shall consist of amounts appropriated to the Fund under section 5609(b) of this title and amounts paid into the Fund under section 5607b of this title.


(b) ExpendituresThe Foundation shall expend from the Fund such sums as the Board determines are necessary to establish and operate the National Center, including such amounts as are necessary for salaries, administration, the provision of mediation and other services, and such other expenses as the Board determines are necessary, including not to exceed $1,000 annually for official reception and representation expenses.


(c) Distinction from Trust FundThe Fund shall be maintained separately from the Trust Fund established under section 5606 of this title.


(d) Investment of amounts(1) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall invest such portion of the Fund as is not, in the judgment of the Secretary, required to meet current withdrawals.


(2) Interest-bearing obligationsInvestments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States.


(3) Acquisition of obligationsFor the purpose of investments under paragraph (1), obligations may be acquired—(A) on original issue at the issue price; or

(B) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price.


(4) Sale of obligationsAny obligation acquired by the Fund may be sold by the Secretary of the Treasury at the market price.


(5) Credits to FundThe interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Fund.



(Pub. L. 102–259, § 10, as added Pub. L. 105–156, § 6(b), Feb. 11, 1998, 112 Stat. 10; amended Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(h) [title V, § 517(c)], Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–480, 2681–512; Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title III, § 306, Dec. 2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Treasury of the United States an Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund to be administered by the Foundation. The Fund shall consist of amounts appropriated to the Fund under section 5609(b) of this title and amounts paid into the Fund under section 5607b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expenditures The Foundation shall expend from the Fund such sums as the Board determines are necessary to establish and operate the National Center, including such amounts as are necessary for salaries, administration, the provision of mediation and other services, and such other expenses as the Board determines are necessary, including not to exceed $1,000 annually for official reception and representation expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distinction from Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distinction from Trust Fund The Fund shall be maintained separately from the Trust Fund established under section 5606 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Investment of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>