<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5607b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5607b"><akn:num>5607b</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of the National Center by Federal agency or other entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5607b. Use of the National Center by Federal agency or other entity(a) AuthorizationA Federal agency may use the Foundation and the National Center to provide assessment, mediation, collaboration, or other related services in connection with a dispute or conflict related to the environment, public lands, or natural resources, or with a Federal, State, or tribal process or procedure that may result in a dispute or conflict.


(b) Payment(1) In generalA Federal agency may enter into a contract and expend funds to obtain the services of the National Center.


(2) Payment into Environmental Dispute Resolution FundA payment from an executive agency on a contract entered into under paragraph (1) shall be paid into the Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund established under section 5607a of this title.



(c) Notification and concurrence(1) NotificationAn agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government shall notify the chairperson of the President’s Council on Environmental Quality when using the Foundation or the National Center to provide the services described in subsection (a).


(2) Notification descriptionsIn a matter involving two or more agencies or instrumentalities of the Federal Government, notification under paragraph (1) shall include a written description of—(A) the issues and parties involved;

(B) prior efforts, if any, undertaken by the agency to resolve or address the issue or issues;

(C) all Federal agencies or instrumentalities with a direct interest or involvement in the matter and a statement that all Federal agencies or instrumentalities agree to mediation, collaboration, and dispute resolution; and

(D) other relevant information.


(3) Concurrence(A) In generalIn a matter that involves two or more agencies or instrumentalities of the Federal Government (including branches or divisions of a single agency or instrumentality), the agencies or instrumentalities of the Federal Government shall obtain the concurrence of the chairperson of the Pres</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization A Federal agency may use the Foundation and the National Center to provide assessment, mediation, collaboration, or other related services in connection with a dispute or conflict related to the environment, public lands, or natural resources, or with a Federal, State, or tribal process or procedure that may result in a dispute or conflict.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification and concurrence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification and concurrence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Non-Federal entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5607b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency management or control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agency management or control Use of the Foundation or National Center to provide independent and impartial assessment, mediation, or other dispute or conflict resolution under this section shall not be considered to be the establishment or use of an advisory committee within the meaning of chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>