<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5891a"><akn:num>5891a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5891a. Definitions
In this Act:(1) Educational service agency; local educational agency; State educational agency; outlying areaThe terms “educational service agency”, “local educational agency”, “State educational agency”, and “outlying area” have the meanings given the terms in section 7801 of this title.


(2) Eligible school attendance area; school attendance areaThe terms “eligible school attendance area” and “school attendance area” have the meanings given the terms in section 6313(a)(2) of this title.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.


(4) StateThe term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each outlying area.


(Pub. L. 106–25, § 3, Apr. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 42; Pub. L. 107–110, title X, § 1076(o), Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 2092; Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9207(a), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2141.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 106–25, Apr. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 41, known as the Education Flexibility Partnership Act of 1999, which enacted sections 5891a and 5891b of this title, amended section 1415 of this title, and enacted provisions set out as notes under sections 1415 and 5891a of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1999 Amendment note set out under section 5801 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Education Flexibility Partnership Act of 1999, and not as part of the Goals 2000: Educate America Act which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2015—Par. (1). Pub. L. 114–95 substituted “Educational service agency; local” for “Local” in heading and, in text, substituted “The terms ‘educational service agency’,” for “The terms” and made technical amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to section 7801 of this title.
2002—Par. (1). Pub. L. 107–110 substituted “7801” for “8801”.

Statutory Notes and Relate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational service agency; local educational agency; State educational agency; outlying area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Educational service agency; local educational agency; State educational agency; outlying area The terms “educational service agency”, “local educational agency”, “State educational agency”, and “outlying area” have the meanings given the terms in section 7801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible school attendance area; school attendance area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible school attendance area; school attendance area The terms “eligible school attendance area” and “school attendance area” have the meanings given the terms in section 6313(a)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) State The term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each outlying area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>