<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5891b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5891b"><akn:num>5891b</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational flexibility program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5891b. Educational flexibility program(a) Educational flexibility program(1) Program authorized(A) In generalThe Secretary may carry out an educational flexibility program under which the Secretary authorizes a State educational agency that serves an eligible State to waive statutory or regulatory requirements applicable to one or more programs described in subsection (b), other than requirements described in subsection (c), for any local educational agency, educational service agency, or school within the State.


(B) DesignationEach eligible State participating in the program described in subparagraph (A) shall be known as an “Ed-Flex Partnership State”.



(2) Eligible StateFor the purpose of this section, the term “eligible State” means a State that—(A) has—(i) developed and implemented the challenging State academic standards, and aligned assessments, described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1111(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6311(b)], and is producing the report cards required by section 1111(h) of such Act; or

(ii) if the State has adopted new challenging State academic standards under section 1111(b)(1) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, as a result of the amendments made to such Act [20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.] by the Every Student Succeeds Act, made substantial progress (as determined by the Secretary) toward developing and implementing such standards and toward producing the report cards required under section 1111(h) of such Act;


(B) will hold local educational agencies, educational service agencies, and schools accountable for meeting the educational goals described in the local applications submitted under paragraph (4) and for engaging in technical assistance and, as applicable and appropriate, implementing comprehensive support and improvement activities and targeted support and improvement activities under section 1111(d) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; and

(C) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational flexibility program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Educational flexibility program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Included programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Included programs The statutory or regulatory requirements referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A) are any such requirements for programs that are authorized under the following provisions and under which the Secretary provides funds to State educational agencies on the basis of a formula:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers not authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waivers not authorized The Secretary and the State educational agency may not waive under subsection (a)(1)(A) any statutory or regulatory requirement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of existing Ed-Flex Partnership States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of existing Ed-Flex Partnership States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5891b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Publication A notice of the Secretary’s decision to authorize State educational agencies to issue waivers under this section, including a description of the rationale the Secretary used to approve applications under subsection (a)(3)(B), shall be published in the Federal Register and the Secretary shall provide for the dissemination of such notice to State educational agencies, interested parties (including educators, parents, students, and advocacy and civil rights organizations), and the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>