<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5965" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5965/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/5965/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5965"><akn:num>5965</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5965. Use of funds(a) In generalA local educational agency shall use grant funds received under this subchapter for one or more of the following activities:(1) Identifying and assessing school violence and discipline problems, including coordinating needs assessment activities with education, law enforcement, judicial, health, social service, and other appropriate agencies and organizations, juvenile justice programs, and gang prevention activities.

(2) Conducting school safety reviews or violence prevention reviews of programs, policies, practices, and facilities to determine what changes are needed to reduce or prevent violence and promote safety and discipline.

(3) Planning for comprehensive, long-term strategies for addressing and preventing school violence and discipline problems through the involvement and coordination of school programs with other education, law enforcement, judicial, health, social service, and other appropriate agencies and organizations.

(4) Training school personnel in programs of demonstrated effectiveness in addressing violence, including violence prevention, conflict resolution, anger management, peer mediation, and identification of high-risk youth.

(5) Activities which involve parents in efforts to promote school safety and prevent school violence.

(6) Community education programs, including video- and technology-based projects, informing parents, businesses, local government, the media and other appropriate entities about—(A) the local educational agency’s plan to promote school safety and reduce and prevent school violence and discipline problems; and

(B) the need for community support.


(7) Coordination of school-based activities designed to promote school safety and reduce or prevent school violence and discipline problems with related efforts of education, law enforcement, judicial, health, social service, and other appropriate agencies and organizations and juvenile justice programs.

(8) Developing and implementing vi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5965_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A local educational agency shall use grant funds received under this subchapter for one or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5965_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>