<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6082"><akn:num>6082</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6082. Definitions
As used in this part:(1) ChildrenThe term “children” means individuals who have not attained the age of 18.


(2) Children’s servicesThe term “children’s services” means the provision on a routine or regular basis of health, day care, education, or library services—(A) that are funded, after March 31, 1994, directly by the Federal Government or through State or local governments, by Federal grant, loan, loan guarantee, or contract programs—(i) administered by either the Secretary of Health and Human Services or the Secretary of Education (other than services provided and funded solely under titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq., 1396 et seq.]); or

(ii) administered by the Secretary of Agriculture in the case of a clinic (as defined in 7 CFR 246.2) under section 17(b)(6) of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1786(b)(6)), or


(B) that are provided in indoor facilities that are constructed, operated, or maintained with such Federal funds, as determined by the appropriate Secretary in any enforcement action under this subchapter,


except that nothing in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) is intended to include facilities (other than clinics) where coupons are redeemed under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.].

(3) PersonThe term “person” means any State or local subdivision thereof, agency of such State or subdivision, corporation, or partnership that owns or operates or otherwise controls and provides children’s services or any individual who owns or operates or otherwise controls and provides such services.


(4) Indoor facilityThe term “indoor facility” means a building that is enclosed.


(5) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.


(Pub. L. 103–227, title X, § 1042, Mar. 31, 1994, 108 Stat. 271.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Child Nutrition Act of 1966, referred to in par. (2), is Pub. L. 89–642, Oct. 11, 1966, 80 Stat. 885, which </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6082_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Children The term “children” means individuals who have not attained the age of 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6082_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Children’s services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Children’s services The term “children’s services” means the provision on a routine or regular basis of health, day care, education, or library services— except that nothing in clause (ii) of subparagraph (A) is intended to include facilities (other than clinics) where coupons are redeemed under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6082_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Person The term “person” means any State or local subdivision thereof, agency of such State or subdivision, corporation, or partnership that owns or operates or otherwise controls and provides children’s services or any individual who owns or operates or otherwise controls and provides such services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6082_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indoor facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Indoor facility The term “indoor facility” means a building that is enclosed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6082_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>