<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6083" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6083/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6083/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6083"><akn:num>6083</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonsmoking policy for children’s services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6083. Nonsmoking policy for children’s services(a) ProhibitionAfter March 31, 1994, no person shall permit smoking within any indoor facility owned or leased or contracted for and utilized by such person for provision of routine or regular kindergarten, elementary, or secondary education or library services to children.


(b) Additional prohibitionAfter March 31, 1994, no person shall permit smoking within any indoor facility (or portion thereof) owned or leased or contracted for by such person for the provision by such person of regular or routine health care or day care or early childhood development (Head Start) services to children or for the use of the employees of such person who provides such services, except that this subsection shall not apply to—(1) any portion of such facility that is used for inpatient hospital treatment of individuals dependent on, or addicted to, drugs or alcohol; and

(2) any private residence.


(c) Federal agencies(1) Kindergarten, elementary, or secondary education or library servicesAfter March 31, 1994, no Federal agency shall permit smoking within any indoor facility in the United States operated by such agency, directly or by contract, to provide routine or regular kindergarten, elementary, or secondary education or library services to children.


(2) Health or day care or early childhood development servicesAfter March 31, 1994, no Federal agency shall permit smoking within any indoor facility (or portion thereof) operated by such agency, directly or by contract, to provide routine or regular health or day care or early childhood development (Head Start) services to children, except that this paragraph shall not apply to—(A) any portion of such facility that is used for inpatient hospital treatment of individuals dependent on, or addicted to, drugs or alcohol; and

(B) any private residence.


(3) Application of provisionsThe provisions of paragraph (2) shall also apply to the provision of such routine or regular kindergarte</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition After March 31, 1994, no person shall permit smoking within any indoor facility owned or leased or contracted for and utilized by such person for provision of routine or regular kindergarten, elementary, or secondary education or library services to children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional prohibition After March 31, 1994, no person shall permit smoking within any indoor facility (or portion thereof) owned or leased or contracted for by such person for the provision by such person of regular or routine health care or day care or early childhood development (Head Start) services to children or for the use of the employees of such person who provides such services, except that this subsection shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice The prohibitions in subsections (a) through (c) shall be incorporated by publication of a notice in the Federal Register by the Secretary (in consultation with the heads of other affected agencies) and by such agency heads in funding arrangements involving the provision of children’s services administered by such heads. Such prohibitions shall be effective 90 days after such notice is published, or 270 days after March 31, 1994, whichever occurs first.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>