<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6303b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6303b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6303b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6303b"><akn:num>6303b</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct student services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6303b. Direct student services(a) State reservation(1) In general(A) StatesEach State educational agency, after meaningful consultation with geographically diverse local educational agencies described in subparagraph (B), may reserve not more than 3 percent of the amount the State educational agency receives under subpart 2 of part A for each fiscal year to carry out this section.


(B) ConsultationA State educational agency shall consult under subparagraph (A) with local educational agencies that include—(i) suburban, rural, and urban local educational agencies;

(ii) local educational agencies serving a high percentage of schools identified by the State for comprehensive support and improvement under section 6311(c)(4)(D)(i) of this title; and

(iii) local educational agencies serving a high percentage of schools implementing targeted support and improvement plans under section 6311(d)(2) of this title.



(2) Program administrationOf the funds reserved under paragraph (1)(A), the State educational agency may use not more than 1 percent to administer the program described in this section.



(b) Awards(1) In generalFrom the amount reserved under subsection (a) by a State educational agency, the State educational agency shall award grants to geographically diverse local educational agencies described in subsection (a)(1)(B)(i).


(2) PriorityIn making such awards, the State educational agency shall prioritize awards to local educational agencies serving the highest percentage of schools, as compared to other local educational agencies in the State—(A) identified by the State for comprehensive support and improvement under section 6311(c)(4)(D)(i) of this title; or

(B) implementing targeted support and improvement plans under section 6311(d)(2) of this title.



(c) Local use of fundsA local educational agency receiving an award under this section—(1) may use not more than 1 percent of its award for outreach and communication to parents about available direct stu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6303b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State reservation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6303b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6303b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local use of funds A local educational agency receiving an award under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6303b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application A local educational agency desiring to receive an award under subsection (b) shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time and in such manner as the State educational agency shall require. At a minimum, each application shall describe how the local educational agency will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6303b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providers and schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Providers and schools A State educational agency that reserves an amount under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>