<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6314" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6314/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6314/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6314"><akn:num>6314</akn:num><akn:heading>Schoolwide programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6314. Schoolwide programs(a) In general(1) Use of funds for schoolwide programs(A) EligibilityA local educational agency may consolidate and use funds under this part, together with other Federal, State, and local funds, in order to upgrade the entire educational program of a school that serves an eligible school attendance area in which not less than 40 percent of the children are from low-income families, or not less than 40 percent of the children enrolled in the school are from such families.


(B) ExceptionA school that serves an eligible school attendance area in which less than 40 percent of the children are from low-income families, or a school for which less than 40 percent of the children enrolled in the school are from such families, may operate a schoolwide program under this section if the school receives a waiver from the State educational agency to do so, after taking into account how a schoolwide program will best serve the needs of the students in the school served under this part in improving academic achievement and other factors.



(2) Identification of students not required(A) In generalNo school participating in a schoolwide program shall be required to identify—(i) particular children under this part as eligible to participate in a schoolwide program; or

(ii) individual services as supplementary.


(B) Supplemental fundsIn accordance with the method of determination described in section 6321(b)(2) of this title, a school participating in a schoolwide program shall use funds available to carry out this section only to supplement the amount of funds that would, in the absence of funds under this part, be made available from non-Federal sources for the school, including funds needed to provide services that are required by law for children with disabilities and English learners.



(3) Exemption from statutory and regulatory requirements(A) ExemptionExcept as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may, through publication of a notice in the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schoolwide program plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Schoolwide program plan An eligible school operating a schoolwide program shall develop a comprehensive plan (or amend a plan for such a program that was in existence on the day before December 10, 2015) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preschool programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preschool programs A school that operates a schoolwide program under this section may use funds available under this part to establish or enhance preschool programs for children who are under 6 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delivery of services The services of a schoolwide program under this section may be delivered by nonprofit or for-profit external providers with expertise in using evidence-based or other effective strategies to improve student achievement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6314_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds for dual or concurrent enrollment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds for dual or concurrent enrollment programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>