<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6321"><akn:num>6321</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6321. Fiscal requirements(a) Maintenance of effortA local educational agency may receive funds under this part for any fiscal year only if the State educational agency involved finds that the local educational agency has maintained the agency’s fiscal effort in accordance with section 7901 of this title.


(b) Federal funds to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds(1) In generalA State educational agency or local educational agency shall use Federal funds received under this part only to supplement the funds that would, in the absence of such Federal funds, be made available from State and local sources for the education of students participating in programs assisted under this part, and not to supplant such funds.


(2) ComplianceTo demonstrate compliance with paragraph (1), a local educational agency shall demonstrate that the methodology used to allocate State and local funds to each school receiving assistance under this part ensures that such school receives all of the State and local funds it would otherwise receive if it were not receiving assistance under this part.


(3) Special ruleNo local educational agency shall be required to—(A) identify that an individual cost or service supported under this part is supplemental; or

(B) provide services under this part through a particular instructional method or in a particular instructional setting in order to demonstrate such agency’s compliance with paragraph (1).


(4) ProhibitionNothing in this section shall be construed to authorize or permit the Secretary to prescribe the specific methodology a local educational agency uses to allocate State and local funds to each school receiving assistance under this part.


(5) TimelineA local educational agency—(A) shall meet the compliance requirement under paragraph (2) not later than 2 years after December 10, 2015; and

(B) may demonstrate compliance with the requirement under paragraph (1) before the end of such 2-year period using the method such local educ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maintenance of effort A local educational agency may receive funds under this part for any fiscal year only if the State educational agency involved finds that the local educational agency has maintained the agency’s fiscal effort in accordance with section 7901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal funds to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal funds to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comparability of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Comparability of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exclusion of funds For the purpose of complying with subsections (b) and (c), a State educational agency or local educational agency may exclude supplemental State or local funds expended in any school attendance area or school for programs that meet the intent and purposes of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>