<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6322"><akn:num>6322</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6322. Coordination requirements(a) In generalEach local educational agency receiving assistance under this part shall carry out the activities described in subsection (b) with Head Start agencies and, if feasible, other entities carrying out early childhood development programs. Each local educational agency shall develop agreements with such Head Start agencies and other entities to carry out such activities.


(b) ActivitiesThe activities referred to in subsection (a) are activities that increase coordination between the local educational agency and a Head Start agency and, if feasible, other entities carrying out early childhood education programs serving children who will attend the schools of the local educational agency, including—(1) developing and implementing a systematic procedure for receiving records regarding such children, transferred with parental consent from a Head Start program or, where applicable, another early childhood education program;

(2) establishing channels of communication between school staff and their counterparts (including teachers, social workers, and health staff) in such Head Start agencies or other entities carrying out early childhood education programs, as appropriate, to facilitate coordination of programs;

(3) conducting meetings involving parents, kindergarten or elementary school teachers, and Head Start teachers or, if appropriate, teachers from other early childhood education programs, to discuss the developmental and other needs of individual children;

(4) organizing and participating in joint transition-related training of school staff, Head Start program staff, and, where appropriate, other early childhood education program staff; and

(5) linking the educational services provided by such local educational agency with the services provided by local Head Start agencies.


(c) Coordination of regulationsThe Secretary shall work with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to coordinate regulations promulgated und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each local educational agency receiving assistance under this part shall carry out the activities described in subsection (b) with Head Start agencies and, if feasible, other entities carrying out early childhood development programs. Each local educational agency shall develop agreements with such Head Start agencies and other entities to carry out such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities The activities referred to in subsection (a) are activities that increase coordination between the local educational agency and a Head Start agency and, if feasible, other entities carrying out early childhood education programs serving children who will attend the schools of the local educational agency, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination of regulations The Secretary shall work with the Secretary of Health and Human Services to coordinate regulations promulgated under this part with regulations promulgated under the Head Start Act [42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>