<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6363" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6363/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6363/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6363"><akn:num>6363</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of appropriated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6363. Allotment of appropriated funds(a) Amounts equal to or less than trigger amountFrom amounts made available for each fiscal year under subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 6302(b) of this title that are equal to or less than the amount described in section 6311(b)(2)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall—(1) reserve one-half of 1 percent for the Bureau of Indian Education;

(2) reserve one-half of 1 percent for the outlying areas;

(3) reserve not more than 20 percent to carry out section 6362 of this title; and

(4) from the remainder, carry out section 6361 of this title by allocating to each State an amount equal to—(A) $3,000,000, except for a fiscal year for which the amounts available are insufficient to allocate such amount to each State, the Secretary shall ratably reduce such amount for each State; and

(B) with respect to any amounts remaining after the allocation under subparagraph (A), an amount that bears the same relationship to such total remaining amounts as the number of students aged 5 through 17 in the State (as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most recent satisfactory data) bears to the total number of such students in all States.



(b) Amounts above trigger amountFor any fiscal year for which the amount made available for a fiscal year under subsection 1 6302(b) of this title exceeds the amount described in section 6311(b)(2)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall make such excess amount available as follows:(1) Competitive grants(A) In generalThe Secretary shall first use such funds to award grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies or consortia of State educational agencies that have submitted applications described in subparagraph (B) to enable such States to carry out the activities described in subparagraphs (C), (H), (I), (J), (K), and (L) of section 6361(a)(2) of this title.


(B) ApplicationsA State, or a consortium of States, that desires a competitive grant under subparag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts equal to or less than trigger amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts equal to or less than trigger amount From amounts made available for each fiscal year under subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 6302(b) of this title that are equal to or less than the amount described in section 6311(b)(2)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts above trigger amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amounts above trigger amount For any fiscal year for which the amount made available for a fiscal year under subsection 1 6302(b) of this title exceeds the amount described in section 6311(b)(2)(I) of this title, the Secretary shall make such excess amount available as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State defined In this part, the term “State” means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition In making funds available to States under this part, the Secretary shall comply with the prohibitions described in section 7909 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>