<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6364" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6364/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6364/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6364"><akn:num>6364</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative assessment and accountability demonstration authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6364. Innovative assessment and accountability demonstration authority(a) Innovative assessment system definedThe term “innovative assessment system” means a system of assessments that may include—(1) competency-based assessments, instructionally embedded assessments, interim assessments, cumulative year-end assessments, or performance-based assessments that combine into an annual summative determination for a student, which may be administered through computer adaptive assessments; and

(2) assessments that validate when students are ready to demonstrate mastery or proficiency and allow for differentiated student support based on individual learning needs.


(b) Demonstration authority(1) In generalThe Secretary may provide a State educational agency, or a consortium of State educational agencies, in accordance with paragraph (3), with the authority to establish an innovative assessment system (referred to in this section as “demonstration authority”).


(2) Demonstration periodIn accordance with the requirements described in subsection (e), each State educational agency, or consortium of State educational agencies, that submits an application under this section shall propose in its application the period of time over which the State educational agency or consortium desires to exercise the demonstration authority, except that such period shall not exceed 5 years.


(3) Initial demonstration authority and expansionDuring the first 3 years that the Secretary provides State educational agencies and consortia with demonstration authority (referred to in this section as the “initial demonstration period”) the Secretary shall provide such demonstration authority to—(A) a total number of not more than 7 participating State educational agencies, including those participating in consortia, that have applications approved under subsection (e); and

(B) consortia that include not more than 4 State educational agencies.



(c) Progress report(1) In generalNot later than 180 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative assessment system defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Innovative assessment system defined The term “innovative assessment system” means a system of assessments that may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Demonstration authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Progress report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Progress report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of the demonstration authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expansion of the demonstration authority Upon completion and publication of the report described in subsection (c), the Secretary may grant demonstration authority to additional State educational agencies or consortia that submit an application under subsection (e). Such State educational agencies or consortia of State educational agencies shall be subject to all of the same terms, conditions, and requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Peer review The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Extension The Secretary may extend an authorization of demonstration authority under this section for an additional 2 years if the State educational agency demonstrates with evidence that the State educational agency’s innovative assessment system is continuing to meet the requirements of subsection (c), including by demonstrating a plan for, and the capacity to, transition to statewide use of the innovative assessment system by the end of the 2-year extension period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of innovative assessment system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of innovative assessment system A State may, during the State’s approved demonstration authority period or 2-year extension, include results from the innovative assessment systems developed under this section in accountability determinations for each student in the participating local educational agencies instead of, or in addition to, results from the assessment system under section 6311(b)(2) of this title if the State demonstrates that the State has met the requirements under subsection (c). The State shall continue to meet all other requirements of section 6311(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Withdrawal of authority The Secretary shall withdraw the authorization for demonstration authority provided to a State educational agency under this section and such State shall return to use of the statewide assessment system under section 6311(b)(2) of this title for all local educational agencies in the State if, at any time during a State’s approved demonstration authority period or 2-year extension, the State educational agency cannot present to the Secretary evidence that the innovative assessment system developed under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6364_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Transition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>