<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6393" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6393/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6393/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6393"><akn:num>6393</akn:num><akn:heading>State allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6393. State allocations(a) State allocationsExcept as provided in subsection (c), each State (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) is entitled to receive under this part an amount equal to the product of—(1) the sum of—(A) the average number of identified eligible migratory children aged 3 through 21 residing in the State, based on data for the preceding 3 years; and

(B) the number of identified eligible migratory children, aged 3 through 21, who received services under this part in summer or intersession programs provided by the State during the previous year; multiplied by


(2) 40 percent of the average per-pupil expenditure in the State, except that the amount determined under this paragraph shall not be less than 32 percent, nor more than 48 percent, of the average per-pupil expenditure in the United States.


(b) Hold harmlessNotwithstanding subsection (a), for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2019, no State shall receive less than 90 percent of the State’s allocation under this section for the preceding fiscal year.


(c) Allocation to Puerto Rico(1) In generalFor each fiscal year, the grant that the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall be eligible to receive under this part shall be the amount determined by multiplying the number of children who would be counted under subsection (a)(1) if such subsection applied to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico by the product of—(A) the percentage that the average per-pupil expenditure in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico is of the lowest average per-pupil expenditure of any of the 50 States, subject to paragraphs (2) and (3); and

(B) 32 percent of the average per-pupil expenditure in the United States.


(2) Minimum percentageThe percentage described in paragraph (1)(A) shall not be less than 85 percent.


(3) LimitationIf the application of paragraph (2) for any fiscal year would result in any of the 50 States or the District of Columbia receiving less under this part than it received under this part for the prece</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State allocations Except as provided in subsection (c), each State (other than the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico) is entitled to receive under this part an amount equal to the product of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hold harmless</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Hold harmless Notwithstanding subsection (a), for each of fiscal years 2017 through 2019, no State shall receive less than 90 percent of the State’s allocation under this section for the preceding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation to Puerto Rico</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation to Puerto Rico</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ratable reductions; reallocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ratable reductions; reallocations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortium arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consortium arrangements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determining numbers of eligible children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Determining numbers of eligible children In order to determine the identified number of migratory children residing in each State for purposes of this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonparticipating States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonparticipating States In the case of a State desiring to receive an allocation under this part for a fiscal year that did not receive an allocation for the previous fiscal year or that has been participating for less than 3 consecutive years, the Secretary shall calculate the State’s number of identified migratory children aged 3 through 21 for purposes of subsection (a)(1)(A) by using the most recent data available that identifies the migratory children residing in the State until data is available to calculate the 3-year average number of such children in accordance with such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>