<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6399" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6399/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6399/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6399"><akn:num>6399</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6399. Definitions
As used in this part:(1) Local operating agencyThe term “local operating agency” means—(A) a local educational agency to which a State educational agency makes a subgrant under this part;

(B) a public or private agency with which a State educational agency or the Secretary makes an arrangement to carry out a project under this part; or

(C) a State educational agency, if the State educational agency operates the State’s migrant education program or projects directly.


(2) Migratory agricultural workerThe term “migratory agricultural worker” means an individual who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months and, after doing so, engaged in new temporary or seasonal employment or personal subsistence in agriculture, which may be dairy work or the initial processing of raw agricultural products. If an individual did not engage in such new employment soon after a qualifying move, such individual may be considered a migratory agricultural worker if the individual actively sought such new employment and has a recent history of moves for temporary or seasonal agricultural employment.


(3) Migratory childThe term “migratory child” means a child or youth who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months—(A) as a migratory agricultural worker or a migratory fisher; or

(B) with, or to join, a parent or spouse who is a migratory agricultural worker or a migratory fisher.


(4) Migratory fisherThe term “migratory fisher” means an individual who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months and, after doing so, engaged in new temporary or seasonal employment or personal subsistence in fishing. If the individual did not engage in such new employment soon after the move, the individual may be considered a migratory fisher if the individual actively sought such new employment and has a recent history of moves for temporary or seasonal fishing employment.


(5) Qualifying moveThe term “qualifying move” means a move due to economic necessity—(A) f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6399_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local operating agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Local operating agency The term “local operating agency” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6399_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Migratory agricultural worker</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Migratory agricultural worker The term “migratory agricultural worker” means an individual who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months and, after doing so, engaged in new temporary or seasonal employment or personal subsistence in agriculture, which may be dairy work or the initial processing of raw agricultural products. If an individual did not engage in such new employment soon after a qualifying move, such individual may be considered a migratory agricultural worker if the individual actively sought such new employment and has a recent history of moves for temporary or seasonal agricultural employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6399_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Migratory child</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Migratory child The term “migratory child” means a child or youth who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6399_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Migratory fisher</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Migratory fisher The term “migratory fisher” means an individual who made a qualifying move in the preceding 36 months and, after doing so, engaged in new temporary or seasonal employment or personal subsistence in fishing. If the individual did not engage in such new employment soon after the move, the individual may be considered a migratory fisher if the individual actively sought such new employment and has a recent history of moves for temporary or seasonal fishing employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6399_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying move</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Qualifying move The term “qualifying move” means a move due to economic necessity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>