<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6435" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6435/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6435/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6435"><akn:num>6435</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6435. Use of funds(a) Uses(1) In generalA State agency shall use funds received under this subpart only for programs and projects that—(A) are consistent with the State plan under section 6434(a) of this title; and

(B) concentrate on providing participants with the knowledge and skills needed to make a successful transition to secondary school completion, career and technical education, further education, or employment.


(2) Programs and projectsSuch programs and projects—(A) may include—(i) the acquisition of equipment;

(ii) pay-for-success initiatives; or

(iii) providing targeted services for youth who have come in contact with both the child welfare system and juvenile justice system;


(B) shall be designed to support educational services that—(i) except for institution-wide projects under section 6436 of this title, are provided to children and youth identified by the State agency as failing, or most at-risk of failing, to meet the challenging State academic standards;

(ii) respond to the educational needs of such children and youth, including by supplementing and improving the quality of the educational services provided to such children and youth by the State agency; and

(iii) afford such children and youth an opportunity to meet challenging State academic standards; and


(C) shall be carried out in a manner consistent with section 6321 of this title and part F (as applied to programs and projects under this part).



(b) Supplement, not supplantA program under this subpart that supplements the number of hours of instruction students receive from State and local sources shall be considered to comply with the supplement, not supplant requirement of section 6321 of this title (as applied to this part) without regard to the subject areas in which instruction is given during those hours.


(Pub. L. 89–10, title I, § 1415, as added Pub. L. 107–110, title I, § 101, Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1585; amended Pub. L. 114–95, title I, § 1401(4), Dec. 10, 2015, 129</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6435_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6435_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supplement, not supplant A program under this subpart that supplements the number of hours of instruction students receive from State and local sources shall be considered to comply with the supplement, not supplant requirement of section 6321 of this title (as applied to this part) without regard to the subject areas in which instruction is given during those hours.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>