<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6571" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6571/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6571/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6571"><akn:num>6571</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6571. Federal regulations(a) In generalThe Secretary may issue, in accordance with subsections (b) through (d) and subject to section 6311(e) of this title, such regulations as are necessary to reasonably ensure that there is compliance with this subchapter.


(b) Negotiated rulemaking process(1) In generalBefore publishing in the Federal Register proposed regulations to carry out this subchapter, the Secretary shall obtain the advice and recommendations of representatives of Federal, State, and local administrators, parents, teachers, principals, other school leaders (including charter school leaders), paraprofessionals, and members of local school boards and other organizations involved with the implementation and operation of programs under this subchapter.


(2) Meetings and electronic exchangeSuch advice and recommendations may be obtained through such mechanisms as regional meetings and electronic exchanges of information. Such regional meetings and electronic exchanges of information shall be public and notice of such meetings and exchanges shall be provided to interested stakeholders.


(3) Proposed regulationsAfter obtaining such advice and recommendations, and before publishing proposed regulations, the Secretary shall—(A) establish a negotiated rulemaking process on, at a minimum, standards, assessments under section 6311(b)(2) of this title, and the requirement under section 6321 of this title that funds under part A be used to supplement, and not supplant, State and local funds;

(B) select individuals to participate in such process from among individuals or groups that provided advice and recommendations, including representation from all geographic regions of the United States, in such numbers as will provide an equitable balance between representatives of parents and students and representatives of educators and education officials; and

(C) prepare a draft of proposed policy options that shall be provided to the individuals selected by the Secreta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6571_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may issue, in accordance with subsections (b) through (d) and subject to section 6311(e) of this title, such regulations as are necessary to reasonably ensure that there is compliance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6571_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiated rulemaking process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Negotiated rulemaking process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6571_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative process for certain exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative process for certain exceptions If consensus, as defined in section 562 of title 5, on any proposed regulation is not reached by the individuals selected under subsection (b)(3)(B) for the negotiated rulemaking process, or if the Secretary determines that a negotiated rulemaking process is unnecessary, the Secretary may propose a regulation in the following manner:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6571_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation Regulations to carry out this subchapter may not require local programs to follow a particular instructional model, such as the provision of services outside the regular classroom or school program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6571_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section affects the applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5 (commonly known as the “Administrative Procedure Act”) or chapter 8 of title 5 (commonly known as the “Congressional Review Act”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>