<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6632"><akn:num>6632</akn:num><akn:heading>Teacher and school leader incentive fund grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6632. Teacher and school leader incentive fund grants(a) Grants authorizedFrom the amounts reserved by the Secretary under section 6621(1) of this title, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to develop, implement, improve, or expand performance-based compensation systems or human capital management systems, in schools served by the eligible entity.


(b) Duration of grants(1) In generalA grant awarded under this subpart shall be for a period of not more than 3 years.


(2) RenewalThe Secretary may renew a grant awarded under this subpart for a period of not more than 2 years if the grantee demonstrates to the Secretary that the grantee is effectively using funds. Such renewal may include allowing the grantee to scale up or replicate the successful program.


(3) LimitationA local educational agency may receive (whether individually or as part of a consortium or partnership) a grant under this subpart, as amended by the Every Student Succeeds Act,11 See References in Text note below. only twice.



(c) ApplicationsAn eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require. The application shall include—(1) a description of the performance-based compensation system or human capital management system that the eligible entity proposes to develop, implement, improve, or expand through the grant;

(2) a description of the most significant gaps or insufficiencies in student access to effective teachers, principals, or other school leaders in high-need schools, including gaps or inequities in how effective teachers, principals, or other school leaders are distributed across the local educational agency, as identified using factors such as data on school resources, staffing patterns, school environment, educator support systems, and other school-level factors;

(3) a description and eviden</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized From the amounts reserved by the Secretary under section 6621(1) of this title, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to develop, implement, improve, or expand performance-based compensation systems or human capital management systems, in schools served by the eligible entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duration of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require. The application shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Award basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching requirement Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 50 percent of the amount of the grant (which may be provided in cash or in kind) to carry out the activities supported by the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6632_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Supplement, not supplant Grant funds provided under this subpart shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds available to carry out activities described in this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>