<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6643" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6643/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6643/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6643"><akn:num>6643</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to eligible entities in support of birth through kindergarten entry literacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6643. Subgrants to eligible entities in support of birth through kindergarten entry literacy(a) Subgrants(1) In generalA State educational agency receiving a grant under this subpart shall, in consultation with the State agencies responsible for administering early childhood education programs and services, including the State agency responsible for administering child care programs, and, if applicable, the State Advisory Council on Early Childhood Education and Care designated or established pursuant to section 9837b(b)(1)(A)(i) of title 42, use a portion of the grant funds, in accordance with section 6642(d)(2)(D)(i) of this title, to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to support high-quality early literacy initiatives for children from birth through kindergarten entry.


(2) DurationThe term of a subgrant under this section shall be determined by the State educational agency awarding the subgrant and shall in no case exceed 5 years.


(3) Sufficient size and scopeEach subgrant awarded under this section shall be of sufficient size and scope to allow the eligible entity to carry out high-quality early literacy initiatives for children from birth through kindergarten entry.



(b) Local applicationsAn eligible entity desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require. Such application shall include a description of—(1) how the subgrant funds will be used to enhance the language and literacy development and school readiness of children, from birth through kindergarten entry, in early childhood education programs, which shall include an analysis of data that support the proposed use of subgrant funds;

(2) how the subgrant funds will be used to prepare and provide ongoing assistance to staff in the programs, including through high-quality profe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6643_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subgrants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6643_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Local applications An eligible entity desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require. Such application shall include a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6643_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the State educational agency shall give priority to an eligible entity that will use the grant funds to implement evidence-based activities, defined for the purpose of this subsection as activities meeting the requirements of section 7801(21)(A)(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6643_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Local uses of funds An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use the subgrant funds, consistent with the entity’s approved application under subsection (b), to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>