<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6644" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6644/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6644/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6644"><akn:num>6644</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to eligible entities in support of kindergarten through grade 12 literacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6644. Subgrants to eligible entities in support of kindergarten through grade 12 literacy(a) Subgrants to eligible entities(1) SubgrantsA State educational agency receiving a grant under this subpart shall use a portion of the grant funds, in accordance with clauses (ii) and (iii) of section 6642(d)(2)(D) of this title, to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the authorized activities described in subsections (c) and (d).


(2) DurationThe term of a subgrant under this section shall be determined by the State educational agency awarding the subgrant and shall in no case exceed 5 years.


(3) Sufficient size and scopeA State educational agency shall award subgrants under this section of sufficient size and scope to allow the eligible entities to carry out high-quality comprehensive literacy instruction in each grade level for which the subgrant funds are provided.


(4) Local applicationsAn eligible entity desiring to receive a subgrant under this section shall submit an application to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may require. Such application shall include, for each school that the eligible entity identifies as participating in a subgrant program under this section, the following information:(A) A description of the eligible entity’s needs assessment conducted to identify how subgrant funds will be used to inform and improve comprehensive literacy instruction at the school.

(B) How the school, the local educational agency, or a provider of high-quality professional development will provide ongoing high-quality professional development to all teachers, principals, other school leaders, specialized instructional support personnel (as appropriate), and other instructional leaders served by the school.

(C) How the school will identify children in need of literacy interventions or other support services.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6644_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subgrants to eligible entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6644_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the State educational agency shall give priority to an eligible entity that will use funds under subsection (c) or (d) to implement evidence-based activities, defined for the purpose of this subsection as activities meeting the requirements of section 7801(21)(A)(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6644_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local uses of funds for kindergarten through grade 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local uses of funds for kindergarten through grade 5 An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use the subgrant funds to carry out the following activities pertaining to children in kindergarten through grade 5:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6644_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local uses of funds for grades 6 through 12</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Local uses of funds for grades 6 through 12 An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section shall use subgrant funds to carry out the following activities pertaining to children in grades 6 through 12:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6644_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allowable uses An eligible entity that receives a subgrant under this section may, in addition to carrying out the activities described in subsections (c) and (d), use subgrant funds to carry out the following activities pertaining to children in kindergarten through grade 12:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>