<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6672" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6672/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6672/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6672"><akn:num>6672</akn:num><akn:heading>Supporting effective educator development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6672. Supporting effective educator development(a) In generalFrom the funds reserved by the Secretary under section 6671(1) of this title for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for the purposes of—(1) providing teachers, principals, or other school leaders from nontraditional preparation and certification routes or pathways to serve in traditionally underserved local educational agencies;

(2) providing evidence-based professional development activities that address literacy, numeracy, remedial, or other needs of local educational agencies and the students the agencies serve;

(3) providing teachers, principals, or other school leaders with professional development activities that enhance or enable the provision of postsecondary coursework through dual or concurrent enrollment programs and early college high school settings across a local educational agency;

(4) making freely available services and learning opportunities to local educational agencies, through partnerships and cooperative agreements or by making the services or opportunities publicly accessible through electronic means; or

(5) providing teachers, principals, or other school leaders with evidence-based professional enhancement activities, which may include activities that lead to an advanced credential.


(b) Program periods and diversity of projects(1) In generalA grant awarded by the Secretary to an eligible entity under this section shall be for a period of not more than 3 years.


(2) RenewalThe Secretary may renew a grant awarded under this section for 1 additional 2-year period.


(3) Diversity of projectsIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that, to the extent practicable, grants are distributed among eligible entities that will serve geographically diverse areas, including urban, suburban, and rural areas.


(4) LimitationThe Secretary shall not award more than 1 grant under this section to an eligible </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general From the funds reserved by the Secretary under section 6671(1) of this title for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for the purposes of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program periods and diversity of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program periods and diversity of projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost-sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications In order to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may reasonably require. Such application shall include, at a minimum, a certification that the services provided by an eligible entity under the grant to a local educational agency or to a school served by the local educational agency will not result in direct fees for participating students or parents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to an eligible entity that will implement evidence-based activities, defined for the purpose of this subsection as activities meeting the requirements of section 7801(21)(A)(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6672_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition of eligible entity In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>