<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6825" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6825/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6825/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6825"><akn:num>6825</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6825. Subgrants to eligible entities(a) Purposes of subgrantsA State educational agency may make a subgrant to an eligible entity from funds received by the agency under this subpart only if the entity agrees to expend the funds to improve the education of English learners by assisting the children to learn English and meet the challenging State academic standards. In carrying out activities with such funds, the eligible entity shall use effective approaches and methodologies for teaching English learners and immigrant children and youth for the following purposes:(1) Developing and implementing new language instruction educational programs and academic content instructional programs for English learners and immigrant children and youth, including early childhood education programs, elementary school programs, and secondary school programs.

(2) Carrying out highly focused, innovative, locally designed activities to expand or enhance existing language instruction educational programs and academic content instructional programs for English learners and immigrant children and youth.

(3) Implementing, within an individual school, schoolwide programs for restructuring, reforming, and upgrading all relevant programs, activities, and operations relating to language instruction educational programs and academic content instruction for English learners and immigrant children and youth.

(4) Implementing, within the entire jurisdiction of a local educational agency, agencywide programs for restructuring, reforming, and upgrading all relevant programs, activities, and operations relating to language instruction educational programs and academic content instruction for English learners and immigrant children and youth.


(b) Direct administrative expensesEach eligible entity receiving funds under section 6824(a) of this title for a fiscal year may use not more than 2 percent of such funds for the cost of administering this subpart.


(c) Required subgrantee activitiesAn eli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes of subgrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes of subgrants A State educational agency may make a subgrant to an eligible entity from funds received by the agency under this subpart only if the entity agrees to expend the funds to improve the education of English learners by assisting the children to learn English and meet the challenging State academic standards. In carrying out activities with such funds, the eligible entity shall use effective approaches and methodologies for teaching English learners and immigrant children and youth for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Direct administrative expenses Each eligible entity receiving funds under section 6824(a) of this title for a fiscal year may use not more than 2 percent of such funds for the cost of administering this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required subgrantee activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Required subgrantee activities An eligible entity receiving funds under section 6824(a) of this title shall use the funds—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized subgrantee activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorized subgrantee activities Subject to subsection (c), an eligible entity receiving funds under section 6824(a) of this title may use the funds to achieve any of the purposes described in subsection (a) by undertaking 1 or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities by agencies experiencing substantial increases in immigrant children and youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Activities by agencies experiencing substantial increases in immigrant children and youth</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of method of instruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Selection of method of instruction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6825_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Supplement, not supplant Federal funds made available under this subpart shall be used so as to supplement the level of Federal, State, and local public funds that, in the absence of such availability, would have been expended for programs for English learners and immigrant children and youth and in no case to supplant such Federal, State, and local public funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>