<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6844" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6844/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/6844/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6844"><akn:num>6844</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with related programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6844. Coordination with related programs
In order to maximize Federal efforts aimed at serving the educational needs of English learners, the Secretary shall coordinate and ensure close cooperation with other entities carrying out programs serving language-minority and English learners that are administered by the Department and other agencies. The Secretary shall report to the Congress on parallel Federal programs in other agencies and departments.
(Pub. L. 89–10, title III, § 3123, formerly § 3124, as added Pub. L. 107–110, title III, § 301, Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1705; renumbered § 3123 and amended Pub. L. 114–95, title III, §§ 3001(2)(B), 3003(j), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 1953, 1963.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 6844, Pub. L. 89–10, title III, § 3134, as added Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101, Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 3646, related to local uses of funds, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 107–110.
A prior section 3123 of Pub. L. 89–10 was renumbered section 3122 and is classified to section 6843 of this title.
Another prior section 3123 of Pub. L. 89–10 was classified to section 6833 of this title, prior to the general amendment of this subchapter by Pub. L. 107–110.

Amendments2015—Pub. L. 114–95, § 3003(j), substituted “needs of English learners” for “needs of children of limited English proficiency” and “and English learners” for “and limited English proficient children” and inserted at end “The Secretary shall report to the Congress on parallel Federal programs in other agencies and departments.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2015 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 114–95 effective Dec. 10, 2015, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95, set out as a note under section 6301 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>