<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/71" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/71/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/71/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_71"><akn:num>71</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 71. Designation of site
The area bounded by Seventh Street, Constitution Avenue, Fourth Street, and North Mall Drive, Northwest, in the District of Columbia, is appropriated to the Smithsonian Institution as a site for a National Gallery of Art. The Smithsonian Institution is authorized to permit the A. W. Mellon Educational and Charitable Trust (hereinafter referred to as the donor) to construct on said site for the Smithsonian Institution a building to be designated the National Gallery of Art, and to remove any existing structure and landscape the grounds within said area. The adjoining area bounded by Fourth Street, Pennsylvania Avenue, Third Street, and North Mall Drive, Northwest, in the District of Columbia, is reserved as a site for future additions to the National Gallery of Art. The project shall be in accordance with plans and specifications approved by the Commission of Fine Arts.
(Mar. 24, 1937, ch. 50, § 1, 50 Stat. 51.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Smithsonian American Art MuseumPub. L. 106–385, Oct. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 1463, provided that:
“SECTION 1. RENAMING OF NATIONAL MUSEUM OF AMERICAN ART.“(a) In General.—The National Museum of American Art, as designated under section 1 of Public Law 96–441 (20 U.S.C. 71 note), shall be known as the ‘Smithsonian American Art Museum’.

“(b) References in Law.—Any reference in any law, regulation, document, or paper to the National Museum of American Art shall be considered to be a reference to the Smithsonian American Art Museum.


“SEC. 2. EFFECTIVE DATE.

“Section 1 shall take effect on the day after the date of enactment of this Act [Oct. 27, 2000].”



Pub. L. 96–441, §§ 1, 3, 4, Oct. 13, 1980, 94 Stat. 1884, provided: 
“That the bureau of the Smithsonian Institution designated as the National Collection of Fine Arts by section 6(c) of the joint resolution entitled ‘Joint Resolution providing for the construction and maintenance of a National Gallery of Art’, approved March 24, 1937 (20 U.S.C</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>