<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7116" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7116/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7116/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7116"><akn:num>7116</akn:num><akn:heading>Local educational agency applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7116. Local educational agency applications(a) EligibilityTo be eligible to receive an allocation under section 7115(a) of this title, a local educational agency shall—(1) submit an application, which shall contain, at a minimum, the information described in subsection (e), to the State educational agency at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State educational agency may reasonably require; and

(2) complete a needs assessment in accordance with subsection (d).


(b) ConsortiumIf a local educational agency desires to carry out the activities described in this subpart in consortium with one or more surrounding local educational agencies as described in section 7115(a)(3) of this title, such local educational agencies shall submit a single application as required under subsection (a).


(c) Consultation(1) In generalA local educational agency, or consortium of such agencies, shall develop its application through consultation with parents, teachers, principals, other school leaders, specialized instructional support personnel, students, community-based organizations, local government representatives (which may include a local law enforcement agency, local juvenile court, local child welfare agency, or local public housing agency), Indian tribes or tribal organizations that may be located in the region served by the local educational agency (where applicable), charter school teachers, principals, and other school leaders (if such agency or consortium of such agencies supports charter schools), and others with relevant and demonstrated expertise in programs and activities designed to meet the purpose of this subpart.


(2) Continued consultationThe local educational agency, or consortium of such agencies, shall engage in continued consultation with the entities described in paragraph (1) in order to improve the local activities in order to meet the purpose of this subpart and to coordinate such implementation with other related strategies</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility To be eligible to receive an allocation under section 7115(a) of this title, a local educational agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consortium If a local educational agency desires to carry out the activities described in this subpart in consortium with one or more surrounding local educational agencies as described in section 7115(a)(3) of this title, such local educational agencies shall submit a single application as required under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Needs assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Needs assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of local application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contents of local application Each application submitted under this section by a local educational agency, or a consortium of such agencies, shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7116_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule Any local educational agency receiving an allocation under section 7115(a)(1) of this title in an amount less than $30,000 shall be required to provide only one of the assurances described in subparagraphs (C), (D), and (E) of subsection (e)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>