<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7221i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7221i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7221i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7221i"><akn:num>7221i</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7221i. Definitions
In this part:(1) Authorized public chartering agencyThe term “authorized public chartering agency” means a State educational agency, local educational agency, or other public entity that has the authority pursuant to State law and approved by the Secretary to authorize or approve a charter school.


(2) Charter schoolThe term “charter school” means a public school that—(A) in accordance with a specific State statute authorizing the granting of charters to schools, is exempt from significant State or local rules that inhibit the flexible operation and management of public schools, but not from any rules relating to the other requirements of this paragraph;

(B) is created by a developer as a public school, or is adapted by a developer from an existing public school, and is operated under public supervision and direction;

(C) operates in pursuit of a specific set of educational objectives determined by the school’s developer and agreed to by the authorized public chartering agency;

(D) provides a program of elementary or secondary education, or both;

(E) is nonsectarian in its programs, admissions policies, employment practices, and all other operations, and is not affiliated with a sectarian school or religious institution;

(F) does not charge tuition;

(G) complies with the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 [42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.], title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.], title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 [20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.], section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 794], the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.), section 1232g of this title (commonly referred to as the “Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974”), and part B of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [20 U.S.C. 1411 et seq.];

(H) is a school to which parents choose to send their children, and that—(i) admits students on the basis of a lottery, consistent with section 7221b(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized public chartering agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Authorized public chartering agency The term “authorized public chartering agency” means a State educational agency, local educational agency, or other public entity that has the authority pursuant to State law and approved by the Secretary to authorize or approve a charter school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Charter school The term “charter school” means a public school that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter management organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Charter management organization The term “charter management organization” means a nonprofit organization that operates or manages a network of charter schools linked by centralized support, operations, and oversight.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charter school support organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Charter school support organization The term “charter school support organization” means a nonprofit, nongovernmental entity that is not an authorized public chartering agency and provides, on a statewide basis—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Developer The term “developer” means an individual or group of individuals (including a public or private nonprofit organization), which may include teachers, administrators and other school staff, parents, or other members of the local community in which a charter school project will be carried out.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Eligible applicant The term “eligible applicant” means a developer that has—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expand</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Expand The term “expand”, when used with respect to a high-quality charter school, means to significantly increase enrollment or add one or more grades to the high-quality charter school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-quality charter school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) High-quality charter school The term “high-quality charter school” means a charter school that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7221i_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Replicate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Replicate The term “replicate”, when used with respect to a high-quality charter school, means to open a new charter school, or a new campus of a high-quality charter school, based on the educational model of an existing high-quality charter school, under an existing charter or an additional charter, if permitted or required by State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>