<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7261" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7261/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7261/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7261"><akn:num>7261</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for education innovation and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7261. Grants for education innovation and research(a) Program authorized(1) In generalFrom funds reserved under section 7251(b)(2)(A) of this title, the Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to—(A) create, develop, implement, replicate, or take to scale entrepreneurial, evidence-based, field-initiated innovations to improve student achievement and attainment for high-need students; and

(B) rigorously evaluate such innovations, in accordance with subsection (e).


(2) Description of grantsThe grants described in paragraph (1) shall include—(A) early-phase grants to fund the development, implementation, and feasibility testing of a program, which prior research suggests has promise, for the purpose of determining whether the program can successfully improve student achievement or attainment for high-need students;

(B) mid-phase grants to fund implementation and a rigorous evaluation of a program that has been successfully implemented under an early-phase grant described in subparagraph (A) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purpose of measuring the program’s impact and cost effectiveness, if possible using existing administrative data; and

(C) expansion grants to fund implementation and a rigorous replication evaluation of a program that has been found to produce sizable, important impacts under a mid-phase grant described in subparagraph (B) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purposes of—(i) determining whether such impacts can be successfully reproduced and sustained over time; and

(ii) identifying the conditions in which the program is most effective.




(b) Eligible entityIn this subpart, the term “eligible entity” means any of the following:(1) A local educational agency.

(2) A State educational agency.

(3) The Bureau of Indian Education.

(4) A consortium of State educational agencies or local educational agencies.

(5) A nonprofit organization.

(6) A State educational agency, a l</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entity In this subpart, the term “eligible entity” means any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rural areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching funds In order to receive a grant under subsection (a), an eligible entity shall demonstrate that the eligible entity will provide matching funds, in cash or through in-kind contributions, from Federal, State, local, or private sources in an amount equal to 10 percent of the funds provided under such grant, except that the Secretary may waive the matching funds requirement, on a case-by-case basis, upon a showing of exceptional circumstances, such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation Each recipient of a grant under this section shall conduct an independent evaluation of the effectiveness of the program carried out under such grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7261_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical assistance The Secretary may reserve not more than 5 percent of the funds appropriated under section 7251(b)(2)(A) of this title for each fiscal year to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>