<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7274" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7274/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7274/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7274"><akn:num>7274</akn:num><akn:heading>Promise neighborhoods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7274. Promise neighborhoods(a) Application requirementsAn eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, including, at a minimum, all of the following:(1) A plan to significantly improve the academic outcomes of children living in a neighborhood that is served by the eligible entity—(A) by providing pipeline services that address the needs of children in the neighborhood, as identified by the needs analysis described in paragraph (4); and

(B) that is supported by effective practices.


(2) A description of the neighborhood that the eligible entity will serve.

(3) Measurable annual objectives and outcomes for the grant, in accordance with the metrics described in subsection (h), for each year of the grant.

(4) An analysis of the needs and assets of the neighborhood identified in paragraph (1), including—(A) the size and scope of the population affected;

(B) a description of the process through which the needs analysis was produced, including a description of how parents, families, and community members were engaged in such analysis;

(C) an analysis of community assets and collaborative efforts (including programs already provided from Federal and non-Federal sources) within, or accessible to, the neighborhood, including, at a minimum, early learning opportunities, family and student supports, local businesses, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education;

(D) the steps that the eligible entity is taking, at the time of the application, to address the needs identified in the needs analysis; and

(E) any barriers the eligible entity, public agencies, and other community-based organizations have faced in meeting such needs.


(5) A description of—(A) all information that the entity used to identify the pipeline services to be provided, which shall not include information that is more than 3 y</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application requirements An eligible entity desiring a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, including, at a minimum, all of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority In awarding grants for activities described in this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that will use funds under subsection (d) for evidence-based activities, which, for purposes of this subsection, is defined as activities meeting the requirements of section 7801(21)(A)(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Memorandum of understanding As eligible entity shall, as part of the application described in subsection (a), submit a preliminary memorandum of understanding, signed by each partner entity or agency described in section 7272(1)(A)(3) of this title (if applicable) and detailing each partner’s financial, programmatic, and long-term commitment with respect to the strategies described in the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uses of funds Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart to carry out a program of activities described in this section shall use the grant funds to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall prepare and submit an annual report to the Secretary, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicly available data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Publicly available data Each eligible entity that receives a grant under this subpart for activities described in this section shall make publicly available, including through electronic means, the information described in subsection (f). To the extent practicable, such information shall be provided in a form and language accessible to parents and families in the neighborhood served under the grant, and such information shall be a part of statewide longitudinal data systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance indicators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Performance indicators</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7274_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Evaluation The Secretary shall reserve not more than 5 percent of the funds made available under section 7251(b)(2)(A) of this title to provide technical assistance and evaluate the implementation and impact of the activities funded under this section, in accordance with section 7981 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>