<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7425" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7425/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7425/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7425"><akn:num>7425</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized services and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7425. Authorized services and activities(a) General requirementsEach local educational agency that receives a grant under this subpart shall use the grant funds, in a manner consistent with the purpose specified in section 7421 of this title, for services and activities that—(1) are designed to carry out the comprehensive program of the local educational agency for Indian students, and described in the application of the local educational agency submitted to the Secretary under section 7424(a) of this title solely for the services and activities described in such application;

(2) are designed to be responsive to the language and cultural needs of the Indian students; and

(3) supplement and enrich the regular school program of such agency.


(b) Particular activitiesThe services and activities referred to in subsection (a) may include—(1) activities that support Native American language programs and Native American language restoration programs, which may be taught by traditional leaders;

(2) culturally related activities that support the program described in the application submitted by the local educational agency;

(3) early childhood and family programs that emphasize school readiness;

(4) enrichment programs that focus on problem solving and cognitive skills development and directly support the attainment of challenging State academic standards;

(5) integrated educational services in combination with other programs that meet the needs of Indian children and their families, including programs that promote parental involvement in school activities and increase student achievement;

(6) career preparation activities to enable Indian students to participate in programs such as the programs supported by the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (20 U.S.C. 2301 et seq.), including programs for mentoring and apprenticeship;

(7) activities to educate individuals so as to prevent violence, suicide, and substance abuse;

(8) the acquisition of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7425_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirements Each local educational agency that receives a grant under this subpart shall use the grant funds, in a manner consistent with the purpose specified in section 7421 of this title, for services and activities that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7425_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Particular activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Particular activities The services and activities referred to in subsection (a) may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7425_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Schoolwide programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Schoolwide programs Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a local educational agency may use funds made available to such agency under this subpart to support a schoolwide program under section 6314 of this title if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7425_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on administrative costs Not more than 5 percent of the funds provided to a grantee under this subpart for any fiscal year may be used for administrative purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7425_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on the use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on the use of funds Funds provided to a grantee under this subpart may not be used for long-distance travel expenses for training activities that are available locally or regionally.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>