<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7426" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7426/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7426/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7426"><akn:num>7426</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of services authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7426. Integration of services authorized(a) PlanAn entity receiving funds under this subpart may submit a plan to the Secretary for the integration of education and related services provided to Indian students.


(b) Consolidation of programsUpon the receipt of an acceptable plan under subsection (a), the Secretary, in cooperation with each Federal agency providing grants for the provision of education and related services to the entity, shall authorize the entity to consolidate, in accordance with such plan, the federally funded education and related services programs of the entity and the Federal programs, or portions of the programs, serving Indian students in a manner that integrates the program services involved into a single, coordinated, comprehensive program and reduces administrative costs by consolidating administrative functions.


(c) Programs affectedThe funds that may be consolidated in a demonstration project under any such plan referred to in subsection (a) shall include funds for any Federal program exclusively serving Indian children, or the funds reserved under any Federal program to exclusively serve Indian children, under which the entity is eligible for receipt of funds under a statutory or administrative formula for the purposes of providing education and related services that would be used to serve Indian students.


(d) Plan requirementsFor a plan to be acceptable pursuant to subsection (b), the plan shall—(1) identify the programs or funding sources to be consolidated;

(2) be consistent with the objectives of this section concerning authorizing the services to be integrated in a demonstration project;

(3) describe a comprehensive strategy that identifies the full range of potential educational opportunities and related services to be provided to assist Indian students to achieve the objectives set forth in this subpart;

(4) describe the way in which services are to be integrated and delivered and the results expected from the plan;

(5</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan An entity receiving funds under this subpart may submit a plan to the Secretary for the integration of education and related services provided to Indian students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consolidation of programs Upon the receipt of an acceptable plan under subsection (a), the Secretary, in cooperation with each Federal agency providing grants for the provision of education and related services to the entity, shall authorize the entity to consolidate, in accordance with such plan, the federally funded education and related services programs of the entity and the Federal programs, or portions of the programs, serving Indian students in a manner that integrates the program services involved into a single, coordinated, comprehensive program and reduces administrative costs by consolidating administrative functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs affected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programs affected The funds that may be consolidated in a demonstration project under any such plan referred to in subsection (a) shall include funds for any Federal program exclusively serving Indian children, or the funds reserved under any Federal program to exclusively serve Indian children, under which the entity is eligible for receipt of funds under a statutory or administrative formula for the purposes of providing education and related services that would be used to serve Indian students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plan requirements For a plan to be acceptable pursuant to subsection (b), the plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan review Upon receipt of the plan from an eligible entity, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of each Federal department providing funds to be used to implement the plan, and with the entity submitting the plan. The parties so consulting shall identify any waivers of statutory requirements or of Federal departmental regulations, policies, or procedures necessary to enable the entity to implement the plan. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of the affected department shall have the authority to waive any regulation, policy, or procedure promulgated by that department that has been so identified by the entity or department, unless the Secretary of the affected department determines that such a waiver is inconsistent with the objectives of this subpart or those provisions of the statute from which the program involved derives authority that are specifically applicable to Indian students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plan approval Within 90 days after the receipt of an entity’s plan by the Secretary, the Secretary shall inform the entity, in writing, of the Secretary’s approval or disapproval of the plan. If the plan is disapproved, the entity shall be informed, in writing, of the reasons for the disapproval and shall be given an opportunity to amend the plan or to petition the Secretary to reconsider such disapproval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Department of Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Responsibilities of Department of Education Not later than 180 days after December 10, 2015, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the head of any other Federal department or agency identified by the Secretary of Education, shall enter into an interdepartmental memorandum of agreement providing for the implementation and coordination of the demonstration projects authorized under this section. The lead agency head for a demonstration project under this section shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of lead agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Responsibilities of lead agency The responsibilities of the lead agency shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report requirements A single report format shall be developed by the Secretary, consistent with the requirements of this section. Such report format shall require that reports described in subsection (h), together with records maintained on the consolidated program at the local level, shall contain such information as will allow a determination that the eligible entity has complied with the requirements incorporated in its approved plan, including making a demonstration of student academic achievement, and will provide assurances to each Secretary that the eligible entity has complied with all directly applicable statutory requirements and with those directly applicable regulatory requirements that have not been waived.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7426_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>No reduction in amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) No reduction in amounts In no case shall the amount of Federal funds available to an eligible entity involved in any demonstration project be reduced as a result of the enactment of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>