<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7427" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7427/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7427/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7427"><akn:num>7427</akn:num><akn:heading>Student eligibility forms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7427. Student eligibility forms(a) In generalThe Secretary shall require that, as part of an application for a grant under this subpart, each applicant shall maintain a file, with respect to each Indian child for whom the local educational agency provides a free public education, that contains a form that sets forth information establishing the status of the child as an Indian child eligible for assistance under this subpart, and that otherwise meets the requirements of subsection (b). All individual data collected shall be protected by the local educational agencies and only aggregated data shall be reported to the Secretary.


(b) FormsThe form described in subsection (a) shall include—(1) either—(A)(i) the name of the tribe or band of Indians (as defined in section 7491 of this title) with respect to which the child claims membership;

(ii) the enrollment number establishing the membership of the child (if readily available); and

(iii) the name and address of the organization that maintains updated and accurate membership data for such tribe or band of Indians; or


(B) the name, the enrollment number (if readily available), and the name and address of the organization responsible for maintaining updated and accurate membership data, of any parent or grandparent of the child from whom the child claims eligibility under this subpart, if the child is not a member of the tribe or band of Indians (as so defined);


(2) a statement of whether the tribe or band of Indians (as so defined), with respect to which the child, or parent or grandparent of the child, claims membership, is federally recognized;

(3) the name and address of the parent or legal guardian of the child;

(4) a signature of the parent or legal guardian of the child that verifies the accuracy of the information supplied; and

(5) any other information that the Secretary considers necessary to provide an accurate program profile.


(c) Statutory constructionNothing in this section shall be construed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall require that, as part of an application for a grant under this subpart, each applicant shall maintain a file, with respect to each Indian child for whom the local educational agency provides a free public education, that contains a form that sets forth information establishing the status of the child as an Indian child eligible for assistance under this subpart, and that otherwise meets the requirements of subsection (b). All individual data collected shall be protected by the local educational agencies and only aggregated data shall be reported to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Forms The form described in subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statutory construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect a definition contained in section 7491 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation and types of proof</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Documentation and types of proof</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and evaluation review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Monitoring and evaluation review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tribal grant and contract schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tribal grant and contract schools Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in calculating the amount of a grant under this subpart to a tribal school that receives a grant or contract from the Bureau of Indian Education, the Secretary shall use only one of the following, as selected by the school:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7427_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of child counts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Timing of child counts For purposes of determining the number of children to be counted in calculating the amount of a local educational agency’s grant under this subpart (other than in the case described in subsection (f)(1)), the local educational agency shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>