<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7428" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7428/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7428/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7428"><akn:num>7428</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7428. Payments(a) In generalSubject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall pay to each local educational agency that submits an application that is approved by the Secretary under this subpart the amount determined under section 7423 of this title. The Secretary shall notify the local educational agency of the amount of the payment not later than June 1 of the year for which the Secretary makes the payment.


(b) Payments taken into account by the StateThe Secretary may not make a grant under this subpart to a local educational agency for a fiscal year if, for such fiscal year, the State in which the local educational agency is located takes into consideration payments made under this chapter 11 So in original. Probably should be “this subpart”. in determining the eligibility of the local educational agency for State aid, or the amount of the State aid, with respect to the free public education of children during such fiscal year or the preceding fiscal year.


(c) Reduction of payment for failure to maintain fiscal effortEach local educational agency shall maintain fiscal effort in accordance with section 7901 of this title or be subject to reduced payments under this subpart in accordance with such section 7901 of this title.


(d) ReallocationsThe Secretary may reallocate, in a manner that the Secretary determines will best carry out the purpose of this subpart, any amounts that—(1) based on estimates made by local educational agencies or other information, the Secretary determines will not be needed by such agencies to carry out approved programs under this subpart; or

(2) otherwise become available for reallocation under this subpart.


(Pub. L. 89–10, title VI, § 6118, formerly title VII, § 7118, as added Pub. L. 107–110, title VII, § 701, Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1918; renumbered title VI, § 6118, and amended Pub. L. 114–95, title VI, §§ 6001(a), (b)(1), (8), 6002(j), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2046, 2047, 2054.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7428_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsections (b) and (c), the Secretary shall pay to each local educational agency that submits an application that is approved by the Secretary under this subpart the amount determined under section 7423 of this title. The Secretary shall notify the local educational agency of the amount of the payment not later than June 1 of the year for which the Secretary makes the payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7428_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments taken into account by the State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments taken into account by the State The Secretary may not make a grant under this subpart to a local educational agency for a fiscal year if, for such fiscal year, the State in which the local educational agency is located takes into consideration payments made under this chapter 11 So in original. Probably should be “this subpart”. in determining the eligibility of the local educational agency for State aid, or the amount of the State aid, with respect to the free public education of children during such fiscal year or the preceding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7428_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of payment for failure to maintain fiscal effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reduction of payment for failure to maintain fiscal effort Each local educational agency shall maintain fiscal effort in accordance with section 7901 of this title or be subject to reduced payments under this subpart in accordance with such section 7901 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7428_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallocations The Secretary may reallocate, in a manner that the Secretary determines will best carry out the purpose of this subpart, any amounts that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>