<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7441" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7441/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7441/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7441"><akn:num>7441</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of educational opportunities for Indian children and youth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7441. Improvement of educational opportunities for Indian children and youth(a) Purpose(1) In generalIt is the purpose of this section to support projects to develop, test, and demonstrate the effectiveness of services and programs to improve educational opportunities and achievement of Indian children and youth.


(2) CoordinationThe Secretary shall take the necessary actions to achieve the coordination of activities assisted under this subpart with—(A) other programs funded under this chapter; and

(B) other Federal programs operated for the benefit of Indian children and youth.



(b) Eligible entitiesIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State educational agency, local educational agency, Indian tribe, Indian organization, federally supported elementary school or secondary school for Indian students, a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 1059c(b) of this title), or a consortium of such entities.


(c) Grants authorizedThe Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to carry out activities that meet the purpose of this section, including—(1) innovative programs related to the educational needs of educationally disadvantaged Indian children and youth;

(2) educational services that are not available to such children and youth in sufficient quantity or quality, including remedial instruction, to raise the achievement of Indian children in one or more of the subjects of English, mathematics, science, foreign languages, art, history, and geography;

(3) bilingual and bicultural programs and projects;

(4) special health and nutrition services, and other related activities, that address the special health, social, and psychological problems of Indian children and youth;

(5) special compensatory and other programs and projects designed to assist and encourage Indian children and youth to enter, remain in, or reenter school, and to increase the rate of high school graduation for Indian children and youth;

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7441_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7441_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities In this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State educational agency, local educational agency, Indian tribe, Indian organization, federally supported elementary school or secondary school for Indian students, a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 1059c(b) of this title), or a consortium of such entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7441_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants authorized The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to carry out activities that meet the purpose of this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7441_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant requirements and applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant requirements and applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7441_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative costs Not more than 5 percent of the funds provided to a grantee under this subpart for any fiscal year may be used for administrative purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>