<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7452" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7452/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7452/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7452"><akn:num>7452</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to tribes for education administrative planning, development, and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7452. Grants to tribes for education administrative planning, development, and coordination(a) In generalThe Secretary may award grants under this section to eligible applicants to enable the eligible applicants to—(1) promote tribal self-determination in education;

(2) improve the academic achievement of Indian children and youth; and

(3) promote the coordination and collaboration of tribal educational agencies with State educational agencies and local educational agencies to meet the unique educational and culturally related academic needs of Indian students.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible applicantIn this section, the term “eligible applicant” means—(A) an Indian tribe or tribal organization approved by an Indian tribe; or

(B) a tribal educational agency.


(2) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” means a federally recognized tribe or a State-recognized tribe.


(3) Tribal educational agencyThe term “tribal educational agency” means the agency, department, or instrumentality of an Indian tribe that is primarily responsible for supporting tribal students’ elementary and secondary education.



(c) Grant programThe Secretary may award grants to—(1) eligible applicants described under subsection (b)(1)(A) to plan and develop a tribal educational agency, if the tribe or organization has no current tribal educational agency, for a period of not more than 1 year; and

(2) eligible applicants described under subsection (b)(1)(B), for a period of not more than 3 years, in order to—(A) directly administer education programs, including formula grant programs under this chapter, consistent with State law and under a written agreement between the parties;

(B) build capacity to administer and coordinate such education programs, and to improve the relationship and coordination between such applicants and the State educational agencies and local educational agencies that educate students from the tribe;

(C) receive training and support from the State educat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may award grants under this section to eligible applicants to enable the eligible applicants to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant program The Secretary may award grants to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7452_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Supplement, not supplant Funds under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, and local programs that meet the needs of tribal students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>