<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/74a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/74a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/74a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_74a"><akn:num>74a</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent loan of funds by Board of Trustees to Treasury; semiannual interest payments to Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 74a. Permanent loan of funds by Board of Trustees to Treasury; semiannual interest payments to Board
The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to receive into the Treasury from time to time as a permanent loan by the Board of Trustees of the National Gallery of Art to the United States sums in cash of not to exceed $5,000,000 in the aggregate, and to pay interest on the principal amount of such loan at a rate which is the higher of the rate of 4 per centum per annum or a rate which is .25 percentage points less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding long-term marketable obligations of the United States, adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum, payable semiannually. Such interest is permanently appropriated for payment to the Board of Trustees of the National Gallery of Art.
(Apr. 10, 1943, ch. 46, 57 Stat. 62; Pub. L. 94–418, Sept. 21, 1976, 90 Stat. 1278.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of act Mar. 24, 1937, ch. 50, 50 Stat. 51, which comprises this subchapter.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–418 inserted provision authorizing alternate interest rate to existing interest rate of 4 per centum per annum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>