<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7517"><akn:num>7517</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7517. Definitions
In this part:(1) Community consultationThe term “community consultation” means a public gathering—(A) to discuss Native Hawaiian education concerns; and

(B) about which the public has been given not less than 30 days notice.


(2) Native HawaiianThe term “Native Hawaiian” means any individual who is—(A) a citizen of the United States; and

(B) a descendant of the aboriginal people who, prior to 1778, occupied and exercised sovereignty in the area that now comprises the State of Hawaii, as evidenced by—(i) genealogical records;

(ii) Kupuna (elders) or Kamaaina (long-term community residents) verification; or

(iii) certified birth records.



(3) Native Hawaiian community-based organizationThe term “Native Hawaiian community-based organization” means any organization that is composed primarily of Native Hawaiians from a specific community and that assists in the social, cultural, and educational development of Native Hawaiians in that community.


(4) Native Hawaiian educational organizationThe term “Native Hawaiian educational organization” means a private nonprofit organization that—(A) serves the interests of Native Hawaiians;

(B) has Native Hawaiians in substantive and policymaking positions within the organization;

(C) incorporates Native Hawaiian perspective, values, language, culture, and traditions into the core function of the organization;

(D) has demonstrated expertise in the education of Native Hawaiian youth; and

(E) has demonstrated expertise in research and program development.


(5) Native Hawaiian languageThe term “Native Hawaiian language” means the single Native American language indigenous to the original inhabitants of the State of Hawaii.


(6) Native Hawaiian organizationThe term “Native Hawaiian organization” means a private nonprofit organization that—(A) serves the interests of Native Hawaiians;

(B) has Native Hawaiians in substantive and policymaking positions within the organization; and

(C) is recognized by the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Community consultation The term “community consultation” means a public gathering—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native Hawaiian</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Native Hawaiian The term “Native Hawaiian” means any individual who is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native Hawaiian community-based organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Native Hawaiian community-based organization The term “Native Hawaiian community-based organization” means any organization that is composed primarily of Native Hawaiians from a specific community and that assists in the social, cultural, and educational development of Native Hawaiians in that community.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native Hawaiian educational organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Native Hawaiian educational organization The term “Native Hawaiian educational organization” means a private nonprofit organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native Hawaiian language</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Native Hawaiian language The term “Native Hawaiian language” means the single Native American language indigenous to the original inhabitants of the State of Hawaii.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Native Hawaiian organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Native Hawaiian organization The term “Native Hawaiian organization” means a private nonprofit organization that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7517_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Hawaiian Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Office of Hawaiian Affairs The term “Office of Hawaiian Affairs” means the Office of Hawaiian Affairs established by the Constitution of the State of Hawaii.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>