<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_76c"><akn:num>76c</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy to foster appreciation of past and contemporary art</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 76c. Policy to foster appreciation of past and contemporary art(a) Solicitations of private donationsIt shall be the policy of the Regents to maintain a worthy standard for the acceptance of art objects for exhibition in the Gallery, and to foster by public exhibitions from time to time in Washington, and other parts of the United States a growing appreciation of art, both of past and contemporary time; and the Regents are authorized to solicit and receive private donations of works of art and contributions of funds from private sources for the purchase of works of art. Funds so received shall be placed in a special deposit account with the Treasurer of the United States and may be expended by the Regents for the purchase of works of art.


(b) Solicitation of funds to acquire and sell works of art, employ artists, award scholarships, etc.In order to encourage the development of contemporary art and to effect the widest distribution and cultivation in matters of such art, the Regents are authorized to solicit and receive funds from private sources, to acquire (by purchase or otherwise) and sell contemporary works of art or copies thereof, to employ artists and other personnel, award scholarships, conduct exhibitions, and generally to do such things and have such other powers as will effectuate the purposes of this subsection. Funds received by the Regents under this subsection shall be placed in a special deposit account with the Treasurer of the United States and may be expended by the Regents for the purposes enumerated in this subsection and for no other purposes: Provided, That the Regents shall not incur any obligations under this subsection in excess of the funds available therefor.


(May 17, 1938, ch. 238, § 4, 52 Stat. 400.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitations of private donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Solicitations of private donations It shall be the policy of the Regents to maintain a worthy standard for the acceptance of art objects for exhibition in the Gallery, and to foster by public exhibitions from time to time in Washington, and other parts of the United States a growing appreciation of art, both of past and contemporary time; and the Regents are authorized to solicit and receive private donations of works of art and contributions of funds from private sources for the purchase of works of art. Funds so received shall be placed in a special deposit account with the Treasurer of the United States and may be expended by the Regents for the purchase of works of art.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of funds to acquire and sell works of art, employ artists, award scholarships, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Solicitation of funds to acquire and sell works of art, employ artists, award scholarships, etc. In order to encourage the development of contemporary art and to effect the widest distribution and cultivation in matters of such art, the Regents are authorized to solicit and receive funds from private sources, to acquire (by purchase or otherwise) and sell contemporary works of art or copies thereof, to employ artists and other personnel, award scholarships, conduct exhibitions, and generally to do such things and have such other powers as will effectuate the purposes of this subsection. Funds received by the Regents under this subsection shall be placed in a special deposit account with the Treasurer of the United States and may be expended by the Regents for the purposes enumerated in this subsection and for no other purposes: Provided, That the Regents shall not incur any obligations under this subsection in excess of the funds available therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>