<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76q–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76q–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/76q–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_76q_1"><akn:num>76q–1</akn:num><akn:heading>John F. Kennedy Center Plaza</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 76q–1. John F. Kennedy Center Plaza(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions apply:(1) Air rightsThe term “air rights” means real property interests conveyed by deed, lease, or permit for the use of space between streets and alleys within the boundaries of the Project.


(2) CenterThe term “Center” means the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts.


(3) Green spacesThe term “green spaces” means areas within the boundaries of the Project or affected by the Project that are covered by grass, trees, or other vegetation.


(4) PlazaThe term “Plaza” means improvements to the area surrounding the John F. Kennedy Center building carried out under the Project and comprised of transportation elements (including roadways, sidewalks, and bicycle lanes) and non-transportation elements (including landscaping, green space, open public space, water, sewer, and utility connections).


(5) ProjectThe term “Project” means the Plaza project, as described in the TEA–21 report, providing for construction of a Plaza adjacent to the Center and for improved bicycle, pedestrian, and vehicular access to and around the Center. The term includes planning, design, engineering, and construction of the Plaza, buildings to be constructed on the Plaza, and related transportation improvements and may include any other elements of the Project identified in the TEA–21 report.


(6) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Transportation.


(7) TEA–21 reportThe term “TEA–21 report” means the report of the Secretary submitted to Congress under section 1214 of the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century (20 U.S.C. 76j note; 112 Stat. 204).



(b) Responsibilities of the Secretary(1) In generalThe Secretary shall be responsible for the Project and may undertake such activities as may be necessary to construct the Project, other than buildings to be constructed on the Plaza, substantially as described in the TEA–21 report.


(2) Planning, design, engineering, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibilities of the Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities of the Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the District of Columbia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Responsibilities of the District of Columbia</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ownership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National highway boundaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National highway boundaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_76q_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) GAO review Until completion of the Project, the Comptroller General shall review the management and oversight of construction of the Project by the Board and report periodically on the results of the review to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>