<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/77" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/77/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/77/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_77"><akn:num>77</akn:num><akn:heading>National Air and Space Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 77. National Air and Space Museum(a) Establishment; board; administration; reimbursement of expensesThere is hereby established under the Smithsonian Institution a bureau to be known as a National Air and Space Museum, which shall be administered by the Smithsonian Institution with the advice of a board to be composed of the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, or his designee, the Chief of Space Operations, or the Chief’s designee, the Chief of Naval Operations, or his designee, the Chief of Staff of the Army, or his designee, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, or his designee, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, or his designee, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or his designee, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or his designee, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and three citizens of the United States appointed by the President from civilian life who shall serve at the pleasure of the President. The members of the board shall serve as such members without compensation but shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as members of the board.


(b) Appointment and compensation of head of museumThe Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, with the advice of the board, may appoint and fix the compensation and duties of the head of a national air and space museum whose appointment shall not be subject to the civil service laws.


(Aug. 12, 1946, ch. 955, § 1, 60 Stat. 997; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 208(b), 61 Stat. 503; Pub. L. 89–509, pt. I, §§ 2, 3, July 19, 1966, 80 Stat. 310; Pub. L. 89–670, §§ 3(e), 6(c)(1), Oct. 15, 1966, 80 Stat. 932, 938; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title IX, § 927(g), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 3832.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 116–283, which directed amendment of subsec. (a) of section 1 of the Act of August 12, 1946 (60 Stat. 997, chapter 995; 20 U.S.C. 77(a)) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; board; administration; reimbursement of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; board; administration; reimbursement of expenses There is hereby established under the Smithsonian Institution a bureau to be known as a National Air and Space Museum, which shall be administered by the Smithsonian Institution with the advice of a board to be composed of the Chief of Staff of the Air Force, or his designee, the Chief of Space Operations, or the Chief’s designee, the Chief of Naval Operations, or his designee, the Chief of Staff of the Army, or his designee, the Commandant of the Marine Corps, or his designee, the Commandant of the Coast Guard, or his designee, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, or his designee, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, or his designee, the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, and three citizens of the United States appointed by the President from civilian life who shall serve at the pleasure of the President. The members of the board shall serve as such member</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_77_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and compensation of head of museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment and compensation of head of museum The Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, with the advice of the board, may appoint and fix the compensation and duties of the head of a national air and space museum whose appointment shall not be subject to the civil service laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>