<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7703c"><akn:num>7703c</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan and authority to assist local educational agencies experiencing growth in enrollment due to for</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7703c. Plan and authority to assist local educational agencies experiencing growth in enrollment due to force structure changes, relocation of military units, or base closures and realignments(a) Plan requiredNot later than January 1, 2007, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth a plan to provide assistance to local educational agencies that experience growth in the enrollment of military dependent students as a result of any of the following events:(1) Force structure changes.

(2) The relocation of a military unit.

(3) The closure or realignment of military installations pursuant to defense base closure and realignment under the base closure laws.


(b) ElementsThe report required by subsection (a), and each updated report required by subsection (c),11 See References in Text note below. shall include the following:(1) An identification, current as of the date of the report, of the total number of military dependent students who are anticipated to be arriving at or departing from military installations as a result of any event described in subsection (a), including—(A) an identification of the military installations affected by such arrivals and departures;

(B) an estimate of the number of such students arriving at or departing from each such installation; and

(C) the anticipated schedule of such arrivals and departures.


(2) Such recommendations as the Office of Economic Adjustment of the Department of Defense considers appropriate for means of assisting affected local educational agencies in accommodating increases in enrollment of military dependent students as a result of any such event.

(3) A plan for outreach to be conducted to affected local educational agencies, commanders of military installations, and members of the Armed Forces and civilian personnel of the Department of Defense regarding information on the assistance to be provided under the plan under subsection (a).


(c) Transition </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan required Not later than January 1, 2007, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth a plan to provide assistance to local educational agencies that experience growth in the enrollment of military dependent students as a result of any of the following events:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements The report required by subsection (a), and each updated report required by subsection (c),11 See References in Text note below. shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transition of military dependents among local educational agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transition of military dependents among local educational agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>