<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7703a"><akn:num>7703a</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact aid for children with severe disabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7703a. Impact aid for children with severe disabilities(a) PaymentsSubject to subsection (f), the Secretary of Defense shall make a payment for fiscal years after fiscal year 2001, to each local educational agency eligible to receive a payment for a child described in subparagraph (A)(ii) or (B), or clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (D), of section 7703(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title that serves two or more such children with severe disabilities, for costs incurred in providing a free appropriate public education to each such child.


(b) Payment amountThe amount of the payment under subsection (a) to a local educational agency for a fiscal year for each child referred to in such subsection with a severe disability shall be—(1) the payment made on behalf of the child with a severe disability that is in excess of the average per pupil expenditure in the State in which the local educational agency is located; less

(2) the sum of the funds received by the local educational agency—(A) from the State in which the child resides to defray the educational and related services for such child;

(B) under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.) to defray the educational and related services for such child; and

(C) from any other source to defray the costs of providing educational and related services to the child which are received due to the presence of a severe disabling condition of such child.



(c) ExclusionsNo payment shall be made under subsection (a) on behalf of a child with a severe disability whose individual cost of educational and related services does not exceed—(1) five times the national or State average per pupil expenditure (whichever is lower), for a child who is provided educational and related services under a program that is located outside the boundaries of the school district of the local educational agency that pays for the free appropriate public education of the student; or

(2) three </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments Subject to subsection (f), the Secretary of Defense shall make a payment for fiscal years after fiscal year 2001, to each local educational agency eligible to receive a payment for a child described in subparagraph (A)(ii) or (B), or clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (D), of section 7703(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title that serves two or more such children with severe disabilities, for costs incurred in providing a free appropriate public education to each such child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment amount The amount of the payment under subsection (a) to a local educational agency for a fiscal year for each child referred to in such subsection with a severe disability shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusions No payment shall be made under subsection (a) on behalf of a child with a severe disability whose individual cost of educational and related services does not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ratable reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ratable reduction If the amount available for a fiscal year for payments under subsection (a) is insufficient to pay the full amount all local educational agencies are eligible to receive under such subsection, the Secretary of Defense shall ratably reduce the amounts of the payments made under such subsection to all local educational agencies by an equal percentage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Each local educational agency desiring a payment under subsection (a) shall report to the Secretary of Defense—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments subject to appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payments subject to appropriation Payments shall be made for any period in a fiscal year under this section only to the extent that funds are appropriated specifically for making such payments for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local educational agency defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Local educational agency defined In this section, the term “local educational agency” has the meaning given that term in section 7713 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>