<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7703d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7703d"><akn:num>7703d</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to local educational agencies that benefit dependents of members of the Armed Forces with</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7703d. Assistance to local educational agencies that benefit dependents of members of the Armed Forces with enrollment changes due to base closures, force structure changes, or force relocations(a) Assistance authorizedTo assist communities in making adjustments resulting from changes in the size or location of the Armed Forces, the Secretary of Defense shall provide financial assistance to an eligible local educational agency described in subsection (b) if, during the period between the end of the school year preceding the fiscal year for which the assistance is authorized and the beginning of the school year immediately preceding that school year, the local educational agency had (as determined by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of Education) an overall increase or reduction of—(1) not less than five percent in the average daily attendance of military dependent students in the schools of the local educational agency; or

(2) not less than 500 military dependent students in average daily attendance in the schools of the local educational agency.


(b) Eligible local educational agenciesA local educational agency is eligible for assistance under subsection (a) for a fiscal year if—(1) 20 percent or more of students enrolled in schools of the local educational agency are military dependent students; and

(2) in the case of assistance described in subsection (a)(1), the overall increase or reduction in military dependent students in schools of the local educational agency is the result of one or more of the following:(A) The global rebasing plan of the Department of Defense.

(B) The official creation or activation of one or more new military units.

(C) The realignment of forces as a result of the base closure process.

(D) A change in the number of housing units on a military installation.

(E) A signed record of decision.



(c) Calculation of amount of assistance(1) Pro rata distributionThe amount of the assistance provided under subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance authorized To assist communities in making adjustments resulting from changes in the size or location of the Armed Forces, the Secretary of Defense shall provide financial assistance to an eligible local educational agency described in subsection (b) if, during the period between the end of the school year preceding the fiscal year for which the assistance is authorized and the beginning of the school year immediately preceding that school year, the local educational agency had (as determined by the Secretary of Defense in consultation with the Secretary of Education) an overall increase or reduction of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible local educational agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible local educational agencies A local educational agency is eligible for assistance under subsection (a) for a fiscal year if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of amount of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Calculation of amount of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duration Assistance may not be provided under subsection (a) after September 30, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notification Not later than June 30, 2023, and June 30 of each fiscal year thereafter for which funds are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary of Defense shall notify each local educational agency that is eligible for assistance under subsection (a) for that fiscal year of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disbursement of funds The Secretary of Defense shall disburse assistance made available under subsection (a) for a fiscal year not later than 30 days after the date on which notification to the eligible local educational agencies is provided pursuant to subsection (e) for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Briefing required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Briefing required Not later than March 1, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the estimated cost of providing assistance to local educational agencies under subsection (a) through September 30, 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7703d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>