<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7710"><akn:num>7710</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7710. Federal administration(a) Payments in whole dollar amountsThe Secretary shall round any payments under this subchapter to the nearest whole dollar amount.


(b) Other agenciesEach Federal agency administering Federal property on which children reside, and each agency principally responsible for an activity that may occasion assistance under this subchapter, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, comply with requests of the Secretary for information the Secretary may require to carry out this subchapter.


(c) Special rules(1) Certain children eligible under subparagraphs (A) and (G)(ii) of section 7703(a)(1)(A) The Secretary shall treat as eligible under subparagraph (A) of section 7703(a)(1) of this title any child who would be eligible under such subparagraph except that the Federal property on which the child resides or on which the child’s parent is employed is not in the same State in which the child attends school, if such child meets the requirements of paragraph (2).

(B) The Secretary shall treat as eligible under subparagraph (G) of section 7703(a)(1) of this title any child who would be eligible under such subparagraph except that such child does not meet the requirements of clause (ii) of such subparagraph, if such child meets the requirements of paragraph (2).


(2) RequirementsA child meets the requirements of this paragraph if—(A) such child resides—(i) in a State adjacent to the State in which the local educational agency serving the school such child attends is located; or

(ii) with a parent employed on Federal property in a State adjacent to the State in which such agency is located;


(B) the schools of such agency are within a more reasonable commuting distance of such child’s home than the schools of the local educational agency that serves the school attendance area where such child resides;

(C) attending the schools of the local educational agency that serves the school attendance area where such child resides will impose a substa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments in whole dollar amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments in whole dollar amounts The Secretary shall round any payments under this subchapter to the nearest whole dollar amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other agencies Each Federal agency administering Federal property on which children reside, and each agency principally responsible for an activity that may occasion assistance under this subchapter, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, comply with requests of the Secretary for information the Secretary may require to carry out this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timely payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>