<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7713"><akn:num>7713</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7713. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) Armed ForcesThe term “Armed Forces” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard.


(2) Average per-pupil expenditureThe term “average per-pupil expenditure” means—(A) the aggregate current expenditures of all local educational agencies in the State; divided by

(B) the total number of children in average daily attendance for whom such agencies provided free public education.


(3) ConstructionThe term “construction” means—(A) the preparation of drawings and specifications for school facilities;

(B) erecting, building, acquiring, altering, remodeling, repairing, or extending school facilities;

(C) inspecting and supervising the construction of school facilities; and

(D) debt service for such activities.


(4) Current expendituresThe term “current expenditures” means expenditures for free public education, including expenditures for administration, instruction, attendance and health services, pupil transportation services, operation and maintenance of plant, fixed charges, and net expenditures to cover deficits for food services and student body activities, but does not include expenditures for community services, capital outlay, and debt service, or any expenditures made from funds awarded under part A of subchapter I. The determination of whether an expenditure for the replacement of equipment is considered a current expenditure or a capital outlay shall be determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles as determined by the State.


(5) Federal property(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraphs (B) through (F), the term “Federal property” means real property that is not subject to taxation by any State or any political subdivision of a State due to Federal agreement, law, or policy, and that is—(i) owned by the United States or leased by the United States from another entity;

(ii)(I) held in trust by the United States for individual Indians or Indian tribes;</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Armed Forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Armed Forces The term “Armed Forces” means the Army, Navy, Air Force, Marine Corps, and Coast Guard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Average per-pupil expenditure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Average per-pupil expenditure The term “average per-pupil expenditure” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Construction The term “construction” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Current expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Current expenditures The term “current expenditures” means expenditures for free public education, including expenditures for administration, instruction, attendance and health services, pupil transportation services, operation and maintenance of plant, fixed charges, and net expenditures to cover deficits for food services and student body activities, but does not include expenditures for community services, capital outlay, and debt service, or any expenditures made from funds awarded under part A of subchapter I. The determination of whether an expenditure for the replacement of equipment is considered a current expenditure or a capital outlay shall be determined in accordance with generally accepted accounting principles as determined by the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Federal property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free public education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Free public education The term “free public education” means education that is provided—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian lands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Indian lands The term “Indian lands” means any Federal property described in paragraph (5)(A)(ii) or (5)(F).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local contribution percentage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Local contribution percentage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local educational agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Local educational agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-rent housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Low-rent housing The term “low-rent housing” means housing located on property that is described in paragraph (5)(A)(iii).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>