<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7824" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7824/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7824/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7824"><akn:num>7824</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated set-aside for Department of the Interior funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7824. Consolidated set-aside for Department of the Interior funds(a) General authority(1) TransferThe Secretary shall transfer to the Department of the Interior, as a consolidated amount for covered programs, the Indian education programs under part A of subchapter VI, and the education for homeless children and youth program under subtitle B of title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 11431 et seq.], the amounts allotted to the Department of the Interior under those programs.


(2) Agreement(A) In generalThe Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall enter into an agreement, consistent with the requirements of the programs specified in paragraph (1), for the distribution and use of those program funds under terms that the Secretary determines best meet the purposes of those programs.


(B) ContentsThe agreement shall—(i) set forth the plans of the Secretary of the Interior for the use of the amount transferred and the achievement measures to assess program effectiveness, including program objectives; and

(ii) be developed in consultation with Indian tribes.




(b) AdministrationThe Department of the Interior may use not more than 1.5 percent of the funds consolidated under this section for its costs related to the administration of the funds transferred under this section.


(c) Accountability system(1) For the purposes of part A of subchapter I, the Secretary of Interior, in consultation with the Secretary, if the Secretary of the Interior requests the consultation, using a negotiated rulemaking process to develop regulations for implementation no later than the 2017-2018 academic year, shall define the standards, assessments, and accountability system consistent with section 6311 of this title, for the schools funded by the Bureau of Indian Education on a national, regional, or tribal basis, as appropriate, taking into account the unique circumstances and needs of such schools and the students served by such schools.

(2) The </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7824_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7824_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration The Department of the Interior may use not more than 1.5 percent of the funds consolidated under this section for its costs related to the administration of the funds transferred under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7824_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accountability system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>