<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7845" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7845/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7845/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7845"><akn:num>7845</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated local plans or applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7845. Consolidated local plans or applications(a) General authority(1) Consolidated planA local educational agency receiving funds under more than one covered program may submit plans or applications to the State educational agency under those programs on a consolidated basis.


(2) Availability to GovernorThe State educational agency shall make any consolidated local plans and applications available to the Governor.



(b) Required consolidated plans or applicationsA State educational agency that has an approved consolidated State plan or application under section 7842 of this title may require local educational agencies in the State receiving funds under more than one program included in the consolidated State plan or consolidated State application to submit consolidated local plans or applications under those programs, but may not require those agencies to submit separate plans.


(c) CollaborationA State educational agency, in consultation with the Governor, shall collaborate with local educational agencies in the State in establishing procedures for the submission of the consolidated State plans or consolidated State applications under this section.


(d) Necessary materialsThe State educational agency shall require only descriptions, information, assurances, and other material that are absolutely necessary for the consideration of the local educational agency plan or application.


(e) Rural consolidated plan(1) In generalTwo or more eligible local educational agencies, a consortium of eligible local educational service agencies, or an educational service agency on behalf of eligible local educational agencies may submit plans or applications for 1 or more covered programs to the State educational agency on a consolidated basis, if each eligible local educational agency impacted elects to participate in the joint application or elects to allow the educational service agency to apply on its behalf.


(2) Eligible local educational agencyFor the purposes of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7845_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7845_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required consolidated plans or applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required consolidated plans or applications A State educational agency that has an approved consolidated State plan or application under section 7842 of this title may require local educational agencies in the State receiving funds under more than one program included in the consolidated State plan or consolidated State application to submit consolidated local plans or applications under those programs, but may not require those agencies to submit separate plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7845_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Collaboration A State educational agency, in consultation with the Governor, shall collaborate with local educational agencies in the State in establishing procedures for the submission of the consolidated State plans or consolidated State applications under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7845_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessary materials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Necessary materials The State educational agency shall require only descriptions, information, assurances, and other material that are absolutely necessary for the consideration of the local educational agency plan or application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7845_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural consolidated plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rural consolidated plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>