<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7883" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7883/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7883/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7883"><akn:num>7883</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaint process for participation of private school children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7883. Complaint process for participation of private school children(a) Procedures for complaintsThe Secretary shall develop and implement written procedures for receiving, investigating, and resolving complaints from parents, teachers, or other individuals and organizations concerning violations of section 7881 of this title by a State educational agency, local educational agency, educational service agency, consortium of those agencies, or entity. The individual or organization shall submit the complaint to the State educational agency for a written resolution by the State educational agency within 45 days.


(b) Appeals to SecretaryThe resolution may be appealed by an interested party to the Secretary not later than 30 days after the State educational agency resolves the complaint or fails to resolve the complaint within the 45-day time limit. The appeal shall be accompanied by a copy of the State educational agency’s resolution, and, if there is one, a complete statement of the reasons supporting the appeal. The Secretary shall investigate and resolve the appeal not later than 90 days after receipt of the appeal.


(Pub. L. 89–10, title VIII, § 8503, formerly title IX, § 9503, as added Pub. L. 107–110, title IX, § 901, Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1977; renumbered title VIII, § 8503, and amended Pub. L. 114–95, title VIII, §§ 8001(a)(5), 8017, Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2088, 2089, 2111.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2015—Pub. L. 114–95, § 8017, added subsecs. (a) and (b) and struck out former subsecs. (a) and (b) which related to procedures for complaints and appeals to Secretary, respectively.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2015 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 114–95 effective Dec. 10, 2015, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95, set out as a note under section 6301 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7883_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for complaints</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Procedures for complaints The Secretary shall develop and implement written procedures for receiving, investigating, and resolving complaints from parents, teachers, or other individuals and organizations concerning violations of section 7881 of this title by a State educational agency, local educational agency, educational service agency, consortium of those agencies, or entity. The individual or organization shall submit the complaint to the State educational agency for a written resolution by the State educational agency within 45 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7883_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appeals to Secretary The resolution may be appealed by an interested party to the Secretary not later than 30 days after the State educational agency resolves the complaint or fails to resolve the complaint within the 45-day time limit. The appeal shall be accompanied by a copy of the State educational agency’s resolution, and, if there is one, a complete statement of the reasons supporting the appeal. The Secretary shall investigate and resolve the appeal not later than 90 days after receipt of the appeal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>