<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7907"><akn:num>7907</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions on Federal Government and use of Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7907. Prohibitions on Federal Government and use of Federal funds(a) General prohibitionNothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government, including through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, to mandate, direct, or control a State, local educational agency, or school’s curriculum, program of instruction, or allocation of State or local resources, or mandate a State or any subdivision thereof to spend any funds or incur any costs not paid for under this chapter.


(b) Prohibition on endorsement of curriculumNotwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, no funds provided to the Department under this chapter may be used by the Department, whether through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, to endorse, approve, develop, require, or sanction any curriculum, including any curriculum aligned to the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative or any other academic standards common to a significant number of States, designed to be used in an elementary school or secondary school.


(c) Local controlNothing in this section shall be construed to—(1) authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government, whether through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement to mandate, direct, review, or control a State, local educational agency, or school’s instructional content, curriculum, and related activities;

(2) limit the application of the General Education Provisions Act (20 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.);

(3) require the distribution of scientifically or medically false or inaccurate materials or to prohibit the distribution of scientifically or medically true or accurate materials; or

(4) create any legally enforceable right.


(d) Prohibition on requiring Federal approval or certification of standards(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, no State shall be required to have academic standards approved or certified by the Federal </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General prohibition Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to authorize an officer or employee of the Federal Government, including through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, to mandate, direct, or control a State, local educational agency, or school’s curriculum, program of instruction, or allocation of State or local resources, or mandate a State or any subdivision thereof to spend any funds or incur any costs not paid for under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on endorsement of curriculum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on endorsement of curriculum Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal law, no funds provided to the Department under this chapter may be used by the Department, whether through a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, to endorse, approve, develop, require, or sanction any curriculum, including any curriculum aligned to the Common Core State Standards developed under the Common Core State Standards Initiative or any other academic standards common to a significant number of States, designed to be used in an elementary school or secondary school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local control Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7907_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on requiring Federal approval or certification of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on requiring Federal approval or certification of standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>