<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7912"><akn:num>7912</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsafe school choice option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7912. Unsafe school choice option(a) Unsafe school choice policyEach State receiving funds under this chapter shall establish and implement a statewide policy requiring that a student attending a persistently dangerous public elementary school or secondary school, as determined by the State in consultation with a representative sample of local educational agencies, or who becomes a victim of a violent criminal offense, as determined by State law, while in or on the grounds of a public elementary school or secondary school that the student attends, be allowed to attend a safe public elementary school or secondary school within the local educational agency, including a public charter school.


(b) CertificationAs a condition of receiving funds under this chapter, a State shall certify in writing to the Secretary that the State is in compliance with this section.


(Pub. L. 89–10, title VIII, § 8532, formerly title IX, § 9532, as added Pub. L. 107–110, title IX, § 901, Jan. 8, 2002, 115 Stat. 1984; renumbered title VIII, § 8532, Pub. L. 114–95, title VIII, § 8001(a)(6), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2088, 2089.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 7912, Pub. L. 89–10, title IX, § 9212, as added Pub. L. 103–382, title I, § 101, Oct. 20, 1994, 108 Stat. 3805, defined terms, prior to the general amendment of former subchapter IX of this chapter by Pub. L. 107–110.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unsafe school choice policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Unsafe school choice policy Each State receiving funds under this chapter shall establish and implement a statewide policy requiring that a student attending a persistently dangerous public elementary school or secondary school, as determined by the State in consultation with a representative sample of local educational agencies, or who becomes a victim of a violent criminal offense, as determined by State law, while in or on the grounds of a public elementary school or secondary school that the student attends, be allowed to attend a safe public elementary school or secondary school within the local educational agency, including a public charter school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certification As a condition of receiving funds under this chapter, a State shall certify in writing to the Secretary that the State is in compliance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>