<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7922" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7922/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7922/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7922"><akn:num>7922</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding travel to and from school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7922. Rule of construction regarding travel to and from school(a) In generalSubject to subsection (b), nothing in this chapter shall authorize the Secretary to, or shall be construed to—(1) prohibit a child from traveling to and from school on foot or by car, bus, or bike when the parents of the child have given permission; or

(2) expose parents to civil or criminal charges for allowing their child to responsibly and safely travel to and from school by a means the parents believe is age appropriate.


(b) No preemption of State or local lawsNotwithstanding subsection (a), nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt State or local laws.


(Pub. L. 89–10, title VIII, § 8542, as added Pub. L. 114–95, title VIII, § 8034, Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2118.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Dec. 10, 2015, except with respect to certain noncompetitive programs and competitive programs, see section 5 of Pub. L. 114–95, set out as an Effective Date of 2015 Amendment note under section 6301 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7922_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsection (b), nothing in this chapter shall authorize the Secretary to, or shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7922_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>No preemption of State or local laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No preemption of State or local laws Notwithstanding subsection (a), nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt State or local laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>