<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7961" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7961/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7961/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7961"><akn:num>7961</akn:num><akn:heading>Gun-free requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7961. Gun-free requirements(a) Short titleThis subpart may be cited as the “Gun-Free Schools Act”.


(b) Requirements(1) In generalEach State receiving Federal funds under any subchapter of this chapter shall have in effect a State law requiring local educational agencies to expel from school for a period of not less than 1 year a student who is determined to have brought a firearm to a school, or to have possessed a firearm at a school, under the jurisdiction of local educational agencies in that State, except that such State law shall allow the chief administering officer of a local educational agency to modify such expulsion requirement for a student on a case-by-case basis if such modification is in writing.


(2) ConstructionNothing in this subpart shall be construed to prevent a State from allowing a local educational agency that has expelled a student from such a student’s regular school setting from providing educational services to such student in an alternative setting.


(3) DefinitionFor the purpose of this section, the term “firearm” has the same meaning given such term in section 921(a) of title 18.



(c) Special ruleThe provisions of this section shall be construed in a manner consistent with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.].


(d) Report to StateEach local educational agency requesting assistance from the State educational agency that is to be provided from funds made available to the State under any subchapter of this chapter shall provide to the State, in the application requesting such assistance—(1) an assurance that such local educational agency is in compliance with the State law required by subsection (b); and

(2) a description of the circumstances surrounding any expulsions imposed under the State law required by subsection (b), including—(A) the name of the school concerned;

(B) the number of students expelled from such school; and

(C) the type of firearms concerned.



(e) ReportingEach State sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This subpart may be cited as the “Gun-Free Schools Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rule The provisions of this section shall be construed in a manner consistent with the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act [20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to State Each local educational agency requesting assistance from the State educational agency that is to be provided from funds made available to the State under any subchapter of this chapter shall provide to the State, in the application requesting such assistance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting Each State shall report the information described in subsection (d) to the Secretary on an annual basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition For the purpose of subsection (d), the term “school” means any setting that is under the control and supervision of the local educational agency for the purpose of student activities approved and authorized by the local educational agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Exception Nothing in this section shall apply to a firearm that is lawfully stored inside a locked vehicle on school property, or if it is for activities approved and authorized by the local educational agency and the local educational agency adopts appropriate safeguards to ensure student safety.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7961_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy regarding criminal justice system referral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Policy regarding criminal justice system referral</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>