<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7981" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7981/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/7981/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7981"><akn:num>7981</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7981. Evaluations(a) Reservation of fundsExcept as provided in subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsections”. (b) and (e), the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, may reserve not more than 0.5 percent of the amount appropriated for each program authorized under this chapter to carry out activities under this section. If the Secretary elects to make a reservation under this subsection, the reserved amounts—(1) shall first be used by the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, to—(A) conduct comprehensive, high-quality evaluations of the programs that—(i) are consistent with the evaluation plan under subsection (d); and

(ii) primarily include impact evaluations that use experimental or quasi-experimental designs, where practicable and appropriate, and other rigorous methodologies that permit the strongest possible causal inferences;


(B) conduct studies of the effectiveness of the programs and the administrative impact of the programs on schools and local educational agencies; and

(C) widely disseminate evaluation findings under this section related to programs authorized under this chapter—(i) in a timely fashion;

(ii) in forms that are understandable, easily accessible, usable, and adaptable for use in the improvement of educational practice;

(iii) through electronic transfer and other means, such as posting, as available, to the websites of State educational agencies, local educational agencies, the Institute of Education Sciences, or the Department, or in another relevant place; and

(iv) in a manner that promotes the utilization of such findings; and



(2) may be used by the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences—(A) to evaluate the aggregate short- and long-term effects and cost efficiencies across—(i) Federal programs assisted or authorized under this chapter; and

(ii) related Federal early childhood education </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7981_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reservation of funds Except as provided in subsection 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsections”. (b) and (e), the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, may reserve not more than 0.5 percent of the amount appropriated for each program authorized under this chapter to carry out activities under this section. If the Secretary elects to make a reservation under this subsection, the reserved amounts—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7981_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subchapter I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subchapter I The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall use funds authorized under section 6302(e) of this title to carry out evaluation activities under this section related to subchapter I, and shall not reserve any other money from such subchapter for evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7981_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consolidation Notwithstanding any other provision of this section or section 6302(e) of this title, the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7981_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation plan The Director of the Institute of Education Sciences, shall, on a biennial basis, develop, submit to Congress, and make publicly available an evaluation plan, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7981_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation activities authorized elsewhere</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation activities authorized elsewhere If, under any other provision of this chapter, funds are authorized to be reserved or used for evaluation activities with respect to a program, the Secretary may not reserve additional funds under this section for the evaluation of that program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>