<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80b"><akn:num>80b</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of site</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80b. Selection of site(a) Authorization of Board of Regents; submission of recommendations to CongressThe Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution is authorized and directed, with the advice and assistance of the Board, to investigate and survey lands and buildings in and near the District of Columbia suitable for the display of military collections. The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution shall, after consulting with and seeking the advice of the Commission on Fine Arts, the National Capital Planning Commission, and the General Services Administration, submit recommendations to the Congress with respect to the acquisition of lands and buildings for such purpose.


(b) Public exhibits and study collections; exhibits of military and naval operationsBuildings acquired pursuant to recommendations made under subsection (a) of this section shall be used to house public exhibits and study collections that are not appropriate for the military exhibits of the Smithsonian Institution on the Mall in the District of Columbia. Facilities shall be provided for the display of large military objects and for the reconstruction, in an appropriate way, on lands acquired pursuant to recommendations made under subsection (a) of this section, of exhibits showing the nature of fortifications, trenches, and other military and naval facilities characteristic of the American colonial period, the War of the Revolution, and subsequent American military and naval operations.


(Pub. L. 87–186, § 3, Aug. 30, 1961, 75 Stat. 415.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Board of Regents; submission of recommendations to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of Board of Regents; submission of recommendations to Congress The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution is authorized and directed, with the advice and assistance of the Board, to investigate and survey lands and buildings in and near the District of Columbia suitable for the display of military collections. The Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution shall, after consulting with and seeking the advice of the Commission on Fine Arts, the National Capital Planning Commission, and the General Services Administration, submit recommendations to the Congress with respect to the acquisition of lands and buildings for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public exhibits and study collections; exhibits of military and naval operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public exhibits and study collections; exhibits of military and naval operations Buildings acquired pursuant to recommendations made under subsection (a) of this section shall be used to house public exhibits and study collections that are not appropriate for the military exhibits of the Smithsonian Institution on the Mall in the District of Columbia. Facilities shall be provided for the display of large military objects and for the reconstruction, in an appropriate way, on lands acquired pursuant to recommendations made under subsection (a) of this section, of exhibits showing the nature of fortifications, trenches, and other military and naval facilities characteristic of the American colonial period, the War of the Revolution, and subsequent American military and naval operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>