<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80q_3"><akn:num>80q–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Trustees of National Museum of the American Indian</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80q–3. Board of Trustees of National Museum of the American Indian(a) In generalThe National Museum shall be under a Board of Trustees with the duties, powers, and authority specified in this section.


(b) General duties and powersThe Board of Trustees shall—(1) recommend annual operating budgets for the National Museum to the Board of Regents;

(2) advise and assist the Board of Regents on all matters relating to the administration, operation, maintenance, and preservation of the National Museum;

(3) adopt bylaws for the Board of Trustees;

(4) designate a chairman and other officers from among the members of the Board of trustees; 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. and

(5) report annually to the Board of Regents on the acquisition, disposition, and display of Native American objects and artifacts and on other appropriate matters.


(c) Sole authoritySubject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, the Board of Trustees shall have the sole authority to—(1) lend, exchange, sell, or otherwise dispose of any part of the collections of the National Museum, with the proceeds of such transactions to be used for additions to the collections of the National Museum or additions to the endowment of the National Museum, as the case may be;

(2) purchase, accept, borrow, or otherwise acquire artifacts and other objects for addition to the collections of the Natural Museum; and

(3) specify criteria for use of the collections of the National Museum for appropriate purposes, including research, evaluation, education, and method of display.


(d) AuthoritySubject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, the Board of Trustees shall have authority to—(1) provide for restoration, preservation, and maintenance of the collections of the National Museum;

(2) solicit funds for the National Museum and determine the purposes to which such funds shall be applied; and

(3) approve expenditures from the endowment of the National Museum for any purpose of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The National Museum shall be under a Board of Trustees with the duties, powers, and authority specified in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General duties and powers The Board of Trustees shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sole authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sole authority Subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, the Board of Trustees shall have the sole authority to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority Subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, the Board of Trustees shall have authority to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial appointments to Board of Trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Initial appointments to Board of Trustees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent appointments to Board of Trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Subsequent appointments to Board of Trustees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Quorum A majority of the members of the Board of Trustees then in office shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Expenses Members of the Board shall be entitled (to the same extent as provided in section 5703 of title 5 with respect to employees serving intermittently in the Government service) to per diem, travel, and transportation expenses for each day (including travel time) during which they are engaged in the performance of their duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>