<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80q–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80q_5"><akn:num>80q–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Museum facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80q–5. Museum facilities(a) National Museum mall facilityThe Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a facility on the area bounded by Third Street, Maryland Avenue, Independence Avenue, Fourth Street, and Jefferson Drive, Southwest, in the District of Columbia to house the portion of the National Museum to be located in the District of Columbia. The Board of Regents shall pay not more than ⅔ of the total cost of planning, designing, and constructing the facility from funds appropriated to the Board of Regents. The remainder of the costs shall be paid from non-Federal sources.


(b) National Museum Heye Center facility(1) Lease of space from GSA(A) TermsNotwithstanding section 586(a) and (b) of title 40, the Administrator of General Services may lease, at a nominal charge, to the Smithsonian Institution space in the Old United States Custom House at One Bowling Green, New York, New York, to house the portion of the National Museum to be located in the city of New York. The lease shall be subject to such terms as may be mutually agreed upon by the Administrator and the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution. The term of the lease shall not be less than 99 years.


(B) Reimbursement of Federal buildings fundThe Administrator of General Services may reimburse the fund established by section 592 of title 40 for the difference between the amount charged to the Smithsonian Institution for leasing space under this paragraph and the commercial charge under section 586(a) and (b) of title 40 which, but for this paragraph, would apply to the leasing of such space. There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator such sums as may be necessary to carry out this subparagraph for fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1990.



(2) Construction(A) Museum facilityThe Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a significant facility for the National Museum in the space leased under paragraph (1).


(B) Auditorium and loading dock facilityThe Ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum mall facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Museum mall facility The Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a facility on the area bounded by Third Street, Maryland Avenue, Independence Avenue, Fourth Street, and Jefferson Drive, Southwest, in the District of Columbia to house the portion of the National Museum to be located in the District of Columbia. The Board of Regents shall pay not more than ⅔ of the total cost of planning, designing, and constructing the facility from funds appropriated to the Board of Regents. The remainder of the costs shall be paid from non-Federal sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum Heye Center facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Museum Heye Center facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Museum Support Center facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Museum Support Center facility The Board of Regents shall plan, design, and construct a facility for the conservation and storage of the collections of the National Museum at the Museum Support Center of the Smithsonian Institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum square footage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Minimum square footage The facilities to be constructed under this section shall have, in the aggregate, a total square footage of at least 400,000 square feet.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to contract with GSA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to contract with GSA The Board of Regents and the Administrator of General Services may enter into such agreements as may be necessary for planning, designing, and constructing facilities under this section (other than subsection (b)(2)(B)). Under such agreements, the Board of Regents shall transfer to the Administrator, from funds available for planning, designing, and constructing such facilities, such amounts as may be necessary for expenses of the General Services Administration with respect to planning, designing, and constructing such facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80q_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on obligation of Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on obligation of Federal funds Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, funds appropriated for carrying out this section may not be obligated for actual construction of any facility under this section until the 60th day after the date on which the Board of Regents transmits to Congress a written analysis of the total estimated cost of the construction and a cost-sharing plan projecting the amount for Federal appropriations and for non-Federal contributions for the construction on a fiscal year basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>