<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80r_3"><akn:num>80r–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80r–3. Council(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Smithsonian Institution a council to be known as the “National Museum of African American History and Culture Council”.


(b) Duties(1) In generalThe Council shall—(A) make recommendations to the Board of Regents concerning the planning, design, and construction of the Museum;

(B) advise and assist the Board of Regents on all matters relating to the administration, operation, maintenance, and preservation of the Museum;

(C) recommend annual operating budgets for the Museum to the Board of Regents;

(D) report annually to the Board of Regents on the acquisition, disposition, and display of objects relating to African American life, art, history, and culture; and

(E) adopt bylaws for the operation of the Council.


(2) Principal responsibilitiesThe Council, subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, shall have sole authority to—(A) purchase, accept, borrow, and otherwise acquire artifacts for addition to the collections of the Museum;

(B) loan, exchange, sell, and otherwise dispose of any part of the collections of the Museum, but only if the funds generated by that disposition are used for additions to the collections of the Museum; or

(C) specify criteria with respect to the use of the collections and resources of the Museum, including policies on programming, education, exhibitions, and research with respect to—(i) the life, art, history, and culture of African Americans;

(ii) the role of African Americans in the history of the United States from the period of slavery to the present; and

(iii) the contributions of African Americans to society.



(3) Other responsibilitiesThe Council, subject to the general policies of the Board of Regents, shall have authority—(A) to provide for preservation, restoration, and maintenance of the collections of the Museum; and

(B) to solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, and devises of personal property for the purpose of aiding an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Smithsonian Institution a council to be known as the “National Museum of African American History and Culture Council”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition and appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chairperson By a majority vote of its voting members, the Council shall elect a chairperson from its members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Quorum A majority of the voting members of the Council holding office shall constitute a quorum for the purpose of conducting business, but a lesser number may receive information on behalf of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>