<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80r–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80r_6"><akn:num>80r–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Building for the National Museum of African American History and Culture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80r–6. Building for the National Museum of African American History and Culture(a) In general(1) Location(A) In generalNot later than 12 months after December 16, 2003, the Board of Regents shall designate a site for the Museum.


(B) Sites for considerationIn designating a site under subparagraph (A), the Board of Regents shall select from among the following sites in the District of Columbia:(i) The Arts and Industries Building of the Smithsonian Institution, located on the National Mall at 900 Jefferson Drive, Southwest, Washington, District of Columbia.

(ii) The area bounded by Constitution Avenue, Madison Drive, and 14th and 15th Streets, Northwest.

(iii) The site known as the “Liberty Loan site”, located on 14th Street Southwest at the foot of the 14th Street Bridge.

(iv) The site known as the “Banneker Overlook site”, located on 10th Street Southwest at the foot of the L’Enfant Plaza Promenade.


(C) Availability of site(i) In generalA site described in subparagraph (B) shall remain available until the date on which the Board of Regents designates a site for the Museum under subparagraph (A).


(ii) Transfer to Smithsonian InstitutionExcept with respect to a site described in clause (i) of subparagraph (B), if the site designated for the Museum is in an area that is under the administrative jurisdiction of a Federal agency, as soon as practicable after the date on which the designation is made, the head of the Federal agency shall transfer to the Smithsonian Institution administrative jurisdiction over the area.



(D) ConsultationThe Board of Regents shall carry out its duties under this paragraph in consultation with the following:(i) The Chair of the National Capital Planning Commission.

(ii) The Chair of the Commission on Fine Arts.

(iii) The Chair and Vice Chair of the Presidential Commission referred to in section 80r–8 of this title.

(iv) The Chair of the Building and Site Subcommittee of the Presidential Commission referred to in section 80r–8</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost sharing The Board of Regents shall pay—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80r_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>