<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80t_3"><akn:num>80t–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and staff of the Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80t–3. Director and staff of the Museum(a) Director(1) In generalThe Museum shall have a Director who shall be appointed by the Secretary, taking into consideration individuals recommended by the council established under section 80t–2 of this title.


(2) DutiesThe Director shall manage the Museum subject to the policies of the Board of Regents.



(b) StaffThe Secretary may appoint 2 additional employees to serve under the Director, except that such additional employees may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.


(c) PayThe employees appointed by the Secretary under subsection (b) may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.


(Pub. L. 116–260, div. T, title I, § 105, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2275.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Staff The Secretary may appoint 2 additional employees to serve under the Director, except that such additional employees may be appointed without regard to the provisions of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pay The employees appointed by the Secretary under subsection (b) may be paid without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of title 5 relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>