<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80t_5"><akn:num>80t–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Building</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80t–5. Building(a) Location(1) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 27, 2020, the Board of Regents shall designate a site for the Museum.


(2) Sites for considerationIn designating a site under paragraph (1), the Board of Regents shall—(A) select a site in the District of Columbia; and

(B) include the consideration of the following sites:(i) The site known as the “South Monument site”, located on the National Mall and bordered by 14th Street Northwest, Jefferson Drive Southwest, Raoul Wallenberg Place Southwest, and Independence Ave Southwest.

(ii) The Northwest United States Capitol site, bordered by 3rd Street Northwest, Constitution Avenue Northwest, 1st Street Northwest, and Pennsylvania Ave Northwest.



(3) Factors consideredIn designating a site under paragraph (1), the Board of Regents shall take into consideration each of the following factors:(A) An estimate of the costs associated with each potential site.

(B) An assessment of the suitability of the space of each potential site, including size, proximity to other buildings and transportation, and other external environmental conditions, as appropriate.

(C) The recommendations of the Congressional Commission.


(4) ConsultationThe Board of Regents shall carry out its duties under this subsection in consultation with each of the following:(A) The Chair of the National Capital Planning Commission.

(B) The Director of the National Park Service.

(C) The Chair of the National Capital Memorial Advisory Commission.

(D) The Chair of the Commission on Fine Arts.

(E) The Chair of the Congressional Commission.

(F) The Architect of the Capitol.

(G) The chair and ranking member of each of the following committees:(i) The Committee on Rules and Administration of the Senate.

(ii) The Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives.

(iii) The Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.

(iv) The Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.

(v) Th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Location</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Site under the jurisdiction of another Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Site under the jurisdiction of another Federal agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of building</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Construction of building The Board of Regents, in consultation with the council established under section 80t–2 of this title, may plan, design, and construct a building for the Museum, which shall be located at the site designated by the Board of Regents under subsection (a), in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commemorative Works Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Commemorative Works Act Chapter 89 of title 40 shall not apply with respect to the Museum, except that the Museum shall not be located in the Reserve (as defined in section 8902(a) of that title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost sharing The Board of Regents shall pay—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>