<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80t–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80t_1"><akn:num>80t–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80t–1. Establishment of Museum(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Smithsonian Institution a comprehensive women’s history museum, to be named by the Board of Regents in consultation with the council established under section 80t–2 of this title (referred to in this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. as the “Museum”).


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the Museum established under this section shall be to provide for—(1) the collection and study of, and the establishment of programs relating to, women’s contributions to various fields and throughout different periods of history that have influenced the direction of the United States;

(2) collaboration with other Smithsonian Institution museums and facilities, outside museums, and educational institutions; and

(3) the creation of exhibitions and programs that recognize diverse perspectives on women’s history and contributions.


(Pub. L. 116–260, div. T, title I, § 103, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2273.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title I of div. T of Pub. L. 116–260, known as the Smithsonian American Women’s History Museum Act, which is classified to this subchapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Smithsonian Institution a comprehensive women’s history museum, to be named by the Board of Regents in consultation with the council established under section 80t–2 of this title (referred to in this subchapter 11 See References in Text note below. as the “Museum”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80t_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the Museum established under this section shall be to provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>