<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/80u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_80u"><akn:num>80u</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum of the American Latino</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 80u. National Museum of the American Latino(a) FindingsCongress finds the following:(1) The United States is a symbol of democracy, freedom, and economic opportunity around the world, and the legacy of Latinos is deeply rooted in the very fabric of the history, democracy, freedom, and economic opportunity of the United States.

(2) There exists no national museum within the Smithsonian Institution that is devoted to the documentation and explication of Latino life, art, history, and culture.

(3) The establishment of the National Museum of the American Latino will be consistent with the purposes of the Smithsonian Institution, created by Congress in 1846, “for the increase and diffusion of knowledge”.

(4) The National Museum of the American Latino—(A) will be the keystone for people in the United States and other Smithsonian Institution visitors to learn about Latino contributions to life, art, history, and culture in the United States at its signature location on the National Mall; and

(B) will serve as a gateway for visitors to view other Latino exhibitions, collections, and programming at other Smithsonian Institution facilities and museums throughout the United States and the territories of the United States.



(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Board of RegentsThe term “Board of Regents” means the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution.


(2) Board of trusteesThe term “Board of Trustees” means the Board of Trustees of the National Museum of the American Latino as established by subsection (d).


(3) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the National Museum of the American Latino.


(4) MuseumThe term “Museum” means the National Museum of the American Latino established by subsection (c).


(5) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution.



(c) Establishment of Museum(1) EstablishmentThere is established within the Smithsonian Institution a museum to be known as the “National Museum of the American </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of Museum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Trustees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board of Trustees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and staff of Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Director and staff of Museum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational and liaison programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Educational and liaison programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum of the American Latino building and support facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) National Museum of the American Latino building and support facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of recommendations of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consideration of recommendations of Commission In carrying out their duties under this section, the Board of Trustees and the Board of Regents shall take into consideration the reports and plans submitted by the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of the American Latino established under section 333 of the Consolidated Natural Resources Act of 2008 (Public Law 110–229; 122 Stat. 784).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional Budget Act compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Congressional Budget Act compliance Authority under this section to enter into contracts or to make payments shall be effective in any fiscal year only to the extent provided in advance in an appropriations Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_80u_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>