<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_906"><akn:num>906</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlements in addition to basic compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 906. Entitlements in addition to basic compensation(a) Cost-of-living increase and additional compensationUnder regulations which shall be prescribed by or under authority of the President, each teacher (other than a teacher employed in a substitute capacity) shall be entitled, in addition to basic compensation, to—(1) cost-of-living allowances equal to those authorized by section 5924 of title 5, and

(2) additional compensation equal to that authorized under section 5941 of title 5.


(b) Post differentialThe cost-of-living allowances and additional compensation provided under subsection (a) of this section for any teacher shall be based on the teaching position in which he rendered services on a school-year basis, except that, if such teacher is employed in another position during any recess period between two school years, such allowances and compensation for such recess period shall be based on the position in which he is employed during such recess period.


(Pub. L. 86–91, § 8, July 17, 1959, 73 Stat. 216; Pub. L. 96–465, title II, § 2206(d), Oct. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 2162.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
In subsec. (a)(2), “section 5941 of title 5” substituted for “section 207 of the Independent Offices Appropriation Act, 1949 (5 U.S.C. 118h)” on authority of Pub. L. 89–554, § 7(b), Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 631, the first section of which enacted Title 5, Government Organization and Employees.
Section was formerly classified to section 2356 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5 by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.

Amendments1980—Subsec. (a)(1). Pub. L. 96–465 substituted reference to section 5924 of title 5 for reference to section 1131(2) of title 22.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1980 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 96–465 effective Feb. 15, 1981, except as otherwise provided, see section 2403 of Pub. L. 96–465, set out as an Effective Date note under section 3901 of Title 22, Foreign R</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-of-living increase and additional compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cost-of-living increase and additional compensation Under regulations which shall be prescribed by or under authority of the President, each teacher (other than a teacher employed in a substitute capacity) shall be entitled, in addition to basic compensation, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Post differential</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Post differential The cost-of-living allowances and additional compensation provided under subsection (a) of this section for any teacher shall be based on the teaching position in which he rendered services on a school-year basis, except that, if such teacher is employed in another position during any recess period between two school years, such allowances and compensation for such recess period shall be based on the position in which he is employed during such recess period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>