<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9101" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9101/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9101/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9101"><akn:num>9101</akn:num><akn:heading>General definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9101. General definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) Determined to be obsceneThe term “determined to be obscene” means determined, in a final judgment of a court of record and of competent jurisdiction in the United States, to be obscene.


(2) Digital literacy skillsThe term “digital literacy skills” means the skills associated with—(A) using technology to enable users to find, evaluate, organize, create, and communicate information; and

(B) developing digital citizenship and the responsible use of technology.


(3) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the Institute appointed under section 9103 of this title.


(4) Final judgmentThe term “final judgment” means a judgment that is—(A) not reviewed by any other court that has authority to review such judgment; or

(B) not reviewable by any other court.


(5) Indian tribeThe term “Indian tribe” means any tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska native village, regional corporation, or village corporation (as defined in, or established pursuant to, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.)), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.


(6) InstituteThe term “Institute” means the Institute of Museum and Library Services established under section 9102 of this title.


(7) Museum and Library Services BoardThe term “Museum and Library Services Board” means the National Museum and Library Services Board established under section 9105a of this title.


(8) ObsceneThe term “obscene” means, with respect to a project, that—(A) the average person, applying contemporary community standards, would find that such project, when taken as a whole, appeals to the prurient interest;

(B) such project depicts or describes sexual conduct in a patently offensive way; and

(C) such project, when taken as a whole, lacks serious literary, artistic, political, or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determined to be obscene</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Determined to be obscene The term “determined to be obscene” means determined, in a final judgment of a court of record and of competent jurisdiction in the United States, to be obscene.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Digital literacy skills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Digital literacy skills The term “digital literacy skills” means the skills associated with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Institute appointed under section 9103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final judgment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Final judgment The term “final judgment” means a judgment that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Indian tribe The term “Indian tribe” means any tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska native village, regional corporation, or village corporation (as defined in, or established pursuant to, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.)), which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Institute The term “Institute” means the Institute of Museum and Library Services established under section 9102 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Museum and Library Services Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Museum and Library Services Board The term “Museum and Library Services Board” means the National Museum and Library Services Board established under section 9105a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9101_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obscene</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Obscene The term “obscene” means, with respect to a project, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>