<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9103"><akn:num>9103</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9103. Director of Institute(a) Appointment(1) In generalThe Institute shall be headed by a Director, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(2) TermThe Director shall serve for a term of 4 years, except that if a successor to the Director has not been appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, as of the date of expiration of the Director’s term, the Director may serve for not more than 1 additional year or until a successor is appointed and confirmed, whichever is earlier.


(3) QualificationsBeginning with the first individual appointed to the position of Director after September 30, 1996, every second individual so appointed shall be appointed from among individuals who have special competence with regard to library and information services. Beginning with the second individual appointed to the position of Director after September 30, 1996, every second individual so appointed shall be appointed from among individuals who have special competence with regard to museum services.



(b) CompensationThe Director may be compensated at the rate provided for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.


(c) Duties and powers(1) Primary responsibilityThe Director shall have primary responsibility for the development and implementation of policy to ensure the availability of museum, library, and information services adequate to meet the essential information, education, research, economic, cultural, and civic needs of the people of the United States.


(2) DutiesIn carrying out the responsibility described in paragraph (1), the Director shall—(A) advise the President, Congress, and other Federal agencies and offices on museum, library, and information services in order to ensure the creation, preservation, organization, and dissemination of knowledge;

(B) engage Federal, State, and local governmental agencies and private entities in assessing the museum, library, and infor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation The Director may be compensated at the rate provided for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties and powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondelegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nondelegation The Director shall not delegate any of the functions of the Director to any person who is not an officer or employee of the Institute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interagency agreements The Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination The Director shall ensure coordination of the policies and activities of the Institute with the policies and activities of other agencies and offices of the Federal Government having interest in and responsibilities for the improvement of museums and libraries and information services. Where appropriate, the Director shall ensure that such policies and activities are coordinated with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Interagency collaboration The Director shall work jointly with the individuals heading relevant Federal departments and agencies, including the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of Education, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Chairman of the National Endowment for the Arts, the Chairman of the National Endowment of the Humanities, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, the Librarian of Congress, the Archivi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulatory authority The Director may promulgate such rules and regulations as are necessary and appropriate to implement the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9103_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Application procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>