<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9105a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9105a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9105a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9105a"><akn:num>9105a</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum and Library Services Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9105a. National Museum and Library Services Board(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Institute a board to be known as the “National Museum and Library Services Board”.


(b) Membership(1) Number and appointmentThe Museum and Library Services Board shall be composed of the following:(A) The Director.

(B) The Deputy Director for the Office of Library Services.

(C) The Deputy Director for the Office of Museum Services.

(D) Ten members appointed by the President, from among individuals who are citizens of the United States and who are specially qualified by virtue of their education, training, or experience in the area of library services, or their commitment to libraries.

(E) Ten members appointed by the President, from among individuals who are citizens of the United States and who are specially qualified by virtue of their education, training, or experience in the area of museum services, or their commitment to museums.


(2) Special qualifications(A) Library membersOf the members of the Museum and Library Services Board appointed under paragraph (1)(D)—(i) five shall be professional librarians or information specialists, of whom—(I) not less than one shall be knowledgeable about electronic information and technical aspects of library and information services and sciences; and

(II) not less than one other shall be knowledgeable about the library and information service needs of underserved communities, including rural communities; and


(ii) the remainder shall have special competence in, or knowledge of, the needs for library and information services in the United States.


(B) Museum membersOf the members of the Museum and Library Services Board appointed under paragraph (1)(E)—(i) five shall be museum professionals who are or have been affiliated with—(I) resources that, collectively, are broadly representative of the curatorial, conservation, educational, and cultural resources of the United States; or

(II) museums that, collectively, are bro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Institute a board to be known as the “National Museum and Library Services Board”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties and powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chairperson The Director shall serve as Chairperson of the Museum and Library Services Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Secretary The General Counsel of the Institute shall serve as Secretary of the Museum and Library Services Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Quorum A majority of the voting members of the Museum and Library Services Board shall constitute a quorum for the conduct of business at official meetings, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Compensation and travel expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9105a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination The Director, with the advice of the Museum and Library Services Board, shall coordinate the development and implementation of policies and activities as described in subsections (f) and (g) of section 9103 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>