<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9134"><akn:num>9134</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9134. State plans(a) State plan required(1) In generalIn order to be eligible to receive a grant under this subchapter, a State library administrative agency shall submit a State plan to the Director once every 5 years, as determined by the Director.


(2) DurationThe State plan shall cover a period of 5 fiscal years.


(3) RevisionsIf a State library administrative agency makes a substantive revision to its State plan, then the State library administrative agency shall submit to the Director an amendment to the State plan containing such revision not later than April 1 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the amendment will be effective.



(b) ContentsThe State plan shall—(1) establish goals, and specify priorities, for the State consistent with the purposes of this subchapter;

(2) describe activities that are consistent with the goals and priorities established under paragraph (1), the purposes of this subchapter, and section 9141 of this title, that the State library administrative agency will carry out during such year using such grant;

(3) describe the procedures that such agency will use to carry out the activities described in paragraph (2);

(4) describe the methodology that such agency will use to evaluate the success of the activities established under paragraph (2) in achieving the goals and meeting the priorities described in paragraph (1);

(5) describe the procedures that such agency will use to involve libraries and library users throughout the State in policy decisions regarding implementation of this subchapter;

(6) describe how the State library administrative agency will work with other State agencies and offices where appropriate to coordinate resources, programs, and activities and leverage, but not replace, the Federal and State investment in—(A) programs and activities under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.] (including programs and activities under subparts 2 and 3 of part B of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State plan required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents The State plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Evaluation and report Each State library administrative agency receiving a grant under this subchapter shall independently evaluate, and report to the Director regarding, the activities assisted under this subchapter, prior to the end of the 5-year plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information Each library receiving assistance under this subchapter shall submit to the State library administrative agency such information as such agency may require to meet the requirements of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9134_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internet safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Internet safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>