<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/923a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/923a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/923a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_923a"><akn:num>923a</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment of certain additional children on tuition-free basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 923a. Enrollment of certain additional children on tuition-free basis(a) Enrollment authorizedUnder regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may authorize the enrollment in schools of the defense dependents’ education system on a tuition-free basis of—(1) the children of full-time, locally-hired employees of the Department of Defense in an overseas area if such employees are citizens or nationals of the United States; and

(2) the children of foreign military members assigned to—(A) the Supreme Headquarters Allied Powers, Europe, but only in a school of the defense dependents’ education system in Mons, Belgium; or

(B) the United Nations Command, but only in a school of the defense dependents’ education system in South Korea or Japan.



(b) FundingThe Secretary may use funds available for the defense dependents’ education system to provide for the education of children enrolled in the defense dependents’ education system under subsection (a).


(c) Special rules regarding enrollment of dependents of foreign military members(1) In the regulations required by subsection (a), the Secretary shall prescribe a methodology based on the estimated total number of dependents of sponsors under section 932(2) of this title enrolled in schools of the defense dependents’ education system described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) to determine the number of children described in that paragraph who will be authorized to enroll under such subsection. The Secretary shall prescribe such methodology with the advice and assistance of the commanders of the geographic combatant commands with jurisdiction over the locations described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a).

(2) If the number of children described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) who seek enrollment in schools of the defense dependents’ education system exceeds the number authorized by the Secretary under paragraph (1), the Secretary may enroll the additional children on a space-available, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enrollment authorized Under regulations to be prescribed by the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary may authorize the enrollment in schools of the defense dependents’ education system on a tuition-free basis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding The Secretary may use funds available for the defense dependents’ education system to provide for the education of children enrolled in the defense dependents’ education system under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_923a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules regarding enrollment of dependents of foreign military members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special rules regarding enrollment of dependents of foreign military members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>