<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/928" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/928/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/928/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_928"><akn:num>928</akn:num><akn:heading>School advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 928. School advisory committees(a) Establishment; functions; membership(1) The Director shall provide for the establishment of an advisory committee for each school in the defense dependents’ education system. An advisory committee for a school shall advise the principal or superintendent of the school with respect to the operation of the school, may make recommendations with respect to curriculum and budget matters, and, except as provided under paragraph (2), shall advise the local military commander with respect to problems concerning dependents’ education within the jurisdiction of the commander. The membership of each such advisory committee shall include an equal number of parents of students enrolled in the school and of employees working at the school and, when appropriate, may include a student enrolled in the school. The membership of each such advisory committee shall also include one nonvoting member designated by the organization recognized as the exclusive bargaining representative of the employees working at the school.

(2) In the case of any military installation or overseas area where there is more than one school in the defense dependents’ education system, the Director shall provide for the establishment of an advisory committee for such military installation or overseas area to advise the local military commander with respect to problems concerning dependents’ education within the jurisdiction of the commander.


(b) Election of members; regulations respecting qualifications and election proceduresExcept in the case of a nonvoting member designated under the last sentence of subsection (a)(1), members of a school advisory committee established under this section shall be elected by individuals of voting age residing in the area to be served by the advisory committee. The Secretary of Defense shall by regulation prescribe the qualifications for election to an advisory committee and procedures for conducting elections of advisory committee membe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_928_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; functions; membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; functions; membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_928_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of members; regulations respecting qualifications and election procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election of members; regulations respecting qualifications and election procedures Except in the case of a nonvoting member designated under the last sentence of subsection (a)(1), members of a school advisory committee established under this section shall be elected by individuals of voting age residing in the area to be served by the advisory committee. The Secretary of Defense shall by regulation prescribe the qualifications for election to an advisory committee and procedures for conducting elections of advisory committee members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_928_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members to serve without pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Members to serve without pay Members of school advisory committees established under this section shall serve without pay.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>