<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/930" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/930/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/930/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_930"><akn:num>930</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of defense dependents’ education system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 930. Study of defense dependents’ education system(a) Scope; conduct and report to Director by contractor(1) The Director may from time to time, but not more frequently than once a year, provide for a comprehensive study of the entire defense dependents’ education system. Any such study shall include a detailed analysis of the education programs and the facilities of the system.

(2) Any study under paragraph (1) shall be conducted by a contractor selected by the Director after an open competition. After conducting such study, the contractor shall submit a report to the Director describing the results of the study and giving its assessment of the defense dependents’ education system.


(b) Consultation requirements respecting study specifications and contractor selectionIn designing the specifications for any study to be conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(1), and in selecting a contractor to conduct such study under subsection (a)(2), the Director shall consult with the Advisory Council on Dependents’ Education established under section 929 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(c) Reporting requirements of DirectorThe Director shall submit to the Congress any report submitted to him under subsection (a)(2) describing the results of a study carried out pursuant to subsection (a)(1), together with the recommendations, if any, of the contractor for legislation or any increase in funding needed to improve the defense dependents’ education system. Notwithstanding any law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, such report shall not be submitted to any review before its transmittal to the Congress, but the Secretary of Defense shall, at the time of the transmittal of such report, submit to the Congress such recommendations as he may have with respect to legislation or any increase in funding needed to improve the defense dependents’ education system.


(Pub. L. 95–561, title XIV, § 1412, Nov. 1, 1978, 92 Stat. 2371; Pub. L. 96–46, § 2(a)(8), Aug. 6, 19</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_930_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope; conduct and report to Director by contractor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scope; conduct and report to Director by contractor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_930_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation requirements respecting study specifications and contractor selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation requirements respecting study specifications and contractor selection In designing the specifications for any study to be conducted pursuant to subsection (a)(1), and in selecting a contractor to conduct such study under subsection (a)(2), the Director shall consult with the Advisory Council on Dependents’ Education established under section 929 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_930_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting requirements of Director The Director shall submit to the Congress any report submitted to him under subsection (a)(2) describing the results of a study carried out pursuant to subsection (a)(1), together with the recommendations, if any, of the contractor for legislation or any increase in funding needed to improve the defense dependents’ education system. Notwithstanding any law, rule, or regulation to the contrary, such report shall not be submitted to any review before its transmittal to the Congress, but the Secretary of Defense shall, at the time of the transmittal of such report, submit to the Congress such recommendations as he may have with respect to legislation or any increase in funding needed to improve the defense dependents’ education system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>