<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9403"><akn:num>9403</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9403. Prohibitions(a) Participation not requiredNo person, including a parent, shall be required to participate in any program of early childhood education, early learning, parent education, or developmental screening pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.


(b) Rights of parentsNothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the rights of parents otherwise established in Federal, State, or local law.


(c) Particular methods or settingsNo entity that receives funds under this chapter shall be required to provide services under this chapter through a particular instructional method or in a particular instructional setting to comply with this chapter.


(d) NonduplicationNo funds provided under this chapter shall be used to carry out an activity funded under another provision of law providing for Federal child care or early learning programs, unless an expansion of such activity is identified in the local needs assessment and performance goals under this chapter.


(Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title VIII, § 804], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–82.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Participation not required No person, including a parent, shall be required to participate in any program of early childhood education, early learning, parent education, or developmental screening pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of parents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rights of parents Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to affect the rights of parents otherwise established in Federal, State, or local law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Particular methods or settings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Particular methods or settings No entity that receives funds under this chapter shall be required to provide services under this chapter through a particular instructional method or in a particular instructional setting to comply with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonduplication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nonduplication No funds provided under this chapter shall be used to carry out an activity funded under another provision of law providing for Federal child care or early learning programs, unless an expansion of such activity is identified in the local needs assessment and performance goals under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>