<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9501" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9501/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9501/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9501"><akn:num>9501</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9501. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1)(A) In generalThe terms “elementary school”, “secondary school”, “local educational agency”, and “State educational agency” have the meanings given those terms in section 7801 of this title.


(B) Outlying areasThe term “outlying areas” has the meaning given such term in section 6331(c) of this title.


(C) Freely associated statesThe term “freely associated states” means the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau.



(2) Applied researchThe term “applied research” means research—(A) to gain knowledge or understanding necessary for determining the means by which a recognized and specific need may be met; and

(B) that is specifically directed to the advancement of practice in the field of education.


(3) Basic researchThe term “basic research” means research—(A) to gain fundamental knowledge or understanding of phenomena and observable facts, without specific application toward processes or products; and

(B) for the advancement of knowledge in the field of education.


(4) BoardThe term “Board” means the National Board for Education Sciences established under section 9516 of this title.


(5) BureauThe term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs.


(6) Comprehensive centerThe term “comprehensive center” means an entity established under section 9602 of this title.


(7) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Education.


(8) DevelopmentThe term “development” means the systematic use of knowledge or understanding gained from the findings of scientifically valid research and the shaping of that knowledge or understanding into products or processes that can be applied and evaluated and may prove useful in areas such as the preparation of materials and new methods of instruction and practices in teaching, that lead to the improvement of the academic skills of students, and that are replicable in different educational settings.


(9) DirectorThe term</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applied research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Applied research The term “applied research” means research—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Basic research The term “basic research” means research—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Board The term “Board” means the National Board for Education Sciences established under section 9516 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Bureau The term “Bureau” means the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Comprehensive center The term “comprehensive center” means an entity established under section 9602 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Development The term “development” means the systematic use of knowledge or understanding gained from the findings of scientifically valid research and the shaping of that knowledge or understanding into products or processes that can be applied and evaluated and may prove useful in areas such as the preparation of materials and new methods of instruction and practices in teaching, that lead to the improvement of the academic skills of students, and that are replicable in different educational settings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the Institute of Education Sciences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9501_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Dissemination The term “dissemination” means the communication and transfer of the results of scientifically valid research, statistics, and evaluations, in forms that are understandable, easily accessible, and usable, or adaptable for use in, the improvement of educational practice by teachers, administrators, librarians, other practitioners, researchers, parents, policymakers, and the public, through technical assistance, publications, electronic transfer, and other means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>