<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9546" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9546/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9546/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9546"><akn:num>9546</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9546. Dissemination(a) General requests(1) In generalThe Statistics Center may furnish transcripts or copies of tables and other statistical records and make special statistical compilations and surveys for State and local officials, public and private organizations, and individuals.


(2) CompilationsThe Statistics Center shall provide State educational agencies, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education with opportunities to suggest the establishment of particular compilations of statistics, surveys, and analyses that will assist those educational agencies.



(b) Congressional requestsThe Statistics Center shall furnish such special statistical compilations and surveys as the relevant congressional committees may request.


(c) Joint statistical projectsThe Statistics Center may engage in joint statistical projects related to the mission of the Center, or other statistical purposes authorized by law, with nonprofit organizations or agencies, and the cost of such projects shall be shared equitably as determined by the Secretary.


(d) Fees(1) In generalStatistical compilations and surveys under this section, other than those carried out pursuant to subsections (b) and (c), may be made subject to the payment of the actual or estimated cost of such work.


(2) Funds receivedAll funds received in payment for work or services described in this subsection may be used to pay directly the costs of such work or services, to repay appropriations that initially bore all or part of such costs, or to refund excess sums when necessary.



(e) Access(1) Other agenciesThe Statistics Center shall, consistent with section 9573 of this title, cooperate with other Federal agencies having a need for educational data in providing access to educational data received by the Statistics Center.


(2) Interested partiesThe Statistics Center shall, in accordance with such terms and conditions as the Center may prescribe, provide all interested parties, including pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9546_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9546_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional requests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional requests The Statistics Center shall furnish such special statistical compilations and surveys as the relevant congressional committees may request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9546_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint statistical projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Joint statistical projects The Statistics Center may engage in joint statistical projects related to the mission of the Center, or other statistical purposes authorized by law, with nonprofit organizations or agencies, and the cost of such projects shall be shared equitably as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9546_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9546_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>