<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9564"><akn:num>9564</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional educational laboratories for research, development, dissemination, and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9564. Regional educational laboratories for research, development, dissemination, and technical assistance(a) Regional educational laboratoriesThe Director shall enter into contracts with entities to establish a networked system of 10 regional educational laboratories that serve the needs of each region of the United States in accordance with the provisions of this section. The amount of assistance allocated to each laboratory by the Evaluation and Regional Assistance Commissioner shall reflect the number of local educational agencies and the number of school-age children within the region served by such laboratory, as well as the cost of providing services within the geographic area encompassed by the region.


(b) RegionsThe regions served by the regional educational laboratories shall be the 10 geographic regions served by the regional educational laboratories established under section 941(h) of the Educational Research, Development, Dissemination, and Improvement Act of 1994 (as such provision existed on the day before November 5, 2002).


(c) Eligible applicantsThe Director may enter into contracts under this section with research organizations, institutions, agencies, institutions of higher education, or partnerships among such entities, or individuals, with the demonstrated ability or capacity to carry out the activities described in this section, including regional entities that carried out activities under the Educational Research, Development, Dissemination, and Improvement Act of 1994 (as such Act existed on the day before November 5, 2002) and title XIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (as such title existed on the day before January 8, 2002).


(d) Applications(1) SubmissionEach applicant desiring a contract under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require.


(2) PlanEach application submitted under paragraph (1) shall contain a 5-y</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional educational laboratories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regional educational laboratories The Director shall enter into contracts with entities to establish a networked system of 10 regional educational laboratories that serve the needs of each region of the United States in accordance with the provisions of this section. The amount of assistance allocated to each laboratory by the Evaluation and Regional Assistance Commissioner shall reflect the number of local educational agencies and the number of school-age children within the region served by such laboratory, as well as the cost of providing services within the geographic area encompassed by the region.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regions The regions served by the regional educational laboratories shall be the 10 geographic regions served by the regional educational laboratories established under section 941(h) of the Educational Research, Development, Dissemination, and Improvement Act of 1994 (as such provision existed on the day before November 5, 2002).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible applicants The Director may enter into contracts under this section with research organizations, institutions, agencies, institutions of higher education, or partnerships among such entities, or individuals, with the demonstrated ability or capacity to carry out the activities described in this section, including regional entities that carried out activities under the Educational Research, Development, Dissemination, and Improvement Act of 1994 (as such Act existed on the day before November 5, 2002) and title XIII of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (as such title existed on the day before January 8, 2002).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entering into contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Entering into contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Central mission and primary function</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Central mission and primary function Each regional educational laboratory awarded a contract under this section shall support applied research, development, wide dissemination, and technical assistance activities by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Activities Each regional educational laboratory awarded a contract under this section shall carry out the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Governing board and allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Governing board and allocation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of governing board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Duties of governing board In order to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the regional educational laboratories, the governing boards of the regional educational laboratories shall establish and maintain a network to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Evaluations The Evaluation and Regional Assistance Commissioner shall provide for independent evaluations of each of the regional educational laboratories in carrying out the duties described in this section in the third year that such laboratory receives assistance under this section in accordance with the standards developed by the Evaluation and Regional Assistance Commissioner and approved by the Board and shall transmit the results of such evaluations to the relevant committees of Congress, the Board, and the appropriate regional educational laboratory governing board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>