<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9576" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9576/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9576/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9576"><akn:num>9576</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to publish</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9576. Authority to publish(a) PublicationThe Director may prepare and publish (including through oral presentation) such research, statistics (consistent with part C), and evaluation information and reports from any office, board, committee, and center of the Institute, as needed to carry out the priorities and mission of the Institute without the approval of the Secretary or any other office of the Department.


(b) Advance copiesThe Director shall provide the Secretary and other relevant offices with an advance copy of any information to be published under this section before publication.


(c) Peer reviewAll research, statistics, and evaluation reports conducted by, or supported through, the Institute shall be subjected to rigorous peer review before being published or otherwise made available to the public.


(d) Items not coveredNothing in subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a), (b), or (c) shall be construed to apply to—(1) information on current or proposed budgets, appropriations, or legislation;

(2) information prohibited from disclosure by law or the Constitution, classified national security information, or information described in section 552(b) of title 5; and

(3) review by officers of the United States in order to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of information described in paragraph (1) or (2).


(Pub. L. 107–279, title I, § 186, Nov. 5, 2002, 116 Stat. 1973.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9576_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Publication The Director may prepare and publish (including through oral presentation) such research, statistics (consistent with part C), and evaluation information and reports from any office, board, committee, and center of the Institute, as needed to carry out the priorities and mission of the Institute without the approval of the Secretary or any other office of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9576_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance copies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advance copies The Director shall provide the Secretary and other relevant offices with an advance copy of any information to be published under this section before publication.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9576_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Peer review All research, statistics, and evaluation reports conducted by, or supported through, the Institute shall be subjected to rigorous peer review before being published or otherwise made available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9576_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Items not covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Items not covered Nothing in subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a), (b), or (c) shall be construed to apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>