<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/960" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/960/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/960/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_960"><akn:num>960</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 960. Authorization of appropriations(a) Contracts, grants-in-aid, and loans to groups, individuals, public agencies, and private nonprofit organizations; availability of appropriations; guidelines(1)(A)(i) For the purpose of carrying out section 954(c) of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated to the National Endowment for the Arts $125,800,000 for fiscal year 1991 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1992 and 1993.

(ii) For fiscal years—(I) 1991 and 1992 not less than 25 percent of the amount appropriated for the respective fiscal year; and

(II) 1993 not less than 27.5 percent of the amount appropriated for such fiscal year;


shall be for carrying out section 954(g) of this title.

(iii) For fiscal years—(I) 1991 and 1992 not less than 5 percent of the amount appropriated for the respective fiscal year; and

(II) 1993 not less than 7.5 percent of the amount appropriated for such fiscal year;


shall be for carrying out programs under section 954(p)(2) of this title (relating to programs to expand public access to the arts in rural and innercity areas). Not less than 50 percent of the funds required by this clause to be used for carrying out such programs shall be used for carrying out such programs in rural areas.


(B) For the purpose of carrying out section 956(c) of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated to the National Endowment for the Humanities $119,900,000 for fiscal year 1991 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1992 and 1993. Of the sums so appropriated for any fiscal year, not less than 20 per centum shall be for carrying out section 956(f) of this title.


(2)(A) There are authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year ending before October 1, 1993, to the National Endowment for the Arts an amount equal to the sum of—(i) the total amounts received by such Endowment under section 959(a)(2) of this title, including the value of property donated, bequeathed, or devised to such Endowment; and

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts, grants-in-aid, and loans to groups, individuals, public agencies, and private nonprofit organizations; availability of appropriations; guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts, grants-in-aid, and loans to groups, individuals, public agencies, and private nonprofit organizations; availability of appropriations; guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriated unexpended funds; notice of availability of funds by advance appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of appropriated unexpended funds; notice of availability of funds by advance appropriation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Total amount of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Total amount of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of grants to production workshops using admission proceeds for unauthorized purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition of grants to production workshops using admission proceeds for unauthorized purposes No grant shall be made to a workshop (other than a workshop conducted by a school, college, or university) for a production for which a direct or indirect admission charge is asked if the proceeds, after deducting reasonable costs, are used for purposes other than assisting the grantee to develop high standards of artistic excellence or encourage greater appreciation of the arts and humanities by our citizens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_960_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations for arts education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Availability of appropriations for arts education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>