<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9605"><akn:num>9605</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional advisory committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9605. Regional advisory committees(a) EstablishmentBeginning in 2004, the Secretary shall establish a regional advisory committee for each region described in section 9564(b) of this title.


(b) Membership(1) CompositionThe membership of each regional advisory committee shall—(A) not exceed 25 members;

(B) contain a balanced representation of States in the region; and

(C) include not more than one representative of each State educational agency geographically located in the region.


(2) EligibilityThe membership of each regional advisory committee may include the following:(A) Representatives of local educational agencies, including rural and urban local educational agencies.

(B) Representatives of institutions of higher education, including individuals representing university-based education research and university-based research on subjects other than education.

(C) Parents.

(D) Practicing educators, including classroom teachers, principals, administrators, school board members, and other local school officials.

(E) Representatives of business.

(F) Researchers.


(3) RecommendationsIn choosing individuals for membership on a regional advisory committee, the Secretary shall consult with, and solicit recommendations from, the chief executive officers of States, chief State school officers, and education stakeholders within the applicable region.


(4) Special rule(A) Total numberThe total number of members on each committee who are selected under subparagraphs (A), (C), and (D) of paragraph (2), collectively, shall exceed the total number of members who are selected under paragraph (1)(C) and subparagraphs (B), (E), and (F) of paragraph (2), collectively.


(B) DissolutionEach regional advisory committee shall be dissolved by the Secretary after submission of such committee’s report described in subsection (c)(2) to the Secretary, but each such committee may be reconvened at the discretion of the Secretary.




(c) DutiesEach regional advisory committee s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Beginning in 2004, the Secretary shall establish a regional advisory committee for each region described in section 9564(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties Each regional advisory committee shall advise the Secretary on the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9605_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regional assessments Each regional advisory committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>