<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9631"><akn:num>9631</akn:num><akn:heading>National Center for Research in Advanced Information and Digital Technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9631. National Center for Research in Advanced Information and Digital Technologies(a) EstablishmentThere shall be established, during the first fiscal year for which appropriations are made available under subsection (c), a nonprofit corporation to be known as the National Center for Research in Advanced Information and Digital Technologies, which shall not be an agency or establishment of the Federal Government. The Center shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and, to the extent consistent with this section, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (sec. 29–501 et seq., D.C. Official Code).


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the Center shall be to support a comprehensive research and development program to harness the increasing capacity of advanced information and digital technologies to improve all levels of learning and education, formal and informal, in order to provide Americans with the knowledge and skills needed to compete in the global economy.


(c) Funding(1) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Center such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.


(2) Additional fundsThe Center is authorized—(A) to accept funds from any Federal agency or entity;

(B) to accept, hold, administer, and spend any gift, devise, or bequest of real or personal property made to the Center; and

(C) to enter into competitive contracts with individuals, public or private organizations, professional societies, and government agencies for the purpose of carrying out the functions of the Center.


(3) ProhibitionThe Center shall not accept gifts, devises, or bequests from a foreign government or foreign source.



(d) Board of Directors; vacancies; compensation(1) In generalA Board of the Center shall be established to oversee the administration of the Center.


(2) Initial compositionThe initial Board shall consist of nine members to be appointed by the Secretary of E</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be established, during the first fiscal year for which appropriations are made available under subsection (c), a nonprofit corporation to be known as the National Center for Research in Advanced Information and Digital Technologies, which shall not be an agency or establishment of the Federal Government. The Center shall be subject to the provisions of this section, and, to the extent consistent with this section, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (sec. 29–501 et seq., D.C. Official Code).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the Center shall be to support a comprehensive research and development program to harness the increasing capacity of advanced information and digital technologies to improve all levels of learning and education, formal and informal, in order to provide Americans with the knowledge and skills needed to compete in the global economy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors; vacancies; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board of Directors; vacancies; compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Director and staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Center activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accountability and reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds subject to appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of funds subject to appropriations The authority to award grants, enter into contracts, or otherwise expend funds under this section is subject to the availability of amounts deposited into the Center under subsection (c), or amounts otherwise appropriated for such purposes by an Act of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9631_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>