<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9701" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9701/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9701/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9701"><akn:num>9701</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9701. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(1) the term “Chairperson” means the Chairperson of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission; and

(2) the term “Commission” means the Financial Literacy and Education Commission established under section 9702 of this title.

(Pub. L. 108–159, title V, § 512, Dec. 4, 2003, 117 Stat. 2003.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection subject to joint regulations establishing effective dates as prescribed by Federal Reserve Board and Federal Trade Commission, except as otherwise provided, see section 3 of Pub. L. 108–159, set out as an Effective Date of 2003 Amendment note under section 1681 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade.

Short TitlePub. L. 108–159, title V, § 511, Dec. 4, 2003, 117 Stat. 2003, provided that: “This title [enacting this chapter] may be cited as the ‘Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act’.”


Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 13455. Establishing the President’s Advisory Council on Financial Literacy
Ex. Ord. No. 13455, Jan. 22, 2008, 73 F.R. 4445, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America and to promote and enhance financial literacy among the American people, it is hereby ordered as follows:
Section 1. Policy. To help keep America competitive and assist the American people in understanding and addressing financial matters, it is the policy of the Federal Government to encourage financial literacy among the American people.
Sec. 2. Establishment of the Council. There is established within the Department of the Treasury the President’s Advisory Council on Financial Literacy (Council).
Sec. 3. Membership and Operation of the Council. (a) The Council shall consist of 19 members appointed by the President from among individuals not employed by the Federal Government, consistent with subsection (b) of this section.
(b) In selecting individuals for appointment to the Council, appropriate consideration</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9701_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) the term “Chairperson” means the Chairperson of the Financial Literacy and Education Commission; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9701_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the term “Commission” means the Financial Literacy and Education Commission established under section 9702 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>