<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9802"><akn:num>9802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9802. Definitions(a) ESEA definitionsUnless otherwise specified in this chapter, the terms used in this chapter have the meanings given the terms in section 7801 of this title.


(b) Other definitionsIn this chapter:(1) Critical foreign languageThe term “critical foreign language” means a foreign language that the Secretary determines, in consultation with the heads of such Federal departments and agencies as the Secretary determines appropriate, is critical to the national security and economic competitiveness of the United States.


(2) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001(a) of this title.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Education.


(4) Scientifically valid researchThe term “scientifically valid research” includes applied research, basic research, and field-initiated research in which the rationale, design, and interpretation are soundly developed in accordance with accepted principles of scientific research.



(Pub. L. 110–69, title VI, § 6001, formerly § 6002, Aug. 9, 2007, 121 Stat. 625; renumbered § 6001, Pub. L. 111–358, title X, § 1002(b)(1), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 4048; Pub. L. 114–95, title IX, § 9215(i)(1), Dec. 10, 2015, 129 Stat. 2167.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 6001 of Pub. L. 110–69 was classified to section 9801 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 111–358.

Amendments2015—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 114–95 made amendment to reference in original act which appears in text as reference to section 7801 of this title. Amendment was executed to this section, which is section 6001 of Pub. L. 110–69, notwithstanding directory language directing amendment of section 6002(a) of Pub. L. 110–69, to reflect the probable intent of Congress and the renumbering of section 6002 of Pub. L. 110–69 as this section. Pub. L. 110–69 does not contain a section 6002.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2015 Amendme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>ESEA definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) ESEA definitions Unless otherwise specified in this chapter, the terms used in this chapter have the meanings given the terms in section 7801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other definitions In this chapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>