<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9832" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9832/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9832/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9832"><akn:num>9832</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9832. Definitions
In this part:(1) Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courseThe term “Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate course” means—(A) a course of college-level instruction provided to secondary school students, terminating in an examination administered by the College Board or the International Baccalaureate Organization, or another such examination approved by the Secretary; or

(B) another highly rigorous, evidence-based, postsecondary preparatory program terminating in an examination administered by another nationally recognized educational organization that has a demonstrated record of effectiveness in assessing secondary school students, or another such examination approved by the Secretary.


(2) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(A) a State educational agency;

(B) a local educational agency; or

(C) a partnership consisting of—(i) a national, regional, or statewide nonprofit organization, with expertise and experience in providing Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate services; and

(ii) a State educational agency or local educational agency.



(3) Low-income studentThe term “low-income student” means an individual who is determined by a State educational agency or local educational agency to be a child ages 5 through 19, from a low-income family, on the basis of data used by the Secretary to determine allocations under section 6333 of this title, data on children eligible for free or reduced-price lunches under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.], data on children in families receiving assistance under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.], or data on children eligible to receive medical assistance under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.], or through an alternate method that combines or extrapolates from those data.


(4) High concentration of low-income studentsThe term “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate course</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate course The term “Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate course” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Eligible entity The term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income student</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Low-income student The term “low-income student” means an individual who is determined by a State educational agency or local educational agency to be a child ages 5 through 19, from a low-income family, on the basis of data used by the Secretary to determine allocations under section 6333 of this title, data on children eligible for free or reduced-price lunches under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.], data on children in families receiving assistance under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.], or data on children eligible to receive medical assistance under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.], or through an alternate method that combines or extrapolates from those data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>High concentration of low-income students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) High concentration of low-income students The term “high concentration of low-income students”, used with respect to a school, means a school that serves a student population 40 percent or more of who are low-income students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-need local educational agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) High-need local educational agency The term “high-need local educational agency” means a local educational agency or educational service agency described in 9812(3)(A) 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9832_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-need school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) High-need school The term “high-need school” means a secondary school—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>