<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9833" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9833/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9833/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9833"><akn:num>9833</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9833. Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate programs(a) Program authorizedFrom the amounts appropriated under subsection (l), the Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the authorized activities described in subsection (g).


(b) Duration of grantsThe Secretary may award grants under this section for a period of not more than 5 years.


(c) CoordinationThe Secretary shall coordinate the activities carried out under this section with any activities carried out under section 7114 or 7117 of this title that provide students access to accelerated learning programs that provide—(1) postsecondary level courses accepted for credit at institutions of higher education, including dual or concurrent enrollment programs, and early college high schools; or

(2) postsecondary level instruction and examinations that are accepted for credit at institutions of higher education, including Advanced Placement and International Baccalaureate programs.


(d) PriorityIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that are part of a statewide strategy for increasing—(1) the availability of Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign languages, and pre-Advanced Placement or pre-International Baccalaureate courses in such subjects, in high-need schools; and

(2) the number of students who participate in Advanced Placement or International Baccalaureate courses in mathematics, science, and critical foreign language in high-need schools, and take and score a 3, 4, or 5 on an Advanced Placement examination in such a subject, or pass an examination administered by the International Baccalaureate Organization in such a subject in such schools.


(e) Equitable distributionThe Secretary, to the extent practicable, shall—(1) ensure an equitable geographic distribution of grants under this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized From the amounts appropriated under subsection (l), the Secretary is authorized to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable the eligible entities to carry out the authorized activities described in subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duration of grants The Secretary may award grants under this section for a period of not more than 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination The Secretary shall coordinate the activities carried out under this section with any activities carried out under section 7114 or 7117 of this title that provide students access to accelerated learning programs that provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that are part of a statewide strategy for increasing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Equitable distribution The Secretary, to the extent practicable, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorized activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Matching requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Supplement not supplant Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal and non-Federal funds available to carry out the activities described in subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9833_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collecting and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Collecting and reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>