<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9903"><akn:num>9903</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9903. Grant program(a) In generalThe Director shall establish a grant program to support programs at institutions of higher education to carry out the purpose of this chapter.


(b) Geographical considerationsIn the administration of this chapter, the Director shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that grants are equitably distributed across all regions of the United States, taking into account population density and other geographic and demographic considerations.


(c) Amount of grantSubject to the requirements of subsection (d), the Director may award grants annually on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education in the amount of $2,000,000, per institution of which—(1) $1,500,000 shall be used—(A) to design, implement, and evaluate a program that meets the requirements of section 9902 of this title;

(B) to employ master teachers at the institution to oversee field experiences;

(C) to provide a stipend to mentor teachers participating in the program; and

(D) to support curriculum development and implementation strategies for science, technology, engineering, and mathematics content courses taught through the program; and


(2) up to $500,000 shall be set aside by the grantee for technical support and evaluation services from the institution whose programs will be replicated.


(d) EligibilityTo be eligible to apply for a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall—(1) include former secondary school science, technology, engineering, or mathematics master teachers as faculty in its science department for this program;

(2) grant terminal degrees in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and

(3) have a process to be used in establishing partnerships with local educational agencies for placement of participating students in their field experiences, including a process for identifying mentor teachers working in local schools to supervise classroom field experiences in cooperation with university-based</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall establish a grant program to support programs at institutions of higher education to carry out the purpose of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographical considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Geographical considerations In the administration of this chapter, the Director shall take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that grants are equitably distributed across all regions of the United States, taking into account population density and other geographic and demographic considerations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of grant Subject to the requirements of subsection (d), the Director may award grants annually on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education in the amount of $2,000,000, per institution of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility To be eligible to apply for a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application requirements An institution of higher education seeking a grant under the program shall submit an application to the Director in such form, at such time, and containing such information and assurances as the Director may require, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching requirement An institution of higher education may not receive a grant under this section unless it provides, from non-federal sources, to carry out the activities supported by the grant, an amount that is not less than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9903_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Guidance Within 90 days after January 4, 2011, the Director shall initiate a proceeding to promulgate guidance for the administration of the grant program established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>