<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/20/9905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9905"><akn:num>9905</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9905. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Field-based courseThe term “field-based course” means a course of instruction offered by an institution of higher education that includes a requirement that students teach a minimum of 3 lessons or sequences of lessons to elementary or secondary students.


(2) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term by section 1001 of this title.


(3) Master teacherThe term “master teacher” means an individual—(A) who has been awarded a master’s or doctoral degree by an institution of higher education;

(B) whose graduate coursework included courses in mathematics, science, computer science, or engineering;

(C) who has at least 3 years teaching experience in K–12 settings; and

(D) whose teaching has been recognized for exceptional accomplishments in educating students, or is demonstrated to have resulted in improved student achievement.


(4) Mentor teacherThe term “mentor teacher” means an elementary or secondary school classroom teacher who assists with the training of students participating in a field-based course.


(5) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the National Science Foundation.


(Pub. L. 111–358, title V, § 555, Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 4025.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Field-based course</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Field-based course The term “field-based course” means a course of instruction offered by an institution of higher education that includes a requirement that students teach a minimum of 3 lessons or sequences of lessons to elementary or secondary students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term by section 1001 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Master teacher</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Master teacher The term “master teacher” means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentor teacher</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Mentor teacher The term “mentor teacher” means an elementary or secondary school classroom teacher who assists with the training of students participating in a field-based course.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the National Science Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>