<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/13/305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/13/305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/13/305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_305"><akn:num>305</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for unlawful export information activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 305. Penalties for unlawful export information activities(a) Criminal Penalties.—(1) Failure to file; submission of false or misleading information.—Any person who knowingly fails to file or knowingly submits false or misleading export information through the Shippers Export Declaration (SED) (or any successor document) or the Automated Export System (AES) shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $10,000 per violation or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.

(2) Furtherance of illegal activities.—Any person who knowingly reports any information on or uses the SED or the AES to further any illegal activity shall be subject to a fine not to exceed $10,000 per violation or imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.

(3) Forfeiture penalties.—Any person who is convicted under this subsection shall, in addition to any other penalty, be subject to forfeiting to the United States—(A) any of that person’s interest in, security of, claim against, or property or contractual rights of any kind in the goods or tangible items that were the subject of the violation;

(B) any of that person’s interest in, security of, claim against, or property or contractual rights of any kind in tangible property that was used in the export or attempt to export that was the subject of the violation; and

(C) any of that person’s property constituting, or derived from, any proceeds obtained directly or indirectly as a result of the violation.



(b) Civil Penalties.—The Secretary (and officers of the Department of Commerce specifically designated by the Secretary) may impose a civil penalty not to exceed $10,000 per violation on any person violating the provisions of this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order issued thereunder, except as provided in section 304. Such penalty may be in addition to any other penalty imposed by law.

(c) Civil Penalty Procedure.—(1) In general.—Whenever a civil penalty is sought for a violation of this section or of section 304, the charged p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Penalties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary (and officers of the Department of Commerce specifically designated by the Secretary) may impose a civil penalty not to exceed $10,000 per violation on any person violating the provisions of this chapter or any rule, regulation, or order issued thereunder, except as provided in section 304. Such penalty may be in addition to any other penalty imposed by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil Penalty Procedure.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Commerce shall promulgate regulations for the implementation and enforcement of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_305_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The criminal fines provided for in this section are exempt from the provisions of section 3571 of title 18, United States Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>