<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1016" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1016/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1016/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1016"><akn:num>1016</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary rail banking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1016. Temporary rail banking
During the 180-day period beginning on May 30, 1980, no rail line or facility of the Rock Island Railroad which has been approved for abandonment by the Commission or the bankruptcy court may be downgraded, scrapped, or otherwise disposed of without the approval of the Secretary under this section. In no case before abandonment has been approved and before the 180-day period has elapsed shall the Secretary approve a disposition of such portion of the rail line or related facility to any carrier or other entity not engaged in providing railroad services or not formed for the purpose of providing railroad services. The Secretary, upon application by the Rock Island Railroad, shall grant such approval unless he finds that—(1) a rail carrier, shipper, State, or other interested party has expressed in writing an interest in purchasing, leasing or rehabilitating the particular rail line or facility for purposes of providing rail service; and

(2) there is a reasonable expectation that such purchase transaction will be consummated.

(Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 121, May 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 409.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Abolition of Interstate Commerce Commission and Transfer of Functions
Interstate Commerce Commission abolished and functions of Commission transferred, except as otherwise provided in Pub. L. 104–88, to Surface Transportation Board effective Jan. 1, 1996, by section 1302 of Title 49, Transportation, and section 101 of Pub. L. 104–88, set out as a note under section 1301 of Title 49. References to Interstate Commerce Commission deemed to refer to Surface Transportation Board, a member or employee of the Board, or Secretary of Transportation, as appropriate, see section 205 of Pub. L. 104–88, set out as a note under section 1301 of Title 49.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1016_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) a rail carrier, shipper, State, or other interested party has expressed in writing an interest in purchasing, leasing or rehabilitating the particular rail line or facility for purposes of providing rail service; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1016_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) there is a reasonable expectation that such purchase transaction will be consummated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>