<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1017" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1017/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1017/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1017"><akn:num>1017</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary operating approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1017. Temporary operating approval(a) Use of tracks and facilities by other rail carriers; terms of compensation; continuation of serviceThe Commission may authorize any rail carrier willing to do so voluntarily to use the tracks and facilities of a carrier which, on January 14, 1983, was the subject of a proceeding pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act or under subchapter IV of chapter 11 of title 11. The use of such tracks and facilities shall be under such terms of compensation as the carriers establish between themselves, or if the carriers are unable to agree, under such terms of compensation as the Commission finds to be reasonable. The Commission shall have authority to authorize continued rail service under this section over the lines of any such carrier which has been ordered by the court having jurisdiction over such a carrier to liquidate its properties until the disposition of the properties of the estate of such carrier.


(b) Use of employeesIn carrying out the provisions of this section, the Commission shall require, to the maximum extent practicable, the use of the employees who would normally have performed work in connection with the traffic subject to the action of the Commission.


(Pub. L. 96–254, title I, § 122, May 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 409; Pub. L. 97–130, § 5(a), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1690; Pub. L. 97–468, title II, § 214, Jan. 14, 1983, 96 Stat. 2545.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 77 of the Bankruptcy Act, referred to in subsec. (a), was classified to section 205 of former Title 11, Bankruptcy. The Bankruptcy Act (act July 1, 1898, ch. 541, 30 Stat. 544) was repealed effective Oct. 1, 1979, by Pub. L. 95–598, §§ 401(a), 402(a), Nov. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 2682, section 101 of which enacted revised Title 11. For current provisions relating to railroad reorganization, see subchapter IV (§ 1161 et seq.) of chapter 11 of Title 11.

Amendments1983—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 97–468, § 214(a), substituted “a carrier which, on January</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1017_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of tracks and facilities by other rail carriers; terms of compensation; continuation of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of tracks and facilities by other rail carriers; terms of compensation; continuation of service The Commission may authorize any rail carrier willing to do so voluntarily to use the tracks and facilities of a carrier which, on January 14, 1983, was the subject of a proceeding pending under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act or under subchapter IV of chapter 11 of title 11. The use of such tracks and facilities shall be under such terms of compensation as the carriers establish between themselves, or if the carriers are unable to agree, under such terms of compensation as the Commission finds to be reasonable. The Commission shall have authority to authorize continued rail service under this section over the lines of any such carrier which has been ordered by the court having jurisdiction over such a carrier to liquidate its properties until the disposition of the properties of the estate of such carrier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1017_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of employees In carrying out the provisions of this section, the Commission shall require, to the maximum extent practicable, the use of the employees who would normally have performed work in connection with the traffic subject to the action of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>