<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1212"><akn:num>1212</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1212. Applicability of other laws(a) Actions subject to other lawsThe provisions of chapter 5 of title 5 (popularly known as the Administrative Procedure Act, and including provisions popularly known as the Government in the Sunshine Act), chapter 10 of title 5, division A of subtitle III of title 54, section 303 of title 49, and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) shall not apply to actions taken pursuant to this chapter, except to the extent that such laws may be applicable to granting of rights-of-way under section 1208 of this title.


(b) Federal surplus property disposal; withdrawal or reservation of land for use of Alaska RailroadThe enactment of this chapter, actions taken during the transition period as provided in section 1204 of this title, and transfer of the rail properties of the Alaska Railroad under authority of this chapter shall be deemed not to be the disposal of Federal surplus property under sections 541 to 555 of title 40 or the Act of October 3, 1944, popularly referred to as the “Surplus Property Act of 1944” (50 U.S.C. App. 1622).11 See References in Text note below. Such events shall not constitute or cause the revocation of any prior withdrawal or reservation of land for the use of the Alaska Railroad under the Act of March 12, 1914 (43 U.S.C. 975 et seq.), the Alaska Statehood Act (note preceding 48 U.S.C. 21), the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), the Act of January 2, 1976 (Public Law 94–204; 89 Stat. 1145), the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (Public Law 96–487; 94 Stat. 2371), and the general land and land management laws of the United States.


(c) Ceiling on Government contributions for Federal employees health benefits insurance premiumsBeginning on January 14, 1983, the ceiling on Government contributions for Federal employees health benefits insurance premiums under section 8906(b)(2) of title 5 shall not apply to the Alaska Railroad.


(d) Acreage e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions subject to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Actions subject to other laws The provisions of chapter 5 of title 5 (popularly known as the Administrative Procedure Act, and including provisions popularly known as the Government in the Sunshine Act), chapter 10 of title 5, division A of subtitle III of title 54, section 303 of title 49, and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) shall not apply to actions taken pursuant to this chapter, except to the extent that such laws may be applicable to granting of rights-of-way under section 1208 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal surplus property disposal; withdrawal or reservation of land for use of Alaska Railroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal surplus property disposal; withdrawal or reservation of land for use of Alaska Railroad The enactment of this chapter, actions taken during the transition period as provided in section 1204 of this title, and transfer of the rail properties of the Alaska Railroad under authority of this chapter shall be deemed not to be the disposal of Federal surplus property under sections 541 to 555 of title 40 or the Act of October 3, 1944, popularly referred to as the “Surplus Property Act of 1944” (50 U.S.C. App. 1622).11 See References in Text note below. Such events shall not constitute or cause the revocation of any prior withdrawal or reservation of land for the use of the Alaska Railroad under the Act of March 12, 1914 (43 U.S.C. 975 et seq.), the Alaska Statehood Act (note preceding 48 U.S.C. 21), the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.), the Act of January 2, 1976 (Public Law 94–204; 89 Stat. 1145), the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (Pu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceiling on Government contributions for Federal employees health benefits insurance premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ceiling on Government contributions for Federal employees health benefits insurance premiums Beginning on January 14, 1983, the ceiling on Government contributions for Federal employees health benefits insurance premiums under section 8906(b)(2) of title 5 shall not apply to the Alaska Railroad.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acreage entitlement of State or Native Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acreage entitlement of State or Native Corporation Nothing in this chapter is intended to enlarge or diminish the acreage entitlement of the State or any Native Corporation pursuant to existing law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1212_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judgments involving interests, etc., of Native Corporations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Judgments involving interests, etc., of Native Corporations With respect to interests of Native Corporations under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.) and the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.), except as provided in this chapter, nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to deny, enlarge, grant, impair, or otherwise affect any judgment heretofore entered in a court of competent jurisdiction, or valid existing right or claim of valid existing right.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>