<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1311"><akn:num>1311</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation for public offering</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1311. Preparation for public offering(a) Public offering managers(1) Not later than 30 days after October 21, 1986, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, shall retain the services of investment banking firms to serve jointly and be compensated equally as co-lead managers of the public offering (hereafter in this part referred to as the “co-lead managers”) and to establish a syndicate to underwrite the public offering. The total number of co-lead managers shall be no fewer than 4 nor greater than 6. The Secretary shall designate one co-lead manager to coordinate and administer the public offering.

(2) In selecting the investment banking firms to serve as co-lead managers of the public offering under paragraph (1), consideration shall be given to the firm’s institutional and retail distribution capabilities, financial strength, knowledge of the railroad industry, experience in large scale public offerings, research capability, and reputation. In addition, recognition shall also be given to contributions made by particular investment banking firms before October 21, 1986, in demonstrating and promoting the long-term financial viability of the Corporation.


(b) Payment to United States(1) Not later than 30 days after October 21, 1986, the Corporation shall transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury $200,000,000.

(2) On or before February 1, 1987, or 30 days before the sale date, whichever occurs first, the Secretary of Transportation shall determine whether to require the Corporation to transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury, in addition to amounts transferred under paragraph (1), not to exceed $100,000,000, taking into account the viability of the Corporation. The Corporation shall transfer such funds as are required to be transferred under this paragraph.


(c) Registration statementThe Corporation shall prepare and cause to be filed with the Securities </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public offering managers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Public offering managers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment to United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registration statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Registration statement The Corporation shall prepare and cause to be filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission a registration statement with respect to the securities to be offered and sold in accordance with the securities laws and the rules and regulations thereunder in connection with the initial and any subsequent public offering.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>