<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1312" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1312/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1312/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1312"><akn:num>1312</akn:num><akn:heading>Public offering</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1312. Public offering(a) Structure of public offering(1) After the registration statement referred to in section 1311(c) of this title is declared effective by the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, and the co-lead managers, shall offer the United States shares for sale in a public offering, except as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3).

(2) The Secretary of Transportation, after such consultation, may elect to offer less than all of the United States shares for sale at the time of the initial sale.

(3) Under no circumstances shall the Secretary of Transportation offer any of the United States shares for sale unless, before the sale date, the Secretary determines, after such consultation, that the estimated sum of the gross proceeds from the sale of all the United States shares will be an adequate amount. A determination by the Secretary under this paragraph shall not be reviewable.

(4) In making a determination under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall have the goal of obtaining at least $2,000,000,000 in aggregate gross proceeds for the United States from the public offering and any payments made under section 1311(b) of this title.


(b) Subsequent salesIf the Secretary of Transportation elects to offer for sale less than all the United States shares, the Secretary shall sell the remaining United States shares in subsequent public offerings.


(c) Consent of Corporation not requiredAny public offering under this section may be made without the consent of the Corporation.


(d) Authority to require stock splits(1) The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the co-lead managers and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, may, in connection with the initial public offering described in subsection (a), before the filing of the registration statement referred to in section 1311(c) of this titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Structure of public offering</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Structure of public offering</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subsequent sales If the Secretary of Transportation elects to offer for sale less than all the United States shares, the Secretary shall sell the remaining United States shares in subsequent public offerings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent of Corporation not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consent of Corporation not required Any public offering under this section may be made without the consent of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to require stock splits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority to require stock splits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of other securities held by United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cancellation of other securities held by United States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minority investment banking firms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Minority investment banking firms The Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that minority owned or controlled investment banking firms shall have an opportunity to participate to a significant degree in any public offering under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment banking firm requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Investment banking firm requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1312_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government Accountability Office authority to conduct audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Government Accountability Office authority to conduct audits The Government Accountability Office may make such audits as may be deemed appropriate by the Comptroller General of the United States of all accounts, books, records, memoranda, correspondence, and other documents and transactions of the Corporation and the co-lead managers associated with the public offering. The co-lead managers shall agree, in writing, to allow the Government Accountability Office to make such audits. The Government Accountability Office shall report the results of all such audits to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>