<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/1323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1323"><akn:num>1323</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1323. Board of Directors
The Board of Directors of the Corporation shall be comprised as follows:(1) Except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the period ending June 30, 1987, the board shall remain as it exists on October 21, 1986, with any vacancies being filled by directors nominated and elected by the remainder of the members of the board.

(2)(A) Except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the period beginning July 1, 1987, the board shall consist of—(i) 3 directors appointed by the Secretary of Transportation;

(ii) the Chief Executive Officer and the Chief Operating Officer of the Corporation; and

(iii) 8 directors appointed from among persons knowledgeable in business affairs by the special court trustees named under subparagraph (C), in consultation with the Secretary of Transportation and the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation, and recognizing the need for and importance of—(I) continuity in the direction of the Corporation’s business and affairs;

(II) preserving the value of the investment of the United States in the Corporation;

(III) preserving essential rail service provided by the Corporation; and

(IV) providing for the sale of the United States shares.



(B) The Secretary of Transportation and the special court trustees may appoint directors under subparagraph (A) from among existing directors of the Corporation.

(C)(i) If more than 50 percent of the interest of the United States in the Corporation has not been sold before June 1, 1987, the special court established under section 719 of this title shall, on that date, name 3 trustees from among persons knowledgeable in business affairs to make the appointments required by subparagraph (A)(iii). The Corporation shall compensate the special court trustees in an amount to be specified by the special court, not to exceed the amount paid by the Corporation to its directors for comparable services.

(ii) No person shall be eligible to be appointed as a special</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Except as provided in paragraph (3), with respect to the period ending June 30, 1987, the board shall remain as it exists on October 21, 1986, with any vacancies being filled by directors nominated and elected by the remainder of the members of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1323_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>