<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231b"><akn:num>231b</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231b. Computation of annuities(a) Amount(1) The annuity of an individual under section 231a(a)(1) of this title shall be in an amount equal to the amount (before any reduction on account of age and before any deductions on account of work) of the old-age insurance benefit or disability insurance benefit to which such individual would have been entitled under the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] if all of his or her service as an employee after December 31, 1936, had been included in the term “employment” as defined in that Act.

(2) For purposes of this subsection, individuals entitled to an annuity under section 231a(a)(1)(ii) of this title shall, except for the purposes of recomputations in accordance with section 215(f) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 415(f)], be deemed to have attained retirement age (as defined by section 216(l) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 416(l)]). For purposes of this subsection, individuals entitled to an annuity under paragraph (iv) or (v) of section 231a(a)(1) of this title shall be deemed to be entitled to a disability insurance benefit under section 223 of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 423].

(3) If an individual entitled to an annuity under section 231a(a)(1)(i) or (iii) of this title on the basis of less than ten years of service is entitled to a benefit under section 202(a), section 202(b), or section 202(c) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 402(a), (b), (c)] which began to accrue before the annuity under section 231a(a)(1)(i) or (iii) of this title, the annuity amount provided such individual under this subsection, shall be computed as though the annuity under this subchapter began to accrue on the later of (A) the date on which the benefit under section 202(a), section 202(b), or section 202(c) of the Social Security Act began, or (B) the date on which the individual first met the conditions for entitlement to an age reduced annuity under this subchapter other than the conditions set forth in se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased annuities under subsection (a)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Increased annuities under subsection (a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (d) Repealed. Pub. L. 97–35, title XI, § 1118(b), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 631</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) , (d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Supplemental annuities The supplemental annuity of an individual under section 231a(b) of this title shall be $23 plus an additional amount of $4 for each year of service that the individual has in excess of 25 years, but in no case shall the supplemental annuity exceed $43.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions in annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reductions in annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased annuities under subsection (b)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Increased annuities under subsection (b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased annuities under subsections (a) and (b)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Increased annuities under subsections (a) and (b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Years of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Years of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Average monthly compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Average monthly compensation The “average monthly compensation” shall be computed in the manner specified in subsection (b) of this section, except (1) that with respect to service prior to January 1, 1937, the monthly compensation shall be the average compensation paid to an employee with respect to calendar months included in his years of service in the years 1924–1931, and (2) the amount of compensation paid or attributable as paid to him with respect to each month of service before September 1941 as a station employee whose duties consisted of or included the carrying of passengers’ hand baggage and otherwise assisting passengers at passenger stations and whose remuneration for service to the employer was, in whole or in substantial part, in the forms of tips, shall be the monthly average of the compensation paid to him as a station employee in his months of service in the period September 1940 through August 1941: Provided, however, That where service in the period 1924 throug</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231b_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Employee representatives The annuity of an individual who shall have been an employee representative shall be determined in the same manner and with the same effect as if the employee organization by which he shall have been employed were an employer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>