<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231c"><akn:num>231c</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of spouse and survivor annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231c. Computation of spouse and survivor annuities(a) Amount of spouses’ annuities; age(1) The annuity of a spouse or divorced wife of an individual under section 231a(c) of this title shall be in an amount equal to the amount (before any reduction on account of age and before any deductions on account of work) of the wife’s insurance benefit or the husband’s insurance benefit to which such spouse or divorced wife would have been entitled under the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] if such individual’s service as an employee after December 31, 1936, had been included in the term “employment” as defined in that Act.

(2) For purposes of this subsection, a spouse entitled to an annuity under section 231a(c)(1)(ii)(B) of this title shall be deemed to have attained retirement age (as defined in section 216(l) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 416(l)] 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a closing parenthesis..

(3) If a spouse entitled to an annuity under section 231a(c)(1)(ii)(A), section 231a(c)(1)(ii)(C), or section 231a(c)(2) of this title or a divorced spouse entitled to an annuity under section 231a(c)(4) of this title on the basis of the employment record of an employee who will have completed less than 10 years of service is entitled to a benefit under section 202(a), section 202(b), or section 202(c) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 402(a), (b), (c)] which began to accrue before the annuity under section 231a(c)(1)(ii)(A), section 231a(c)(1)(ii)(C), section 231a(c)(2), or section 231a(c)(4) of this title, the annuity amount provided under this subsection shall be computed as though the annuity under this subchapter began to accrue on the later of (A) the date on which the benefit under section 202(a), section 202(b), or section 202(c) of the Social Security Act began or (B) the first date on which the annuitant met the conditions for entitlement to an age reduced annuity under this subchapter other than the conditions set forth</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of spouses’ annuities; age</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of spouses’ annuities; age</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in spouses’ annuities in accordance with section 231b(b), (c), (d) of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Increases in spouses’ annuities in accordance with section 231b(b), (c), (d) of this title The amount of the annuity of a spouse of an individual provided under subsection (a) of this section shall be increased by an amount equal to 45 per centum of that portion of the individual’s annuity as is computed under subsection (b) of section 231b of this title: Provided, however, That if the spouse is entitled to an annuity amount provided by subsection (e)(1) or (e)(2) of this section, the amount of such spouse’s annuity provided by the preceding provisions of this subsection shall be reduced by the amount by which the amount computed in accordance with the provisions of clause (C) of subsection (e)(1) or (e)(2) of this section was increased by the Social Security Amendments of 1965, 1967, and 1969, disregarding (A) the amount of any such increase resulting from the Social Security Amendments of 1967 equal to, or less than, the excess of $5 over 5.8 per centum of the lesser of (i) the a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 107–90, title I, § 104(b), Dec. 21, 2001, 115 Stat. 882</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in spouses’ annuities in accordance with section 231b(g) of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Increases in spouses’ annuities in accordance with</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in particular spouses’ annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Increases in particular spouses’ annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of survivors’ annuities; age; entitlement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Amount of survivors’ annuities; age; entitlement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in survivor’s annuities in accordance with subsection (f)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Increases in survivor’s annuities in accordance with subsection (f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in particular widows’ and widowers’ annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Increases in particular widows’ and widowers’ annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reductions in survivors’ annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reductions in survivors’ annuities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>