<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/231f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_231f"><akn:num>231f</akn:num><akn:heading>Railroad Retirement Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 231f. Railroad Retirement Board(a) AdministrationThis subchapter shall be administered by the Railroad Retirement Board established by the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 [45 U.S.C. 228a et seq.] as an independent agency in the executive branch of the Government and composed of three members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Each member shall hold office for a term of five years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of the term and any member holding office pursuant to appointment under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 when this subchapter becomes effective shall hold office until the term for which he was appointed under such Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 expires. One member shall be appointed from recommendations made by representatives of the employees and one member shall be appointed from recommendations made by representatives of employers as defined in paragraph (i) of section 231(a)(1) of this title, in both cases as the President shall direct, so as to provide representation on the Board satisfactory to the largest number, respectively, of employees and employers concerned. One member, who shall be the chairman of the Board, shall be appointed without recommendation by either employers or employees and shall not be in the employment of or be pecuniarily or otherwise interested in any employer or organization of employees. Vacancies in the Board shall not impair the powers or affect the duties of the Board or of the remaining members of the Board, of whom a majority of those in office shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business. Upon the expiration of his term of office a member shall continue to serve until his successor is appointed and shall have qualified.


(b) Powers and duties(1) The Board shall have and exercise all the duties and powers necessary to a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration This subchapter shall be administered by the Railroad Retirement Board established by the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 [45 U.S.C. 228a et seq.] as an independent agency in the executive branch of the Government and composed of three members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Each member shall hold office for a term of five years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was appointed shall be appointed for the remainder of the term and any member holding office pursuant to appointment under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 when this subchapter becomes effective shall hold office until the term for which he was appointed under such Railroad Retirement Act of 1937 expires. One member shall be appointed from recommendations made by representatives of the employees and one member shall be appointed from recommendations made by representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Powers and duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of payments; adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sources of payments; adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hospital insurance benefits; certified beneficiaries; disability insurance benefits; services in Canada; exchange of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hospital insurance benefits; certified beneficiaries; disability insurance benefits; services in Canada; exchange of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts and bequests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acceptance of gifts and bequests The Board is authorized to accept on behalf of the United States money gifts and bequests made unconditionally to the Railroad Retirement Account, to the Railroad Retirement Supplemental Account, or to the Railroad Unemployment Insurance Account, or to the Board, or any member, officer, or employee thereof, for the benefit of such accounts or any activity financed through such accounts. Any such gift accepted pursuant to the authority granted in this subsection shall be deposited in the specific account designated by the donor or, if the donor has made no such specific designation, in the Railroad Retirement Account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_231f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional copies of documents submitted or transmitted to President or Office of Management and Budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Congressional copies of documents submitted or transmitted to President or Office of Management and Budget Whenever the Board submits or transmits any budget estimate, budget request, supplemental budget estimate, or other budget information, legislative recommendation, prepared testimony for congressional hearings, or comment on legislation to the President or to the Office of Management and Budget, it shall concurrently transmit a copy thereof to the Congress. No officer or agency of the United States shall have any authority to require the Board to submit its budget requests or estimates, legislative recommendations, prepared testimony for congressional hearings, or comments on legislation to any officer or agency of the United States for approval, comments, or review, prior to the submission of such recommendations, testimony, or comments to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>