<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/352" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/352/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/352/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_352"><akn:num>352</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 352. Benefits(a) Days for which benefits payable; determination of amount(1)(A) Payment of Unemployment Benefits.—(i) Generally.—Except as otherwise provided in this subparagraph, benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of unemployment in excess of 4 during any registration period within a period of continuing unemployment.

(ii) Waiting period for first registration period.—Benefits shall be payable to any qualified employee for each day of unemployment in excess of 7 during that employee’s first registration period in a period of continuing unemployment if such period of continuing unemployment is the employee’s initial period of continuing unemployment commencing in the benefit year.

(iii) Strikes.—(I) Initial 14-day waiting period.—If the Board finds that a qualified employee has a period of continuing unemployment that includes days of unemployment due to a stoppage of work because of a strike in the establishment, premises, or enterprise at which such employee was last employed, no benefits shall be payable for such employee’s first 14 days of unemployment due to such stoppage of work.

(II) Subsequent days of unemployment.—For subsequent days of unemployment due to the same stoppage of work, benefits shall be payable as provided in clause (i) of this subparagraph.

(III) Subsequent periods of continuing unemployment.—If such period of continuing unemployment ends by reason of clause (v) but the stoppage of work continues, the waiting period established in clause (ii) shall apply to the employee’s first registration period in a new period of continuing unemployment based upon the same stoppage of work.


(iv) Definition of period of continuing unemployment.—Except as limited by clause (v), for the purposes of this subparagraph, the term “period of continuing unemployment” means—(I) a single registration period that includes more than 4 days of unemployment;

(II) a series of consecutive registration periods, each of which includes m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Days for which benefits payable; determination of amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Days for which benefits payable; determination of amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time of payments The benefits provided for in this section shall be paid to an employee at such reasonable intervals as the Board may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum number of days for benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Maximum number of days for benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Overpayment of benefits; recovery; liability of officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Overpayment of benefits; recovery; liability of officers If the Board finds that at any time more than the correct amount of benefits has been paid to any individual under this chapter or a payment has been made to an individual not entitled thereto (including payments made prior to July 1, 1940), recovery by adjustments in subsequent payments to which such individual is entitled under this chapter or any other Act administered by the Board may, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, be made under regulations prescribed by the Board. If such individual dies before recovery is completed, recovery may be made by set-off or adjustments, under regulations prescribed by the Board, in subsequent payments due, under this chapter or any other Act administered by the Board, to the estate, designee, next of kin, legal representative, or surviving spouse of such individual, with respect to the employment of such individual.
Adjustments under this subsection may be made either by ded</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment, taxation, garnishment, attachment, etc., of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assignment, taxation, garnishment, attachment, etc., of benefits Notwithstanding any other law of the United States, or of any State, Territory, or the District of Columbia, no benefits shall be assignable or be subject to any tax or to garnishment, attachment, or other legal process under any circumstances whatsoever, nor shall the payment thereof be anticipated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of payment of benefits for remunerable period; payment of surplus remuneration to Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of payment of benefits for remunerable period; payment of surplus remuneration to Board If (i) benefits are paid to any employee with respect to unemployment or sickness in any registration period, and it is later determined that remuneration is payable to such employee with respect to any period which includes days in such registration period which had been determined to be days of unemployment or sickness, and (ii) the person or company from which such remuneration is payable has, before payment thereof, notice of the payment of benefits upon the basis of days of unemployment or sickness included in such period, the remuneration so payable shall not be reduced by reason of such benefits but the remuneration so payable, to the extent to which benefits were paid upon the basis of days which had been determined to be days of unemployment or sickness and which are included in the period for which such remuneration is payable, shall be held to be a special fund in trust for the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_352_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of accrued benefits upon death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment of accrued benefits upon death Benefits accrued to an individual but not yet paid at death shall, upon certification by the Board, be paid, without necessity of filing further claims therefor, to the same individual or individuals to whom any accrued annuities under section 231e(a)(1) of this title are paid. In the event that no such accrued annuities are paid, and if application for such accrued benefits is filed prior to the expiration of two years after the death of the individual to whom such benefits accrued, such accrued benefits shall be paid, upon certification by the Board, to the individual or individuals who would be entitled thereto under section 231e(a)(1) of this title if such accrued benefits were accrued annuities. If there is no individual to whom all or any part of such accrued benefits can be paid in accordance with the foregoing provisions, such benefits or part thereof shall escheat to the credit of the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>