<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/358" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/358/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/358/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_358"><akn:num>358</akn:num><akn:heading>Contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 358. Contributions(a) Employer contribution(1) In general(A) General rule(i) Contribution rate generallyEvery employer shall pay a contribution, with respect to having employees in his service, equal to the percentage determined under subparagraph (B), (C), or (D), whichever is applicable, of so much of the compensation paid in any calendar month by such employer to any employee as is not in excess of the monthly compensation base for that month as computed under section 351(i) of this title.


(ii) Multiple employer limitationIf compensation is paid to an employee by more than one employer in any calendar month—(I) the contributions required by this subsection shall not apply to any amount of the aggregate compensation paid to such employee by all such employers in such calendar month which is in excess of such monthly compensation base; and

(II) each employer (other than a subordinate unit of a national-railway-labor-organization employer) shall be liable for that portion of the contribution with respect to such compensation paid by all such employers which the compensation paid by him to such employee bears to the total compensation paid in such month by all such employers to such employee.



 In the event that the compensation paid by such employers to the employee in such month is less than such monthly compensation base, each subordinate unit of a national-railway-labor-organization employer shall be liable for such portion of any additional contribution as the compensation paid by such employer to such employee in such month bears to the total compensation paid by all such employers to such employee in such month.

(B) Transitional rule(i) 1st, 2d, and 3d calendar yearsExcept as provided in clause (vi), with respect to compensation paid in calendar years 1988, 1989, and 1990, the contribution rate shall be 8 percent.


(ii) 4th calendar yearWith respect to compensation paid in calendar year 1991, the contribution rate shall be the smaller of—(I) the maxim</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employer contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employer contribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee representative contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employee representative contribution Each employee representative shall pay a contribution with respect to so much of the compensation paid to him for services performed as an employee representative as is not in excess of the monthly compensation base computed in accordance with section 351(i) of this title, at a rate which shall be determined under subsection (a) in the same manner and with the same effect as if the employee organization by which such employee representative is employed were an employer as defined in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board proclamation of balance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board proclamation of balance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notifications by Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notifications by Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information to verify accuracy to be made available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Information to verify accuracy to be made available Notwithstanding any other provision of law, upon request by an employer or employee representative, the Board shall make available to such employer or employee representative any information available to the Board which may be necessary to verify the accuracy of a contribution rate determined by the Board to be applicable to such employer or employee representative, or of any component of that contribution rate including the accuracy of the employer’s individual employer record, upon payment by such employer or employee representative to the Board of the cost incurred by the Board in making such information available. The amounts so paid to the Board shall be credited to and deposited in the fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fractional parts of a cent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fractional parts of a cent In the payment of any contribution under this chapter, a fractional part of a cent shall be disregarded unless it amounts to one-half cent or more, in which case it shall be increased to one cent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments for improper payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Adjustments for improper payments If more or less than the correct amount of the contribution required by this section is paid with respect to any compensation, then, under regulations prescribed under this chapter by the Board, proper adjustments with respect to the contribution shall be made, without interest, in connection with subsequent contribution payments made under this chapter by the same employer or employee representative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refunding overpayment; collecting underpayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Refunding overpayment; collecting underpayment If more or less than the correct amount of the contribution required by this section is paid with respect to any compensation and the overpayment or underpayment of the contribution cannot be adjusted under subsection (d) of this section, the amount of the overpayment shall be refunded from the account, or the amount of the underpayment shall be collected, in such manner and at such times (subject to the statute of limitations properly applicable thereto) as may be prescribed by regulations of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and deposit of contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Collection and deposit of contributions The contributions required by this chapter shall be collected by the Board and shall be deposited by it with the Secretary of the Treasury of the United States, such part thereof as equals 0.65 per centum of the total compensation on which such contributions are based to be deposited to the credit of the fund and the balance to be deposited to the credit of the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_358_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for payment; failure to pay promptly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Time for payment; failure to pay promptly The contributions required by this chapter shall be collected and paid quarterly or at such other times and in such manner and under such conditions not inconsistent with this chapter as may be prescribed by regulations of the Board, and shall not be deducted, in whole or in part, from the compensation of employees in the employer’s employ. If a contribution required by this chapter is not paid when due, there shall be added to the amount payable (except in the case of adjustments made in accordance with the provisions of this chapter) interest at the rate of 1 per centum per month or fraction of a month from the date the contribution became due until paid. Any interest collected pursuant to this subsection shall be credited to the account.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>