<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/362" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/362/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/362/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_362"><akn:num>362</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and powers of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 362. Duties and powers of Board(a) Witnesses; subpenas, service, fees, etc.For the purpose of any investigation or other proceeding relative to the determination of any right to benefits, or relative to any other matter within its jurisdiction under this chapter, the Board shall have the power to issue subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence, documentary or otherwise, that relates to any matter under investigation or in question, before the Board or any member, employee, or representative thereof. Any member of the Board or any of its employees or representatives designated by it may administer oaths and affirmations, examine witnesses, and receive evidence. Such attendance of witnesses and production of evidence may be required from any place in the United States or any Territory or possession thereof at any designated place of hearing. All subpenas may be served and returned by anyone authorized by the Board in the same manner as is now provided by law for the service and return by United States marshals of subpenas in suits in equity. Such service may also be made by registered mail or by certified mail and in such case the return post-office receipt shall be proof of service. Witnesses summoned in accordance with this subsection shall be paid the same fees and mileage as are paid witnesses in the district courts of the United States.


(b) Enforcement of subpenas by courts; contempts; service of orders, writs, or processesIn case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena lawfully issued to, any person, the Board may invoke the aid of the district court of the United States or the United States courts of any Territory or possession, where such person is found or resides or is otherwise subject to service of process, or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the District of Columbia, or the United States District Court for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Witnesses; subpenas, service, fees, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Witnesses; subpenas, service, fees, etc. For the purpose of any investigation or other proceeding relative to the determination of any right to benefits, or relative to any other matter within its jurisdiction under this chapter, the Board shall have the power to issue subpenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence, documentary or otherwise, that relates to any matter under investigation or in question, before the Board or any member, employee, or representative thereof. Any member of the Board or any of its employees or representatives designated by it may administer oaths and affirmations, examine witnesses, and receive evidence. Such attendance of witnesses and production of evidence may be required from any place in the United States or any Territory or possession thereof at any designated place of hearing. All subpenas may be served and returned by anyone authorized by the Board in the same manner as is now provided by law for t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of subpenas by courts; contempts; service of orders, writs, or processes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enforcement of subpenas by courts; contempts; service of orders, writs, or processes In case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpena lawfully issued to, any person, the Board may invoke the aid of the district court of the United States or the United States courts of any Territory or possession, where such person is found or resides or is otherwise subject to service of process, or the United States District Court for the District of Columbia if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the District of Columbia, or the United States District Court for the Northern District of Illinois, if the investigation or proceeding is being carried on in the Northern District of Illinois, in requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence. Any such court shall issue an order requiring such person to appear before the Board or its specified employee or representative at the place specified in the subpena of the Board, whether within or witho</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 91–452, title II, § 239, Oct. 15, 1970, 84 Stat. 930</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information as confidential</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information as confidential Information obtained by the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter shall not be revealed or open to inspection nor be published in any manner revealing an employee’s identity: Provided, however, That (i) the Board may arrange for the exchange of any information with governmental agencies engaged in functions related to the administration of this chapter; (ii) the Board may disclose such information in cases in which the Board finds that such disclosure is clearly in furtherance of the interest of the employee or his estate; (iii) any claimant of benefits under this chapter shall, upon his request, be supplied with information from the Board’s records pertaining to his claim; and (iv) the Board shall disclose to any base-year employer of a claimant for benefits any information, including information as to the claimant’s identity, that is necessary or appropriate to notify such employer of the claim for benefits or to full and fair par</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of claims; authorization of employee to make payments; bond</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification of claims; authorization of employee to make payments; bond The Board shall provide for the certification of claims for benefits and refunds and may arrange total or partial settlements at such times and in such manner as may appear to the Board to be expedient. The Board shall designate and authorize one or more of its employees to sign vouchers for the payment of benefits and refunds under this chapter. Each such employee shall give bond, in form and amount fixed by the Board, conditioned upon the faithful performance of his duties. The premiums due on such bonds shall be paid from the fund and deemed to be a part of the expenses of administering this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with other agencies administering unemployment or sickness compensation laws; agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cooperation with other agencies administering unemployment or sickness compensation laws; agreements The Board may cooperate with or enter into agreement with the appropriate agencies charged with the administration of State, Territorial, Federal, or foreign unemployment-compensation or sickness laws or employment offices, with respect to investigations, the exchange of information and services, the establishment, maintenance, and use of free employment service facilities, and such other matters as the Board deems expedient in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such agency for services or facilities supplied to the Board in connection with the administration of this chapter. The Board may enter also into agreements with any such agency, pursuant to which any unemployment or sickness benefits provided for by this chapter or any other unemployment-compensation or sickness law, may be paid through a single agency to persons who have, during the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits also subject to a State law; mutual reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Benefits also subject to a State law; mutual reimbursement In determining whether an employee has qualified for benefits in accordance with section 353 of this title, and in determining the amount of benefits to be paid to such employee in accordance with section 352(a) and (c) of this title, the Board is authorized to consider as employment (and compensation therefor) services for hire other than employment (and remuneration therefor) if such services for hire are subject to an unemployment or sickness compensation law of any State, provided that such State has agreed to reimburse the United States such portion of the benefits to be paid upon such basis to such employee as the Board deems equitable. Any amounts collected pursuant to this paragraph shall be credited to the account.
If a State, in determining whether an employee is eligible for unemployment or sickness benefits under an unemployment or sickness compensation law of such State, and in determining the amount of unemplo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance from employers and labor organizations; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Assistance from employers and labor organizations; compensation The Board may enter into agreements or arrangements with employers, organizations of employers, and railway-labor organizations which are duly organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act [45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.], for securing the performance of services or the use of facilities in connection with the administration of this chapter, and may compensate any such employer or organization therefor upon such reasonable basis as the Board shall prescribe, but not to exceed the additional expense incurred by such employer or organization by reason of the performance of such services or making available the use of such facilities pursuant to such agreements or arrangements. Such employers and organizations, and persons employed by either of them, shall not be subject to section 209 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free employment offices; registration of unemployed; statements of sickness; reemployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Free employment offices; registration of unemployed; statements of sickness; reemployment The Board may establish, maintain, and operate free employment offices, and may designate as free employment offices facilities maintained by (i) a railway labor organization which is duly authorized and designated to represent employees in accordance with the Railway Labor Act [45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.], or (ii) any other labor organization which has been or may be organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, or (iii) one or more employers, or (iv) an organization of employers, or (v) a group of such employers and labor organizations, or (vi) a State, Territorial, foreign, or the Federal Government. The Board may also enter into agreements or arrangements with one or more employers or railway labor organizations organized in accordance with the provisions of the Railway Labor Act, pursuant to which notice of the availability of work and the rights of employees with respe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_362_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory councils; members’ remuneration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Advisory councils; members’ remuneration The Board may appoint national or local advisory councils composed of equal numbers of representatives of employers, representatives of employees, and persons representing the general public, for the purpose of discussing problems in connection with the administration of this chapter and aiding the Board in formulating policies. The members of such councils shall serve without remuneration, but shall be reimbursed for any necessary traveling and subsistence expenses or on a per diem basis in lieu of subsistence expenses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>