<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_711"><akn:num>711</akn:num><akn:heading>Formation and structure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 711. Formation and structure(a) EstablishmentThere is established, in accordance with the provisions of this section, an incorporated nonprofit association to be known as the United States Railway Association.


(b) AdministrationThe Association shall be directed by a Board of Directors. The individuals designated, pursuant to subsection (d)(2) of this section, as the Government members of such Board shall be deemed the incorporators of the Association and shall take whatever steps are necessary to establish the Association, including filing of articles of incorporation, and serving as an acting Board of Directors for a period of not more than 45 days after the date of incorporation of the Association.


(c) StatusThe Association shall be a government corporation of the District of Columbia subject, to the extent not inconsistent with this subchapter, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act. Except as otherwise provided, employees of the Association shall not be deemed employees of the Federal Government. The Association shall have succession until dissolved by Act of Congress, shall maintain its principal office in the District of Columbia, and shall be deemed to be a resident of the District of Columbia with respect to venue in any legal proceeding.


(d) Board of Directors(1) The Board of Directors of the Association shall consist of five individuals, as follows:(A) The Chairman, who shall be the individual serving as Chairman on August 13, 1981, until the expiration of his term of office or his resignation, or his replacement, who shall be selected by the outgoing Chairman and the other members of the Board.

(B) The Secretary of Transportation.

(C) The Comptroller General of the United States.

(D) The Chairman of the Commission.

(E) The Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Corporation.


(2) The Chairman may not have any employment or other direct financial relationship with any freight railroad. The Chairman shall receive $300 per diem </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established, in accordance with the provisions of this section, an incorporated nonprofit association to be known as the United States Railway Association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration The Association shall be directed by a Board of Directors. The individuals designated, pursuant to subsection (d)(2) of this section, as the Government members of such Board shall be deemed the incorporators of the Association and shall take whatever steps are necessary to establish the Association, including filing of articles of incorporation, and serving as an acting Board of Directors for a period of not more than 45 days after the date of incorporation of the Association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status The Association shall be a government corporation of the District of Columbia subject, to the extent not inconsistent with this subchapter, to the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act. Except as otherwise provided, employees of the Association shall not be deemed employees of the Federal Government. The Association shall have succession until dissolved by Act of Congress, shall maintain its principal office in the District of Columbia, and shall be deemed to be a resident of the District of Columbia with respect to venue in any legal proceeding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Board of Directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Term of office The term of office of the Chairman of the Board of Directors of the Association shall expire on December 31, 1987. The Chairman may be reappointed and the term of the Chairman shall be 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quorum Three members of the Board of Directors, or their representatives, shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of any function of the Association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assumption of Finance Committee functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assumption of Finance Committee functions The Board of Directors shall, on August 13, 1981, assume the functions previously performed by the Finance Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation at meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Representation at meetings The members of the Board of Directors may send representatives to meetings of such Board, and such representatives may exercise full powers of the members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous 11 See Codification note below.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Miscellaneous</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of names 1</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Use of names No person, except the Association, shall hereafter use the words “United States Railway Association” as a name for any business purpose. Violations of this provision may be enjoined by any court of general jurisdiction in an action commenced by the Association. In any such action, the Association may recover any actual damages flowing from such violation, and, in addition, shall be entitled to punitive damages (regardless of the existence or nonexistence of actual damage) in an amount not to exceed $100 for each day during which such violation was committed. The district courts of the United States shall have jurisdiction over actions brought under this subsection, without regard to the amount in controversy or the citizenship of the parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>