<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/716" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/716/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/716/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_716"><akn:num>716</akn:num><akn:heading>Final system plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 716. Final system plan(a) GoalsThe final system plan shall be formulated in such a way as to effectuate the following goals:(1) the creation, through a process of reorganization, of a financially self-sustaining rail and express service system in the region;

(2) the establishment and maintenance of a rail service system adequate to meet the rail transportation needs and service requirements of the region;

(3) the establishment of improved high-speed rail passenger service, consonant with the recommendations of the Secretary in his report of September 1971, entitled “Recommendations for Northeast Corridor Transportation”;

(4) the preservation, to the extent consistent with other goals, of existing patterns of service by railroads (including short-line and terminal railroads), and of existing railroad trackage in areas in which fossil fuel natural resources are located, and the utilization of those modes of transportation in the region which require the smallest amount of scarce energy resources and which can most efficiently transport energy resources;

(5) the retention and promotion of competition in the provision of rail and other transportation services in the region;

(6) the attainment and maintenance of any environmental standards, particularly the applicable national ambient air quality standards and plans established under the Clean Air Act Amendments of 1970, taking into consideration the environmental impact of alternative choices of action;

(7) the movement of passengers and freight in rail transportation in the region in the most efficient manner consistent with safe operation, including the requirements of commuter and intercity rail passenger service; the extent to which there should be coordination with the National Railroad Passenger Corporation and similar entities; and the identification of all short-to-medium distance corridors in densely populated areas in which the major upgrading of rail lines for high-speed passenger operation would retu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Goals The final system plan shall be formulated in such a way as to effectuate the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Factors The final system plan shall be based upon due consideration of all factors relevant to the realization of the goals set forth in subsection (a) of this section. Such factors include the need for and the cost of rehabilitation and modernization of track, equipment, and other facilities; methods of achieving economies in the cost of rail operations in the region; means of achieving rationalization of rail services and the rail service system in the region; marketing studies; the impact on railroad employees; consumer needs; traffic analyses; financial studies; and any other factors identified by the Association under section 712(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title or in the report of the Secretary required under section 714(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designations The final system plan shall designate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfers All transfers or conveyances pursuant to the final system plan shall be made in accordance with, and subject to, the following principles:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corporation features</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Corporation features The final system plan shall set forth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Value The final system plan shall designate the value of all rail properties to be transferred under the final system plan and the value of the securities and other benefits to be received for transferring those rail properties to the Corporation in accordance with the final system plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other provisions The final system plan may recommend arrangements among various railroads for joint use or operation of rail properties on a shared ownership, cooperative, pooled, or condominium-type basis, subject to such terms and conditions as may be specified in the final system plan. The final system plan shall also make such designations as are determined to be necessary in accordance with the provisions of section 762 or 763 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligational authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Obligational authority The final system plan shall recommend the amount of obligations of the Association which are necessary to enable it to implement the final system plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions for securities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Terms and conditions for securities The final system plan may include terms and conditions for any securities to be issued by the Corporation in exchange for the conveyance of rail properties under the final system plan which in the judgement of the Association will minimize any actual or potential debt burden on the Corporation. Any such terms and conditions for securities of the Corporation which purport to directly obligate the Association shall not become effective without affirmative approval, with or without modification by a joint resolution of the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_716_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional properties deemed designated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Additional properties deemed designated Any rail properties over which rail service was being provided as of February 5, 1976, and which were recommended in the preliminary system plan for transfer to the Corporation, shall be deemed to be designated in the final system plan for transfer to the Corporation under subsection (c)(1)(A) of this section. Any designation in the final system plan, pursuant to subsection (c)(1)(B) of this section, of overhead trackage rights to be acquired by a profitable railroad operating in the region over specified rail properties to be acquired by the Corporation, where such designation does not (1) authorize such profitable railroad to interchange traffic with at least one railroad, or (2) provide for the connection of portions of such profitable railroad’s rail properties, and where the transfer of ownership of such rail properties (including trackage rights) to such profitable railroad was recommended in the preliminary system plan, and the Commiss</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>