<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/717" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/717/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/717/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_717"><akn:num>717</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of final system plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 717. Adoption of final system plan(a) Preliminary system plan(1) Within 420 days after January 2, 1974, the Association shall adopt and release a preliminary system plan prepared by it on the basis of reports and other information submitted to it by the Secretary, the Office, and interested persons in accordance with this chapter and on the basis of its own investigations, consultations, research, evaluation, and analysis pursuant to this chapter. Copies of the preliminary system plan shall be transmitted by the Association to the Secretary, the Office, the Governor and public utility commission of each State in the region, the Congress, each court having jurisdiction over a railroad in reorganization in the region, the special court, and interested persons, and a copy shall be published in the Federal Register. The Association shall invite and afford interested persons an opportunity to submit comments on the preliminary system plan to the Association within 60 days after the date of its release.

(2) The Office is authorized and directed to hold public hearings on the preliminary system plan and to make available to the Association a summary and analysis of the evidence received in the course of such proceedings, together with its critique and evaluation of the preliminary system plan, not later than 60 days after the date of release of such plan. The Office is authorized to hold public hearings on any supplement to the preliminary system plan and to make available to the Association a summary and analysis of the evidence received in the course of such proceedings, together with its critique and evaluation of such supplement, not later than 30 days after the release of such supplement.


(b) Approval(1) Within 120 days after January 2, 1974, each United States district court or other court having jurisdiction over a railroad in reorganization shall decide whether the railroad is reorganizable on an income basis within a reasonable time under section 77 of the Ba</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary system plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preliminary system plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adoption Within 540 days after January 2, 1974, the executive committee of the Association shall prepare and submit a final system plan for the approval of the Board of Directors of the Association. A copy of such submission shall be simultaneously presented to the Commission. The submission shall reflect evaluation of all responses and summaries of responses received, testimony at any public hearings, and the results of additional study and review. Within 30 days thereafter, the Board of Directors of the Association shall by a majority vote of all its members approve a final system plan which meets all of the requirements of section 716 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_717_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review of Commission Within 30 days following the adoption of the final system plan by the Association under subsection (c) of this section and the submission of such plan to Congress under section 718(a) of this title, the Commission shall submit to the Congress an evaluation of the final system plan delivered to both Houses of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>