<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/718" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/718/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/718/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_718"><akn:num>718</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 718. Review by Congress(a) GeneralThe Board of Directors of the Association shall deliver the final system plan adopted by the Association to both Houses of Congress and to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate. The final system plan shall be deemed approved at the end of the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after such date of transmittal unless either the House of Representatives or the Senate passes a resolution during such period stating that it does not favor the final system plan.


(b) Revised planIf either the House or the Senate passes a resolution of disapproval under subsection (a) of this section, the Association, with the cooperation and assistance of the Secretary and the Office, shall prepare, determine, and adopt a revised final system plan. Each such revised plan shall be submitted to Congress for review pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.


(c) ComputationFor purposes of this section—(1) continuity of session of Congress is broken only by an adjournment sine die; and

(2) the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of the 60-day period.


(d) Additions(1) The supplemental report, dated September 18, 1975, to the final system plan, and the provisions of the Association’s official errata supplement to the final system plan, dated December 1, 1975, including all designations made therein, shall be treated for all purposes as if they had been part of and included in the final system plan adopted by the Association and reviewed by the Congress. The final system plan shall, for all purposes, be deemed to be approved as modified and amended by such supplemental report and such supplement.

(2) The Association may, upon petition of any State, modify the final system plan to make further designations with respect t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General The Board of Directors of the Association shall deliver the final system plan adopted by the Association to both Houses of Congress and to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate. The final system plan shall be deemed approved at the end of the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after such date of transmittal unless either the House of Representatives or the Senate passes a resolution during such period stating that it does not favor the final system plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revised plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revised plan If either the House or the Senate passes a resolution of disapproval under subsection (a) of this section, the Association, with the cooperation and assistance of the Secretary and the Office, shall prepare, determine, and adopt a revised final system plan. Each such revised plan shall be submitted to Congress for review pursuant to subsection (a) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Computation For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_718_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>