<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/719" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/719/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/719/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_719"><akn:num>719</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 719. Judicial review(a) GeneralNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the final system plan which is adopted by the Association and which becomes effective after review by the Congress is not subject to review by any court except in accordance with this section. After the final system plan becomes effective under section 718 of this title, it may be reviewed with respect to matters concerning the value of the rail properties to be conveyed under the plan and the value of the consideration to be received for such properties.


(b) Special court(1) Within 30 days after January 2, 1974, the Association shall make application to the judicial panel on multi-district litigation authorized by section 1407 of title 28 for the consolidation in a single, three-judge district court of the United States of all judicial proceedings with respect to the final system plan. Within 30 days after such application is received, the panel shall make the consolidation in a district court (cited herein as the “special court”) which the panel determines to be convenient to the parties and the one most likely to be able to conduct any proceedings under this section with the least delay and the greatest possible fairness and ability. Such proceedings shall be conducted by the special court which shall be composed of three Federal judges who shall be selected by the panel, except that none of the judges selected may be a judge assigned to a proceeding involving any railroad in reorganization in the region under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act. The special court is authorized to exercise the powers of a district judge in any judicial district with respect to such proceedings and such powers shall include those of a reorganization court. The special court shall have the power to order the conveyance of rail properties of railroads leased, operated, or controlled by a railroad in reorganization in the region. The special court may issue rules for the conduct of any proceedings under this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the final system plan which is adopted by the Association and which becomes effective after review by the Congress is not subject to review by any court except in accordance with this section. After the final system plan becomes effective under section 718 of this title, it may be reviewed with respect to matters concerning the value of the rail properties to be conveyed under the plan and the value of the consideration to be received for such properties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special court</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of plan to special court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Delivery of plan to special court Within 90 days after its effective date, the Association shall deliver a certified copy of the final system plan to the special court and shall certify to the special court— Notwithstanding any other provisions of this subsection and subsection (d) of this section, the time for the delivery of a certified copy of the final system plan shall be March 12, 1976, and may be extended to a date not more than 30 days thereafter, prescribed in a notice filed by the Association not later than February 17, 1976, with the special court, the Congress, and each court referred to in such subsection (d). Such notice shall contain the certification of the Association that an orderly conveyance of rail properties cannot reasonably be effected before the date for conveyance determined with respect to such notice. The time prescribed in section 743(a) of this title shall be determined with respect to the date prescribed in such notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bankruptcy courts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Bankruptcy courts Within 90 days after its effective date, the Association shall deliver a certified copy of the final system plan to each district court of the United States or any other court having jurisdiction over a railroad in reorganization in the region and shall certify to each such court—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original and exclusive jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Original and exclusive jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of cash deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Disposition of cash deposits Whenever the compensation which is deposited with the special court under section 743(a) of this title is in the form of cash, such cash shall be invested and reinvested upon such terms and conditions as the special court shall determine, pending the making of the findings referred to in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 743(c) of this title. Notwithstanding section 743(c)(4) of this title, the special court may order (1) the income from such investments, (2) the dividends or interest, if any, received on any securities or obligations deposited with the special court under such section 743(a) of this title, and (3) the income, if any, received with respect to any other form of compensation so deposited, to be distributed to the trustee of each railroad in reorganization and to any person leased, operated or controlled by such a railroad which conveyed the right, title, and interest in the rail properties with respect to which such cash, securities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_719_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stay of court proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Stay of court proceedings The special court may stay or enjoin any action or proceeding in any State court or in any court of the United States other than the Supreme Court or Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit if such action or proceeding is contrary to any provision of this chapter, impairs the effective implementation of this chapter, or interferes with the execution of any order of the special court pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>