<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/721" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/721/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/721/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_721"><akn:num>721</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 721. Loans(a) GeneralThe Association is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this section and such rules and regulations as it shall prescribe, to make loans to the Corporation, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, and other railroads (including a railroad in reorganization which has been found to be reorganizable under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act pursuant to section 717(b) of this title) in the region, for purposes of achieving the goals of this chapter; to a State or local or regional transportation authority pursuant to section 763 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and to provide assistance in the form of loans to any railroad which (A) connects with a railroad in reorganization, and (B) is in need of financial assistance to avoid reorganization proceedings under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act. No such loan shall be made by the Association to a railroad unless such loans shall, where applicable, be treated as an expense of administration. The rights referred to in the last sentence of section 77(j) of the Bankruptcy Act shall in no way be affected by this chapter.


(b) ApplicationsEach application for such a loan shall be made in writing to the Association in such form and with such content and other submissions as the Association shall prescribe to protect reasonably the interests of the United States. The Association shall publish a notice of the receipt of each such application in the Federal Register and shall afford interested persons an opportunity to comment thereon.


(c) Terms and conditionsEach loan shall be extended in such form, under such terms and conditions, and pursuant to such regulations as the Association deems appropriate. Such loan shall bear interest at a rate not less than the greater of a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration (1) the rate prevailing in the private market for similar loans as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, or (2) the current </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General The Association is authorized, in accordance with the provisions of this section and such rules and regulations as it shall prescribe, to make loans to the Corporation, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation, and other railroads (including a railroad in reorganization which has been found to be reorganizable under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act pursuant to section 717(b) of this title) in the region, for purposes of achieving the goals of this chapter; to a State or local or regional transportation authority pursuant to section 763 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and to provide assistance in the form of loans to any railroad which (A) connects with a railroad in reorganization, and (B) is in need of financial assistance to avoid reorganization proceedings under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act. No such loan shall be made by the Association to a railroad unless such loans shall, where applicable, be treated as an expense of administration. The rig</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications Each application for such a loan shall be made in writing to the Association in such form and with such content and other submissions as the Association shall prescribe to protect reasonably the interests of the United States. The Association shall publish a notice of the receipt of each such application in the Federal Register and shall afford interested persons an opportunity to comment thereon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions Each loan shall be extended in such form, under such terms and conditions, and pursuant to such regulations as the Association deems appropriate. Such loan shall bear interest at a rate not less than the greater of a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury taking into consideration (1) the rate prevailing in the private market for similar loans as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, or (2) the current average yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the Association with remaining periods of maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, plus such additional charge, if any, toward covering costs of the Association as the Association may determine to be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Modifications The Association is authorized to approve any modification of any provision of a loan under this section, including the rate of interest, time of payment of interest or principal, security, or any other term or condition, upon agreement of the recipient of the loan and upon a finding by the Association that such modification is equitable and necessary or appropriate to achieve the policy declared in subsection (f) of this section. Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in the case of a loan made under subsection (a) of this section to a railroad in the region, the Association is not required to make the findings with respect to subsections (e)(3) and (f) and may, upon the request of such railroad— The Association may not take any action pursuant to the preceding sentence of this subsection after December 31, 1981.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prerequisites The Association shall make a finding in writing, before making a loan to any applicant under this section, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Policy It is the intent of Congress that loans made under this section shall be made on terms and conditions which furnish reasonable assurance that the Corporation or the railroads to which such loans are granted will be able to repay them within the time fixed and that the goals of this chapter are reasonably likely to be achieved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-conveyance loans to Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Pre-conveyance loans to Corporation During the period between the effective date of the final system plan and the date of the conveyance of rail properties pursuant to section 743(b) of this title, the Association may make such loans in such amounts to the Corporation as the Association deems essential to provide for the purchase by the Corporation of material, supplies, equipment, and services necessary to permit the orderly and efficient implementation of the final system plan. Notwithstanding any inability of the Association during such period to make the finding required by subsection (e)(3) of this section because of any existing contingencies, the Association may make any such loans to the Corporation, subject to— In order to assure that necessary funds are available to the Corporation for implementation of the final system plan, the Corporation is authorized to accept such loans as may be approved by the Association under this subsection, and any such acceptance shall be dee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_721_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans for payment of obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Loans for payment of obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>