<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/727" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/727/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/727/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_727"><akn:num>727</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional purchases of Series A preferred stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 727. Additional purchases of Series A preferred stock(a) Federal investmentIn addition to the authority provided under section 726 of this title, the Association shall purchase shares of Series A preferred stock and accounts receivable of the Corporation after August 13, 1981, in amounts not to exceed a total of $137,000,000.


(b) Accounts receivable(1) In any further purchase under this section or section 726 of this title the Association shall purchase accounts receivable of the Corporation attributable to the dispute over the right-of-way related costs described in section 1111 11 See References in Text note below. of this title until the Commission resolves such dispute under such section, and accounts receivable of the Corporation attributable to delays in reimbursement from commuter authorities.

(2) From funds provided under this section or section 726 of this title, the Association shall purchase Series A preferred stock of the Corporation, to the extent of losses on commuter service, in an amount not to exceed $15,000,000.


(c) States and localitiesThe Corporation shall be exempt from liability for any State tax, except for any tax imposed by any political subdivision of a State applicable to any taxable period commencing before January 1, 1987.


(d) DebenturesThe Association shall return debentures to the Corporation in an amount equal to the value of the properties conveyed by the Corporation to Amtrak Commuter and any commuter authority.


(e) Rights retainedThe Corporation shall retain the right to collect any accounts receivable attributable to delays in reimbursement from commuter authorities that are purchased by the Association under this section. No agency or instrumentality of the United States shall be required to collect such accounts.


(f) Authorization of appropriations(1) There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $262,000,000—(A) of which not to exceed $137,000,000 shall be appropriated to the Association for purposes of purc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal investment In addition to the authority provided under section 726 of this title, the Association shall purchase shares of Series A preferred stock and accounts receivable of the Corporation after August 13, 1981, in amounts not to exceed a total of $137,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounts receivable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Accounts receivable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>States and localities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) States and localities The Corporation shall be exempt from liability for any State tax, except for any tax imposed by any political subdivision of a State applicable to any taxable period commencing before January 1, 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debentures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Debentures The Association shall return debentures to the Corporation in an amount equal to the value of the properties conveyed by the Corporation to Amtrak Commuter and any commuter authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights retained</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rights retained The Corporation shall retain the right to collect any accounts receivable attributable to delays in reimbursement from commuter authorities that are purchased by the Association under this section. No agency or instrumentality of the United States shall be required to collect such accounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_727_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>