<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/745" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/745/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/745/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_745"><akn:num>745</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing reorganization; supplemental transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 745. Continuing reorganization; supplemental transactions(a) ProposalsIf the Secretary or the Association determines that, as part of continuing reorganization, further restructuring of rail properties in the region through transactions supplemental to the final system plan would promote the establishment and retention of a financially self-sustaining rail service system in the region adequate to meet the needs of the region, the Secretary or the Association, as the case may be, may develop proposals for such supplemental transactions as are necessary or appropriate to implement the needed restructuring. Transfers of rail properties included in proposals developed by the Association shall be limited to (1) rail properties which would have qualified for designation under section 716(c)(1)(A) of this title but which were not transferred or conveyed under the final system plan, and which the Association finds to be essential to the efficient operations of the Corporation, and (2) transfers, consistent with the final system plan, of rail properties from the Corporation to a subsidiary thereof. Each proposal (other than a proposal developed by the Association) shall be submitted in writing to the Association and shall state and describe any transactions proposed, the rail properties involved, the parties to such transactions, the financial and other terms of such transactions, the purposes of the chapter or the goals of the final system plan intended to be effectuated by such transactions, and such other information incidental thereto as the Association may prescribe. Within 10 days after receipt of a proposal developed by the Secretary, and upon the development of a proposal developed by the Association, the Association shall publish a summary of such proposal in the Federal Register, and shall afford interested persons (including the Corporation when property is to be transferred to or from the Corporation) an opportunity to comment thereon.


(b) Evaluation by Assoc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposals If the Secretary or the Association determines that, as part of continuing reorganization, further restructuring of rail properties in the region through transactions supplemental to the final system plan would promote the establishment and retention of a financially self-sustaining rail service system in the region adequate to meet the needs of the region, the Secretary or the Association, as the case may be, may develop proposals for such supplemental transactions as are necessary or appropriate to implement the needed restructuring. Transfers of rail properties included in proposals developed by the Association shall be limited to (1) rail properties which would have qualified for designation under section 716(c)(1)(A) of this title but which were not transferred or conveyed under the final system plan, and which the Association finds to be essential to the efficient operations of the Corporation, and (2) transfers, consistent with the final system plan, of rail proper</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation by Association</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation by Association The Association shall analyze each proposal containing one or more supplemental transactions, taking into account the comments of interested persons and statements and exhibits submitted at any public hearings which may have been held. The Association shall, within 120 days after the publication of a summary thereof under subsection (a) of this section, publish in the Federal Register a report evaluating such proposal. Such evaluation shall state whether the supplemental transactions contained in such proposal, considered in their entirety, are (1) in the public interest and consistent with the purposes of this chapter and the goals of the final system plan, and (2) fair and equitable. If the Corporation opposes, or seeks modification of, any such proposed transfer, its written comments shall be given due consideration by the Association and shall be published as part of the evaluation. Within 30 days after the Association publishes its report, each propos</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review by Commission Within 90 days after the publication in the Federal Register of each report referred to in subsection (b) of this section, the Commission shall determine whether the supplemental transactions referred to in the report, considered in their entirety, would be in the public interest and consistent with the purposes of this chapter and the goals of the final system plan. In making such determination, the Commission shall give due consideration to the views received by it, within 30 days after the publication of the applicable report, from the Corporation and the Secretary. The Commission may condition its approval of such supplemental transactions on such reasonable terms and conditions as it may deem necessary in the public interest. The approval by the Commission of such supplemental transactions shall not be a prerequisite to the consummation of such transactions, but any determination of the Commission modifying, approving, or disapproving any proposed suppleme</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special court proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special court proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Fair and equitable” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Fair and equitable” defined As used in this section, the term “fair and equitable” means fair and equitable, in accordance with the standards applicable to the approval of a plan of reorganization (or a step in such plan) under section 77 of the Bankruptcy Act 11 See References in Text note below. to— Whenever any property or securities of the Corporation are required to be valued in order to determine whether the terms of a supplemental transaction are fair and equitable, the special court shall give proper recognition to the contributions to the Corporation by all classes of security holders, except that such court shall not assign to the series B preferred stock or the common stock of the Corporation any values added to those securities, by reason of investment by the Association in debentures and series A preferred stock of the Corporation, in excess of any value required by constitutional principles applicable to a reorganization process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expedited proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_745_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of properties and freight service obligations of specific lines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer of properties and freight service obligations of specific lines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>