<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/748" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/748/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/748/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_748"><akn:num>748</akn:num><akn:heading>Abandonments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 748. Abandonments(a) GeneralThe Corporation may, in accordance with this section, file with the Commission an application for a certificate of abandonment for any line which is part of the system of the Corporation. Any such application shall be governed by this section and shall not, except as specifically provided in this section, be subject to the provisions of chapter 109 of title 49.


(b) Applications for abandonmentAny application for abandonment that is filed by the Corporation under this section before December 1, 1981, shall be granted by the Commission within 90 days after the date such application is filed unless, within such 90-day period, an offer of financial assistance is made in accordance with subsection (d) of this section with respect to the line to be abandoned.


(c) Notice of insufficient revenues(1) The Corporation may, prior to November 1, 1985, file with the Commission a notice of insufficient revenues for any line which is part of the system of the Corporation.

(2) At any time after the 90-day period beginning with the filing of a notice of insufficient revenues for a line, the Corporation may file an application for abandonment for such line. An application for abandonment that is filed by the Corporation under this subsection for a line for which a notice of insufficient revenues was filed under paragraph (1) shall be granted by the Commission within 90 days after the date such application is filed unless, within such 90-day period, an offer of financial assistance is made in accordance with subsection (d) of this section with respect to such line.


(d) Offers of financial assistance(1) The provisions of section 10904 of title 49 (including the timing requirements of subsection (d) thereof) shall apply to any offer of financial assistance under subsection (b) or (c) of this section.

(2) The Corporation shall provide any person that intends to make an offer of financial assistance under subsection (b) or (c) of this section with such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General The Corporation may, in accordance with this section, file with the Commission an application for a certificate of abandonment for any line which is part of the system of the Corporation. Any such application shall be governed by this section and shall not, except as specifically provided in this section, be subject to the provisions of chapter 109 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for abandonment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications for abandonment Any application for abandonment that is filed by the Corporation under this section before December 1, 1981, shall be granted by the Commission within 90 days after the date such application is filed unless, within such 90-day period, an offer of financial assistance is made in accordance with subsection (d) of this section with respect to the line to be abandoned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of insufficient revenues</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of insufficient revenues</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Offers of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Offers of financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Liquidation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_748_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employee protection The provisions of section 10903(b)(3) 11 So in original. Section 10903(b) of Title 49, Transportation, does not contain a par. (3). of title 49 shall not apply to any abandonment granted under this section. Any employee who was protected by the compensatory provisions of subchapter V 22 See References in Text note below. of this chapter immediately prior to August 13, 1981, who is deprived of employment by such an abandonment shall be eligible for employee protection under section 797 2 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>