<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/791" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/791/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/791/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_791"><akn:num>791</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 791. Relationship to other laws(a) Antitrust(1) Except as specifically provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection, no provision of this chapter shall be deemed to convey to any railroad or employee or director thereof any immunity from civil or criminal liability, or to create defenses to actions, under the antitrust laws.

(2) The antitrust laws are inapplicable with respect to any action taken to formulate or implement the final system plan where such action was in compliance with the requirements of such plan and with respect to any action taken to formulate or implement any supplemental transaction.

(3) As used in this subsection, “antitrust laws” includes the Act of July 2, 1890 (ch. 647, 26 Stat. 209), as amended; the Act of October 15, 1914 (ch. 323, 38 Stat. 730), as amended; the Federal Trade Commission Act (38 Stat. 717), as amended [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.], sections 73 and 74 of the Act of August 27, 1894 (28 Stat. 570), as amended [15 U.S.C. 8, 9]; the Act of June 19, 1936 (ch. 592, 49 Stat. 1526), as amended; and the antitrust laws of any State or subdivision thereof.


(b) Commerce, securities, and bankruptcy(1) The provisions of subtitle IV of title 49 and the Bankruptcy Act, are inapplicable (A) to actions taken under this chapter to formulate and implement the final system plan where such action was in compliance with the requirements of such plan, and (B) to actions taken under this chapter to formulate or implement any supplemental transaction.

(2) All securities of the Corporation which are issued to the Association as the initial holder, or which are issued in connection with the transfer to the Corporation or a subsidiary thereof of rail properties under this chapter, shall be deemed for all purposes to have been issued subject to and authorized pursuant to section 11301 11 See References in Text note below. of title 49.

(3) The provisions of section 77e of title 15, shall not apply to transactions involving the issuance of any security of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_791_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Antitrust</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_791_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce, securities, and bankruptcy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Commerce, securities, and bankruptcy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_791_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environment The provisions of section 4332(2)(C) of title 42 shall not apply with respect to any action taken under authority of this chapter before, and including, the conveyance of rail properties ordered by the special court under section 743 (b)(1) of this title, and shall not apply thereafter to any action taken in compliance with the requirements of the final system plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_791_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Northeast Corridor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Northeast Corridor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>