<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/909" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/909/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/45/909/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_909"><akn:num>909</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary unemployment insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 909. Supplementary unemployment insurance(a) Eligible employeesAny employee of the Milwaukee Railroad—(1) who (A) is employed by the restructured Milwaukee Railroad, and (B) is separated from that employment by reason of any reduction in service by such railroad prior to April 1, 1984; or

(2) who (A) is separated from his employment with the Milwaukee Railroad in connection with a restructuring transaction carried out by such railroad, and obtains employment, prior to April 1, 1981, with another rail carrier, and (B) is separated from employment with such other carrier prior to April 1, 1984,


shall be entitled to receive monthly supplementary unemployment insurance in accordance with the provisions of this section.

(b) Period of paymentEach employee described in subsection (a) of this section shall be entitled to receive supplementary unemployment insurance during each month in which such employee is not employed, for all or a portion of such month, by the Milwaukee Railroad or another rail carrier. Each such employee shall be entitled to receive such insurance for a total of not more than 36 months, except that—(1) the period of entitlement for assistance under this section shall not exceed the employee’s total months of service with the Milwaukee Railroad; and

(2) no compensation shall be provided under this section after April 1, 1984, unless it is necessary in order to provide an employee with at least 8 months of such insurance, but after such date, such employee only shall receive such 8-month minimum if such employee is not employed continuously after such date.


(c) Amount of paymentSupplementary unemployment insurance under this section shall be payable to an employee on a monthly basis in an amount equal to—(1) eighty percent of such employee’s average monthly normal compensation from employment with the Milwaukee Railroad during the period beginning June 1, 1977, and ending on November 4, 1979, less

(2) the sum of (A) the amount of any benefits p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligible employees Any employee of the Milwaukee Railroad— shall be entitled to receive monthly supplementary unemployment insurance in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Period of payment Each employee described in subsection (a) of this section shall be entitled to receive supplementary unemployment insurance during each month in which such employee is not employed, for all or a portion of such month, by the Milwaukee Railroad or another rail carrier. Each such employee shall be entitled to receive such insurance for a total of not more than 36 months, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of payment Supplementary unemployment insurance under this section shall be payable to an employee on a monthly basis in an amount equal to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Filing of application An application for supplementary unemployment insurance shall be filed with the Board in such time and manner as the Board by regulation shall prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance as compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Insurance as compensation Any supplementary unemployment insurance received by any employee pursuant to this section shall be considered to be compensation solely—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees not covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employees not covered</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_909_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furloughed employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Furloughed employees For purposes of this section, any employee of the Milwaukee Railroad who is furloughed shall be considered to be separated from his employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>