<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/20144" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/20144/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/20144/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_20144"><akn:num>20144</akn:num><akn:heading>Prize authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 20144. Prize authority(a) In General.—The Administration may carry out a program to competitively award cash prizes to stimulate innovation in basic and applied research, technology development, and prototype demonstration that have the potential for application to the performance of the space and aeronautical activities of the Administration. The Administration may carry out a program to award prizes only in conformity with this section.

(b) Topics.—In selecting topics for prize competitions, the Administrator shall consult widely both within and outside the Federal Government, and may empanel advisory committees. The Administrator shall give consideration to prize goals such as the demonstration of the ability to provide energy to the lunar surface from space-based solar power systems, demonstration of innovative near-Earth object survey and deflection strategies, and innovative approaches to improving the safety and efficiency of aviation systems.

(c) Advertising.—The Administrator shall widely advertise prize competitions to encourage participation.

(d) Requirements and Registration.—For each prize competition, the Administrator shall publish a notice in the Federal Register announcing the subject of the competition, the rules for being eligible to participate in the competition, the amount of the prize, and the basis on which a winner will be selected.

(e) Eligibility.—To be eligible to win a prize under this section, an individual or entity—(1) shall have registered to participate in the competition pursuant to any rules promulgated by the Administrator under subsection (d);

(2) shall have complied with all the requirements under this section;

(3) in the case of a private entity, shall be incorporated in and maintain a primary place of business in the United States, and in the case of an individual, whether participating singly or in a group, shall be a citizen or permanent resident of the United States; and

(4) shall not be a Federal entity or Federa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administration may carry out a program to competitively award cash prizes to stimulate innovation in basic and applied research, technology development, and prototype demonstration that have the potential for application to the performance of the space and aeronautical activities of the Administration. The Administration may carry out a program to award prizes only in conformity with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Topics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In selecting topics for prize competitions, the Administrator shall consult widely both within and outside the Federal Government, and may empanel advisory committees. The Administrator shall give consideration to prize goals such as the demonstration of the ability to provide energy to the lunar surface from space-based solar power systems, demonstration of innovative near-Earth object survey and deflection strategies, and innovative approaches to improving the safety and efficiency of aviation systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advertising.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall widely advertise prize competitions to encourage participation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements and Registration.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) For each prize competition, the Administrator shall publish a notice in the Federal Register announcing the subject of the competition, the rules for being eligible to participate in the competition, the amount of the prize, and the basis on which a winner will be selected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) To be eligible to win a prize under this section, an individual or entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judges.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) For each competition, the Administration, either directly or through an agreement under subsection (h), shall assemble a panel of qualified judges to select the winner or winners of the prize competition on the basis described pursuant to subsection (d). Judges for each competition shall include individuals from outside the Administration, including from the private sector. A judge may not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering the Competition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) The Administrator may enter into an agreement with a private, nonprofit entity to administer the prize competition, subject to the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_20144_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Administration Name or Insignia.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) A registered participant in a competition under this section may use the Administration’s name, initials, or insignia only after prior review and written approval by the Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>