<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/40308" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/40308/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/40308/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_40308"><akn:num>40308</akn:num><akn:heading>Space grant review panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 40308. Space grant review panel(a) Establishment.—The Administrator shall establish an independent committee known as the space grant review panel, which shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.

(b) Duties.—The panel shall take such steps as may be necessary to review, and shall advise the Administrator with respect to—(1) applications or proposals for, and performance under, grants and contracts awarded pursuant to sections 40304 and 40305 of this title;

(2) the space grant fellowship program;

(3) the designation and operation of space grant colleges and space grant regional consortia, and the operation of space grant and fellowship programs;

(4) the formulation and application of the planning guidelines and priorities pursuant to subsections (a) and (b)(1) of section 40303 of this title; and

(5) such other matters as the Administrator refers to the panel for review and advice.


(c) Personnel and Administrative Services.—The Administrator shall make available to the panel any information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance which is reasonable to carry out the duties of the panel.

(d) Members.—(1) Appointment.—The Administrator shall appoint the voting members of the panel. A majority of the voting members shall be individuals who, by reason of knowledge, experience, or training, are especially qualified in one or more of the disciplines and fields related to space. The other voting members shall be individuals who, by reason of knowledge, experience, or training, are especially qualified in, or representative of, education, extension services, State government, industry, economics, planning, or any other activity related to efforts to enhance the understanding, assessment, development, or utilization of space resources. The Administrator shall consider the potential conflict of interest of any individual in making appointments to the panel.

(2) Chairman and vice chairman.—The Administrator shall select one voting</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40308_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator shall establish an independent committee known as the space grant review panel, which shall not be subject to the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40308_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The panel shall take such steps as may be necessary to review, and shall advise the Administrator with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40308_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel and Administrative Services.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Administrator shall make available to the panel any information, personnel, and administrative services and assistance which is reasonable to carry out the duties of the panel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_40308_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Members.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>