<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50115" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50115/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50115/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50115"><akn:num>50115</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of Earth science data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50115. Sources of Earth science data(a) Acquisition.—The Administrator shall, to the extent possible and while satisfying the scientific or educational requirements of the Administration, and where appropriate, of other Federal agencies and scientific researchers, acquire, where cost-effective, space-based and airborne Earth remote sensing data, services, distribution, and applications from a commercial provider.

(b) Treatment as Commercial Product or Commercial Service Under Acquisition Laws.—Acquisitions by the Administrator of the data, services, distribution, and applications referred to in subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with applicable acquisition laws and regulations (including applicable provisions of chapters 201 through 285, 341 through 343, and 363 of title 10). For purposes of such law and regulations, such data, services, distribution, and applications shall be considered to be a commercial product or commercial service. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the United States from acquiring, through contracts with commercial providers, sufficient rights in data to meet the needs of the scientific and educational community or the needs of other government activities.

(c) Safety Standards.—Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from requiring compliance with applicable safety standards.

(d) Administration and Execution.—This section shall be carried out as part of the Commercial Remote Sensing Program at the Stennis Space Center.

(Pub. L. 111–314, § 3, Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3398; Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 836(g)(10)(B), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1874; Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(l)(10), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2161.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


50115(a)42 U.S.C. 14715(a).Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 107(a), (b), (d), (e), Oct. 28, 1998, 112 Stat. 2853, 2854.
50115(b)42 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50115_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator shall, to the extent possible and while satisfying the scientific or educational requirements of the Administration, and where appropriate, of other Federal agencies and scientific researchers, acquire, where cost-effective, space-based and airborne Earth remote sensing data, services, distribution, and applications from a commercial provider.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50115_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as Commercial Product or Commercial Service Under Acquisition Laws.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acquisitions by the Administrator of the data, services, distribution, and applications referred to in subsection (a) shall be carried out in accordance with applicable acquisition laws and regulations (including applicable provisions of chapters 201 through 285, 341 through 343, and 363 of title 10). For purposes of such law and regulations, such data, services, distribution, and applications shall be considered to be a commercial product or commercial service. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude the United States from acquiring, through contracts with commercial providers, sufficient rights in data to meet the needs of the scientific and educational community or the needs of other government activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50115_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Safety Standards.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit the Federal Government from requiring compliance with applicable safety standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50115_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration and Execution.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) This section shall be carried out as part of the Commercial Remote Sensing Program at the Stennis Space Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>