<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50302"><akn:num>50302</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantees for production of commercial reusable in-space transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50302. Loan guarantees for production of commercial reusable in-space transportation(a) Authority To Make Loan Guarantees.—The Secretary may guarantee loans made to eligible United States commercial providers for purposes of producing commercial reusable in-space transportation services or systems.

(b) Eligible United States Commercial Providers.—The Secretary shall prescribe requirements for the eligibility of United States commercial providers for loan guarantees under this section. Such requirements shall ensure that eligible providers are financially capable of undertaking a loan guaranteed under this section.

(c) Limitation on Loans Guaranteed.—The Secretary may not guarantee a loan for a United States commercial provider under this section unless the Secretary determines that credit would not otherwise be reasonably available at the time of the guarantee for the commercial reusable in-space transportation service or system to be produced utilizing the proceeds of the loan.

(d) Credit Subsidy.—(1) Collection required.—The Secretary shall collect from each United States commercial provider receiving a loan guarantee under this section an amount equal to the amount, as determined by the Secretary, to cover the cost, as defined in section 502(5) of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (2 U.S.C. 661a(5)), of the loan guarantee.

(2) Periodic disbursements.—In the case of a loan guarantee in which proceeds of the loan are disbursed over time, the Secretary shall collect the amount required under this subsection on a pro rata basis, as determined by the Secretary, at the time of each disbursement.


(e) Other Terms and Conditions.—(1) Prohibition on subordination.—A loan guaranteed under this section may not be subordinated to another debt contracted by the United States commercial provider concerned, or to any other claims against such provider.

(2) Restriction on income.—A loan guaranteed under this section may not—(A) provide income which is excluded from g</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority To Make Loan Guarantees.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary may guarantee loans made to eligible United States commercial providers for purposes of producing commercial reusable in-space transportation services or systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible United States Commercial Providers.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall prescribe requirements for the eligibility of United States commercial providers for loan guarantees under this section. Such requirements shall ensure that eligible providers are financially capable of undertaking a loan guaranteed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on Loans Guaranteed.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary may not guarantee a loan for a United States commercial provider under this section unless the Secretary determines that credit would not otherwise be reasonably available at the time of the guarantee for the commercial reusable in-space transportation service or system to be produced utilizing the proceeds of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit Subsidy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other Terms and Conditions.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of Rights.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50302_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit Instruments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>