<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50906" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50906/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50906/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50906"><akn:num>50906</akn:num><akn:heading>Experimental permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50906. Experimental permits(a) A person may apply to the Secretary of Transportation for an experimental permit under this section in the form and manner the Secretary prescribes. Consistent with the protection of the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States, the Secretary, not later than 120 days after receiving an application pursuant to this section, shall issue a permit if the Secretary decides in writing that the applicant complies, and will continue to comply, with this chapter and regulations prescribed under this chapter. The Secretary shall inform the applicant of any pending issue and action required to resolve the issue if the Secretary has not made a decision not later than 90 days after receiving an application. The Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a written notice not later than 15 days after any occurrence when the Secretary has failed to act on a permit within the deadline established by this section.

(b) In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may establish procedures for safety approvals of launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, safety systems, processes, services, or personnel that may be used in conducting commercial space launch or reentry activities pursuant to a permit.

(c) In order to encourage the development of a commercial space flight industry, the Secretary may when issuing permits use the authority granted under section 50905(b)(2)(C).

(d) The Secretary may issue a permit only for reusable suborbital rockets or reusable launch vehicles that will be launched into a suborbital trajectory or reentered under that permit solely for—(1) research and development to test design concepts, equipment, or operating techniques;

(2) showing compliance with requirements as part of the process for obtaining a license under this chapter; or

(3) crew </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) A person may apply to the Secretary of Transportation for an experimental permit under this section in the form and manner the Secretary prescribes. Consistent with the protection of the public health and safety, safety of property, and national security and foreign policy interests of the United States, the Secretary, not later than 120 days after receiving an application pursuant to this section, shall issue a permit if the Secretary decides in writing that the applicant complies, and will continue to comply, with this chapter and regulations prescribed under this chapter. The Secretary shall inform the applicant of any pending issue and action required to resolve the issue if the Secretary has not made a decision not later than 90 days after receiving an application. The Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives and Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a written notice not later than 15 days after any occurre</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary may establish procedures for safety approvals of launch vehicles, reentry vehicles, safety systems, processes, services, or personnel that may be used in conducting commercial space launch or reentry activities pursuant to a permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In order to encourage the development of a commercial space flight industry, the Secretary may when issuing permits use the authority granted under section 50905(b)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary may issue a permit only for reusable suborbital rockets or reusable launch vehicles that will be launched into a suborbital trajectory or reentered under that permit solely for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Permits issued under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Permits shall not be transferable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(g) The Secretary may issue a permit under this section notwithstanding any license issued under this chapter. The issuance of a license under this chapter may not invalidate a permit issued under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(h) No person may operate a reusable suborbital rocket or reusable launch vehicle under a permit for carrying any property or human being for compensation or hire.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50906_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(i) For the purposes of sections 50907, 50908, 50909, 50910, 50912, 50914, 50917, 50918, 50919, and 50923 of this chapter— This subsection shall not be construed to allow the transfer of a permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>