<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50909" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50909/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50909/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50909"><akn:num>50909</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition, suspension, and end of launches, operation of launch sites and reentry sites, and reent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50909. Prohibition, suspension, and end of launches, operation of launch sites and reentry sites, and reentries(a) General Authority.—The Secretary of Transportation may prohibit, suspend, or end immediately the launch of a launch vehicle or the operation of a launch site or reentry site, or reentry of a reentry vehicle, licensed under this chapter if the Secretary decides the launch or operation or reentry is detrimental to the public health and safety, the safety of property, or a national security or foreign policy interest of the United States.

(b) Effective Periods of Orders.—An order under this section takes effect immediately and remains in effect during a review under section 50912 of this title.

(Pub. L. 103–272, § 1(e), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1334, § 70108 of title 49; Pub. L. 105–303, title I, § 102(a)(8), Oct. 28, 1998, 112 Stat. 2848; renumbered § 70108 then § 50909 of title 51 and amended Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2), (3)(I), (5)(L), Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3440–3442.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


70108(a)49 App.:2610(a).Oct. 30, 1984, Pub. L. 98–575, § 11, 98 Stat. 3059.
70108(b)49 App.:2610(b).



Editorial Notes
Amendments2010—Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(2), (3)(I), successively renumbered section 70108 of title 49 and section 70108 of this title as this section.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 111–314, § 4(d)(5)(L), substituted “section 50912” for “section 70110”.
1998—Pub. L. 105–303, § 102(a)(8)(A), substituted “Prohibition, suspension, and end of launches, operation of launch sites and reentry sites, and reentries” for “Prohibition, suspension, and end of launches and operation of launch sites” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 105–303, § 102(a)(8)(B), inserted “or reentry site, or reentry of a reentry vehicle,” after “operation of a launch site” and “or reentry” after “launch or operation”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50909_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Authority.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary of Transportation may prohibit, suspend, or end immediately the launch of a launch vehicle or the operation of a launch site or reentry site, or reentry of a reentry vehicle, licensed under this chapter if the Secretary decides the launch or operation or reentry is detrimental to the public health and safety, the safety of property, or a national security or foreign policy interest of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50909_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective Periods of Orders.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) An order under this section takes effect immediately and remains in effect during a review under section 50912 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>