<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50914" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50914/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/50914/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_50914"><akn:num>50914</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability insurance and financial responsibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 50914. Liability insurance and financial responsibility requirements(a) General Requirements.—(1) When a launch or reentry license is issued or transferred under this chapter, the licensee or transferee shall obtain liability insurance or demonstrate financial responsibility in amounts to compensate for the maximum probable loss from claims by—(A) a third party for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out under the license; and

(B) the United States Government against a person for damage or loss to Government property resulting from an activity carried out under the license.


(2) The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the amounts required under paragraph (1)(A) and (B) of this subsection, after consulting with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of the Air Force, and the heads of other appropriate executive agencies.

(3) For the total claims related to one launch or reentry, a licensee or transferee is not required to obtain insurance or demonstrate financial responsibility of more than—(A)(i) $500,000,000 under paragraph (1)(A) of this subsection; or

(ii) $100,000,000 under paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection; or


(B) the maximum liability insurance available on the world market at reasonable cost if the amount is less than the applicable amount in clause (A)(i) or (ii) of this paragraph.


(4) An insurance policy or demonstration of financial responsibility under this subsection shall protect the following, to the extent of their potential liability for involvement in launch services or reentry services, at no cost to the Government:(A) the Government.

(B) executive agencies and personnel, contractors, and subcontractors of the Government.

(C) contractors, subcontractors, and customers of the licensee or transferee.

(D) contractors and subcontractors of the customer.

(E) space flight participants.


(5) Subparagraph (E) of paragraph (4) ceases to be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Requirements.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reciprocal Waiver of Claims.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of Maximum Probable Losses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary of Transportation shall determine the maximum probable losses under subsection (a)(1)(A) and (B) of this section associated with an activity under a license not later than 90 days after a licensee or transferee requires a determination and submits all information the Secretary requires. The Secretary shall amend the determination as warranted by new information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Launches or Reentries Involving Government Facilities and Personnel.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Secretary of Transportation shall establish requirements consistent with this chapter for proof of financial responsibility and other assurances necessary to protect the Government and its executive agencies and personnel from liability, death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss as a result of a launch or operation of a launch site or reentry site or a reentry involving a facility or personnel of the Government. The Secretary may not relieve the Government of liability under this subsection for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from the willful misconduct of the Government or its agents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and Crediting Payments.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) The head of a department, agency, or instrumentality of the Government shall collect a payment owed for damage or loss to Government property under its jurisdiction or control resulting from an activity carried out under a launch or reentry license issued or transferred under this chapter. The payment shall be credited to the current applicable appropriation, fund, or account of the department, agency, or instrumentality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_50914_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Jurisdiction.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Any claim by a third party or space flight participant for death, bodily injury, or property damage or loss resulting from an activity carried out under the license shall be the exclusive jurisdiction of the Federal courts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>