<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/51302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/51302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/51302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_51302"><akn:num>51302</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial exploration and commercial recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 51302. Commercial exploration and commercial recovery(a) In General.—The President, acting through appropriate Federal agencies, shall—(1) facilitate commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources by United States citizens;

(2) discourage government barriers to the development in the United States of economically viable, safe, and stable industries for commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources in manners consistent with the international obligations of the United States; and

(3) promote the right of United States citizens to engage in commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources free from harmful interference, in accordance with the international obligations of the United States and subject to authorization and continuing supervision by the Federal Government.


(b) Report.—Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the President shall submit to Congress a report on commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources by United States citizens that specifies—(1) the authorities necessary to meet the international obligations of the United States, including authorization and continuing supervision by the Federal Government; and

(2) recommendations for the allocation of responsibilities among Federal agencies for the activities described in paragraph (1).


(Added Pub. L. 114–90, title IV, § 402(a), Nov. 25, 2015, 129 Stat. 721.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date of enactment of this section, referred to in subsec. (b), is the date of enactment of Pub. L. 114–90, which was approved Nov. 25, 2015.

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 13914. Encouraging International Support for the Recovery and Use of Space Resources
Ex. Ord. No. 13914, Apr. 6, 2020, 85 F.R. 20381, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, including title IV of the U.S. Commercial Space Launch Co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The President, acting through appropriate Federal agencies, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_51302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the President shall submit to Congress a report on commercial exploration for and commercial recovery of space resources by United States citizens that specifies—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>