<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60113"><akn:num>60113</akn:num><akn:heading>Data policy for Landsat 7</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60113. Data policy for Landsat 7(a) Landsat 7 Data Policy.—The Landsat Program Management, in consultation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, shall develop a data policy for Landsat 7 which should—(1) ensure that unenhanced data are available to all users at the cost of fulfilling user requests;

(2) ensure timely and dependable delivery of unenhanced data to the full spectrum of civilian, national security, commercial, and foreign users and the National Satellite Land Remote Sensing Data Archive;

(3) ensure that the United States retains ownership of all unenhanced data generated by Landsat 7;

(4) support the development of the commercial market for remote sensing data;

(5) ensure that the provision of commercial value-added services based on remote sensing data remains exclusively the function of the private sector; and

(6) to the extent possible, ensure that the data distribution system for Landsat 7 is compatible with the Earth Observing System Data and Information System.


(b) Additional Data Policy Considerations.—In addition, the data policy for Landsat 7 may provide for—(1) United States private sector entities to operate ground receiving stations in the United States for Landsat 7 data;

(2) other means for direct access by private sector entities to unenhanced data from Landsat 7; and

(3) the United States Government to charge a per image fee, license fee, or other such fee to entities operating ground receiving stations or distributing Landsat 7 data.


(Pub. L. 111–314, § 3, Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3413.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


6011315 U.S.C. 5615(a), (b).Pub. L. 102–555, title I, § 105(a), (b), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 4170.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Landsat 7 Data Policy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Landsat Program Management, in consultation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, shall develop a data policy for Landsat 7 which should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional Data Policy Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In addition, the data policy for Landsat 7 may provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>