<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60121"><akn:num>60121</akn:num><akn:heading>General licensing authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60121. General licensing authority(a) Licensing Authority of Secretary.—(1) In general.—In consultation with other appropriate United States Government agencies, the Secretary is authorized to license private sector parties to operate private remote sensing space systems for such period as the Secretary may specify and in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.

(2) Limitation with respect to system used for other purposes.—In the case of a private space system that is used for remote sensing and other purposes, the authority of the Secretary under this subchapter shall be limited only to the remote sensing operations of such space system.


(b) Compliance With Law, Regulations, International Obligations, and National Security.—(1) In general.—No license shall be granted by the Secretary unless the Secretary determines in writing that the applicant will comply with the requirements of this chapter, any regulations issued pursuant to this chapter, and any applicable international obligations and national security concerns of the United States.

(2) List of requirements for complete application.—The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a complete and specific list of all information required to comprise a complete application for a license under this subchapter. An application shall be considered complete when the applicant has provided all information required by the list most recently published in the Federal Register before the date the application was first submitted. Unless the Secretary has, within 30 days after receipt of an application, notified the applicant of information necessary to complete an application, the Secretary may not deny the application on the basis of the absence of any such information.


(c) Deadline for Action on Application.—The Secretary shall review any application and make a determination thereon within 120 days of the receipt of such application. If final action has not occurred within such time, the Secretary </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60121_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing Authority of Secretary.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60121_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance With Law, Regulations, International Obligations, and National Security.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60121_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadline for Action on Application.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Secretary shall review any application and make a determination thereon within 120 days of the receipt of such application. If final action has not occurred within such time, the Secretary shall inform the applicant of any pending issues and of actions required to resolve them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60121_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improper Basis for Denial.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Secretary shall not deny such license in order to protect any existing licensee from competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60121_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement To Provide Unenhanced Data.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>