<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/60602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_60602"><akn:num>60602</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 60602. Integrated strategy(a) In General.—The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the interagency working group and upon the advice of the advisory group, shall develop a strategy for coordinated observation of space weather among members of the interagency working group (in this chapter, referred to as the “integrated strategy”). The integrated strategy shall identify—(1) observations and measurements that must be sustained beyond the lifetime of current ground-based and space-based assets, as described under section 60603, that are essential for space weather research, models, forecasting, and prediction;

(2) new observations and measurements that may significantly improve space weather forecasting and prediction; and

(3) plans for follow-on space-based observations under section 60603.


(b) Considerations.—In developing the integrated strategy in subsection (a), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall consider, as appropriate, the following:(1) Potential contributions of commercial solutions, prize authority, academic and international partnerships, microsatellites, small satellite options, ground-based instruments, and hosted payloads for observations identified in section 60602(a)(2).

(2) Work conducted before the date of enactment of the PROSWIFT Act by the National Science and Technology Council with respect to space weather.

(3) The survey under section 60601(d).

(4) Any relevant recommendations from the most recent National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine Decadal Survey for Solar and Space Physics (Heliophysics).


(c) Review of Integrated Strategy.—(1) Review.—The Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in consultation with Federal agencies participating in the interagency working group, shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Eng</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60602_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in collaboration with the interagency working group and upon the advice of the advisory group, shall develop a strategy for coordinated observation of space weather among members of the interagency working group (in this chapter, referred to as the “integrated strategy”). The integrated strategy shall identify—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60602_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In developing the integrated strategy in subsection (a), the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall consider, as appropriate, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60602_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of Integrated Strategy.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60602_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation Plan.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Not later than 180 days after delivery of the review of the integrated strategy in subsection (c)(3), the interagency working group shall develop a plan to implement the integrated strategy, including an estimate of the cost and schedule required for implementation. Upon completion, the interagency working group shall submit the implementation plan to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology and Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Armed Services of the Senate. The implementation plan shall be made publicly available within 30 days of submittal to Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_60602_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reevaluation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The Director, in collaboration with the interagency working group, shall update the integrated strategy not later than 1 year after the reevaluation of the user survey from section 60601(d)(3)(F) in accordance with the requirements of subsections (a) through (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>