<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70503"><akn:num>70503</akn:num><akn:heading>Ground-based analog capabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70503. Ground-based analog capabilities(a) In General.—The Administrator may establish a ground-based analog capability in remote United States locations in order to assist in the development of lunar operations, life support, and in-situ resource utilization experience and capabilities.

(b) Environmental Characteristics.—The Administrator shall select locations for the activities described in subsection (a) that—(1) are regularly accessible;

(2) have significant temperature extremes and range; and

(3) have access to energy and natural resources (including geothermal, permafrost, volcanic, or other potential resources).


(c) Involvement of Local Populations and Private Sector Partners.—In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall involve local populations, academia, and industrial partners as much as possible to ensure that ground-based benefits and applications are encouraged and developed.

(Pub. L. 111–314, § 3, Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3430.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


7050342 U.S.C. 16764.Pub. L. 109–155, title V, § 504, Dec. 30, 2005, 119 Stat. 2929.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In General.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator may establish a ground-based analog capability in remote United States locations in order to assist in the development of lunar operations, life support, and in-situ resource utilization experience and capabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Characteristics.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Administrator shall select locations for the activities described in subsection (a) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Involvement of Local Populations and Private Sector Partners.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall involve local populations, academia, and industrial partners as much as possible to ensure that ground-based benefits and applications are encouraged and developed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>