<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/51/70708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_70708"><akn:num>70708</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 70708. Compensation and travel expenses(a) Compensation.—Each member of a Commission may be compensated at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for positions at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5 for each day during which that member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Commission.

(b) Travel Expenses.—While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members of a Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5.

(Pub. L. 111–314, § 3, Dec. 18, 2010, 124 Stat. 3435.)











Historical and Revision Notes


RevisedSectionSource (U.S. Code)Source (Statutes at Large)


7070842 U.S.C. 16848.Pub. L. 109–155, title VIII, § 828, Dec. 30, 2005, 119 Stat. 2944.


In subsection (a), the words “at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate” for “at not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate” for consistency in title 51.
In subsection (b), the words “section 5703 of title 5” are substituted for “section 5703(b) of title 5” to correct an error in the law. Section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, does not contain a subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Each member of a Commission may be compensated at a rate not to exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay in effect for positions at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5 for each day during which that member is engaged in the actual performance of the duties of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_70708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel Expenses.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) While away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission, members of a Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>