<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/10412" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/10412/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/10412/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10412"><akn:num>10412</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of senior official for Department of Defense activities relating to, and implementation </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10412. Designation of senior official for Department of Defense activities relating to, and implementation plan for, the AUKUS partnership(a) Designation of senior officialNot later than 90 days after December 22, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior civilian official of the Department of Defense who shall be responsible for overseeing Department of Defense activities relating to the AUKUS partnership.


(b) Plan(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after December 22, 2023, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Administrator for Nuclear Security and the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report containing an implementation plan outlining Department of Defense efforts relating to the AUKUS partnership.


(2) ElementsThe plan required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) Timelines and major anticipated milestones for the implementation of the AUKUS partnership.

(B) An identification of dependencies of such milestones on defense requirements that are—(i) unrelated to the AUKUS partnership; and

(ii) solely within the decisionmaking responsibility of Australia or the United Kingdom.


(C) A consideration of the implications of the plan on the industrial base with respect to—(i) the expansion of existing United States submarine construction capacity to fulfill United States, United Kingdom, and Australia requirements;

(ii) acceleration of the restoration of United States capabilities for producing highly enriched uranium to fuel submarine reactors;

(iii) stabilization of commodity markets and expanding supplies of high-grade steel, construction materials, and other resources required for improving shipyard condition and expanding throughput capacity; and

(iv) coordination and synchronization of industrial sourcing opportunities among Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States.


(D) A description of resourcing and personnel requirements, including—(i) a detailed assessmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10412_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of senior official</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of senior official Not later than 90 days after December 22, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall designate a senior civilian official of the Department of Defense who shall be responsible for overseeing Department of Defense activities relating to the AUKUS partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10412_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10412_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Semiannual updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Semiannual updates Not later than 60 days after the date on which the plan required by subsection (b) is submitted, and semiannually thereafter not later than April 1 and October 1 each year through 2029, the senior civilian official designated under subsection (a) shall provide the congressional defense committees and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate with a briefing on the status of all Department activities to implement the AUKUS partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>