<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1171...1195" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1171...1195/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1171...1195/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1171___1195"><akn:num>1171...1195</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 1171 to 1195. Transferred
Editorial Notes
Codification
Section 1171, R.S. § 1689, which related to general application of provisions to consular officers, was transferred to section 4191 of this title.
Section 1172, R.S. § 4082, which related to solemnization of marriages, was transferred to section 4192 of this title and subsequently repealed.
Section 1173, R.S. § 1707; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 39, 62 Stat. 992, which related to receipt by consuls and vice consuls of protests, was transferred to section 4193 of this title.
Section 1174, R.S. § 1708; Feb. 14, 1903, ch. 552, § 10, 32 Stat. 829, which related to lists and returns of seamen and vessels, etc., was transferred to section 4194 of this title.
Section 1175, R.S. § 1709; Mar. 3, 1911, ch. 223, 36 Stat. 1083; June 10, 1921, ch. 18, § 304, 42 Stat. 24; July 12, 1940, ch. 618, 54 Stat. 758, which related to estates of decedents generally and to General Accounting Office as conservator, was transferred to section 4195 of this title and subsequently repealed.
Section 1176, R.S. § 1710; July 12, 1940, ch. 618, 54 Stat. 760, which related to notification of death of decedent and transmission of inventory of effects of decedent, was transferred to section 4196 of this title.
Section 1177, R.S. § 1711; July 12, 1940, ch. 618, 54 Stat. 760, which related to a consular or diplomatic officer following testamentary directions and assistance to a testamentary appointee, was transferred to section 4197 of this title.
Section 1178, act June 30, 1902, ch. 1331, § 1, 32 Stat. 546, which related to execution of a bond as administrator or guardian and to an action on bond, was transferred to section 4198 of this title.
Section 1179, act June 30, 1902, ch. 1331, § 2, 32 Stat. 547, which related to penalty for failure to give bond and for embezzlement, was transferred to section 4199 of this title.
Section 1180, R.S. § 1715, which related to certification by consular officers of invoices generally, was transferred to section </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>