<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1391"><akn:num>1391</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of property and rights to Philippine Commonwealth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1391. Transfer of property and rights to Philippine Commonwealth
All the property and rights which may have been acquired in the Philippine Islands by the United States under the treaties mentioned in the first section of this Act, except such land or other property as has heretofore been designated by the President of the United States for Military and other reservations of the Government of the United States, and except such land or other property or rights or interests therein as may have been sold or otherwise disposed of in accordance with law, are granted to the government of the Commonwealth of the Philippine Islands when constituted.
(Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 5, 48 Stat. 459.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextTreaties mentioned in the first section of this Act, referred to in text, were treaty of peace between the United States and Spain of December 10, 1898, and treaty between Spain and the United States concluded at Washington, Nov. 7, 1900.
The first section of this Act, referred to in text, is section 1 of act Mar. 24, 1934, which was classified to section 1231 of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions, and was omitted from the Code.
Since their independence, the Philippine Islands have been a republic, and are no longer designated as a “Commonwealth”, referred to in text. See note below.

Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to those in this section were contained in act Jan. 17, 1933, ch. 11, § 5, 47 Stat. 764.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
SeparabilityAct Mar. 24, 1934, ch. 84, § 16, 48 Stat. 464, provided: “If any provision of this Act [enacting this section and sections 1281a, 1393 to 1395 of this title, amending sections 1231 to 1234, 1237 to 1239, 1241 to 1243, 1245, 1247, and 1248 of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions] is declared unconstitutional or the applicability thereof to any person or circumstances is held invalid, the validity of the remainder of the act and the applicability of such provisions and circum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>