<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1465ee"><akn:num>1465ee</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1465ee. Authorization of appropriations(a) Authorization of appropriationsIn addition to amounts otherwise made available under section 201 for such purposes, there are authorized to be appropriated to the United States Information Agency, $16,000,000 for the fiscal year 1990 and $16,000,000 for the fiscal year 1991 for television broadcasting to Cuba in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Limitation(1) Subject to paragraph (2), no funds authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) may be obligated or expended unless the President determines and notifies the appropriate committees of Congress that the test of television broadcasting to Cuba (as authorized by title V of the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1989 (Public Law 100–459)) has demonstrated television broadcasting to Cuba is feasible and will not cause objectionable interference with the broadcasts of incumbent domestic licensees. The Federal Communications Commission shall furnish to the appropriate committees of Congress all interim and final reports and other appropriate documentation concerning objectionable interference from television broadcasting to Cuba to incumbent domestic licensees.

(2) Not less than 30 days before the President makes the determination under paragraph (1), the President shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of the Congress which includes the findings of the test of television broadcasting to Cuba. The period for the test of television broadcasting may be extended until—(A) the date of the determination and notification by the President under paragraph (1), or

(B) 30 days,


whichever comes first.


(c) Availability of fundsAmounts appropriated to carry out the purposes of this subchapter are authorized to be available until expended.


(Pub. L. 101–246, title II, § 247, Feb. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 62; Pub. L. 102–138, title II, § 232, Oct. 28, 1991, 105 Stat. 703.)

Repeal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations In addition to amounts otherwise made available under section 201 for such purposes, there are authorized to be appropriated to the United States Information Agency, $16,000,000 for the fiscal year 1990 and $16,000,000 for the fiscal year 1991 for television broadcasting to Cuba in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of funds Amounts appropriated to carry out the purposes of this subchapter are authorized to be available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>