<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1465b"><akn:num>1465b</akn:num><akn:heading>Cuba Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1465b. Cuba Service
The Broadcasting Board of Governors shall establish within the International Broadcasting Bureau a Cuba Service (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Service”). The Service shall be responsible for all radio broadcasts to Cuba authorized by section 1465a of this title. The Broadcasting Board of Governors shall appoint a head of the Service and shall employ such staff as the head of the Service may need to carry out his duties. The Cuba Service shall be administered separately from other Voice of America functions and the head of the Cuba Service shall report directly to the Board 11 So in original. There is no Board of the International Broadcasting Bureau. of the International Broadcasting Bureau.
(Pub. L. 98–111, § 4, Oct. 4, 1983, 97 Stat. 750; Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 305(e)(1), formerly § 305(d)(1), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 436; Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, subdiv. A, title XIII, §§ 1323(f)(1), 1324(3), (4), (6), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–779, 2681–781.)

Repeal of SectionSection repealed upon transmittal of determination by President under section 6063(c)(3) of this title that democratically elected government in Cuba is in power, see section 6037(c) of this title.

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act which comprises this subchapter, and not as part of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–277, § 1324(6), substituted “Board” for “Director” in last sentence.
Pub. L. 105–277, § 1324(4), which directed the amendment of this section by substituting “the International Broadcasting Bureau” for “the Voice of America”, was executed by making the substitution for text in two places to reflect the probable intent of Congress.
Pub. L. 105–277, § 1324(3), which directed the substitution of “the Broadcasting Board of Governors” for “the Director of the United States Information Agency” each pla</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>