<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1465a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1465a"><akn:num>1465a</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional functions of Broadcasting Board of Governors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1465a. Additional functions of Broadcasting Board of Governors(a) Radio broadcasting to CubaIn order to carry out the objectives set forth in section 1465 of this title, the Broadcasting Board of Governors (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”) shall provide for the open communication of information and ideas through the use of radio broadcasting to Cuba. Radio broadcasting to Cuba shall serve as a consistently reliable and authoritative source of accurate, objective, and comprehensive news.


(b) Broadcasting as part of Voice of AmericaRadio broadcasting in accordance with subsection (a) shall be part of the Voice of America radio broadcasting to Cuba and shall be in accordance with all Voice of America standards to ensure the broadcast of programs which are objective, accurate, balanced, and which present a variety of views.


(c) Location of broadcast facilities; frequency; leased time from nongovernmental shortwave stationsRadio broadcasting to Cuba authorized by this subchapter shall utilize the broadcasting facilities located at Marathon, Florida, and the 1180 AM frequency that were used by the Voice of America prior to October 4, 1983. Other frequencies, not on the commercial Amplitude Modulation (AM) Band (535 kHz to 1605 kHz), may also be simultaneously utilized: Provided, That no frequency shall be used for radio broadcasts to Cuba in accordance with this subchapter which is not also used for all other Voice of America broadcasts to Cuba. Time leased from nongovernmental shortwave radio stations may be used to carry all or part of the Service programs and to rebroadcast Service programs: Provided, That not less than 30 per centum of the programs broadcast or rebroadcast shall be regular Voice of America broadcasts with particular emphasis on news and programs meeting the requirements of section 1463(2) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(d) Changes in frequencies to other AM bands; jamming and interferenceNotwithsta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Radio broadcasting to Cuba</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Radio broadcasting to Cuba In order to carry out the objectives set forth in section 1465 of this title, the Broadcasting Board of Governors (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”) shall provide for the open communication of information and ideas through the use of radio broadcasting to Cuba. Radio broadcasting to Cuba shall serve as a consistently reliable and authoritative source of accurate, objective, and comprehensive news.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadcasting as part of Voice of America</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Broadcasting as part of Voice of America Radio broadcasting in accordance with subsection (a) shall be part of the Voice of America radio broadcasting to Cuba and shall be in accordance with all Voice of America standards to ensure the broadcast of programs which are objective, accurate, balanced, and which present a variety of views.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of broadcast facilities; frequency; leased time from nongovernmental shortwave stations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Location of broadcast facilities; frequency; leased time from nongovernmental shortwave stations Radio broadcasting to Cuba authorized by this subchapter shall utilize the broadcasting facilities located at Marathon, Florida, and the 1180 AM frequency that were used by the Voice of America prior to October 4, 1983. Other frequencies, not on the commercial Amplitude Modulation (AM) Band (535 kHz to 1605 kHz), may also be simultaneously utilized: Provided, That no frequency shall be used for radio broadcasts to Cuba in accordance with this subchapter which is not also used for all other Voice of America broadcasts to Cuba. Time leased from nongovernmental shortwave radio stations may be used to carry all or part of the Service programs and to rebroadcast Service programs: Provided, That not less than 30 per centum of the programs broadcast or rebroadcast shall be regular Voice of America broadcasts with particular emphasis on news and programs meeting the requirements of section 1463</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Changes in frequencies to other AM bands; jamming and interference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Changes in frequencies to other AM bands; jamming and interference Notwithstanding subsection (c), in the event that broadcasts to Cuba on the 1180 AM frequency are subject to jamming or interference greater by 25 per centum or more than the average daily jamming or interference in the twelve months preceding September 1, 1983, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may lease time on commercial or noncommercial educational AM band radio broadcasting stations. The Federal Communications Commission shall determine levels of jamming and interference by conducting regular monitoring of the 1180 AM frequency. In the event that more than two hours a day of time is leased, not less than 30 per centum of the programing broadcast shall be regular Voice of America broadcasts with particular emphasis on news and programs meeting the requirements of section 1463(2) 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voice of America: Cuba Service; Voice of America: Radio Marti program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Voice of America: Cuba Service; Voice of America: Radio Marti program Any program of United States Government radio broadcasts to Cuba authorized by this section shall be designated “Voice of America: Cuba Service” or “Voice of America: Radio Marti program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1465a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of other facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of other facilities In the event broadcasting facilities located at Marathon, Florida, are rendered inoperable by natural disaster or by unlawful destruction, the Broadcasting Board of Governors may, for the period in which the facilities are inoperable but not to exceed one hundred and fifty days, use other United States Government-owned transmission facilities for Voice of America broadcasts to Cuba authorized by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>