<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1475a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1475a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1475a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1475a"><akn:num>1475a</akn:num><akn:heading>Replacement of passenger motor vehicles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1475a. Replacement of passenger motor vehicles
The exchange allowances or proceeds derived from the exchange or sale of passenger motor vehicles used abroad for purposes of this chapter or the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.] shall be available without fiscal year limitation for replacement of an equal number of such vehicles in accordance with section 503 of title 40.
(Jan. 27, 1948, ch. 36, title VIII, § 806, as added Pub. L. 94–350, title II, § 204, July 12, 1976, 90 Stat. 830; amended Pub. L. 96–60, title II, § 204(c), Aug. 15, 1979, 93 Stat. 400.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 87–256, Sept. 21, 1961, 75 Stat. 527, which is classified principally to chapter 33 (§ 2451 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2451 of this title and Tables.

Codification
“Section 503 of title 40” substituted in text for “section 201(c) of the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949” on authority of Pub. L. 107–217, § 5(c), Aug. 21, 2002, 116 Stat. 1303, the first section of which enacted Title 40, Public Buildings, Property, and Works.

Amendments1979—Pub. L. 96–60 substituted “shall be available” for “are authorized to be made available”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1979 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 96–60 effective Oct. 1, 1979, and applicable only with respect to funds appropriated after Aug. 15, 1979, where new authorities provide for expenditures of appropriated funds, see section 209 of Pub. L. 96–60, set out as a note under section 1471 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>