<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1626"><akn:num>1626</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1626. Payments(a) Principal and interest; regulationsSubject to the limitations hereinafter provided, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to pay, as prescribed by section 1627 of this title, an amount not exceeding the principal of each award, plus accrued interest on such awards as bear interest, certified pursuant to section 1624 of this title, in accordance with the award. Such payments, and applications for such payments, shall be made in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe.


(b) Deductions; coverage into Treasury; reimbursement for expenses(1) There shall be deducted from the amount of each payment made pursuant to subsection (c) of section 1627 of this title, as reimbursement for the expenses incurred by the United States, an amount equal to 5 per centum of such payment. All amounts so deducted shall be covered into the Treasury to the credit of miscellaneous receipts.

(2) The Secretary of the Treasury shall deduct from any amounts covered, subsequent to July 24, 1968, into any special fund, created pursuant to section 1627 of this title, 5 per centum thereof as reimbursement to the Government of the United States for expenses incurred by the Commission and by the Treasury Department in the administration of this subchapter. The amounts so deducted shall be covered into the Treasury to the credit of miscellaneous receipts.


(c) To whom made; exceptionsPayments made pursuant to this subchapter shall be made only to the person or persons on behalf of whom the award is made, except that—(1) if any person to whom any payment is to be made pursuant to this subchapter is deceased or is under a legal disability, payment shall be made to his legal representative, except that if any payment to be made is not over $1,000 and there is no qualified executor or administrator, payment may be made to the person or persons found by the Secretary of the Treasury to be entitled thereto, without the necessity </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal and interest; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Principal and interest; regulations Subject to the limitations hereinafter provided, the Secretary of the Treasury is authorized and directed to pay, as prescribed by section 1627 of this title, an amount not exceeding the principal of each award, plus accrued interest on such awards as bear interest, certified pursuant to section 1624 of this title, in accordance with the award. Such payments, and applications for such payments, shall be made in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary of the Treasury may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deductions; coverage into Treasury; reimbursement for expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deductions; coverage into Treasury; reimbursement for expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>To whom made; exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) To whom made; exceptions Payments made pursuant to this subchapter shall be made only to the person or persons on behalf of whom the award is made, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Erroneous payments as bar to further recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Erroneous payments as bar to further recovery Whenever the Secretary of the Treasury shall find that any person is entitled to any such payment, after such payment shall have been received by such person, it shall be an absolute bar to recovery by any other person against the United States, its officers, agents, or employees with respect to such payment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquiescence in conditions of subchapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acquiescence in conditions of subchapter Any person who makes application for any such payment shall be held to have consented to all the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1626_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-assumption of liability by United States on claims against foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Non-assumption of liability by United States on claims against foreign governments Nothing in this subchapter shall be construed as the assumption of any liability by the United States for the payment or satisfaction, in whole or in part, of any claim on behalf of any national of the United States against any foreign government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>