<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1741a"><akn:num>1741a</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1741a. Special Envoy for Hostage Affairs(a) EstablishmentThere shall be a Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall report to the Secretary of State.


(b) RankThe Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.


(c) ResponsibilitiesThe Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall—(1) lead diplomatic engagement on United States hostage policy;

(2) coordinate all diplomatic engagements and strategy in support of hostage recovery efforts, in coordination with the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell and consistent with policy guidance communicated through the Hostage Response Group;

(3) in coordination with the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell as appropriate, coordinate diplomatic engagements regarding cases in which a foreign government has detained a United States national and the United States Government regards such detention as unlawful or wrongful;

(4) provide senior representation from the Special Envoy’s office to the Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell established under section 1741b of this title and the Hostage Response Group established under section 1741c of this title; and

(5) ensure that families of United States nationals unlawfully or wrongly detained abroad receive updated information about developments in cases and government policy.


(d) Family Engagement CoordinatorThere shall be, in the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, a Family Engagement Coordinator, who shall ensure—(1) for a United States national unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, that—(A) any interaction by executive branch officials with any family member of such United States national occurs in a coordinated fashion;

(B) such family member receives consistent and accurate information from the United States Government; and

(C) appropriate coordination with the Family Engagement Coordinator described in section 1741b(c)(2) of this title; an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be a Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall report to the Secretary of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rank The Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities The Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Engagement Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Family Engagement Coordinator There shall be, in the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for Hostage Affairs, a Family Engagement Coordinator, who shall ensure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>