<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1741d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1741d"><akn:num>1741d</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of imposition of sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1741d. Authorization of imposition of sanctions(a) In generalThe President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines, based on credible evidence—(1) is responsible for or is complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing, the hostage-taking of a United States national abroad or the unlawful or wrongful detention of a United States national abroad; or

(2) knowingly provides financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services in support of, an activity described in paragraph (1).


(b) Sanctions describedThe sanctions described in this subsection are the following:(1) Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole(A) Visas, admission, or paroleAn alien described in subsection (a) may be—(i) inadmissible to the United States;

(ii) ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and

(iii) otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.).


(B) Current visas revoked(i) In generalAn alien described in subsection (a) may be subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.


(ii) Immediate effectA revocation under clause (i) may—(I) take effect immediately; and

(II) cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.




(2) Blocking of property(A) In generalThe President may exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.), to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the poss</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person the President determines, based on credible evidence—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sanctions described The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exceptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Penalties A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (b)(2) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1705) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of sanctions The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a person if the President determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting requirement If the President terminates sanctions pursuant to subsection (d),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (e),”. the President shall report to the appropriate congressional committees a written justification for such termination within 15 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Implementation of regulatory authority The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception relating to importation of goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exception relating to importation of goods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1741d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>