<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1853" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1853/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1853/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1853"><akn:num>1853</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to Yugoslavia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1853. Assistance to Yugoslavia
In furnishing assistance to Yugoslavia, the President shall continuously assure himself (1) that Yugoslavia continues to maintain its independence, (2) that Yugoslavia is not participating in any policy or program for the Communist conquest of the world, and (3) that the furnishing of such assistance is in the interest of the national security of the United States. The President shall keep the Foreign Relations Committee and the Appropriations Committee of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives fully and constantly informed of any assistance furnished to Yugoslavia under this chapter.
(Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937, ch. II, § 143, as added July 18, 1956, ch. 627, § 5, 70 Stat. 556; amended Pub. L. 85–141, § 5(b), Aug. 14, 1957, 71 Stat. 356.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1957—Pub. L. 85–141 required the President to continuously assure himself that Yugoslavia continues to maintain its independence, that she is not participating in any policy or program for the Communist conquest of the world, and that the furnishing of assistance is in the interest of national security, and provided that certain committees of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives should be constantly informed of assistance furnished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>