<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1978" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1978/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/1978/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1978"><akn:num>1978</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on importation of fishery or wildlife products from countries which violate internationa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1978. Restriction on importation of fishery or wildlife products from countries which violate international fishery or endangered or threatened species programs(a) Certification to President(1) When the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, determines that nationals of a foreign country, directly or indirectly, are conducting fishing operations in a manner or under circumstances which diminish the effectiveness of an international fishery conservation program, the Secretary of Commerce shall certify such fact to the President.

(2) When the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of State, finds that nationals of a foreign country, directly or indirectly, are engaging in trade or taking which diminishes the effectiveness of any international program for endangered or threatened species, the Secretary making such finding shall certify such fact to the President.

(3) In administering this subsection, the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary of the Interior, as appropriate, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall—(A) periodically monitor the activities of foreign nationals that may affect the international programs referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2);

(B) promptly investigate any activity by foreign nationals that, in the opinion of the Secretary, may be cause for certification under paragraph (1) or (2); and

(C) promptly conclude; and reach a decision with respect to; any investigation commenced under subparagraph (B).


(4) The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior shall each report to Congress each certification to the President made by such Secretary under this subsection, within 15 days after making such certification.

(5) Upon receipt of any certification made under paragraph (1) or (2), the President may direct the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit the bringing or the importation into the United States of any products from the offending cou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification to President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Certification to President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification to Congress Within sixty days following certification by the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary of the Interior, the President shall notify the Congress of any action taken by him pursuant to such certification. In the event the President fails to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to prohibit the importation of fish products or wildlife products of the offending country, or if such prohibition does not cover all fish products or wildlife products of the offending country, the President shall inform the Congress of the reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importation of fish products from offending country prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Importation of fish products from offending country prohibited It shall be unlawful for any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States knowingly to bring or import into, or cause to be imported into, the United States any products prohibited by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review by Secretary of Commerce or Secretary of the Interior; termination of certification; notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Periodic review by Secretary of Commerce or Secretary of the Interior; termination of certification; notice After making a certification to the President under subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary of the Interior, as the case may be, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall periodically review the activities of the nationals of the offending country to determine if the reasons for which the certification was made no longer prevail. Upon determining that such reasons no longer prevail, the Secretary concerned shall terminate the certification and publish notice thereof, together with a statement of the facts on which such determination is based, in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties; forfeiture; customs laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Penalties; forfeiture; customs laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations The Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior are each authorized to prescribe such regulations as he determines necessary to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1978_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>