<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2054" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2054/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2054/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2054"><akn:num>2054</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2054. Statement of purpose
The purpose of this subchapter is to promote better relations and understanding between the United States and the nations of Asia and the Pacific (hereinafter referred to as “the East”) through cooperative study, training, and research, by establishing in Hawaii a Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Between East and West where scholars and students in various fields from the nations of the East and West may study, give and receive training, exchange ideas and views, and conduct other activities primarily in support of the objectives of the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948, as amended [22 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.], title III of chapter II of the Mutual Security Act of 1954, and other Acts promoting the international, educational, cultural, and related activities of the United States.
(Pub. L. 86–472, ch. VII, § 702, May 14, 1960, 74 Stat. 141.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948, as amended, referred to in text, is act Jan. 27, 1948, ch. 36, 62 Stat. 6, which is classified generally to chapter 18 (§ 1431 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1431 of this title and Tables.
The Mutual Security Act of 1954, referred to in text, is act Aug. 26, 1954, ch. 937, 68 Stat. 832, as amended by acts July 8, 1955, ch. 301, 69 Stat. 283; July 18, 1956, ch. 627, §§ 2 to 11, 70 Stat. 555; Aug. 14, 1957, Pub. L. 85–141, 71 Stat. 355; June 30, 1958, Pub. L. 85–477, ch. 1, §§ 101 to 103, ch. II, §§ 201 to 205, ch. III, § 301, ch. IV, § 401, ch. V, § 501, 72 Stat. 261; July 24, 1959, Pub. L. 86–108, § 2, ch. 1, § 101, ch. II, §§ 201 to 205(a) to (i), (k) to (n), ch. III, § 301, ch. IV, § 401(a) to (k), (m), 73 Stat. 246; May 14, 1960, Pub. L. 86–472, ch. I to V, 74 Stat. 134. Title III of chapter II of the Act was classified to sections 1891 to 1896, 1897, and 1898 of this tit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>