<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2124c"><akn:num>2124c</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Tourism Development Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2124c. Rural Tourism Development Foundation(a) Establishment of FoundationIn order to assist in the development and promotion of rural tourism, there is established a charitable and nonprofit corporation to be known as the Rural Tourism Development Foundation (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Foundation”).


(b) FunctionsThe functions of the Foundation shall be the planning, development, and implementation of projects and programs which have the potential to increase travel and tourism export revenues by attracting foreign visitors to rural America. Initially, such projects and programs shall include—(1) participation in the development and distribution of educational and promotional materials pertaining to both private and public attractions located in rural areas of the United States, including Federal parks and recreational lands, which can be used by foreign visitors;

(2) development of educational resources to assist in private and public rural tourism development; and

(3) participation in Federal agency outreach efforts to make such resources available to private enterprises, State and local governments, and other persons and entities interested in rural tourism development.


(c) Board of Directors(1) Composition(A) The Foundation shall have a Board of Directors (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Board”) that—(i) during its first two years shall consist of nine voting members; and

(ii) thereafter shall consist of those nine members plus up to six additional voting members as determined in accordance with the bylaws of the Foundation.


(B)(i) The Secretary of Commerce shall, within six months after September 30, 1992, appoint the initial nine voting members of the Board and thereafter shall appoint the successors of each of three such members, as provided by such bylaws.

(ii) The voting members of the Board, other than those referred to in clause (i), shall be appointed in accordance with procedures established by such bylaws.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Foundation In order to assist in the development and promotion of rural tourism, there is established a charitable and nonprofit corporation to be known as the Rural Tourism Development Foundation (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Foundation”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The functions of the Foundation shall be the planning, development, and implementation of projects and programs which have the potential to increase travel and tourism export revenues by attracting foreign visitors to rural America. Initially, such projects and programs shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Board of Directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation and expenses No compensation shall be paid to the members of the Board for their services as members, but they may be reimbursed for actual and necessary traveling and subsistence expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties as such members out of Foundation funds available to the Board for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts, devises, and bequests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Acceptance of gifts, devises, and bequests</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Investments Except as otherwise required by the instrument of transfer, the Foundation may sell, lease, invest, reinvest, retain, or otherwise dispose of or deal with any property or income thereof as the Board may from time to time determine. The Foundation shall not engage in any business, nor shall the Foundation make any investment that may not lawfully be made by a trust company in the District of Columbia, except that the Foundation may make any investment authorized by the instrument of transfer and may retain any property accepted by the Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Perpetual succession; liability of Board members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Perpetual succession; liability of Board members The Foundation shall have perpetual succession, with all the usual powers and obligations of a corporation acting as a trustee, including the power to sue and to be sued in its own name, but the members of the Board shall not be personally liable, except for malfeasance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractual power</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Contractual power The Foundation shall have the power to enter into contracts, to execute instruments, and generally to do any and all lawful acts necessary or appropriate to its purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from taxes; contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Exemption from taxes; contributions The Foundation and any income or property received or owned by it, and all transactions relating to such income or property, shall be exempt from all Federal, State, and local taxation with respect thereto. The Foundation may, however, in the discretion of the Board, contribute toward the costs of local government in amounts not in excess of those which it would be obligated to pay such government if it were not exempt from taxation by virtue of this subsection or by virtue of its being a charitable and nonprofit corporation and may agree so to contribute with respect to property transferred to it and the income derived therefrom if such agreement is a condition of the transfer. Contributions, gifts, and other transfers made to or for the use of the Foundation shall be regarded as contributions, gifts, or transfers to or for the use of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>