<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2124/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2124"><akn:num>2124</akn:num><akn:heading>Tourism Policy Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2124. Tourism Policy Council(a) EstablishmentIn order to ensure that the United States’ national interest in tourism is fully considered in Federal decision making, there is established a coordinating council to be known as the Tourism Policy Council (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).


(b) MembershipThe Council shall consist of the following individuals:(1) The Secretary of Commerce, who shall serve as the Chairman of the Council.

(2) The Under Secretary of Commerce for International Trade.

(3) The Director of the Office of Management and Budget.

(4) The Secretary of State.

(5) The Secretary of the Interior.

(6) The Secretary of Labor.

(7) The Secretary of Transportation.

(8) The Commissioner of the United States Customs Service.

(9) The President of the United States National Tourism Organization.

(10) The Commissioner of the Immigration and Naturalization Service.

(11) Representatives of other Federal agencies which have affected interests at each meeting as deemed appropriate and invited by the Chairman.


(c) No additional compensation for Council membersMembers of the Council shall serve without additional compensation.


(d) Council meetingsThe Council shall conduct its first meeting not later than 6 months after October 11, 1996. Thereafter the Council shall meet not less than 2 times each year.


(e) Involvement of Federal agencies and departments(1) The Council shall coordinate national policies and programs relating to international travel and tourism, recreation, and national heritage resources, which involve Federal agencies;

(2) The Council may request directly from any Federal department or agency such personnel, information, services, or facilities as deemed necessary by the Chairman and to the extent permitted by law and within the limits of available funds.

(3) Federal departments and agencies may, in their discretion, detail to temporary duty with the Council such personnel as the Chairman may request for carry</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to ensure that the United States’ national interest in tourism is fully considered in Federal decision making, there is established a coordinating council to be known as the Tourism Policy Council (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Council shall consist of the following individuals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>No additional compensation for Council members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) No additional compensation for Council members Members of the Council shall serve without additional compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Council meetings The Council shall conduct its first meeting not later than 6 months after October 11, 1996. Thereafter the Council shall meet not less than 2 times each year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Involvement of Federal agencies and departments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Involvement of Federal agencies and departments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Closed meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Closed meetings Where necessary to prevent the public disclosure of non-public information which may be presented by a Council member, the Council may hold, at the discretion of the Chairman, a closed meeting which may exclude any individual who is not an officer or employee of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual report The Council shall submit an annual report for the preceding fiscal year to the President for transmittal to the Congress on or before December 31 of each year. The report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2124_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5 The membership of the President of the United States National Tourism Organization on the Council shall not in itself make chapter 10 of title 5 applicable to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>