<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151b_2"><akn:num>2151b–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to combat HIV/AIDS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151b–2. Assistance to combat HIV/AIDS(a) FindingCongress recognizes that the alarming spread of HIV/AIDS in countries in sub-Saharan Africa, the Caribbean, Central Asia, Eastern Europe, Latin America and other developing countries is a major global health, national security, development, and humanitarian crisis.


(b) Policy(1) ObjectivesIt is a major objective of the foreign assistance program of the United States to provide assistance for the prevention and treatment of HIV/AIDS and the care of those affected by the disease. It is the policy objective of the United States, by 2013, to—(A) assist partner countries to—(i) prevent 12,000,000 new HIV infections worldwide;

(ii) support—(I) the increase in the number of individuals with HIV/AIDS receiving antiretroviral treatment above the goal established under section 7672(a)(3) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and increased pursuant to paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 7673(d) 1 of this title; and

(II) additional treatment through coordinated multilateral efforts;


(iii) support care for 12,000,000 individuals infected with or affected by HIV/AIDS, including 5,000,000 orphans and vulnerable children affected by HIV/AIDS, with an emphasis on promoting a comprehensive, coordinated system of services to be integrated throughout the continuum of care;

(iv) provide at least 80 percent of the target population with access to counseling, testing, and treatment to prevent the transmission of HIV from mother-to-child;

(v) provide care and treatment services to children with HIV in proportion to their percentage within the HIV-infected population of a given partner country; and

(vi) train and support retention of health care professionals, paraprofessionals, and community health workers in HIV/AIDS prevention, treatment, and care, with the target of providing such training to at least 140,000 new health care professionals and paraprofessionals with an emphasis on training and in country deployme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Finding Congress recognizes that the alarming spread of HIV/AIDS in countries in sub-Saharan Africa, the Caribbean, Central Asia, Eastern Europe, Latin America and other developing countries is a major global health, national security, development, and humanitarian crisis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Policy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities supported</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities supported Assistance provided under subsection (c) shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be used to carry out the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compacts and framework agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compacts and framework agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding limitation Of the funds made available to carry out this section in any fiscal year, not more than 7 percent may be used for the administrative expenses of the United States Agency for International Development in support of activities described in section 2151b(c) of this title, this section, section 2151b–3 of this title, and section 2151b–4 of this title. Such amount shall be in addition to other amounts otherwise available for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>