<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151b"><akn:num>2151b</akn:num><akn:heading>Population planning and health programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151b. Population planning and health programs(a) Congressional declaration of policyThe Congress recognizes that poor health conditions and uncontrolled population growth can vitiate otherwise successful development efforts.
Large families in developing countries are the result of complex social and economic factors which change relatively slowly among the poor majority least affected by economic progress, as well as the result of a lack of effective birth control. Therefore, effective family planning depends upon economic and social change as well as the delivery of services and is often a matter of political and religious sensitivity. While every country has the right to determine its own policies with respect to population growth, voluntary population planning programs can make a substantial contribution to economic development, higher living standards, and improved health and nutrition.
Good health conditions are a principal element in improved quality of life and contribute to the individual’s capacity to participate in the development process, while poor health and debilitating disease can limit productivity.


(b) Assistance for voluntary population planningIn order to increase the opportunities and motivation for family planning and to reduce the rate of population growth, the President is authorized to furnish assistance, on such terms and conditions as he may determine, for voluntary population planning. In addition to the provision of family planning information and services, including also information and services which relate to and support natural family planning methods, and the conduct of directly relevant demographic research, population planning programs shall emphasize motivation for small families.


(c) Assistance for health programs; special health needs of children and mothers; Child Survival Fund; promotion of immunization and oral rehydration; control of AIDS and tuberculosis(1) In order to contribute to improvements in the health of the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional declaration of policy The Congress recognizes that poor health conditions and uncontrolled population growth can vitiate otherwise successful development efforts.
Large families in developing countries are the result of complex social and economic factors which change relatively slowly among the poor majority least affected by economic progress, as well as the result of a lack of effective birth control. Therefore, effective family planning depends upon economic and social change as well as the delivery of services and is often a matter of political and religious sensitivity. While every country has the right to determine its own policies with respect to population growth, voluntary population planning programs can make a substantial contribution to economic development, higher living standards, and improved health and nutrition.
Good health conditions are a principal element in improved quality of life and contribute to the individual’s capacity to participate in the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for voluntary population planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance for voluntary population planning In order to increase the opportunities and motivation for family planning and to reduce the rate of population growth, the President is authorized to furnish assistance, on such terms and conditions as he may determine, for voluntary population planning. In addition to the provision of family planning information and services, including also information and services which relate to and support natural family planning methods, and the conduct of directly relevant demographic research, population planning programs shall emphasize motivation for small families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for health programs; special health needs of children and mothers; Child Survival Fund; promotion of immunization and oral rehydration; control of AIDS and tuberculosis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance for health programs; special health needs of children and mothers; Child Survival Fund; promotion of immunization and oral rehydration; control of AIDS and tuberculosis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and analysis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Research and analysis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds for performance or research respecting abortions or involuntary sterilization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on use of funds for performance or research respecting abortions or involuntary sterilization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>