<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151p–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151p–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151p–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151p_1"><akn:num>2151p–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Tropical forests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151p–1. Tropical forests(a) Importance of forests and tree coverIn enacting section 2151a(b)(3) of this title the Congress recognized the importance of forests and tree cover to the developing countries. The Congress is particularly concerned about the continuing and accelerating alteration, destruction, and loss of tropical forests in developing countries, which pose a serious threat to development and the environment. Tropical forest destruction and loss—(1) result in shortages of wood, especially wood for fuel; loss of biologically productive wetlands; siltation of lakes, reservoirs, and irrigation systems; floods; destruction of indigenous peoples; extinction of plant and animal species; reduced capacity for food production; and loss of genetic resources; and

(2) can result in desertification and destabilization of the earth’s climate.


Properly managed tropical forests provide a sustained flow of resources essential to the economic growth of developing countries, as well as genetic resources of value to developed and developing countries alike.

(b) PrioritiesThe concerns expressed in subsection (a) and the recommendations of the United States Interagency Task Force on Tropical Forests shall be given high priority by the President—(1) in formulating and carrying out programs and policies with respect to developing countries, including those relating to bilateral and multilateral assistance and those relating to private sector activities; and

(2) in seeking opportunities to coordinate public and private development and investment activities which affect forests in developing countries.


(c) Assistance to developing countriesIn providing assistance to developing countries, the President shall do the following:(1) Place a high priority on conservation and sustainable management of tropical forests.

(2) To the fullest extent feasible, engage in dialogues and exchanges of information with recipient countries—(A) which stress the importance of conserving and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Importance of forests and tree cover</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Importance of forests and tree cover In enacting section 2151a(b)(3) of this title the Congress recognized the importance of forests and tree cover to the developing countries. The Congress is particularly concerned about the continuing and accelerating alteration, destruction, and loss of tropical forests in developing countries, which pose a serious threat to development and the environment. Tropical forest destruction and loss— Properly managed tropical forests provide a sustained flow of resources essential to the economic growth of developing countries, as well as genetic resources of value to developed and developing countries alike.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priorities The concerns expressed in subsection (a) and the recommendations of the United States Interagency Task Force on Tropical Forests shall be given high priority by the President—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to developing countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to developing countries In providing assistance to developing countries, the President shall do the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>PVOs and other nongovernmental organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) PVOs and other nongovernmental organizations Whenever feasible, the President shall accomplish the objectives of this section through projects managed by private and voluntary organizations or international, regional, or national nongovernmental organizations which are active in the region or country where the project is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country analysis requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Country analysis requirements Each country development strategy statement or other country plan prepared by the Agency for International Development shall include an analysis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151p_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report Each annual report required by section 2394(a) of this title shall include a report on the implementation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>