<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151r"><akn:num>2151r</akn:num><akn:heading>Sahel development program; planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151r. Sahel development program; planning(a) Congressional supportThe Congress reaffirms its support of the initiative of the United States Government in undertaking consultations and planning with the countries concerned, with other nations providing assistance, with the United Nations, and with other concerned international and regional organizations, toward the development and support of a comprehensive long-term African Sahel development program.


(b) Presidential authorizationThe President is authorized to develop a long-term comprehensive development program for the Sahel and other drought-stricken nations in Africa.


(c) Presidential guidelinesIn developing this long-term program, the President shall—(1) consider international coordination for the planning and implementation of such program;

(2) seek greater participation and support by African countries and organizations in determining development priorities; and

(3) begin such planning immediately.


(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 120, formerly pt. III, § 639B, as added Pub. L. 93–189, § 20, Dec. 17, 1973, 87 Stat. 725; renumbered pt. I, § 494B and amended Pub. L. 94–161, title I, § 101(5), (7), Dec. 20, 1975, 89 Stat. 850; renumbered pt. I, § 120 and amended Pub. L. 95–88, title I, § 115(1), (2), Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 539; Pub. L. 95–424, title V, § 502(d)(1), Oct. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 959.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to sections 2292e and 2399–1b of this title.

Amendments1978—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 95–424 struck out subsec. (d) authorizing appropriations for development of a long-term African Sahel development program.
1977—Pub. L. 95–88, § 115(2), substituted “Sahel” for “African” in section catchline.
1975—Pub. L. 94–161, § 101(7)(A), struck out “Sahel” after “African” in section catchline.
Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 94–161, § 101(7)(B), (C), designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and substituted “Congress reaffirms its support of” for “Congress supports”.
Subsecs. (b)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional support The Congress reaffirms its support of the initiative of the United States Government in undertaking consultations and planning with the countries concerned, with other nations providing assistance, with the United Nations, and with other concerned international and regional organizations, toward the development and support of a comprehensive long-term African Sahel development program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presidential authorization The President is authorized to develop a long-term comprehensive development program for the Sahel and other drought-stricken nations in Africa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential guidelines In developing this long-term program, the President shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>