<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151y"><akn:num>2151y</akn:num><akn:heading>Accelerated loan repayments; annual review of countries with bilateral concessional loan balances; p</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151y. Accelerated loan repayments; annual review of countries with bilateral concessional loan balances; priority of determinations respecting negotiations with countries having balances; criteria for determinations
The Administrator of the agency primarily responsible for administering subchapter I of this chapter shall conduct an annual review of bilateral concessional loan balances and shall determine and identify those countries whose financial resources make possible accelerated loan repayments. In particular, European countries that were recipients of concessional loans by predecessor agencies to the agency primarily responsible for administering subchapter I of this chapter shall be contacted to negotiate accelerated repayments. The criteria used by the Administrator in making these determinations shall be established in conjunction with the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.
(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 127, as added Pub. L. 96–53, title V, § 508(a), Aug. 14, 1979, 93 Stat. 379.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
References to Subchapter I Deemed To Include Certain Parts of Subchapter IIReferences to subchapter I of this chapter are deemed to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, and references to subchapter II are deemed to exclude such parts. See section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226, set out as a note under section 2346 of this title, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title.

Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1979, see section 512(a) of Pub. L. 96–53, set out as an Effective Date of 1979 Amendment note under section 2151 of this title.

Negotiating Efforts Concerning Accelerated Loan Repayments To Be Included in Annual Reports on Foreign Assistance for 1980 and 1981Pub. L. 96–53, title V, § 508(b), Aug. 14, 1979, 93 Stat. 379, which related to loan repayment provisions in reports, wa</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>