<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151a"><akn:num>2151a</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural development in rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151a. Agricultural development in rural areas(a) Authorization to President to furnish assistance; appropriations(1) In recognition of the fact that the great majority of the people of developing countries live in rural areas and are dependent on agriculture and agricultural-related pursuits for their livelihood, the President is authorized to furnish assistance, on such terms and conditions as he may determine, for agriculture, rural development, and nutrition—(A) to alleviate starvation, hunger, and malnutrition;

(B) to expand significantly the provision of basic services to rural poor people to enhance their capacity for self-help; and

(C) to help create productive farm and off-farm employment in rural areas to provide a more viable economic base and enhance opportunities for improved incomes, living standards, and contributions by rural poor people to the economic and social development of their countries.


(2) There are authorized to be appropriated to the President for purposes of this section, in addition to funds otherwise available for such purposes, $760,000,000 for fiscal year 1986 and $760,000,000 for fiscal year 1987. Of these amounts, the President may use such amounts as he deems appropriate to carry out the provisions of section 316 of the International Security and Development Cooperation Act of 1980. Amounts appropriated under this section are authorized to remain available until expended.

(3) Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated in paragraph (2) for the fiscal year 1987, not less than $2,000,000 shall be available only for the purpose of controlling and eradicating amblyomma variegatum (heartwater) in bovine animals in the Caribbean.


(b) Use of assistance primarily in aid of rural poor; multilateral infrastructure projects; forestry proj­ects(1) Assistance provided under this section shall be used primarily for activities which are specifically designed to increase the productivity and income of the rural poor, through such means </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to President to furnish assistance; appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization to President to furnish assistance; appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of assistance primarily in aid of rural poor; multilateral infrastructure projects; forestry proj­ects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of assistance primarily in aid of rural poor; multilateral infrastructure projects; forestry proj­ects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased agricultural production in least developed countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Increased agricultural production in least developed countries The Congress finds that the greatest potential for significantly expanding availability of food for people in rural areas and augmenting world food production at relatively low cost lies in increasing the productivity of small farmers who constitute a majority of the agricultural producers in developing countries. Increasing the emphasis on rural development and expanded food production in the poorest nations of the developing world is a matter of social justice and a principal element contributing to broadly based economic growth, as well as an important factor in alleviating inflation in the industrialized countries. In the allocation of funds under this section, special attention shall be given to increasing agricultural production in countries which have been designated as “least developed” by the United Nations General Assembly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with population planning and health programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with population planning and health programs Assistance provided under this section shall also be used in coordination with programs carried out under section 2151b of this title to help improve nutrition of the people of developing countries through encouragement of increased production of crops with greater nutritional value; improvement of planning, research, and education with respect to nutrition, particularly with reference to improvement and expanded use of indigenously produced foodstuffs; and the undertaking of pilot or demonstration programs explicitly addressing the problem of malnutrition of poor and vulnerable people. In particular, the President is encouraged—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of local currency proceeds from sales of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of local currency proceeds from sales of commodities Local currency proceeds from sales of commodities provided under the Food for Peace Act [7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.] which are owned by foreign governments shall be used whenever practicable to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National food security policies and programs; bilateral and multilateral assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National food security policies and programs; bilateral and multilateral assistance The Congress finds that the efforts of developing countries to enhance their national food security deserves encouragement as a matter of United States development assistance policy. Measures complementary to assistance for expanding food production in developing countries are needed to help assure that food becomes increasingly available on a regular basis to the poor in such countries. Therefore, United States bilateral assistance under this chapter and the Food for Peace Act [7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.], and United States participation in multilateral institutions, shall emphasize policies and programs which assist developing countries to increase their national food security by improving their food policies and management and by strengthening national food reserves, with particular concern for the needs of the poor, through measures encouraging domestic production, building national food reserves, ex</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Fund for Agricultural Development; participation and contributions; availability of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) International Fund for Agricultural Development; participation and contributions; availability of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>