<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151t–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151t–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151t–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151t_1"><akn:num>2151t–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151t–1. Establishment of program(a) In generalIn carrying out part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.] and other relevant foreign assistance laws, the President, acting through the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall establish a program of training and other technical assistance to assist foreign countries in—(1) developing and strengthening laws and regulations to protect intellectual property; and

(2) developing the infrastructure necessary to implement and enforce such laws and regulations.


(b) Participation of other agenciesThe Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development—(1) shall utilize the expertise of the Patent and Trademark Office and other agencies of the United States Government in designing and implementing the program of assistance provided for in this section;

(2) shall coordinate assistance under this section with efforts of other agencies of the United States Government to increase international protection of intellectual property, including implementation of international agreements containing high levels of protection of intellectual property; and

(3) shall consult with the heads of such other agencies in determining which foreign countries will receive assistance under this section.


(Pub. L. 103–392, title V, § 501, Oct. 22, 1994, 108 Stat. 4103.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 87–195, Sept. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 424. Part I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 2151 et seq.) of this chapter. For provisions deeming references to subchapter I to include parts IV (§ 2346 et seq.), VI (§ 2348 et seq.), and VIII (§ 2349aa et seq.) of subchapter II of this chapter, see section 202(b) of Pub. L. 92–226, set out as a note under section 2346 of this title, and sections 2348c and 2349aa–5 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151t_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In carrying out part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.] and other relevant foreign assistance laws, the President, acting through the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall establish a program of training and other technical assistance to assist foreign countries in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151t_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participation of other agencies The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>