<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2151q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2151q"><akn:num>2151q</akn:num><akn:heading>Endangered species</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2151q. Endangered species(a) Congressional findings and purposesThe Congress finds the survival of many animal and plant species is endangered by over-hunting, by the presence of toxic chemicals in water, air and soil, and by the destruction of habitats. The Congress further finds that the extinction of animal and plant species is an irreparable loss with potentially serious environmental and economic consequences for developing and developed countries alike. Accordingly, the preservation of animal and plant species through the regulation of the hunting and trade in endangered species, through limitations on the pollution of natural ecosystems, and through the protection of wildlife habitats should be an important objective of the United States development assistance.


(b) Remedial measuresIn order to preserve biological diversity, the President is authorized to furnish assistance under subchapter I of this chapter, notwithstanding section 2420 of this title, to assist countries in protecting and maintaining wildlife habitats and in developing sound wildlife management and plant conservation programs. Special efforts should be made to establish and maintain wildlife sanctuaries, reserves, and parks; to enact and enforce anti-poaching measures; and to identify, study, and catalog animal and plant species, especially in tropical environments.


(c) Funding levelFor fiscal year 1987, not less than $2,500,000 of the funds available to carry out subchapter I of this chapter (excluding funds made available to carry out section 2151b(c)(2) of this title, relating to the Child Survival Fund) shall be allocated for assistance pursuant to subsection (b) for activities which were not funded prior to fiscal year 1987. In addition, the Agency for International Development shall, to the fullest extent possible, continue and increase assistance pursuant to subsection (b) for activities for which assistance was provided in fiscal years prior to fiscal year 1987.


(d) Country an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings and purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings and purposes The Congress finds the survival of many animal and plant species is endangered by over-hunting, by the presence of toxic chemicals in water, air and soil, and by the destruction of habitats. The Congress further finds that the extinction of animal and plant species is an irreparable loss with potentially serious environmental and economic consequences for developing and developed countries alike. Accordingly, the preservation of animal and plant species through the regulation of the hunting and trade in endangered species, through limitations on the pollution of natural ecosystems, and through the protection of wildlife habitats should be an important objective of the United States development assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedial measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Remedial measures In order to preserve biological diversity, the President is authorized to furnish assistance under subchapter I of this chapter, notwithstanding section 2420 of this title, to assist countries in protecting and maintaining wildlife habitats and in developing sound wildlife management and plant conservation programs. Special efforts should be made to establish and maintain wildlife sanctuaries, reserves, and parks; to enact and enforce anti-poaching measures; and to identify, study, and catalog animal and plant species, especially in tropical environments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding level</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding level For fiscal year 1987, not less than $2,500,000 of the funds available to carry out subchapter I of this chapter (excluding funds made available to carry out section 2151b(c)(2) of this title, relating to the Child Survival Fund) shall be allocated for assistance pursuant to subsection (b) for activities which were not funded prior to fiscal year 1987. In addition, the Agency for International Development shall, to the fullest extent possible, continue and increase assistance pursuant to subsection (b) for activities for which assistance was provided in fiscal years prior to fiscal year 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country analysis requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Country analysis requirements Each country development strategy statement or other country plan prepared by the Agency for International Development shall include an analysis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Local involvement To the fullest extent possible, projects supported under this section shall include close consultation with and involvement of local people at all stages of design and implementation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>PVOs and other nongovernmental organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) PVOs and other nongovernmental organizations Whenever feasible, the objectives of this section shall be accomplished through projects managed by appropriate private and voluntary organizations, or international, regional, or national nongovernmental organizations, which are active in the region or country where the project is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by AID</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Actions by AID The Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2151q_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual reports Each annual report required by section 2394(a) of this title shall include, in a separate volume, a report on the implementation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>