<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2152d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2152d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2152d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2152d"><akn:num>2152d</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to foreign countries to meet minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2152d. Assistance to foreign countries to meet minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking(a) AuthorizationThe President is authorized to provide assistance to foreign countries directly, or through nongovernmental and multilateral organizations, for programs, projects, and activities designed to meet the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking (as defined in section 7102 of this title), including—(1) the drafting of laws to prohibit and punish acts of trafficking;

(2) the investigation and prosecution of traffickers, including investigation of individuals and entities that may be involved in trafficking in persons involving sexual exploitation;

(3) the creation and maintenance of facilities, programs, projects, and activities for the protection of victims; and

(4) the expansion of exchange programs and international visitor programs for governmental and nongovernmental personnel to combat trafficking.


(b) FundingAmounts made available to carry out the other provisions of subchapter I of this chapter (including part IV of subchapter II of this chapter) and the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 [22 U.S.C. 5401 et seq.] shall be made available to carry out this section. Assistance may be provided under this section notwithstanding section 2420 of this title.


(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 134, as added Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 109, Oct. 28, 2000, 114 Stat. 1481; amended Pub. L. 108–193, § 6(f), Dec. 19, 2003, 117 Stat. 2883; Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 103(b), Dec. 23, 2008, 122 Stat. 5046.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 101–179, Nov. 28, 1989, 103 Stat. 1298, which is classified principally to chapter 63 (§ 5401 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5401 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2008—Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 110–457 inserted</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2152d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization The President is authorized to provide assistance to foreign countries directly, or through nongovernmental and multilateral organizations, for programs, projects, and activities designed to meet the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking (as defined in section 7102 of this title), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2152d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding Amounts made available to carry out the other provisions of subchapter I of this chapter (including part IV of subchapter II of this chapter) and the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 [22 U.S.C. 5401 et seq.] shall be made available to carry out this section. Assistance may be provided under this section notwithstanding section 2420 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>