<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2166" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2166/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2166/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2166"><akn:num>2166</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional development in Africa</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2166. Regional development in Africa
The President is requested to seek and to take appropriate action, in cooperation and consultation with African and other interested nations and with international development organizations, to further and assist in the advancement of African regional development institutions, including the African Development Bank, with the view toward promoting African economic development.
(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 206, as added Pub. L. 89–171, pt. I, § 102(b), Sept. 6, 1965, 79 Stat. 653.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
African Assistance Policy; Presidential Report to CongressPub. L. 93–559, § 49, Dec. 30, 1974, 88 Stat. 1816, which related to Presidential review and report on African assistance policy, was repealed by Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(8), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1560.

Portuguese African Territories of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau: Independence PolicyPub. L. 93–559, § 50, Dec. 30, 1974, 88 Stat. 1816, as amended by Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(8), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1560, provided that:
“(a)(1) Congress finds that the Government of Portugal’s recognition of the right to independence of the African territories of Angola, Mozambique, and Guinea-Bissau marks a significant advance toward the goal of self-determination for all the peoples of Africa, without which peace on the continent is not secure.

“(2) Congress finds that progress toward independence for the Portuguese African territories will have a significant impact on the international organizations and the community of nations.

“(3) Congress commends the Portuguese Government’s initiatives on these fronts as evidence of a reaffirmation of that Government’s support for her obligations under both the United Nations Charter and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.


“(b) Therefore, Congress calls upon the President and the Secretary of State to take the following actions designed to make clear United States support for a peaceful and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>