<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2185" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2185/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2185/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2185"><akn:num>2185</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade credit insurance program for Poland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2185. Trade credit insurance program for Poland(a) General authority(1) Assurance to Export-Import Bank of repaymentThe President is authorized to provide guarantees to the Bank for liabilities described in paragraph (2) in order to satisfy the requirement of section 2(b)(1)(B) of the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 (12 U.S.C. 635(b)(1)(B)) that the Bank have 11 So in original. Probably should be “has”. reasonable assurance of repayment.


(2) Liabilities which may be guaranteedThe liabilities that may be guaranteed under paragraph (1) are liabilities incurred by the Bank in connection with guarantees or insurance provided under the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [12 U.S.C. 635 et seq.] for financing for transactions involving the export of goods and services for the use of the private sector in Poland.



(b) Guarantees available only for short-term guarantees and insuranceGuarantees provided under subsection (a) shall be for short-term guarantees and insurance extended by the Bank which shall be repayable within a period not to exceed one year from the date of arrival at the port of importation of the goods and services covered by such guarantees or insurance.


(c) Agreement on criteria and proceduresGuarantees or insurance extended by the Bank and guaranteed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be provided by the Bank in accordance with criteria and procedures agreed to by the Administrator and the Bank.


(d) Reserve fundThe agreement referred to in subsection (c) shall also provide for the establishment of a reserve fund by the administering agency, with such funds made available to the reserve as the Administrator deems necessary to discharge liabilities under guarantees provided under subsection (a).


(e) Discharge of liabilities(1) Funds which may be usedSuch amounts of the funds made available to carry out part IV of subchapter II of this chapter (relating to the economic support fund) as the President determines are necessary may be made available to discha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guarantees available only for short-term guarantees and insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guarantees available only for short-term guarantees and insurance Guarantees provided under subsection (a) shall be for short-term guarantees and insurance extended by the Bank which shall be repayable within a period not to exceed one year from the date of arrival at the port of importation of the goods and services covered by such guarantees or insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement on criteria and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement on criteria and procedures Guarantees or insurance extended by the Bank and guaranteed pursuant to subsection (a) shall be provided by the Bank in accordance with criteria and procedures agreed to by the Administrator and the Bank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reserve fund The agreement referred to in subsection (c) shall also provide for the establishment of a reserve fund by the administering agency, with such funds made available to the reserve as the Administrator deems necessary to discharge liabilities under guarantees provided under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discharge of liabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discharge of liabilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations action required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appropriations action required Commitments to guarantee under subsection (a) are authorized only to the extent and in the amounts provided in advance in appropriations Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on outstanding commitments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on outstanding commitments The aggregate amount of outstanding commitments under subsection (a) may not exceed $200,000,000 of contingent liability for loan principal during any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Administrative and technical assistance The Bank shall provide, without reimbursement, such administrative and technical assistance to the administering agency as the Bank and the Administrator determine appropriate to assist the administering agency in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2185_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fees and premiums The Bank is authorized to charge fees and premiums, in connection with guarantees or insurance guaranteed by the administering agency under subsection (a), that are commensurate (in the judgment of the Bank) with the Bank’s administrative costs and the risks covered by the agency’s guarantees. Any amounts received by the Bank in excess of the estimated costs incurred by the Bank in administering such guarantees or insurance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>