<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2201"><akn:num>2201</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to disadvantaged children in Asia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2201. Assistance to disadvantaged children in Asia(a) Congressional findingsThe Congress recognizes the humanitarian needs of disadvantaged children in Asian countries where there has been or continues to be a heavy presence of United States military and related personnel in recent years. Moreover, the Congress finds that inadequate provision has been made for the care and welfare of such disadvantaged children, particularly those fathered by the 11 So in original. United States citizens.


(b) Authority of PresidentAccordingly, the President is authorized to expend up to $3,000,000 of funds made available under part I of this subchapter, in addition to funds otherwise available for such purposes, to help meet the needs of these disadvantaged children in Asia by assisting in the expansion and improvement of orphanages, hostels, day care centers, school feeding programs, and health, education, and welfare programs. Assistance provided under this section shall be furnished under the auspices of and by international organizations or private voluntary agencies operating within, and in cooperation with, the countries of Asia where these disadvantaged children reside.


(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 241, as added Pub. L. 95–424, title I, § 116, Oct. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 952; amended Pub. L. 99–83, title IX, § 903(a), Aug. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 268.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 2201, Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 241, Sept. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 433; Pub. L. 88–205, pt. I, § 105, Dec. 16, 1963, 77 Stat. 382, related to general authority of President respecting development research and use of funds for research into problems of population growth, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 94–161, title III, § 306(1), Dec. 20, 1975, 89 Stat. 858.

Amendments1985—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 99–83 substituted “$3,000,000” for “$2,000,000”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
References to Part I Deemed To Include Section 2293References to part I of this subchapter are deemed to include a re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings The Congress recognizes the humanitarian needs of disadvantaged children in Asian countries where there has been or continues to be a heavy presence of United States military and related personnel in recent years. Moreover, the Congress finds that inadequate provision has been made for the care and welfare of such disadvantaged children, particularly those fathered by the 11 So in original. United States citizens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of President Accordingly, the President is authorized to expend up to $3,000,000 of funds made available under part I of this subchapter, in addition to funds otherwise available for such purposes, to help meet the needs of these disadvantaged children in Asia by assisting in the expansion and improvement of orphanages, hostels, day care centers, school feeding programs, and health, education, and welfare programs. Assistance provided under this section shall be furnished under the auspices of and by international organizations or private voluntary agencies operating within, and in cooperation with, the countries of Asia where these disadvantaged children reside.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>