<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2213" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2213/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2213/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2213"><akn:num>2213</akn:num><akn:heading>United States Microfinance Loan Facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2213. United States Microfinance Loan Facility(a) EstablishmentThe President is authorized to establish a United States Microfinance Loan Facility (in this section referred to as the “Facility”) to pool and manage the risk from natural disasters, war or civil conflict, national financial crisis, or short-term financial movements that threaten the long-term development of United States-supported financial intermediaries.


(b) Disbursements(1) In generalThe Administrator shall make disbursements from the Facility to United States-supported financial intermediaries to prevent the bankruptcy of such institutions caused by—(A) natural disasters;

(B) national wars or civil conflict; or

(C) national financial crisis or other short-term financial movements that threaten the long-term development of United States-supported financial intermediaries.


(2) Form of assistanceAssistance under this section shall be in the form of loans or loan guarantees for financial intermediaries that demonstrate the capacity to resume self-sustained operations within a reasonable time period.


(3) Congressional notification proceduresDuring each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009, funds may not be made available from the Facility until 15 days after notification of the proposed availability of the funds has been provided to the congressional committees specified in section 2394–1 of this title in accordance with the procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under that section.



(c) General provisions(1) Policy provisionsIn providing the credit assistance authorized by this section, the Administrator should apply, as appropriate, the policy provisions in subchapter I of this chapter that are applicable to development assistance activities.


(2) Default and procurement provisions(A) Default provisionThe provisions of section 2370(q) of this title, or any comparable provision of law, shall not be construed to prohibit assistance to a country in the event that a private sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2213_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The President is authorized to establish a United States Microfinance Loan Facility (in this section referred to as the “Facility”) to pool and manage the risk from natural disasters, war or civil conflict, national financial crisis, or short-term financial movements that threaten the long-term development of United States-supported financial intermediaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2213_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disbursements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2213_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2213_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>