<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2220a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2220a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2220a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2220a"><akn:num>2220a</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2220a. General provisions(a) Congressional objectives and findingsThe Congress declares that, in order to achieve the mutual goals among nations of ensuring food security, human health, agricultural growth, trade expansion, and the wise and sustainable use of natural resources, the United States should mobilize the capacities of the United States land-grant universities, other eligible universities, and public and private partners of universities in the United States and other countries, consistent with sections 2151a and 2151a–1 of this title, for: (1) global research on problems affecting food, agriculture, forestry, and fisheries; (2) improved human capacity and institutional resource development for the global application of agricultural and related environmental sciences; (3) agricultural development and trade research and extension services in the United States and other countries to support the entry of rural industries into world markets; and (4) providing for the application of agricultural sciences to solving food, health, nutrition, rural income, and environmental problems, especially such problems in low-income, food deficit countries.
The Congress so declares because it finds—(A) that the establishment, endowment, and continuing support of land-grant universities in the United States by Federal, State, and county governments has led to agricultural progress with and through the private sector in this country and to understanding processes of economic development;

(B) that land-grant and other universities in the United States have demonstrated over many years their ability to cooperate with international agencies, educational and research institutions in other countries, the private sector, and nongovernmental organizations worldwide, in expanding global agricultural production, processing, business and trade, to the benefit of aid recipient countries and of the United States;

(C) that, in a world of growing populations with rising expectations, inc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional objectives and findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional objectives and findings The Congress declares that, in order to achieve the mutual goals among nations of ensuring food security, human health, agricultural growth, trade expansion, and the wise and sustainable use of natural resources, the United States should mobilize the capacities of the United States land-grant universities, other eligible universities, and public and private partners of universities in the United States and other countries, consistent with sections 2151a and 2151a–1 of this title, for: (1) global research on problems affecting food, agriculture, forestry, and fisheries; (2) improved human capacity and institutional resource development for the global application of agricultural and related environmental sciences; (3) agricultural development and trade research and extension services in the United States and other countries to support the entry of rural industries into world markets; and (4) providing for the application of agricultural sciences </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration for collation of components to increase world food production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional declaration for collation of components to increase world food production Accordingly, the Congress declares that, in order to prevent famine and establish freedom from hunger, the following components must be brought together in a coordinated program to increase world food and fiber production, agricultural trade, and responsible management of natural resources, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>University involvement, participation, and cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) University involvement, participation, and cooperation The United States should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Universities As used in this subpart, the term “universities” means those colleges or universities in each State, territory, or possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, now receiving, or which may hereafter receive, benefits under the Act of July 2, 1862 (known as the First Morrill Act) [7 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], or the Act of August 30, 1890 (known as the Second Morrill Act) [7 U.S.C. 321 et seq.], which are commonly known as “land-grant” universities; institutions now designated or which may hereafter be designated as sea-grant colleges under the Act of October 15, 1966 (known as the National Sea Grant College and Program Act) [33 U.S.C. 1121 et seq.], which are commonly known as sea-grant colleges; Native American land-grant colleges as authorized under the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (7 U.S.C. 301 note); and other United States colleges and universities which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrator As used in this subpart, the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public and private partners of universities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public and private partners of universities As used in this subpart, the term “public and private partners of universities” includes entities that have cooperative or contractual agreements with universities, which may include formal or informal associations of universities, other education institutions, United States Government and State agencies, private voluntary organizations, nongovernmental organizations, firms operated for profit, nonprofit organizations, multinational banks, and, as designated by the Administrator, any organization, institution, or agency incorporated in other countries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Agriculture As used in this subpart, the term “agriculture” includes the science and practice of activity related to food, feed, and fiber production, processing, marketing, distribution, utilization, and trade, and also includes family and consumer sciences, nutrition, food science and engineering, agricultural economics and other social sciences, forestry, wildlife, fisheries, aquaculture, floraculture, veterinary medicine, and other environmental and natural resources sciences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2220a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agriculturists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Agriculturists As used in this subpart, the term “agriculturists” includes farmers, herders, and livestock producers, individuals who fish and others employed in cultivating and harvesting food resources from salt and fresh waters, individuals who cultivate trees and shrubs and harvest nontimber forest products, as well as the processors, managers, teachers, extension specialists, researchers, policymakers, and others who are engaged in the food, feed, and fiber system and its relationships to natural resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>