<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2225" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2225/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2225/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2225"><akn:num>2225</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration of women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2225. Integration of women
The President is requested to instruct each representative of the United States to each international organization of which the United States is a member (including but not limited to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the Asian Development Bank, the Inter-American Development Bank, the International Monetary Fund, the United Nations, and the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development) to carry out their duties with respect to such organizations in such a manner as to encourage and promote the integration of women into the national economies of member and recipient countries and into professional and policy-making positions within such organizations, thereby improving the status of women. The President is further requested, in making United States contributions to such organizations, to take into account the progress, or lack of progress, of such organizations in adopting and implementing policies and practices which encourage and promote the integration of women into the national economies of member and recipient countries, and into professional and policy-making positions within such organizations, in accordance with the World Plan of Action of the Decade for Women.
(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 305, as added Pub. L. 93–559, § 54, Dec. 30, 1974, 88 Stat. 1818; amended Pub. L. 94–161, title III, § 313(b), Dec. 20, 1975, 89 Stat. 866; Pub. L. 95–88, title I, § 118(b), Aug. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 540.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1977—Pub. L. 95–88 inserted request that President, in making United States contributions, take into account the progress, or lack of progress, of organizations in adopting and implementing policies and practices which encourage and promote the integration of women into the national economies of member and recipient countries, and into professional and policy-making positions within such organizations, in accordance with the World Plan of Action of the Decade for Women.
1975—Pub. L. 94–16</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>