<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2228" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2228/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2228/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2228"><akn:num>2228</akn:num><akn:heading>International Muslim Youth Opportunity Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2228. International Muslim Youth Opportunity Fund(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to strengthen the public educational systems in predominantly Muslim countries by—(1) authorizing the establishment of an International Muslim Youth Educational Fund through which the United States dedicates resources, either through a separate fund or through an international organization, to assist those countries that commit to education reform; and

(2) providing resources for the Fund and to the President to help strengthen the public educational systems in those countries.


(b) Establishment of Fund(1) AuthorityThe President is authorized to establish an International Muslim Youth Opportunity Fund and to carry out programs consistent with paragraph (4) under existing authorities, including the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (commonly referred to as the “Fulbright-Hays Act”) [22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.].


(2) LocationThe Fund may be established—(A) as a separate fund in the Treasury; or

(B) through an international organization or international financial institution, such as the United Nations Educational, Science and Cultural Organization, the United Nations Development Program, or the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development.


(3) Transfers and receiptsThe head of any department, agency, or instrumentality of the United States Government may transfer any amount to the Fund, and the Fund may receive funds from private enterprises, foreign countries, or other entities.


(4) Activities of the FundThe Fund shall support programs described in this paragraph to improve the education environment in predominantly Muslim countries.(A) Assistance to enhance modern educational programs(i) The establishment in predominantly Muslim countries of a program of reform to create a modern education curriculum in the public educational systems in such countries.

(ii) The establishment or modernization of educational materials to advance a modern educa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2228_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to strengthen the public educational systems in predominantly Muslim countries by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2228_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>