<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2275" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2275/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2275/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2275"><akn:num>2275</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2275. Authorization of appropriations(a) Fiscal years 1988 and 1989In addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, for the purpose of furnishing nonmilitary assistance for Central American countries, $1,200,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1988 and 1989, which are authorized to remain available until expended.


(b) Transfer of fundsFor the purpose of providing the assistance described in subsection (a), funds appropriated pursuant to the authorizations in that subsection may be transferred by the President for obligation in accordance with the authorities of subchapter I of this chapter (including part IV of subchapter II of this chapter), the Peace Corps Act [22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.], the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 [22 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.], the United States Information and Education Exchange Act of 1948 [22 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.], the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.], the National Endowment for Democracy Act [22 U.S.C. 4411 et seq.], and the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956.


(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 465, as added Pub. L. 99–83, title VII, § 701, Aug. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 237.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Peace Corps Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 87–293, Sept. 22, 1961, 75 Stat. 612, which is classified principally to chapter 34 (§ 2501 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2501 of this title and Tables.
The Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962, referred to in subsec. (b), is Pub. L. 87–510, June 28, 1962, 76 Stat. 121, which is classified principally to chapter 36 (§ 2601 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2601 of this title and Tables.
The United States Information and Education Exchange Act of 1948, referred to in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2275_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal years 1988 and 1989</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fiscal years 1988 and 1989 In addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, for the purpose of furnishing nonmilitary assistance for Central American countries, $1,200,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1988 and 1989, which are authorized to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2275_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of funds For the purpose of providing the assistance described in subsection (a), funds appropriated pursuant to the authorizations in that subsection may be transferred by the President for obligation in accordance with the authorities of subchapter I of this chapter (including part IV of subchapter II of this chapter), the Peace Corps Act [22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.], the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 [22 U.S.C. 2601 et seq.], the United States Information and Education Exchange Act of 1948 [22 U.S.C. 1431 et seq.], the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.], the National Endowment for Democracy Act [22 U.S.C. 4411 et seq.], and the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>