<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2277a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2277a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2277a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2277a"><akn:num>2277a</akn:num><akn:heading>Targeted sanctions to fight corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,11 So in original. Honduras, and N</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2277a. Targeted sanctions to fight corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,11 So in original. Honduras, and Nicaragua(a) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(1) corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,1 Honduras, and Nicaragua by private citizens and select officials in local, regional, and Federal governments significantly damages the economies of such countries and deprives citizens of opportunities;

(2) corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,1 Honduras, and Nicaragua is facilitated and carried out not only by private citizens and select officials from those countries but also in many instances by individuals from third countries; and

(3) imposing targeted sanctions on individuals from throughout the world and particularly in the Western Hemisphere who are engaged in acts of significant corruption that impact El Salvador, Guatemala,,1 Honduras, and Nicaragua or obstruction of investigations into such acts of corruption will benefit the citizens and governments of such countries.


(b) Report requiredNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an unclassified report with classified annex if necessary that identifies each foreign person who the President determines to have knowingly engaged in actions that undermine democratic processes or institutions, or in significant corruption or obstruction of investigations into such acts of corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,1 Honduras, and Nicaragua, including the following:(1) Corruption related to government contracts.

(2) Bribery and extortion.

(3) The facilitation or transfer of the proceeds of corruption, including through money laundering.

(4) Acts of violence, harassment, or intimidation directed at governmental and nongovernmental corruption investigators.


(c) Imposition of sanctionsThe President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to each </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report required Not later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, and not less frequently than annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an unclassified report with classified annex if necessary that identifies each foreign person who the President determines to have knowingly engaged in actions that undermine democratic processes or institutions, or in significant corruption or obstruction of investigations into such acts of corruption in El Salvador, Guatemala,,1 Honduras, and Nicaragua, including the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Imposition of sanctions The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (d) with respect to each foreign person identified in the report required under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Sanctions described</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National security waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National security waiver The President may waive the application of the sanctions under subsection (c) 33 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (d)”. if the President—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination The authority to impose sanctions under subsection (b),44 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (c),”. and any sanctions imposed pursuant to such authority, shall expire on the date that is 3 years after December 27, 2020.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public availability The unclassified portion of the report required by subsection (b) shall be made available to the public, including through publication in the Federal Register. In any case in which the President concludes that such publication would be harmful to the national security of the United States, only a statement that a determination or finding has been made by the President, including the name and section of the Act under which it was made, shall be published.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2277a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>