<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2291"><akn:num>2291</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy, general authorities, coordination, foreign police actions, definitions, and other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2291. Policy, general authorities, coordination, foreign police actions, definitions, and other provisions(a) Policy and general authorities(1) Statements of policy(A) International narcotics trafficking poses an unparalleled transnational threat in today’s world, and its suppression is among the most important foreign policy objectives of the United States.

(B) Under the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs, 1961, and under the United Nations Convention Against Illicit Traffic in Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances, the parties are required to criminalize certain drug-related activities, provide appropriately severe penalties, and cooperate in the extradition of accused offenders.

(C) International narcotics control programs should include, as priority goals, the suppression of the illicit manufacture of and trafficking in narcotic and psychotropic drugs, money laundering, and precursor chemical diversion, and the progressive elimination of the illicit cultivation of the crops from which narcotic and psychotropic drugs are derived.

(D) International criminal activities, particularly international narcotics trafficking, money laundering, and corruption, endanger political and economic stability and democratic development, and assistance for the prevention and suppression of international criminal activities should be a priority for the United States.

(E) The international community should provide assistance, where appropriate, to those producer and transit countries which require assistance in discharging these primary obligations.

(F) The objective of the United States in dealing with the problem of international money laundering is to ensure that countries adopt comprehensive domestic measures against money laundering and cooperate with each other in narcotics money laundering investigations, prosecutions, and related forfeiture actions.

(G) Effective international cooperation is necessary to control the illicit cultivation, production, and smuggling</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy and general authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policy and general authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of all United States antinarcotics assistance to foreign countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination of all United States antinarcotics assistance to foreign countries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in foreign police actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participation in foreign police actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of herbicides for aerial eradication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of herbicides for aerial eradication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this part and other provisions of this chapter relating specifically to international narcotics matters—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>