<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2291g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2291g"><akn:num>2291g</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on acquisition of real property and construction of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2291g. Limitations on acquisition of real property and construction of facilities(a) Acquisition of real property(1) ProhibitionFunds made available to carry out this part may not be used to acquire (by purchase or other means) any land or other real property for use by foreign military, paramilitary, or law enforcement forces.


(2) Exception for certain leasesParagraph (1) shall not apply to the acquisition of real property by lease of a duration not to exceed 2 years.



(b) Construction of facilities(1) LimitationFunds made available to carry out this part may not be used for construction of facilities for use by foreign military, paramilitary, or law enforcement forces unless, at least 15 days before obligating funds for such construction, the President notifies the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with procedures applicable to reprogramming notifications under section 2394–1 of this title.


(2) ExceptionParagraph (1) shall not apply to the construction of facilities which would require the obligation of less than $750,000 under this part.



(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. I, § 488, as added Pub. L. 100–690, title IV, § 4505, Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4285; amended Pub. L. 102–583, § 4(g), Nov. 2, 1992, 106 Stat. 4917; Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title VI, § 671(3), Sept. 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 1407.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2002—Subsec.(a)(3). Pub. L. 107–228 struck out heading and text of par. (3). Text read as follows: “The Secretary of State shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate within 30 days after the end of each quarter of the fiscal year a detailed report on all leases entered into pursuant to paragraph (2), including the cost and duration of such lease, a description of the property leased, and the purpose for which such lease was entered into.”
1992—Pub. L. 102–583 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “Funds made a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acquisition of real property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2291g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>