<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2295b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2295b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2295b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2295b"><akn:num>2295b</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities relating to assistance and other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2295b. Authorities relating to assistance and other provisions(a) Assistance through governments and nongovernmental organizationsAssistance under this part may be provided to governments or through nongovernmental organizations.


(b) Technical and managerial assistanceTechnical assistance under this part shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be provided on a long term, on-site basis and shall emphasize the provision of practical, management and other problem-solving advice, particularly advice on private enterprise provided by United States business volunteers.


(c) Enterprise fundsActivities supported pursuant to this part may include the establishment of and the provision of support for one or more enterprise funds for the independent states of the former Soviet Union. If the President determines that an enterprise fund should be established and supported under this part, the provisions contained in section 201 of the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 [22 U.S.C. 5421] (excluding the authorizations of appropriations provided in subsection (b) of that section) shall be deemed to apply with respect to such enterprise fund and to funds made available to such enterprise fund pursuant to this part.


(d) Cooperative development and research projectsAssistance under this part may include support for cooperative development projects, including cooperative development research projects, among the United States, other countries, and independent states of the former Soviet Union.


(e) Administration of justice programsIn order to strengthen the administration of justice in the independent states of the former Soviet Union under paragraph (2)(J) of section 2295 of this title, the President may exercise the same authorities as are available under section 2346c of this title, subject to the limitations and requirements of that section, other than subsection (c) and the last two sentences of subsection (e).


(f) Use of economic support fundsAny funds</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance through governments and nongovernmental organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assistance through governments and nongovernmental organizations Assistance under this part may be provided to governments or through nongovernmental organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical and managerial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Technical and managerial assistance Technical assistance under this part shall, to the maximum extent feasible, be provided on a long term, on-site basis and shall emphasize the provision of practical, management and other problem-solving advice, particularly advice on private enterprise provided by United States business volunteers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enterprise funds Activities supported pursuant to this part may include the establishment of and the provision of support for one or more enterprise funds for the independent states of the former Soviet Union. If the President determines that an enterprise fund should be established and supported under this part, the provisions contained in section 201 of the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 [22 U.S.C. 5421] (excluding the authorizations of appropriations provided in subsection (b) of that section) shall be deemed to apply with respect to such enterprise fund and to funds made available to such enterprise fund pursuant to this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative development and research projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative development and research projects Assistance under this part may include support for cooperative development projects, including cooperative development research projects, among the United States, other countries, and independent states of the former Soviet Union.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of justice programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administration of justice programs In order to strengthen the administration of justice in the independent states of the former Soviet Union under paragraph (2)(J) of section 2295 of this title, the President may exercise the same authorities as are available under section 2346c of this title, subject to the limitations and requirements of that section, other than subsection (c) and the last two sentences of subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of economic support funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of economic support funds Any funds that have been allocated under part 4 of subchapter II of this chapter for assistance for the independent states of the former Soviet Union may be used in accordance with the provisions of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of SEED agency funds and administrative authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of SEED agency funds and administrative authorities The President may authorize any agency of the United States Government that has authority to conduct activities under the Support for East European Democracy (SEED) Act of 1989 [22 U.S.C. 5401 et seq.] to use— to conduct activities authorized by section 2295 of this title with respect to the independent states of the former Soviet Union.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procurement restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Procurement restrictions Funds made available for assistance under this part may be used for procurement—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Terms and conditions Assistance under this part shall be provided on such terms and conditions as the President may determine, consistent with applicable provisions of law (except as otherwise provided in subsection (j)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2295b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of certain provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Waiver of certain provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>