<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2304" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2304/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2304/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2304"><akn:num>2304</akn:num><akn:heading>Human rights and security assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2304. Human rights and security assistance(a) Observance of human rights as principal goal of foreign policy; implementation requirements(1) The United States shall, in accordance with its international obligations as set forth in the Charter of the United Nations and in keeping with the constitutional heritage and traditions of the United States, promote and encourage increased respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms throughout the world without distinction as to race, sex, language, or religion. Accordingly, a principal goal of the foreign policy of the United States shall be to promote the increased observance of internationally recognized human rights by all countries.

(2) Except under circumstances specified in this section, no security assistance may be provided to any country the government of which engages in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights. Security assistance may not be provided to the police, domestic intelligence, or similar law enforcement forces of a country, and licenses may not be issued under the Export Administration Act of 1979 for the export of crime control and detection instruments and equipment to a country, the government of which engages in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights unless the President certifies in writing to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the chairman of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate (when licenses are to be issued pursuant to the Export Administration Act of 1979).11 So in original. The period probably should not appear. that extraordinary circumstances exist warranting provision of such assistance and issuance of such licenses. Assistance may not be provided under part V of this subchapter to a country the government of which engages in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Observance of human rights as principal goal of foreign policy; implementation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Observance of human rights as principal goal of foreign policy; implementation requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by Secretary of State on practices of proposed recipient countries; considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report by Secretary of State on practices of proposed recipient countries; considerations The Secretary of State shall transmit to the Congress, as part of the presentation materials for security assistance programs proposed for each fiscal year, a full and complete report, prepared with the assistance of the Assistant Secretary of State for Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor and with the assistance of the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom, with respect to practices regarding the observance of and respect for internationally recognized human rights in each country proposed as a recipient of security assistance. Wherever applicable, such report shall include consolidated information regarding the commission of war crimes, crimes against humanity, and evidence of acts that may constitute genocide (as defined in article 2 of the Convention on the Prevention and Punishment of the Crime of Genocide and modified by the United States instrument of ratification to tha</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional request for information; information required; 30-day period; failure to supply information; termination or restriction of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Congressional request for information; information required; 30-day period; failure to supply information; termination or restriction of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal of prohibition on assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Removal of prohibition on assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds authorized to be appropriated under subchapter I of this chapter may be made available for the furnishing of assistance to any country with respect to which the President finds that such a significant improvement in its human rights record has occurred as to warrant lifting the prohibition on furnishing such assistance in the national interest of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations concerned with performance record of recipient countries without contravention of other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocations concerned with performance record of recipient countries without contravention of other provisions In allocating the funds authorized to be appropriated by this chapter and the Arms Export Control Act [22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.], the President shall take into account significant improvements in the human rights records of recipient countries, except that such allocations may not contravene any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress on use of certain authorities relating to human rights conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report to Congress on use of certain authorities relating to human rights conditions Whenever the provisions of subsection (e) or (f) of this section are applied, the President shall report to the Congress before making any funds available pursuant to those subsections. The report shall specify the country involved, the amount and kinds of assistance to be provided, and the justification for providing the assistance, including a description of the significant improvements which have occurred in the country’s human rights record.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on practices of recipient countries relating to trafficking in persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report on practices of recipient countries relating to trafficking in persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>44 So in original. Two subsecs. (i) have been enacted. Report on status of freedom of the press in recipient countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) The report required by subsection (b) shall include, wherever applicable—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2304_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>4 Child marriage status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>