<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2323" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2323/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2323/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2323"><akn:num>2323</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of defense articles or services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2323. Transfer of defense articles or services(a) Notice to CongressNotwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds available to the Department of Defense for the current fiscal year and hereafter may be obligated or expended to transfer to another nation or an international organization any defense articles or services (other than intelligence services) for use in the activities described in subsection (b) unless the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate are notified 15 days in advance of such transfer.


(b) Activities affectedThis section applies to—(1) any international peacekeeping or peace-enforcement operation under the authority of chapter VI or chapter VII of the United Nations Charter under the authority of a United Nations Security Council resolution; and

(2) any other international peacekeeping, peace-enforcement, or humanitarian assistance operation.


(c) Contents of noticeA notice under subsection (a) shall include the following:(1) A description of the equipment, supplies, or services to be transferred.

(2) A statement of the value of the equipment, supplies, or services to be transferred.

(3) In the case of a proposed transfer of equipment or supplies—(A) a statement of whether the inventory requirements of all elements of the Armed Forces (including the reserve components) for the type of equipment or supplies to be transferred have been met; and

(B) a statement of whether the items proposed to be transferred will have to be replaced and, if so, how the President proposes to provide funds for such replacement.



(Pub. L. 113–235, div. C, title VIII, § 8050, Dec. 16, 2014, 128 Stat. 2264.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2015, and also as part of the Consolidated and Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2015, and not as part of the Foreign </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2323_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to Congress Notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds available to the Department of Defense for the current fiscal year and hereafter may be obligated or expended to transfer to another nation or an international organization any defense articles or services (other than intelligence services) for use in the activities described in subsection (b) unless the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate are notified 15 days in advance of such transfer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2323_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities affected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities affected This section applies to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2323_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of notice A notice under subsection (a) shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>