<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2348a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2348a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2348a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2348a"><akn:num>2348a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2348a. Authorization of appropriations(a) Fiscal years 1986 and 1987There are authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out the purposes of this part, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, $37,000,000 for fiscal year 1986 and $37,000,000 for fiscal year 1987.


(b) Availability of fundsAmounts appropriated under this section are authorized to remain available until expended.


(c) Emergency transfer of fundsIf the President determines that, as the result of an unforeseen emergency, the provision of assistance under this part in amounts in excess of funds otherwise available for such assistance is important to the national interests of the United States, the President may (1) exercise the authority of section 2360(a) of this title to transfer funds available to carry out part IV of this subchapter for use under this part without regard to the 20-percent increase limitation contained in such section, except that the total amount so transferred in any fiscal year may not exceed $15,000,000; and (2) in the event the President also determines that such unforeseen emergency requires the immediate provision of assistance under this part, direct the drawdown of commodities and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government of an aggregate value not to exceed $25,000,000 in any fiscal year. In addition to the aggregate value of $25,000,000 authorized in paragraph (2) of the preceding sentence, the President may direct the drawdown of commodities and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government for the purposes of providing necessary and immediate assistance to Taiwan of a value not to exceed $25,000,000 in any fiscal year.


(d) Reimbursement of applicable appropriation, fund, or accountThere are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the applicable appropriation, fund, or account for commodities and se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal years 1986 and 1987</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fiscal years 1986 and 1987 There are authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out the purposes of this part, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, $37,000,000 for fiscal year 1986 and $37,000,000 for fiscal year 1987.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of funds Amounts appropriated under this section are authorized to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emergency transfer of funds If the President determines that, as the result of an unforeseen emergency, the provision of assistance under this part in amounts in excess of funds otherwise available for such assistance is important to the national interests of the United States, the President may (1) exercise the authority of section 2360(a) of this title to transfer funds available to carry out part IV of this subchapter for use under this part without regard to the 20-percent increase limitation contained in such section, except that the total amount so transferred in any fiscal year may not exceed $15,000,000; and (2) in the event the President also determines that such unforeseen emergency requires the immediate provision of assistance under this part, direct the drawdown of commodities and services from the inventory and resources of any agency of the United States Government of an aggregate value not to exceed $25,000,000 in any fiscal year. In addition to the aggregate value </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2348a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of applicable appropriation, fund, or account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement of applicable appropriation, fund, or account There are authorized to be appropriated to the President such sums as may be necessary to reimburse the applicable appropriation, fund, or account for commodities and services provided under subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>