<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349bb–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349bb–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349bb–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2349bb_4"><akn:num>2349bb–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2349bb–4. Authorization of appropriations(a) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this part $162,000,000 for fiscal year 2003.


(b) Availability of fundsFunds made available under subsection (a) may be used notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than section 2304 or 2371 of this title) and shall remain available until expended.


(c) Treatment of appropriationsAmounts made available by the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002, under “Nonproliferation, Antiterrorism, Demining, and Related Programs” and “Assistance for the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union” accounts for the activities described in subsection (d) shall be considered to be made available pursuant to this part.


(d) Covered activitiesThe activities referred to in subsection (c) are—(1) assistance under the Nonproliferation and Disarmament Fund;

(2) assistance for science and technology centers in the independent states of the former Soviet Union;

(3) export control assistance; and

(4) export control and border assistance under part XI of subchapter I of this chapter or the FREEDOM Support Act (22 U.S.C. 5801 et seq.).


(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. II, § 586, formerly § 585, as added Pub. L. 106–280, title III, § 301, Oct. 6, 2000, 114 Stat. 852; renumbered § 586 and amended Pub. L. 107–228, div. B, title XIII, §§ 1301(a), 1303(1), Sept. 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 1435, 1436.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002, referred to in subsec. (c), is Pub. L. 107–115, Jan. 10, 2002, 115 Stat. 2118, also known as the Kenneth M. Ludden Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, Fiscal Year 2002. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Tables.
The FREEDOM Support Act, referred to in subsec. (d)(4), is Pub. L. 102–511, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3320, also</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349bb_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the President to carry out this part $162,000,000 for fiscal year 2003.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349bb_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of funds Funds made available under subsection (a) may be used notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than section 2304 or 2371 of this title) and shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349bb_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of appropriations Amounts made available by the Foreign Operations, Export Financing, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2002, under “Nonproliferation, Antiterrorism, Demining, and Related Programs” and “Assistance for the Independent States of the Former Soviet Union” accounts for the activities described in subsection (d) shall be considered to be made available pursuant to this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349bb_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Covered activities The activities referred to in subsection (c) are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>