<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349aa–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349aa–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2349aa–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2349aa_9"><akn:num>2349aa–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Ban on importing goods and services from countries supporting terrorism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2349aa–9. Ban on importing goods and services from countries supporting terrorism(a) AuthorityThe President may ban the importation into the United States of any good or service from any country which supports terrorism or terrorist organizations or harbors terrorists or terrorist organizations.


(b) ConsultationThe President, in every possible instance, shall consult with the Congress before exercising the authority granted by this section and shall consult regularly with the Congress so long as that authority is being exercised.


(c) ReportsWhenever the President exercises the authority granted by this section, he shall immediately transmit to the Congress a report specifying—(1) the country with respect to which the authority is to be exercised and the imports to be prohibited;

(2) the circumstances which necessitate the exercise of such authority;

(3) why the President believes those circumstances justify the exercise of such authority; and

(4) why the President believes the prohibitions are necessary to deal with those circumstances.


At least once during each succeeding 6-month period after transmitting a report pursuant to this subsection, the President shall report to the Congress with respect to the actions taken, since the last such report, pursuant to this section and with respect to any changes which have occurred concerning any information previously furnished pursuant to this subsection.

(d) “United States” definedFor purposes of this section, the term “United States” includes territories and possessions of the United States.


(Pub. L. 99–83, title V, § 505, Aug. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 221.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the International Security and Development Cooperation Act of 1985, and not as part of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1985, see section 1301 of Pub. L. 99–83, set out as an Effective Da</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349aa_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The President may ban the importation into the United States of any good or service from any country which supports terrorism or terrorist organizations or harbors terrorists or terrorist organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349aa_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation The President, in every possible instance, shall consult with the Congress before exercising the authority granted by this section and shall consult regularly with the Congress so long as that authority is being exercised.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349aa_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports Whenever the President exercises the authority granted by this section, he shall immediately transmit to the Congress a report specifying— At least once during each succeeding 6-month period after transmitting a report pursuant to this subsection, the President shall report to the Congress with respect to the actions taken, since the last such report, pursuant to this section and with respect to any changes which have occurred concerning any information previously furnished pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2349aa_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“United States” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “United States” defined For purposes of this section, the term “United States” includes territories and possessions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>