<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2370" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2370/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2370/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2370"><akn:num>2370</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions against furnishing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2370. Prohibitions against furnishing assistance(a) Cuba; embargo on all trade(1) No assistance shall be furnished under this chapter to the present government of Cuba. As an additional means of implementing and carrying into effect the policy of the preceding sentence, the President is authorized to establish and maintain a total embargo upon all trade between the United States and Cuba.

(2) Except as may be deemed necessary by the President in the interest of the United States, no assistance shall be furnished under this chapter to any government of Cuba, nor shall Cuba be entitled to receive any quota authorizing the importation of Cuban sugar into the United States or to receive any other benefit under any law of the United States, until the President determines that such government has taken appropriate steps according to international law standards to return to United States citizens, and to entities not less than 50 per centum beneficially owned by United States citizens, or to provide equitable compensation to such citizens and entities for property taken from such citizens and entities on or after January 1, 1959, by the Government of Cuba.


(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(1), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1560

(c) Indebtedness of foreign country to United States citizen or personNo assistance shall be provided under this chapter to the government of any country which is indebted to any United States citizen or person for goods or services furnished or ordered where (i) such citizen or person has exhausted available legal remedies, which shall include arbitration, or (ii) the debt is not denied or contested by such government, or (iii) such indebtedness arises under an unconditional guaranty of payment given by such government, or any predecessor government, directly or indirectly, through any controlled entity: Provided, That the President does not find such action contrary to the national security.


(d) Productive enterprises competing w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cuba; embargo on all trade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cuba; embargo on all trade</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(1), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1560</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indebtedness of foreign country to United States citizen or person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indebtedness of foreign country to United States citizen or person No assistance shall be provided under this chapter to the government of any country which is indebted to any United States citizen or person for goods or services furnished or ordered where (i) such citizen or person has exhausted available legal remedies, which shall include arbitration, or (ii) the debt is not denied or contested by such government, or (iii) such indebtedness arises under an unconditional guaranty of payment given by such government, or any predecessor government, directly or indirectly, through any controlled entity: Provided, That the President does not find such action contrary to the national security.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Productive enterprises competing with United States enterprise; conditions on assistance; import controls; waiver of restriction by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Productive enterprises competing with United States enterprise; conditions on assistance; import controls; waiver of restriction by President No assistance shall be furnished on a loan basis under part I of subchapter I of this chapter for construction or operation of any productive enterprise in any country where such enterprise will compete with United States enterprise unless such country has agreed that it will establish appropriate procedures to prevent the exportation for use or consumption in the United States of more than twenty per centum of the annual production of such facility during the life of the loan. In case of failure to implement such agreement by the other contracting party, the President is authorized to establish necessary import controls to effectuate the agreement. The restrictions imposed by or pursuant to this subsection may be waived by the President where he determines that such waiver is in the national security interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nationalization, expropriation or seizure of property of United States citizens, or taxation or other exaction having same effect; failure to compensate or to provide relief from taxes, exactions, or conditions; report on full value of property by Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; act of state doctrine</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nationalization, expropriation or seizure of property of United States citizens, or taxation or other exaction having same effect; failure to compensate or to provide relief from taxes, exactions, or conditions; report on full value of property by Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; act of state doctrine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against assistance to Communist countries; conditions for waiver of restriction by President; enumeration of Communist countries; removal from application of provisions; preconditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition against assistance to Communist countries; conditions for waiver of restriction by President; enumeration of Communist countries; removal from application of provisions; preconditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of assistance funds to compensate owners for expropriated or nationalized property; waiver for land reform programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of assistance funds to compensate owners for expropriated or nationalized property; waiver for land reform programs Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no monetary assistance shall be made available under this chapter to any government or political subdivision or agency of such government which will be used to compensate owners for expropriated or nationalized property and, upon finding by the President that such assistance has been used by any government for such purpose, no further assistance under this chapter shall be furnished to such government until appropriate reimbursement is made to the United States for sums so diverted. This prohibition shall not apply to monetary assistance made available for use by a government (or a political subdivision or agency of a government) to compensate nationals of that country in accordance with a land reform program, if the President determines that monetary assistance for such land reform program will further the national inte</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and procedures to insure aid is not used contrary to the best interests of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations and procedures to insure aid is not used contrary to the best interests of the United States The President shall adopt regulations and establish procedures to insure that United States foreign aid is not used in a manner which, contrary to the best interests of the United States, promotes or assists the foreign aid projects or activities of any country that is a Communist country for purposes of subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–113, title VII, § 734(a)(1), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1560</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2370_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Damage or destruction by mob action of United States property; termination of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Damage or destruction by mob action of United States property; termination of assistance The President shall consider terminating assistance under this chapter or any other Act to any country which permits, or fails to take adequate measures to prevent, the damage or destruction by mob action of United States property within such country, and fails to take appropriate measures to prevent a recurrence thereof and to provide adequate compensation for such damage or destruction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>