<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2371"><akn:num>2371</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on assistance to governments supporting international terrorism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2371. Prohibition on assistance to governments supporting international terrorism(a) ProhibitionThe United States shall not provide any assistance under this chapter, the Food for Peace Act [7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.], the Peace Corps Act [22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.], or the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [12 U.S.C. 635 et seq.] to any country if the Secretary of State determines that the government of that country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.


(b) Publication of determinationsEach determination of the Secretary of State under subsection (a), including each determination in effect on December 12, 1989, shall be published in the Federal Register.


(c) RescissionA determination made by the Secretary of State under subsection (a) may not be rescinded unless the President submits to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate—(1) before the proposed rescission would take effect, a report certifying that—(A) there has been a fundamental change in the leadership and policies of the government of the country concerned;

(B) that government is not supporting acts of international terrorism; and

(C) that government has provided assurances that it will not support acts of international terrorism in the future; or


(2) at least 45 days before the proposed rescission would take effect, a report justifying the rescission and certifying that—(A) the government concerned has not provided any support for international terrorism during the preceding 6-month period; and

(B) the government concerned has provided assurances that it will not support acts of international terrorism in the future.



(d) WaiverAssistance prohibited by subsection (a) may be provided to a country described in that subsection if—(1) the President determines that national security interests or humanitarian reasons justify a waiver of subsection (a), except that humanitarian reasons may not be used to ju</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition The United States shall not provide any assistance under this chapter, the Food for Peace Act [7 U.S.C. 1691 et seq.], the Peace Corps Act [22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.], or the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 [12 U.S.C. 635 et seq.] to any country if the Secretary of State determines that the government of that country has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Publication of determinations Each determination of the Secretary of State under subsection (a), including each determination in effect on December 12, 1989, shall be published in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rescission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rescission A determination made by the Secretary of State under subsection (a) may not be rescinded unless the President submits to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2371_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver Assistance prohibited by subsection (a) may be provided to a country described in that subsection if— The waiver authority granted in this subsection may not be used to provide any assistance under this chapter which is also prohibited by section 2780 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>