<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2393a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2393a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2393a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2393a"><akn:num>2393a</akn:num><akn:heading>Requests by Government Accountability Office and Congressional committees for documents and material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2393a. Requests by Government Accountability Office and Congressional committees for documents and materials
None of the funds made available pursuant to the provisions of this chapter shall be used to carry out any provision of this chapter in any country or with respect to any project or activity, after the expiration of the thirty-five-day period which begins on the date the Government Accountability Office or any committee of the Congress charged with considering legislation, appropriations or expenditures under this chapter, has delivered to the office of the head of any agency carrying out such provision, a written request that it be furnished any document, paper, communication, audit, review, finding, recommendation, report, or other material in its custody or control relating to the administration of such provision in such country or with respect to such project or activity, unless and until there has been furnished to the Government Accountability Office, or to such committee, as the case may be, (1) the document, paper, communication, audit, review, finding, recommendation, report, or other material so requested, or (2) a certification by the President that he has forbidden the furnishing thereof pursuant to request and his reason for so doing.
(Pub. L. 87–195, pt. III, § 633A, as added Pub. L. 95–424, title V, § 502(a)(1), Oct. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 957; amended Pub. L. 108–271, § 8(b), July 7, 2004, 118 Stat. 814.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 87–195, Sept. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 424, known as the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2151 of this title and Tables.

Codification
This section was formerly classified to subsec. (c) of section 2394 of this title prior to the complete revision of section 2394 of this title by Pub. L. 95–424, title V, § 502(a)(2), Oct. 6, 1978, 92 Stat. 95</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>