<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2395" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2395/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2395/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2395"><akn:num>2395</akn:num><akn:heading>General authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2395. General authorities(a) Manner of furnishing assistance; emphasis on loansExcept as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, assistance under this chapter may be furnished on a grant basis or on such terms, including cash, credit, or other terms of repayment (including repayment in foreign currencies or by transfer to the United States Government of commodities) as may be determined to be best suited to the achievement of the purposes of this chapter, and shall emphasize loans rather than grants wherever possible.


(b) Authority of the PresidentThe President may make loans, advances, and grants to, make and perform agreements and contracts with, or enter into other transactions with, any individual, corporation, or other body of persons, friendly government or government agency, whether within or without the United States, and international organizations in furtherance of the purposes and within the limitations of this chapter.


(c) Utilization of services and facilities of voluntary, nonprofit organizationsIt is the sense of Congress that the President, in furthering the purposes of this chapter, shall use to the maximum extent practicable the services and facilities of voluntary, nonprofit organizations registered with, and approved by, the Agency for International Development.


(d) Acceptance of gifts, devises, bequests, grants, etc.The President may accept and use in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, money, funds, property, and services of any kind made available by gift, devise, bequest, grant, or otherwise for such purpose.


(e) Health and accident insurance for foreign participants and foreign employees(1) Any agency of the United States Government is authorized to pay the cost of health and accident insurance for foreign participants in any program of furnishing technical information and assistance administered by such agency while such participants are absent from their homes for the purpose of participation in such program.

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of furnishing assistance; emphasis on loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Manner of furnishing assistance; emphasis on loans Except as otherwise specifically provided in this chapter, assistance under this chapter may be furnished on a grant basis or on such terms, including cash, credit, or other terms of repayment (including repayment in foreign currencies or by transfer to the United States Government of commodities) as may be determined to be best suited to the achievement of the purposes of this chapter, and shall emphasize loans rather than grants wherever possible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of the President The President may make loans, advances, and grants to, make and perform agreements and contracts with, or enter into other transactions with, any individual, corporation, or other body of persons, friendly government or government agency, whether within or without the United States, and international organizations in furtherance of the purposes and within the limitations of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of services and facilities of voluntary, nonprofit organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Utilization of services and facilities of voluntary, nonprofit organizations It is the sense of Congress that the President, in furthering the purposes of this chapter, shall use to the maximum extent practicable the services and facilities of voluntary, nonprofit organizations registered with, and approved by, the Agency for International Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of gifts, devises, bequests, grants, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Acceptance of gifts, devises, bequests, grants, etc. The President may accept and use in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter, money, funds, property, and services of any kind made available by gift, devise, bequest, grant, or otherwise for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health and accident insurance for foreign participants and foreign employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Health and accident insurance for foreign participants and foreign employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission of alien participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Admission of alien participants Alien participants in any program of furnishing technical information and assistance under this chapter may be admitted to the United States if otherwise qualified as nonimmigrants under section 1101(a)(15) of title 8, for such time and under such conditions as may be prescribed by regulations promulgated by the Secretary of State and the Attorney General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers and authorities of the President with respect to loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Powers and authorities of the President with respect to loans In making loans under this chapter, the President—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of contracts and agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Term of contracts and agreements A contract or agreement which entails commitments for the expenditure of funds made available under part I (except development loans) and subpart II of part II of subchapter I and under subchapter II of this chapter, may, subject to any future action of the Congress, extend at any time for not more than five years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement and arbitration of claims arising under investment guaranty operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Settlement and arbitration of claims arising under investment guaranty operations Claims arising as a result of investment guaranty operations may be settled, and disputes arising as a result thereof may be arbitrated with the consent of the parties, on such terms and conditions as the President may direct. Payment made pursuant to any such settlement, or as a result of an arbitration award, shall be final and conclusive notwithstanding any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2395_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial transactions with foreign governments; exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Financial transactions with foreign governments; exemption The provisions of section 955 of title 18 shall not apply to prevent any person, including any individual, partnership, corporation, or association, from acting for, or participating in, any operation or transaction arising under this chapter, or from acquiring any obligation issued in connection with any operation or transaction arising under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>