<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2431f"><akn:num>2431f</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to engage in debt-for-nature swaps and debt buybacks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2431f. Authority to engage in debt-for-nature swaps and debt buybacks(a) Loans and credits eligible for sale, reduction, or cancellation(1) Debt-for-nature swaps(A) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may, in accordance with this section, sell to any eligible purchaser described in subparagraph (B) any concessional loans described in section 2431d(a)(1) of this title or any credits described in section 2431e(a)(1) of this title, or on receipt of payment from an eligible purchaser described in subparagraph (B), reduce or cancel such loans (or credits) or portion thereof, only for the purpose of facilitating a debt-for-nature swap to support eligible activities described in section 2431g(d) of this title.


(B) Eligible purchaser describedA loan or credit may be sold, reduced, or canceled under subparagraph (A) only to a purchaser who presents plans satisfactory to the President for using the loan or credit for the purpose of engaging in debt-for-nature swaps to support eligible activities described in section 2431g(d) of this title.


(C) Consultation requirementBefore the sale under subparagraph (A) to any eligible purchaser described in subparagraph (B), or any reduction or cancellation under such subparagraph (A), of any loan or credit made to an eligible country, the President shall consult with the country concerning the amount of loans or credits to be sold, reduced, or canceled and their uses for debt-for-nature swaps to support eligible activities described in section 2431g(d) of this title.


(D) Authorization of appropriationsFor the cost (as defined in section 661a(5) of title 2) for the reduction of any debt pursuant to subparagraph (A), amounts authorized to be appropriated under sections 2431d(a)(2), 2431e(a)(2), and 2431d(d) of this title shall be made available for such reduction of debt pursuant to subparagraph (A).



(2) Debt buybacksNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may, in accordance with </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans and credits eligible for sale, reduction, or cancellation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Loans and credits eligible for sale, reduction, or cancellation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deposit of proceeds The proceeds from the sale, reduction, or cancellation of any loan sold, reduced, or canceled pursuant to this section shall be deposited in the United States Government account or accounts established for the repayment of such loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>