<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2431a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2431a"><akn:num>2431a</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2431a. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) Administering bodyThe term “administering body” means the entity provided for in section 2431g(c) of this title.


(2) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on International Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and

(B) the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.


(3) Beneficiary countryThe term “beneficiary country” means an eligible country with respect to which the authority of section 2431d(a)(1) of this title, section 2431e(a)(1) of this title, or paragraph (1) or (2) of section 2431f(a) of this title is exercised.


(4) BoardThe term “Board” means the board referred to in section 2431i of this title.


(5) Developing country with a tropical forest or coral reefThe term “developing country with a tropical forest or coral reef” means—(A)(i) a country that has a per capita income of $725 or less in 1994 United States dollars (commonly referred to as “low-income country”), as determined and adjusted on an annual basis by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development in its World Development Report; or

(ii) a country that has a per capita income of more than $725 but less than $8,956 in 1994 United States dollars (commonly referred to as “middle-income country”), as determined and adjusted on an annual basis by the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development in its World Development Report; and


(B) a country that contains at least one tropical forest or coral reef that is globally outstanding in terms of its biological diversity or represents one of the larger intact blocks of tropical forests or coral reefs left, on a regional, continental, or global scale.


(6) Eligible countryThe term “eligible country” means a country designated by the President in accordance with section 2431c of this title.


(7) Conservation AgreementThe term “Co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administering body</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administering body The term “administering body” means the entity provided for in section 2431g(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Beneficiary country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Beneficiary country The term “beneficiary country” means an eligible country with respect to which the authority of section 2431d(a)(1) of this title, section 2431e(a)(1) of this title, or paragraph (1) or (2) of section 2431f(a) of this title is exercised.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Board The term “Board” means the board referred to in section 2431i of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developing country with a tropical forest or coral reef</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Developing country with a tropical forest or coral reef The term “developing country with a tropical forest or coral reef” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible country</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Eligible country The term “eligible country” means a country designated by the President in accordance with section 2431c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Conservation Agreement The term “Conservation Agreement” or “Agreement” means a Conservation Agreement provided for in section 2431g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation Facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Conservation Facility The term “Conservation Facility” or “Facility” means the Conservation Facility established in the Department of the Treasury by section 2431b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conservation Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Conservation Fund The term “Conservation Fund” or “Fund” means a Conservation Fund provided for in section 2431h of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2431a_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coral</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Coral The term “coral” means species of the phylum Cnidaria, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>