<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2456" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2456/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2456/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2456"><akn:num>2456</akn:num><akn:heading>J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2456. J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board(a) Appointment; members; considerations for selection(1) For the purpose of selecting students, scholars, teachers, trainees, and other persons to participate in the programs authorized under section 2452(a)(1) of this title, and of supervising such programs and the programs authorized under section 2452(b)(4) and (6) of this title, there is continued the authority of the President to appoint a board of foreign scholarships which shall be known as the “J. William Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board” (hereinafter referred to as the “Board”) consisting of twelve members. In connection with appointments to such Board, due consideration shall be given to the selection of distinguished representatives of cultural, educational, student advisory, and war veterans groups, and representatives of the United States Department of Education, the United States Department of Veterans Affairs, public and private nonprofit educational institutions.

(2) In the selection of American citizens for participation in programs under this chapter, preference shall be given to those who have served in the Armed Forces of the United States, and due consideration shall be given to applicants from all geographical areas of the United States.


(b) Omitted

(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1336(2), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–790

(d) Creation of interagency and other advisory committees; conferences of personsThe President is authorized to create such interagency and other advisory committees as in his judgment may be of assistance in carrying out the purposes of this chapter, and from time to time to convene conferences of persons interested in educational and cultural affairs to consider matters relating to the purposes of this chapter.


(e) Availability of appropriations for expenses; transportation expenses and per diem; compensation of members of Board and CommitteesThe provisions of section 1346(b) of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment; members; considerations for selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment; members; considerations for selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, subdiv. A, title XIII, § 1336(2), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–790</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation of interagency and other advisory committees; conferences of persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Creation of interagency and other advisory committees; conferences of persons The President is authorized to create such interagency and other advisory committees as in his judgment may be of assistance in carrying out the purposes of this chapter, and from time to time to convene conferences of persons interested in educational and cultural affairs to consider matters relating to the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations for expenses; transportation expenses and per diem; compensation of members of Board and Committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of appropriations for expenses; transportation expenses and per diem; compensation of members of Board and Committees The provisions of section 1346(b) of title 31 shall be applicable to any interagency committee created pursuant to the provisions of this chapter. Members of the committees provided for in this section shall be entitled (i) to transportation expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence at the rate prescribed by or established pursuant to section 5703 of title 5 while away from home in connection with attendance at meetings or in consultation with officials of the Government or otherwise carrying out duties as authorized, and (ii) if not otherwise in the employ of the United States Government, to compensation at rates not in excess of $50 per diem while performing services for such committees. Members of the Board shall be entitled to such expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence as provided for under clause (i) of the preceding sentence and, while p</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2456_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial and staff assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Secretarial and staff assistance The President is authorized to provide for necessary secretarial and staff assistance for the Board and such committees as may be created under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>