<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2504"><akn:num>2504</akn:num><akn:heading>Peace Corps volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2504. Peace Corps volunteers(a) Persons eligible; terms and conditions of service; Federal employee status; racial, sex, religious, or color discriminationThe President may enroll in the Peace Corps for service abroad qualified citizens and nationals of the United States (referred to in this chapter as “volunteers”). The terms and conditions of the enrollment, training (including training under section 2507a of this title), compensation, hours of work, benefits, leave, termination, and all other terms and conditions of the service of volunteers shall be exclusively those set forth in this chapter and those consistent therewith which the President may prescribe; and, except as provided in this chapter, volunteers shall not be deemed officers or employees or otherwise in the service or employment of, or holding office under, the United States for any purpose. In carrying out this subsection, there shall be no discrimination against any person on account of race, sex, creed, or color.


(b) Living allowances, travel, leave and related items; transfers of supplies and equipmentVolunteers shall be provided with such living, travel, and leave allowances, and such housing, transportation, supplies, equipment, subsistence, and clothing as the President may determine to be necessary for their maintenance and to insure their health and their capacity to serve effectively. Supplies or equipment provided volunteers to insure their capacity to serve effectively may be transferred to the government or to other entities of the country or area with which they have been serving, when no longer necessary for such purpose, and when such transfers would further the purposes of this chapter. Transportation and travel allowances may also be provided, in such circumstances as the President may determine, for applicants for enrollment to or from places of training and places of enrollment, and for former volunteers from places of termination to their homes in the United States.


(c) Rea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons eligible; terms and conditions of service; Federal employee status; racial, sex, religious, or color discrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Persons eligible; terms and conditions of service; Federal employee status; racial, sex, religious, or color discrimination The President may enroll in the Peace Corps for service abroad qualified citizens and nationals of the United States (referred to in this chapter as “volunteers”). The terms and conditions of the enrollment, training (including training under section 2507a of this title), compensation, hours of work, benefits, leave, termination, and all other terms and conditions of the service of volunteers shall be exclusively those set forth in this chapter and those consistent therewith which the President may prescribe; and, except as provided in this chapter, volunteers shall not be deemed officers or employees or otherwise in the service or employment of, or holding office under, the United States for any purpose. In carrying out this subsection, there shall be no discrimination against any person on account of race, sex, creed, or color.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Living allowances, travel, leave and related items; transfers of supplies and equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Living allowances, travel, leave and related items; transfers of supplies and equipment Volunteers shall be provided with such living, travel, and leave allowances, and such housing, transportation, supplies, equipment, subsistence, and clothing as the President may determine to be necessary for their maintenance and to insure their health and their capacity to serve effectively. Supplies or equipment provided volunteers to insure their capacity to serve effectively may be transferred to the government or to other entities of the country or area with which they have been serving, when no longer necessary for such purpose, and when such transfers would further the purposes of this chapter. Transportation and travel allowances may also be provided, in such circumstances as the President may determine, for applicants for enrollment to or from places of training and places of enrollment, and for former volunteers from places of termination to their homes in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Readjustment allowances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Readjustment allowances Volunteers shall be entitled to receive a readjustment allowance at a rate not less than $125 for each month of satisfactory service as determined by the President. The readjustment allowance of each volunteer shall be payable on his return to the United States: Provided, however, That, under such circumstances as the President may determine, the accrued readjustment allowance, or any part thereof, may be paid to the volunteer, members of his family or others, during the period of his service, or prior to his return to the United States. In the event of the volunteer’s death during the period of his service, the amount of any unpaid readjustment allowance shall be paid in accordance with the provisions of section 5582(b) of title 5. For purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, a volunteer shall be deemed to be paid and to receive each amount of a readjustment allowance to which he is entitled after December 31, 1964, when such amount is transferred fro</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 89–554, § 8(a), Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 661</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Health care Volunteers shall receive such health care (including, if necessary, for volunteers and trainees, services under section 2507b of this title) during their service, applicants for enrollment shall receive such health examinations preparatory to their service, applicants for enrollment who have accepted an invitation to begin a period of training under section 2507(a) of this title shall receive, preparatory to their service, such immunization, dental care, and information on prescription options and potential interactions, as necessary and appropriate and in accordance with subsection (f), and former volunteers shall receive such health examinations within six months after termination of their service, including services provided in accordance with section 2507b of this title (except that the six-month limitation shall not apply in the case of such services), as the President may deem necessary or appropriate. Subject to such conditions as the President may prescribe, suc</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescription of medications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prescription of medications The Director of the Peace Corps shall consult with health experts outside the Peace Corps, including experts licensed in the field of mental health, and follow guidance by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention regarding the prescription of medications to a volunteer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement and other credits based upon length of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Retirement and other credits based upon length of service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment to other entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Assignment to other entities The President may detail or assign volunteers or otherwise make them available to any entity referred to in paragraph (1) of section 2509(a) of this title on such terms and conditions as he may determine: Provided, That not to exceed two hundred volunteers may be assigned to carry out secretarial or clerical duties on the staffs of the Peace Corps representatives abroad: Provided, however, That any volunteer so detailed or assigned shall continue to be entitled to the allowances, benefits and privileges of volunteers authorized under or pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tort claims; absentee voting; general average contributions for transportation of baggage; check cashing and currency exchange; claims for overpayment of pay; passport fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Tort claims; absentee voting; general average contributions for transportation of baggage; check cashing and currency exchange; claims for overpayment of pay; passport fees Volunteers shall be deemed employees of the United States Government for the purposes of the Federal Tort Claims Act and any other Federal tort liability statute, section 3342 of title 31, section 5732 and section 5584 of title 5 (and readjustment allowances paid under this chapter shall be considered as pay for purposes of such section), and section 214 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2504_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination of service The service of a volunteer may be terminated at any time at the pleasure of the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>