<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2507h"><akn:num>2507h</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal and assessment and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2507h. Removal and assessment and evaluation(a) In generalIf a volunteer requests removal from the site in which such volunteer is serving because the volunteer feels at risk of imminent bodily harm, the President shall, as expeditiously as practical after receiving such request, remove the volunteer from the site. If the President receives such a request, the President shall assess and evaluate the safety of such site and may not assign another volunteer to the site until such time as the assessment and evaluation is complete and the site has been determined to be safe. Volunteers may remain at a site during the assessment and evaluation.


(b) Determination of site as unsafeIf the President determines that a site is unsafe for any remaining volunteers at the site, the President shall, as expeditiously as practical, remove all volunteers from the site.


(c) Tracking and recordingThe President shall establish a global tracking and recording system to track and record incidents of crimes against volunteers.


(Pub. L. 87–293, title I, § 8H, as added Pub. L. 112–57, § 2, Nov. 21, 2011, 125 Stat. 743.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If a volunteer requests removal from the site in which such volunteer is serving because the volunteer feels at risk of imminent bodily harm, the President shall, as expeditiously as practical after receiving such request, remove the volunteer from the site. If the President receives such a request, the President shall assess and evaluate the safety of such site and may not assign another volunteer to the site until such time as the assessment and evaluation is complete and the site has been determined to be safe. Volunteers may remain at a site during the assessment and evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of site as unsafe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of site as unsafe If the President determines that a site is unsafe for any remaining volunteers at the site, the President shall, as expeditiously as practical, remove all volunteers from the site.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tracking and recording</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tracking and recording The President shall establish a global tracking and recording system to track and record incidents of crimes against volunteers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>