<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2507e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2507e"><akn:num>2507e</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer feedback and Peace Corps review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2507e. Volunteer feedback and Peace Corps review(a) Monitoring and evaluationNot later than 1 year after November 21, 2011, the President shall establish goals, metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for all Peace Corps programs. Monitoring and evaluation plans shall incorporate best practices from monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses.


(b) Performance plans and elementsThe President shall establish performance plans with performance elements and standards for Peace Corps representatives, ensure that each such plan includes a consideration of the results, with respect to each such representative and the country of service of each such representative, of each survey conducted under subsection (c),,11 So in original. and review the performance of Peace Corps representatives not less than annually to determine whether they have met these performance elements and standards. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the discretion of the President to remove a Peace Corps representative.


(c) Annual volunteer surveysAnnually through September 30, 2023, the President shall conduct a confidential survey of volunteers regarding the effectiveness of Peace Corps programs and staff and the safety of volunteers. The results shall be provided in aggregate form without identifying information to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. Results from the annual volunteer survey shall be considered in reviewing the performance of Peace Corps representatives under subsection (b). The President shall publish, on a publicly available website of the Peace Corps, a report summarizing the results of each survey related to volunteer satisfaction in each country in which volunteers serve, and the early termination rate of volunteers serving in each such country. The information published shall be posted in an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Monitoring and evaluation Not later than 1 year after November 21, 2011, the President shall establish goals, metrics, and monitoring and evaluation plans for all Peace Corps programs. Monitoring and evaluation plans shall incorporate best practices from monitoring and evaluation studies and analyses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance plans and elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Performance plans and elements The President shall establish performance plans with performance elements and standards for Peace Corps representatives, ensure that each such plan includes a consideration of the results, with respect to each such representative and the country of service of each such representative, of each survey conducted under subsection (c),,11 So in original. and review the performance of Peace Corps representatives not less than annually to determine whether they have met these performance elements and standards. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as limiting the discretion of the President to remove a Peace Corps representative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual volunteer surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual volunteer surveys Annually through September 30, 2023, the President shall conduct a confidential survey of volunteers regarding the effectiveness of Peace Corps programs and staff and the safety of volunteers. The results shall be provided in aggregate form without identifying information to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives. Results from the annual volunteer survey shall be considered in reviewing the performance of Peace Corps representatives under subsection (b). The President shall publish, on a publicly available website of the Peace Corps, a report summarizing the results of each survey related to volunteer satisfaction in each country in which volunteers serve, and the early termination rate of volunteers serving in each such country. The information published shall be posted in an easily accessible place near the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peace Corps Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Peace Corps Inspector General The Inspector General of the Peace Corps shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2507e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Portfolio reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Portfolio reviews</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>