<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2514a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2514a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2514a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2514a"><akn:num>2514a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for Peace Corps to provide separation pay for host country resident personal services </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2514a. Authorization for Peace Corps to provide separation pay for host country resident personal services contractors of the Peace Corps(a) Establishment of fundThere is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund for the Peace Corps to provide separation pay for host country resident personal services contractors of the Peace Corps.


(b) FundingThe Director of the Peace Corps may deposit in the fund established under subsection (a)—(1) amounts previously obligated and not canceled to provide the separation pay described in such subsection; and

(2) amounts obligated for fiscal years after fiscal year 2006 for current and future costs of providing such separation pay.


(c) AvailabilityBeginning in fiscal year 2007, amounts deposited in the fund established under subsection (a) shall be available without fiscal year limitation for severance, retirement, or other separation payments to host country resident personal services contractors of the Peace Corps in countries where such payments are legally authorized.


(Pub. L. 110–86, § 1, Sept. 27, 2007, 121 Stat. 979.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Peace Corps Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of fund There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund for the Peace Corps to provide separation pay for host country resident personal services contractors of the Peace Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding The Director of the Peace Corps may deposit in the fund established under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2514a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability Beginning in fiscal year 2007, amounts deposited in the fund established under subsection (a) shall be available without fiscal year limitation for severance, retirement, or other separation payments to host country resident personal services contractors of the Peace Corps in countries where such payments are legally authorized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>