<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2573" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2573/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2573/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2573"><akn:num>2573</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy formulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2573. Policy formulation(a) FormulationThe Secretary of State shall prepare for the President, and the heads of such other Government agencies as the President may determine, recommendations and advice concerning United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy.


(b) ProhibitionNo action shall be taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act that would obligate the United States to reduce or limit the Armed Forces or armaments of the United States in a militarily significant manner, except pursuant to the treaty-making power of the President set forth in Article II, Section 2, Clause 2 of the Constitution or unless authorized by the enactment of further affirmative legislation by the Congress of the United States.


(c) Statutory constructionNothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any policy or action by any Government agency which would interfere with, restrict, or prohibit the acquisition, possession, or use of firearms by an individual for the lawful purpose of personal defense, sport, recreation, education, or training.


(Pub. L. 87–297, title III, § 303, formerly § 33, Sept. 26, 1961, 75 Stat. 634; Pub. L. 88–186, § 3, Nov. 26, 1963, 77 Stat. 342; Pub. L. 103–236, title VII, § 709, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 494; renumbered § 303 and amended Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, subdiv. A, title XII, § 1223(8), (21), subdiv. B, title XXVI, § 2602, Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–769, 2681–772, 2681–839.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this chapter” and was translated as reading “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 87–297, Sept. 26, 1961, 75 Stat. 631, known as the Arms Control and Disarmament Act, which is classified generally to this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments1998—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 105–277, § 1223(8), substituted “Secretary of State” for “Director” and struck out “the Secretary of State,” after “the President,”.
Subsec. (c). Pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2573_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Formulation The Secretary of State shall prepare for the President, and the heads of such other Government agencies as the President may determine, recommendations and advice concerning United States arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2573_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition No action shall be taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act that would obligate the United States to reduce or limit the Armed Forces or armaments of the United States in a militarily significant manner, except pursuant to the treaty-making power of the President set forth in Article II, Section 2, Clause 2 of the Constitution or unless authorized by the enactment of further affirmative legislation by the Congress of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2573_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statutory construction Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed to authorize any policy or action by any Government agency which would interfere with, restrict, or prohibit the acquisition, possession, or use of firearms by an individual for the lawful purpose of personal defense, sport, recreation, education, or training.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>