<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2593e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2593e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2593e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2593e"><akn:num>2593e</akn:num><akn:heading>Measures against persons involved in activities that violate arms control treaties or agreements wit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2593e. Measures against persons involved in activities that violate arms control treaties or agreements with the United States(a) Reports on persons that violate treaties or agreements(1) In generalNot later than 30 days after the submittal to Congress of an annual report on the status of United States policy and actions with respect to arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament pursuant to section 2593a of this title, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods, identifying every person with respect to whom there is credible information indicating that—(A) the person—(i)(I) is an individual who is a citizen, national, or permanent resident of a country described in paragraph (2); or

(II) is an entity organized under the laws of a country described in paragraph (2); and


(ii) has engaged in any activity that contributed to or is a significant factor in the President’s or the Secretary of State’s determination that such country is not in full compliance with its obligations as further described in paragraph (2); or


(B) the person has provided material support for such non-compliance to a person described in subparagraph (A).


(2) Country describedA country described in this paragraph is a country (other than a country described in paragraph (3)) that the President or the Secretary of State has determined, in the most recent annual report described in paragraph (1), to be not in full compliance with its obligations undertaken in all arms control, nonproliferation, and disarmament agreements or commitments to which the United States is a participating state.


(3) Excluded countriesThe following countries are not described for purposes of paragraph (2):(A) The United States.

(B) Any country determined by the Director of National Intelligence to be closely cooperating in intelligence matters with the United States in the period covered by </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on persons that violate treaties or agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports on persons that violate treaties or agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Imposition of measures Except as provided in subsections (d), (e), and (f), the President shall impose the measures described in subsection (c) with respect to each person identified in a report under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measures described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Measures described</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver for lack of knowing violation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver for lack of knowing violation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver to prevent disclosure of intelligence sources and methods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver to prevent disclosure of intelligence sources and methods The President may waive the application of measures on a case-by-case basis under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of imposition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Timing of imposition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2593e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appropriate congressional committees defined In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>