<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2605" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2605/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2605/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2605"><akn:num>2605</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds and personnel; savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2605. Use of funds and personnel; savings provision(a) Use of fundsFunds made available for the purposes of this chapter shall be available for—(1) compensation, allowances, and travel of personnel, including members of the Foreign Service whose services are utilized primarily for the purpose of this chapter, and without regard to the provisions of any other law, for printing and binding, and for expenditures outside the United States for the procurement of supplies and services and for other administrative and operating purposes (other than compensation of personnel) without regard to such laws and regulations governing the obligation and expenditure of Government funds as may be necessary to accomplish the purposes of this chapter;

(2) employment or assignment of members of the Foreign Service serving under limited appointments for the duration of operations under this chapter;

(3) exchange of funds without regard to section 3651 11 See References in Text note below. of the Revised Statutes (31 U.S.C. 543), and loss by exchanges;

(4) expenses authorized by the Foreign Service Act of 1980 [22 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.], not otherwise provided for;

(5) expenses authorized by the Act of August 1, 1956 (70 Stat. 890–892), as amended;

(6) contracting for personal services abroad, and individuals employed by contract to perform such services shall not be considered to be employees of the United States for purposes of any law administered by the Office of Personnel Management, except that the Secretary of State may determine the applicability to such individuals of section 2(f) of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (22 U.S.C. 2669(f)) and of any other law administered by the Secretary concerning the employment of such individuals abroad; and

(7) all other expenses determined by the President to be necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Savings provisionExcept as may be expressly provided to the contrary in this chapter, all determina</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2605_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of funds Funds made available for the purposes of this chapter shall be available for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2605_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Savings provision Except as may be expressly provided to the contrary in this chapter, all determinations, authorizations, regulations, orders, contracts, agreements and other actions issued, undertaken, or entered into under authority of any provision of law repealed by this chapter shall continue in full force and effect until modified, revoked, or superseded under the authority of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2605_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of personnel Personnel funded pursuant to this section are authorized to provide administrative assistance to personnel assigned to the bureau charged with carrying out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>