<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2606" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2606/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2606/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2606"><akn:num>2606</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits of U.S. funds received by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2606. Audits of U.S. funds received by the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees(a) Program auditsFunds may not be available to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) under this chapter or any other Act unless provision is made for—(1) annual program audits to determine the use of UNHCR funds, including the use of such funds by implementing partners; and

(2) such audits are made available through the Department of State for inspection by the Comptroller General of the United States.


(b) First program auditThe first program audit pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall begin not later than June 1, 1986.


(Pub. L. 87–510, § 8, as added Pub. L. 99–93, title I, § 113, Aug. 16, 1985, 99 Stat. 411; amended Pub. L. 101–246, title VII, § 701, Feb. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 74; Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1111(a), Dec. 21, 1995, 109 Stat. 723.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 87–510, June 28, 1962, 76 Stat. 121, known as the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962, which enacted this chapter, amended section 1104 of Title 8, Aliens and Nationality, repealed sections 1925(a), (c), (d), and 1951(c) of this title, enacted a provision set out as a note under section 2601 of this title, and amended a provision set out as a note under section 1182 of Title 8. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2601 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1995—Subsecs. (b), (c). Pub. L. 104–66 redesignated subsec. (c) as (b) and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “The Comptroller General of the United States shall inspect each such audit and submit a report of that inspection to the Congress.”
1990—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 101–246 amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “Funds may not be made available to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program audits Funds may not be available to the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) under this chapter or any other Act unless provision is made for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2606_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>First program audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) First program audit The first program audit pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall begin not later than June 1, 1986.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>