<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262c"><akn:num>262c</akn:num><akn:heading>Commitments for United States contributions to international financial institutions fostering econom</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262c. Commitments for United States contributions to international financial institutions fostering economic development in less developed countries; continuation of participation(a) Congressional findingsIt is the sense of the Congress that—(1) for humanitarian, economic, and political reasons, it is in the national interest of the United States to assist in fostering economic development in the less developed countries of this world;

(2) the development-oriented international financial institutions have proved themselves capable of playing a significant role in assisting economic development by providing to less developed countries access to capital and technical assistance and soliciting from them maximum self-help and mutual cooperation;

(3) this has been achieved with minimal risk of financial loss to contributing countries;

(4) such institutions have proved to be an effective mechanism for sharing the burden among developed countries of stimulating economic development in the less developed world; and

(5) although continued United States participation in the international financial institutions is an important part of efforts by the United States to assist less developed countries, more of this burden should be shared by other developed countries. As a step in that direction, in future negotiations, the United States should work toward aggregate contributions to future replenishments to international financial institutions covered by this Act not to exceed 25 per centum.


(b) Funding commitments to international financial institutions; availability of funds subject to appropriationsThe Congress recognizes that economic development is a long-term process needing funding commitments to international financial institutions. It also notes that the availability of funds for the United States contribution to international financial institutions is subject to the appropriations process.


(Pub. L. 95–118, title I, § 101, Oct. 3, 1977, 91 Stat. 1067.)

Editoria</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings It is the sense of the Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding commitments to international financial institutions; availability of funds subject to appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding commitments to international financial institutions; availability of funds subject to appropriations The Congress recognizes that economic development is a long-term process needing funding commitments to international financial institutions. It also notes that the availability of funds for the United States contribution to international financial institutions is subject to the appropriations process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>