<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262h"><akn:num>262h</akn:num><akn:heading>Opposition by United States Executive Directors of international financial institutions to assistanc</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262h. Opposition by United States Executive Directors of international financial institutions to assistance for production or extraction of export commodities or minerals in surplus on world markets
The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the International Monetary Fund, the Asian Development Bank, the Inter-American Investment Corporation, the African Development Bank, and the African Development Fund to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any assistance by such institutions, using funds appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to any provision of law, for the production or extraction of any commodity or mineral for export, if—(1) such commodity or mineral, as the case may be, is in surplus on world markets; and

(2) the export of such commodity or mineral, as the case may be, would cause substantial injury to the United States producers of the same, similar, or competing commodity or mineral.

(Pub. L. 99–472, § 22, Oct. 15, 1986, 100 Stat. 1210.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Similar ProvisionsPub. L. 118–47, div. F, title VII, § 7025(c), Mar. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 775, provided that: “The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States executive director of each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any assistance by such institution, using funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act [div. F of Pub. L. 118–47, 138 Stat. 729, see Tables for classification], for the production or extraction of any commodity or mineral for export, if it is in surplus on world markets and if the assistance will cause substantial injury to United States producers of the same, similar, or competing commodity.”

Similar provisions were contained in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262h_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) such commodity or mineral, as the case may be, is in surplus on world markets; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262h_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) the export of such commodity or mineral, as the case may be, would cause substantial injury to the United States producers of the same, similar, or competing commodity or mineral.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>