<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262l_2"><akn:num>262l–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Sustainable use of natural resources; use of agricultural and industrial chemicals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262l–2. Sustainable use of natural resources; use of agricultural and industrial chemicals(a) Instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development BanksIt is the policy of the United States that sustainable economic growth must be predicated on sustainable use of natural resources. The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the Multilateral Development Banks (MDB’s) to—(1) promote the adoption of internal guidelines requiring the use of least-cost planning techniques in evaluating proposed energy loans, and consider refusal to support power generation, utilization or energy sector loans unless cost-effective conservation measures have been fully evaluated and considered;

(2) encourage each MDB to offer technical assistance to borrower nations in preparing national energy plans. Special emphasis shall be given to least-cost analysis in making decisions on energy use and development, and such analyses shall take into account all demand-side as well as supply-side options;

(3) promote expansion of MDB expertise in the areas of energy conservation and renewable energy sources;

(4) promote the adoption of lending strategies which place increased emphasis on energy conservation and efficiency as opposed to merely increasing generating capacity;

(5) promote adoption of policies which minimize emissions of greenhouse gases;

(6) promote the adoption of lending strategies that place increased emphasis on energy efficient transportation programs. Such strategies shall consider alternatives to conventional mechanized transport such as nonmotorized vehicles, public transport and increased energy and cost efficiency of transportation systems; and

(7) promote the use of existing and the development of new mechanisms to promote conservation of biological diversity. Existing resources to be consulted shall include but not be limited to Conservation Data Centers.


(b) Bilateral and multilateral discussions to strengthen e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development Banks It is the policy of the United States that sustainable economic growth must be predicated on sustainable use of natural resources. The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the Multilateral Development Banks (MDB’s) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral and multilateral discussions to strengthen environmental performance of Multilateral Development Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Bilateral and multilateral discussions to strengthen environmental performance of Multilateral Development Banks The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, shall conduct bilateral and multilateral discussions with other members of the MDB’s to further strengthen the environmental performance of each bank. These discussions shall include, but not be limited to organizational, administrative and procedural arrangements to remove impediments to the efficient and effective management of assistance programs necessary to protect and ensure the sustainable use of natural resources and to carry out such assistance programs in consultation with affected local communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Administrator of Agency for International Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of Administrator of Agency for International Development The Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>