<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262l–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262l_1"><akn:num>262l–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Sustainable economic growth and management of natural resources; environmental impact of loans; pest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262l–1. Sustainable economic growth and management of natural resources; environmental impact of loans; pest management; addition of trained professionals; “early warning system”(a) Implementation of programs to promote sustainable economic growth and management of natural resources; instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development BanksIt is the policy of the United States that participation in international financial institutions is predicated on the implementation of programs to promote environmentally sustainable economic growth and sustainable management of natural resources. The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the Multilateral Development Banks (MDB’s) to continue to vigorously promote a commitment of these institutions to—(1) add appropriately trained professional staff with expertise, and rigorously strengthen existing staffs’ training in ecology and related areas;

(2) develop and implement management plans to ensure systematic environmental review of all projects;

(3) fully inform and involve host country environmental and health officials (Federal and local) and nongovernmental environmental and indigenous peoples organizations at all stages of the project cycle in environmentally sensitive projects as well as in policy based lending to ensure the active participation of local communities and non-governmental organizations in the planning of projects that may adversely affect them;

(4) substantially increase the proportion of lending supporting environmentally beneficial projects and project components, including but not limited to technical assistance for environmental ministries and institutions, resource rehabilitation projects and project components, protection of indigenous peoples, and appropriate light capital technology projects. Other examples of such projects include small scale mixed farming and multiple cropping, agroforestry, programs to promote kitchen gardens, watershed ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of programs to promote sustainable economic growth and management of natural resources; instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation of programs to promote sustainable economic growth and management of natural resources; instructions to Executive Directors of Multilateral Development Banks It is the policy of the United States that participation in international financial institutions is predicated on the implementation of programs to promote environmentally sustainable economic growth and sustainable management of natural resources. The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the Multilateral Development Banks (MDB’s) to continue to vigorously promote a commitment of these institutions to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact of loans; instructions to Executive Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Environmental impact of loans; instructions to Executive Directors The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the MDB’s and, where appropriate, the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 101–240, title V, § 541(d)(8), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2518</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pest management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pest management In order to promote sustainable and non-chemical dependent agriculture, the Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the MDB’s to initiate discussions with other directors of the MDB’s to propose that policies be established that integrated pest management and biological control of pests be a preferential and priority approach to pest management on all bank sponsored agricultural projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Instructions to Executive Director to IMF</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Instructions to Executive Director to IMF The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director to the International Monetary Fund to promote the requirement that the IMF conduct an in-depth analysis of the impact of its adjustment policies and conditionality of its lending facilities on the environment, public health, natural resources and indigenous people.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support of donor nations for additional trained professionals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Support of donor nations for additional trained professionals No later than March 30, 1988, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall initiate discussions with other donor nations, to explore ways in which said donor nations can support the addition of professionals trained in environmental and socio-cultural impact analysis to the Inter-American Development Bank, Asian Development Bank and African Development Bank. On the basis of such discussions the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall provide resources, including professional staff on loan, and/or financial support, to ensure with other donor nations the addition of sufficient staff trained in environmental and socio-cultural impact analysis to each of the above named regional development banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bilateral and multilateral discussions to strengthen environmental performance of Multilateral Development Banks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Bilateral and multilateral discussions to strengthen environmental performance of Multilateral Development Banks The Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, in cooperation with the Administrator of the Agency for International Development, shall conduct bilateral and multilateral discussions with other members of the MDB’s to further strengthen the environmental performance of each bank. These discussions shall include, but not be limited to organizational, administrative and procedural arrangements to remove impediments to the efficient and effective management of assistance programs necessary to protect and ensure the sustainable use of natural resources and to carry out such assistance programs in consultation with affected local communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation of “early warning system”</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Operation of “early warning system” The Administrator of the Agency for International Development, in consultation with the Secretaries of Treasury and State, shall continue, and work to enhance, the operation of the “early warning system”, by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adverse impacts to environment, natural resources, or indigenous peoples; instructions to Executive Director of appropriate Multilateral Development Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Adverse impacts to environment, natural resources, or indigenous peoples; instructions to Executive Director of appropriate Multilateral Development Bank If a review required by subsection (h) identifies adverse impacts to the environment, natural resources, or indigenous peoples, the Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director of the appropriate MDB to seek changes to the project necessary to eliminate or mitigate those impacts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262l_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by February 1, 1988</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Report by The Committee on Health and Environment of the Agency for International Development, called for in section 262l(i) of this title, shall report its findings to the Committees on Appropriations by February 1, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>