<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262o–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262o–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262o–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262o_1"><akn:num>262o–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Military spending by recipient countries; military involvement in economies of recipient countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262o–1. Military spending by recipient countries; military involvement in economies of recipient countries(a) Consideration of commitment to achieving certain goals(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the international financial institutions (as defined in section 262r(c)(2) of this title) to promote growth in the international economy by taking into account, when considering whether to support or oppose loan proposals at these institutions, the extent to which the recipient government has demonstrated a commitment to achieving the following goals:(A) to provide accurate and complete data on the annual expenditures and receipts of the armed forces;

(B) to establish good and publicly accountable governance, including an end to excessive military involvement in the economy; and

(C) to make substantial reductions in excessive military spending and forces.



(b) Steps to achieve goals requiredThe Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the international financial institutions (as so defined) to promote a policy at each institution under which—(1) the respective institution monitors closely and, through regular policy consultations with recipient governments, seeks to influence the composition of public expenditure in favor of funding growth and development priorities and away from unproductive expenditure, including excessive military expenditures;

(2) the respective institution supports lending operations which assist efforts of recipient governments to promote good governance, including public participation, and reduce military expenditures; and

(3) the allocation of resources and the extension of credit by the respective institution takes into account the performance of recipient governments in the areas of good governance, ending excessive military involvement in the economy and reducing excessive military e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262o_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of commitment to achieving certain goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consideration of commitment to achieving certain goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262o_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Steps to achieve goals required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Steps to achieve goals required The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Directors of the international financial institutions (as so defined) to promote a policy at each institution under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>