<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/262s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262s"><akn:num>262s</akn:num><akn:heading>Multilateral development bank procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262s. Multilateral development bank procurement(a) Executive DirectorsThe Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director of each multilateral development bank to attach a high priority to promoting opportunities for exports for goods and services from the United States and, in carrying out this function, to investigate thoroughly any complaints from United States bidders about the awarding of procurement contracts by the multilateral development banks to ensure that all contract procedures and rules of the banks are observed and that United States firms are treated fairly.


(b) 11 So in original. Two subsecs. (b) have been enacted. Officer of procurement(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary of the Treasury shall designate, within the Office of International Affairs in the Department of the Treasury, an officer of multilateral development bank procurement.


(2) FunctionThe officer shall act as the liaison between the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, and the United States Executive Directors’ offices in the multilateral development banks, in carrying out this section. The officer shall cooperate with the Department of Commerce in efforts to improve opportunities for multilateral development bank procurement by United States companies.



(b) 1 “Multilateral development bank” definedAs used in this section, the term “multilateral development bank” includes the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the InterAmerican Investment Corporation, the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Bank, and the African Development Fund.


(Pub. L. 95–118, title XVIII, § 1801, formerly Pub. L. 100–418, title III, § 3202, Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1382; renumbered § 1801 of Pub. L. 95–118, Pub. L. 101–240, title V, § 541(b)(1), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2517.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Executive Directors The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director of each multilateral development bank to attach a high priority to promoting opportunities for exports for goods and services from the United States and, in carrying out this function, to investigate thoroughly any complaints from United States bidders about the awarding of procurement contracts by the multilateral development banks to ensure that all contract procedures and rules of the banks are observed and that United States firms are treated fairly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two subsecs. (b) have been enacted. Officer of procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 “Multilateral development bank” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) As used in this section, the term “multilateral development bank” includes the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the International Development Association, the International Finance Corporation, the Inter-American Development Bank, the InterAmerican Investment Corporation, the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Bank, and the African Development Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>