<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2655a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2655a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2655a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2655a"><akn:num>2655a</akn:num><akn:heading>Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs within Department of State; </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2655a. Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs within Department of State; Assistant Secretary of State as head of Bureau
There is established within the Department of State a Bureau of Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs. There shall be an Assistant Secretary of State for Oceans and International Environmental and Scientific Affairs, appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, who shall be the head of the Bureau and who shall have responsibility for matters relating to oceans, environmental, scientific, fisheries, wildlife, and conservation affairs and for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate.
(Pub. L. 93–126, § 9(a), formerly § 9, Oct. 18, 1973, 87 Stat. 453, renumbered Pub. L. 93–312, § 9, June 8, 1974, 88 Stat. 238; Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(q)(1), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 410; Pub. L. 103–415, § 1(f)(4)(B), Oct. 25, 1994, 108 Stat. 4300.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Pub. L. 103–236, as amended by Pub. L. 103–415, substituted “There shall” for “In addition to the positions provided under section 2652 of this title, there shall” and inserted before period at end “and for such other related duties as the Secretary may from time to time designate”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1994 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 103–236 applicable with respect to officials, offices, and bureaus of Department of State when executive orders, regulations, or departmental directives implementing the amendments by sections 161 and 162 of Pub. L. 103–236 become effective, or 90 days after Apr. 30, 1994, whichever comes earlier, see section 161(b) of Pub. L. 103–236, as amended, set out as a note under section 2651a of this title.


Authority of Secretary of State
Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and referen</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>