<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2669a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2669a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2669a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2669a"><akn:num>2669a</akn:num><akn:heading>Diplomatic Telecommunications Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2669a. Diplomatic Telecommunications Service(a) Diplomatic Telecommunications Service financial managementIn fiscal year 1995 and each succeeding fiscal year—(1) the Secretary of State shall provide funds for the operation of the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service (DTS) in a sufficient amount to sustain the current level of support services being provided by the DTS, and no portion of such amount may be reprogrammed or transferred for any other purpose;

(2) all funds for the operation and enhancement of the DTS shall be directly available for use by the Diplomatic Telecommunications Service Program Office (DTS–PO); and

(3) the DTS–PO financial management officer shall be provided direct access to the Department of State financial management system to independently monitor and control the obligation and expenditure of all funds for the operation and enhancement of the DTS.


(b) DTS Policy BoardWithin 60 days after August 26, 1994, the Secretary of State and the Director of the DTS–PO shall restructure the DTS Policy Board to provide for representation on the Board, during fiscal year 1995 and each succeeding fiscal year, by—(1) the Director of the DTS–PO;

(2) the senior information management official from each agency currently serving on the Board;

(3) a senior career information management official from each of the Department of Commerce and the Defense Intelligence Agency; and

(4) a senior career information management official from each of 2 other Federal agencies served by the DTS, each of whom shall be appointed on a rotating basis by the Secretary of State and the Director of the DTS–PO for a 2-year term.


(c) DTS consolidation pilot program(1) In generalThe Secretary of State and the Director of the DTS–PO shall carry out a program under which total DTS consolidation will be completed before October 1, 1995, at not less than five embassies of medium to large size.


(2) Pilot program requirementsUnder the program required in paragraph (1)—(A) each</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2669a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diplomatic Telecommunications Service financial management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Diplomatic Telecommunications Service financial management In fiscal year 1995 and each succeeding fiscal year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2669a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>DTS Policy Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) DTS Policy Board Within 60 days after August 26, 1994, the Secretary of State and the Director of the DTS–PO shall restructure the DTS Policy Board to provide for representation on the Board, during fiscal year 1995 and each succeeding fiscal year, by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2669a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>DTS consolidation pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) DTS consolidation pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2669a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>DTS planning report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) DTS planning report Not later than January 15, 1995, the Secretary of State and the Director of the DTS–PO shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations a DTS planning report. The report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>