<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2679c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2679c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2679c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2679c"><akn:num>2679c</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on discriminatory contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2679c. Prohibition on discriminatory contracts(a) Prohibition(1) Except for real estate leases and as provided in subsection (b), the Department of State may not enter into any contract that expends funds appropriated to the Department of State for an amount in excess of the small purchase threshold (as defined in section 134 of title 41— 11 So in original. Probably should be “41)—”.(A) with a foreign person that complies with the Arab League boycott of Israel, or

(B) with any foreign or United States person that discriminates in the award of subcontracts on the basis of religion.


(2) For purposes of this section—(A) a foreign person complies with the boycott of Israel by Arab League countries when that foreign person takes or knowingly agrees to take any action, with respect to the boycott of Israel by Arab League countries, which section 4607(a) 22 See References in Text note below. of title 50 prohibits a United States person from taking, except that for purposes of this paragraph, the term “United States person” as used in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of section 4607(a)(1) 2 of title 50 shall be deemed to mean “person”; and

(B) the term “foreign person” means any person other than a United States person as defined in section 4618(2) 2 of title 50.


(3) For purposes of paragraph (1), a foreign person shall be deemed not to comply with the boycott of Israel by Arab League countries if that person, or the Secretary of State or his designee on the basis of available information, certifies that the person violates or otherwise does not comply with the boycott of Israel by Arab League countries by taking any actions prohibited by section 4607(a) 2 of title 50. Certification by the Secretary of State or his designee may occur only 30 days after notice has been given to the Congress that this certification procedure will be utilized at a specific overseas mission.


(b) Waiver by Secretary of StateThe Secretary of State may waive the requirements of this section on </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver by Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver by Secretary of State The Secretary of State may waive the requirements of this section on a country-by-country basis for a period not to exceed one year upon certification to the Congress by the Secretary that such waiver is in the national interest and is necessary to carry on diplomatic functions of the United States. Each such certification shall include a detailed justification for the waiver with respect to each such country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2679c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responses to contract solicitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responses to contract solicitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>