<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2680b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2680b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2680b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2680b"><akn:num>2680b</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for certain monthly workers’ compensation payments and other payments for Department o</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2680b. Special rules for certain monthly workers’ compensation payments and other payments for Department of State personnel under chief of mission authority(a) Adjustment of compensation for certain injuries(1) IncreaseThe Secretary of State or the head of any other Federal agency may pay an additional monthly monetary benefit, provided that the covered employee is receiving benefits under section 8105 or 8106 of title 5, and may determine the amount of each monthly monetary benefit amount by taking into account—(A) the severity of the qualifying injury;

(B) the circumstances by which the covered employee became injured; and

(C) the seniority of the covered employee, particularly for purposes of compensating for lost career growth.


(2) MaximumNotwithstanding chapter 81 of title 5, the total amount of monthly compensation increased under paragraph (1) may not exceed the monthly pay of the maximum rate of basic pay for GS–15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of such title.



(b) Costs for treating qualifying injuriesThe Secretary of State may pay the costs of or reimburse for diagnosing and treating—(1) a qualifying injury of a covered employee for such costs, that are not otherwise covered by chapter 81 of title 5 or other provision of Federal law; or

(2) a covered individual, or a covered dependent, for such costs that are not otherwise covered by Federal law.


(c) Information exchangeTo avoid duplicate or otherwise improper payments under this subsection, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of State, and, as appropriate, the head of any other Federal agency paying benefits under this section shall exchange information about the amounts paid for treatment of qualifying injuries.


(d) RegulationsNot later than 120 days after December 20, 2019, the Secretary of State shall—(1) prescribe regulations ensuring the fair and equitable implementation of this section; and

(2) submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of compensation for certain injuries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Adjustment of compensation for certain injuries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs for treating qualifying injuries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Costs for treating qualifying injuries The Secretary of State may pay the costs of or reimburse for diagnosing and treating—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information exchange</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information exchange To avoid duplicate or otherwise improper payments under this subsection, the Secretary of Labor, the Secretary of State, and, as appropriate, the head of any other Federal agency paying benefits under this section shall exchange information about the amounts paid for treatment of qualifying injuries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations Not later than 120 days after December 20, 2019, the Secretary of State shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation by the Secretary of State of another foreign country or duty station</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Designation by the Secretary of State of another foreign country or duty station The Secretary of State may designate another foreign country for the purposes of this section, provided that the Secretary reports such designation to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and includes in such report a rationale for each such designation. The Secretary of State may not designate an added foreign country or duty station for purposes of providing additional monetary benefit pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (i) for a qualifying injury to covered employees, covered dependents, or covered individuals under this section unless the Secretary of State—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Treatment of amounts For purposes of section 104 of title 26, amounts paid pursuant to this section shall be treated as amounts described in subsection (a)(5) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other injuries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Other injuries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2680b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Expansion of authorities The head of any Federal agency may exercise the authorities of this section, including to designate an incident, whether the incident occurred in the United States or abroad, for purposes of subparagraphs (A)(ii) and (B)(ii) of subsection (e)(4) when the incident affects United States Government employees of the agency or their dependents who are not under the security responsibility of the Secretary of State as set forth in section 4802 of this title or when operational control of overseas security responsibility for such employees or dependents has been delegated to the head of the agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>