<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2684b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2684b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2684b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2684b"><akn:num>2684b</akn:num><akn:heading>Strengthening the Chief Information Officer of the Department of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2684b. Strengthening the Chief Information Officer of the Department of State(a) In generalThe Chief Information Officer of the Department shall be consulted on all decisions to approve or disapprove, significant new unclassified information technology expenditures, including software, of the Department, including expenditures related to information technology acquired, managed, and maintained by other bureaus and offices within the Department, in order to—(1) encourage the use of enterprise software and information technology solutions where such solutions exist or can be developed in a timeframe and manner consistent with maintaining and enhancing the continuity and improvement of Department operations;

(2) increase the bargaining power of the Department in acquiring information technology solutions across the Department;

(3) reduce the number of redundant Authorities to Operate (ATO), which, instead of using one ATO-approved platform across bureaus, requires multiple ATOs for software use cases across different bureaus;

(4) enhance the efficiency, reduce redundancy, and increase interoperability of the use of information technology across the enterprise of the Department;

(5) enhance training and alignment of information technology personnel with the skills required to maintain systems across the Department;

(6) reduce costs related to the maintenance of, or effectuate the retirement of, legacy systems;

(7) ensure the development and maintenance of security protocols regarding the use of information technology solutions and software across the Department; and

(8) improve end-user training on the operation of information technology solutions and to enhance end-user cybersecurity practices.


(b) Strategy and implementation plan required(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 22, 2023, the Chief Information Officer of the Department shall develop, in consultation with relevant bureaus and offices as appropriate, a strategy and a 5-year impleme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Chief Information Officer of the Department shall be consulted on all decisions to approve or disapprove, significant new unclassified information technology expenditures, including software, of the Department, including expenditures related to information technology acquired, managed, and maintained by other bureaus and offices within the Department, in order to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy and implementation plan required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Strategy and implementation plan required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement plan for the Bureau for Information Resources Management 11 So in original. Probably should be “Bureau of Information Resource Management”.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Improvement plan for the Bureau for Information Resources Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Significant expenditure defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Significant expenditure defined For purposes of this section, the term “significant expenditure” means any cumulative expenditure in excess of $250,000 total in a single fiscal year for a new unclassified software or information technology capability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2684b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>