<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2686a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2686a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2686a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2686a"><akn:num>2686a</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of Special Coordinator for water policy negotiations and water resources policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2686a. Appointment of Special Coordinator for water policy negotiations and water resources policy(a) DesignationThe Secretary of State shall designate a Special Coordinator—(1) to coordinate the United States Government response to international water resource disputes and needs;

(2) to represent the United States Government, whenever appropriate, in multilateral fora in discussions concerning access to fresh water; and

(3) to formulate United States policy to assist in the resolution of international problems posed by the lack of fresh water supplies.


(b) Other responsibilitiesThe individual designated under subsection (a) may carry out the functions of subsection (a) in addition to other assigned responsibilities.


(Pub. L. 102–138, title I, § 180, Oct. 28, 1991, 105 Stat. 682.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Authority of Secretary of State
Except as otherwise provided, Secretary of State to have and exercise any authority vested by law in any official or office of Department of State and references to such officials or offices deemed to refer to Secretary of State or Department of State, as appropriate, see section 2651a of this title and section 161(d) of Pub. L. 103–236, set out as a note under section 2651a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2686a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation The Secretary of State shall designate a Special Coordinator—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2686a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other responsibilities The individual designated under subsection (a) may carry out the functions of subsection (a) in addition to other assigned responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>