<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2707" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2707/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2707/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2707"><akn:num>2707</akn:num><akn:heading>International communications and information policy; duties of Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2707. International communications and information policy; duties of Secretary of State(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(k)(1)(A), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 408.

(b) The Secretary of State shall be responsible for formulation, coordination, and oversight of foreign policy related to international communications and information policy. The Secretary of State shall—(1) exercise primary authority for the conduct of foreign policy with respect to such telecommunications functions, including the determination of United States positions and the conduct of United States participation in negotiations with foreign governments and international bodies. In exercising this responsibility, the Secretary shall coordinate with other agencies as appropriate, and, in particular, shall give full consideration to the authority vested by law or Executive order in the Federal Communications Commission, the Department of Commerce and the Office of the United States Trade Representative in this area;

(2) maintain continuing liaison with other executive branch agencies concerned with international communications and information policy and with the Federal Communications Commission, as appropriate;

(3) in accordance with such authority as may be delegated by the President pursuant to Executive order, supervise and coordinate the activities of any senior interagency policymaking group on international telecommunications and information policy and chair such interagency meetings as may be necessary to coordinate actions on pending issues;; 11 So in original.

(4) coordinate the activities of, and assist as appropriate, interagency working level task forces and committees concerned with specific aspects of international communications and information policy;

(5) maintain liaison with the members and staffs of committees of the Congress concerned with international communications and information policy and provide testimony before such committees;

(6) maintain appropriate liai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 162(k)(1)(A), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 408.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2707_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of State shall be responsible for formulation, coordination, and oversight of foreign policy related to international communications and information policy. The Secretary of State shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>