<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2708"><akn:num>2708</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of State rewards program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2708. Department of State rewards program(a) Establishment(1) In generalThere is established a program for the payment of rewards to carry out the purposes of this section.


(2) PurposeThe rewards program shall be designed to assist in the prevention of acts of international terrorism, international narcotics trafficking, serious violations of international humanitarian law, foreign election interference, transnational organized crime, and other related criminal acts.


(3) ImplementationThe rewards program shall be administered by the Secretary of State, in consultation, as appropriate, with the Attorney General.



(b) Rewards authorizedIn the sole discretion of the Secretary (except as provided in subsection (c)(2)) and in consultation, as appropriate, with the heads of other relevant departments or agencies, the Secretary may pay a reward to any individual who furnishes information leading to—(1) the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual for the commission of an act of international terrorism against a United States person or United States property;

(2) the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual conspiring or attempting to commit an act of international terrorism against a United States person or United States property;

(3) the arrest or conviction in any country of any individual for committing, primarily outside the territorial jurisdiction of the United States, any narcotics-related offense if that offense involves or is a significant part of conduct that involves—(A) a violation of United States narcotics laws such that the individual would be a major violator of such laws;

(B) the killing or kidnapping of—(i) any officer, employee, or contract employee of the United States Government while such individual is engaged in official duties, or on account of that individual’s official duties, in connection with the enforcement of United States narcotics laws or the implementing of United States narcotics control objectives; or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rewards authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rewards authorized In the sole discretion of the Secretary (except as provided in subsection (c)(2)) and in consultation, as appropriate, with the heads of other relevant departments or agencies, the Secretary may pay a reward to any individual who furnishes information leading to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations and certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Ineligibility An officer or employee of any entity of Federal, State, or local government or of a foreign government who, while in the performance of his or her official duties, furnishes information described in subsection (b) shall not be eligible for a reward under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication regarding rewards offered by foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication regarding rewards offered by foreign governments Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, in the sole discretion of the Secretary, the resources of the rewards program shall be available for the publication of rewards offered by foreign governments regarding acts of international terrorism which do not involve United States persons or property or a violation of the narcotics laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Media surveys and advertisements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Media surveys and advertisements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2708_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Determinations of Secretary A determination made by the Secretary under this section shall be final and conclusive and shall not be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>