<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2712" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2712/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2712/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2712"><akn:num>2712</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to control certain terrorism-related services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2712. Authority to control certain terrorism-related services(a) AuthorityThe Secretary of State may, by regulation, impose controls on the provision of the services described in subsection (b) if the Secretary determines that provision of such services would aid and abet international terrorism.


(b) Services subject to controlThe services subject to control under subsection (a) are the following:(1) Serving in or with the security forces of a designated foreign government.

(2) Providing training or other technical services having a direct military, law enforcement, or intelligence application, to or for the security forces of a designated foreign government.


Any regulations issued to impose controls on services described in paragraph (2) shall list the specific types of training and other services subject to the controls.

(c) Persons subject of controlsThese services may be controlled under subsection (a) when they are provided within the United States by any individual or entity and when they are provided anywhere in the world by a United States person.


(d) LicensesIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State may require licenses, which may be revoked, suspended, or amended, without prior notice, whenever such action is deemed to be advisable.


(e) Definitions(1) Designated foreign governmentAs used in this section, the term “designated foreign government” means a foreign government that the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of section 4605(j)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 50, has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.


(2) Security forcesAs used in this section, the term “security forces” means any military or paramilitary forces, any police or other law enforcement agency (including any police or other law enforcement agency at the regional or local level), and any intelligence agency of a foreign government.


(3) United StatesAs used in this section, the term “United States” incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Secretary of State may, by regulation, impose controls on the provision of the services described in subsection (b) if the Secretary determines that provision of such services would aid and abet international terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services subject to control</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Services subject to control The services subject to control under subsection (a) are the following: Any regulations issued to impose controls on services described in paragraph (2) shall list the specific types of training and other services subject to the controls.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons subject of controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Persons subject of controls These services may be controlled under subsection (a) when they are provided within the United States by any individual or entity and when they are provided anywhere in the world by a United States person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Licenses In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of State may require licenses, which may be revoked, suspended, or amended, without prior notice, whenever such action is deemed to be advisable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Congressional oversight</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2712_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Relationship to other laws The authority granted by this section is in addition to the authorities granted by any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>