<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2713"><akn:num>2713</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of historic and artistic furnishings of reception areas of the Harry S Truman Federal Bui</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2713. Protection of historic and artistic furnishings of reception areas of the Harry S Truman Federal Building(a) In generalThe Secretary of State shall administer the historic and artistic articles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects of the reception areas of the Department of State by such means and measures as conform to the purposes of the reception areas, which include conserving those articles, fixtures, and objects and providing for their enjoyment in such manner and by such means as will leave them for the use of the American people. Nothing shall be done under this subsection which conflicts with the administration of the Department of State or with the use of the reception areas for official purposes of the United States Government.


(b) Disposition of historic and artistic items(1) Items coveredArticles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects of the reception areas (and similar articles, fixtures, and objects acquired by the Secretary of State), when declared by the Secretary of State to be of historic or artistic interest, shall thereafter be considered to be the property of the Secretary in his or her official capacity and shall be subject to disposition solely in accordance with this subsection.


(2) Sale or tradeWhenever the Secretary of State determines that—(A) any item covered by paragraph (1) is no longer needed for use or display in the reception areas, or

(B) in order to upgrade the reception areas, a better use of that article would be its sale or exchange,


the Secretary may, with the advice and concurrence of the Director of the National Gallery of Art, sell the item at fair market value or trade it, without regard to the requirements of chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41. The proceeds of any such sale may be credited to the unconditional gift account of the Department of State, and items obtained in trade shall be </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of State shall administer the historic and artistic articles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects of the reception areas of the Department of State by such means and measures as conform to the purposes of the reception areas, which include conserving those articles, fixtures, and objects and providing for their enjoyment in such manner and by such means as will leave them for the use of the American people. Nothing shall be done under this subsection which conflicts with the administration of the Department of State or with the use of the reception areas for official purposes of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of historic and artistic items</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition of historic and artistic items</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2713_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Reception areas” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Reception areas” defined For purposes of this section, the term “reception areas” means the areas of the Harry S Truman Federal Building, located at 2201 C Street, Northwest, Washington, District of Columbia, known as the Diplomatic Reception Rooms (eighth floor), the Secretary of State’s offices (seventh floor), the Deputy Secretary of State’s offices (seventh floor), and the seventh floor reception area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>