<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2728" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2728/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2728/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2728"><akn:num>2728</akn:num><akn:heading>Crimes committed by diplomats</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2728. Crimes committed by diplomats(a) Annual report concerning diplomatic immunity(1) Report to Congress180 days after October 21, 1998, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State shall prepare and submit to the Congress, a report concerning diplomatic immunity entitled “Report on Cases Involving Diplomatic Immunity”.


(2) Content of reportIn addition to such other information as the Secretary of State may consider appropriate, the report under paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) The number of persons residing in the United States who enjoy full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.

(B) Each case involving an alien described in subparagraph (A) in which an appropriate authority of a State, a political subdivision of a State, or the United States reported to the Department of State that the authority had reasonable cause to believe the alien committed a serious criminal offense within the United States, and any additional information provided to the Secretary relating to other serious criminal offenses that any such authority had reasonable cause to believe the alien committed before the period covered by the report. The Secretary may omit from such report any matter the provision of which the Secretary reasonably believes would compromise a criminal investigation or prosecution or which would directly compromise law enforcement or intelligence sources or methods.

(C) Each case described in subparagraph (B) in which the Secretary of State has certified that a person enjoys full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.

(D) The number of United States citizens who are residing in a receiving state and who enjoy full immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of such state under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.

(E) Each case involving a United States citizen under subparag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2728_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report concerning diplomatic immunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report concerning diplomatic immunity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2728_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States policy concerning reform of diplomatic immunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States policy concerning reform of diplomatic immunity It is the sense of the Congress that the Secretary of State should explore, in appropriate fora, whether states should enter into agreements and adopt legislation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2728_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of diplomatic corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of diplomatic corps The Secretary should periodically notify each foreign mission of United States policies relating to criminal offenses committed by individuals with immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States under laws extending diplomatic privileges and immunities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>