<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2730" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2730/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2730/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2730"><akn:num>2730</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on funding the involuntary return of refugees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2730. Prohibition on funding the involuntary return of refugees(a) Prohibition(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), none of the funds made available to the Department of State, or the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund established in section 2601(c) of this title, may be available to effect the involuntary return by the United States of any person to a country in which the person has a well-founded fear of persecution on account of race, religion, nationality, membership in a particular social group, or political opinion.


(2) ExceptionThe prohibition in paragraph (1) does not apply to the return of any person on grounds recognized as precluding protection as a refugee under the United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees of July 28, 1951, and the Protocol Relating to the Status of Refugees of January 31, 1967, subject to the reservations contained in the United States Senate resolution of advice and consent to ratification of the Protocol.



(b) Congressional notification required in all casesNone of the funds made available to the Department of State, or the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund established in section 2601(c) of this title, may be available to effect the involuntary return by the United States of any person to any country unless the Secretary first notifies the appropriate congressional committees, except that, in the case of an emergency involving a threat to human life, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees as soon as practicable.


(c) Statutory constructionNothing in this section shall be construed as affecting activities of the Department of State that relate to removal proceedings under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.] or extradition.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2730_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2730_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional notification required in all cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Congressional notification required in all cases None of the funds made available to the Department of State, or the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund established in section 2601(c) of this title, may be available to effect the involuntary return by the United States of any person to any country unless the Secretary first notifies the appropriate congressional committees, except that, in the case of an emergency involving a threat to human life, the Secretary shall notify the appropriate congressional committees as soon as practicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2730_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statutory construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting activities of the Department of State that relate to removal proceedings under the Immigration and Nationality Act [8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.] or extradition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2730_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>