<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2731" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2731/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2731/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2731"><akn:num>2731</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and combating anti-Semitism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2731. Monitoring and combating anti-Semitism(a) Office to Monitor and Combat anti-Semitism(1) Establishment of OfficeThe Secretary shall establish within the Department of State an Office to Monitor and Combat anti-Semitism (in this section referred to as the “Office”).


(2) Head of Office(A) Special Envoy for Monitoring and Combating anti-SemitismThe head of the Office shall be the Special Envoy for Monitoring and Combating anti-Semitism (in this section referred to as the “Special Envoy”), who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Special Envoy shall report directly to the Secretary.


(B) Nomination of head of OfficeIf the President determines that such is appropriate, the President may nominate the Special Envoy from among officers and employees of the Department. Such officer or employee may not retain the position (or the responsibilities associated with such position) held by such officer or employee prior to the nomination of such officer or employee to the position of Special Envoy under this paragraph.



(3) DutiesThe Special Envoy shall serve as the primary advisor to, and coordinate efforts across, the United States Government relating to monitoring and combating anti-Semitism and anti-Semitic incitement that occur in foreign countries.


(4) Rank and status of ambassadorThe Special Envoy shall have the rank of ambassador.


(5) QualificationsThe Special Envoy should be a person of recognized distinction in the field of combating anti-Semitism.



(b) Purpose of OfficeUpon establishment, the Office shall assume the primary responsibility for—(1) monitoring and combating acts of anti-Semitism and anti-Semitic incitement that occur in foreign countries;

(2) coordinating and assisting in the preparation of that portion of the report required by sections 2151n(d)(7) and 2304(b) of this title relating to an assessment and description of the nature and extent of acts of anti-Semitism and anti-Semitic in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office to Monitor and Combat anti-Semitism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office to Monitor and Combat anti-Semitism</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of Office Upon establishment, the Office shall assume the primary responsibility for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2731_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultations The Special Envoy shall consult with domestic and international nongovernmental organizations and multilateral organizations and institutions, as the Special Envoy considers appropriate to fulfill the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>