<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2732" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2732/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2732/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2732"><akn:num>2732</akn:num><akn:heading>Public diplomacy responsibilities of the Department of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2732. Public diplomacy responsibilities of the Department of State(a) Integral componentThe Secretary of State shall make public diplomacy an integral component in the planning and execution of United States foreign policy.


(b) Coordination and development of strategyThe Secretary shall make every effort to—(1) coordinate, subject to the direction of the President, the public diplomacy activities of Federal agencies; and

(2) coordinate with the Broadcasting Board of Governors to—(A) develop a comprehensive and coherent strategy for the use of public diplomacy resources; and

(B) develop and articulate long-term measurable objectives for United States public diplomacy.



(c) ObjectivesThe strategy developed pursuant to subsection (b) shall include public diplomacy efforts targeting developed and developing countries and select and general audiences, using appropriate media to properly explain the foreign policy of the United States to the governments and populations of such countries, with the objectives of increasing support for United States policies and providing news and information. The Secretary shall, through the most effective mechanisms, counter misinformation and propaganda concerning the United States. The Secretary shall continue to articulate the importance of freedom, democracy, and human rights as fundamental principles underlying United States foreign policy goals.


(d) Identification of United States foreign assistanceIn cooperation with the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and other public and private assistance organizations and agencies, the Secretary should ensure that information relating to foreign assistance provided by the United States, nongovernmental organizations, and private entities of the United States is disseminated widely, and particularly, to the extent practicable, within countries and regions that receive such assistance. The Secretary should ensure that, to the extent practicable, projects funded</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2732_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integral component</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Integral component The Secretary of State shall make public diplomacy an integral component in the planning and execution of United States foreign policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2732_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and development of strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination and development of strategy The Secretary shall make every effort to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2732_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Objectives The strategy developed pursuant to subsection (b) shall include public diplomacy efforts targeting developed and developing countries and select and general audiences, using appropriate media to properly explain the foreign policy of the United States to the governments and populations of such countries, with the objectives of increasing support for United States policies and providing news and information. The Secretary shall, through the most effective mechanisms, counter misinformation and propaganda concerning the United States. The Secretary shall continue to articulate the importance of freedom, democracy, and human rights as fundamental principles underlying United States foreign policy goals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2732_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of United States foreign assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Identification of United States foreign assistance In cooperation with the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and other public and private assistance organizations and agencies, the Secretary should ensure that information relating to foreign assistance provided by the United States, nongovernmental organizations, and private entities of the United States is disseminated widely, and particularly, to the extent practicable, within countries and regions that receive such assistance. The Secretary should ensure that, to the extent practicable, projects funded by USAID not involving commodities, including projects implemented by private voluntary organizations, are identified as provided by the people of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>