<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2734a"><akn:num>2734a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities related to personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2734a. Authorities related to personnel(a) Extension of certain Foreign Service benefitsThe Secretary, or the head of any agency with respect to personnel of that agency, may extend to any individuals assigned, detailed, or deployed to carry out reconstruction and stabilization activities pursuant to section 2734 of this title (as added by section 1605 11 See References in Text note below. of this title), the benefits or privileges set forth in sections 3973, 4024, and 4081 of this title to the same extent and manner that such benefits and privileges are extended to members of the Foreign Service.


(b) Authority regarding detailsThe Secretary is authorized to accept details or assignments of any personnel, and any employee of a State or local government, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis for the purpose of carrying out this title,1 and the head of any agency is authorized to detail or assign personnel of such agency on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis to the Department of State for purposes of section 2734 of this title, as added by section 1605 1 of this title.


(Pub. L. 110–417, [div. A], title XVI, § 1606, Oct. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 4656.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 1605 of this title, referred to in text, means section 1605 of title XVI of Pub. L. 110–417.
This title, the first time appearing in subsec. (b), means title XVI of Pub. L. 110–417, [div. A], Oct. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 4652, known as the Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2008, which enacted this section, sections 2368 and 2734 of this title, and provisions set out as notes under this section and sections 2151 and 2368 of this title. For complete classification of this title to the Code, see Short Title of 2008 Amendment note set out under section 2151 of this title and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
DefinitionsPub. L. 110–417, [div. A], title XVI, § 1603, Oct. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 4653, provided that: 
“In this title [enactin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of certain Foreign Service benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Extension of certain Foreign Service benefits The Secretary, or the head of any agency with respect to personnel of that agency, may extend to any individuals assigned, detailed, or deployed to carry out reconstruction and stabilization activities pursuant to section 2734 of this title (as added by section 1605 11 See References in Text note below. of this title), the benefits or privileges set forth in sections 3973, 4024, and 4081 of this title to the same extent and manner that such benefits and privileges are extended to members of the Foreign Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority regarding details</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority regarding details The Secretary is authorized to accept details or assignments of any personnel, and any employee of a State or local government, on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis for the purpose of carrying out this title,1 and the head of any agency is authorized to detail or assign personnel of such agency on a reimbursable or nonreimbursable basis to the Department of State for purposes of section 2734 of this title, as added by section 1605 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>