<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2734f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2734f"><akn:num>2734f</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic staffing plan for the Department of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2734f. Strategic staffing plan for the Department of State(a) In generalNot later than 18 months after December 27, 2021, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a comprehensive 5-year strategic staffing plan for the Department that is aligned with and furthers the objectives of the National Security Strategy of the United States of America issued in December 2017, or any subsequent strategy issued not later than 18 months after December 27, 2021, which shall include the following:(1) A dataset displaying comprehensive workforce data, including all shortages in bureaus described in GAO report GAO–19–220, for all current and planned employees of the Department, disaggregated by—(A) Foreign Service officer and Foreign Service specialist rank;

(B) civil service job skill code, grade level, and bureau of assignment;

(C) contracted employees, including the equivalent job skill code and bureau of assignment;

(D) employees hired under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations, including the equivalent grade and job skill code and bureau of assignment of such employee; and

(E) overseas region.


(2) Recommendations on the number of Foreign Service officers disaggregated by service cone that should be posted at each United States diplomatic post and in the District of Columbia, with a detailed basis for such recommendations.

(3) Recommendations on the number of civil service officers that should be employed by the Department, with a detailed basis for such recommendations.


(b) MaintenanceThe dataset required under subsection (a)(1) shall be maintained and updated on a regular basis.


(c) ConsultationThe Secretary shall lead the development of the plan required under subsection (a) but may consult or partner with private sector entities with expertise in labor economics, management, or human resources, as well as organi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 18 months after December 27, 2021, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a comprehensive 5-year strategic staffing plan for the Department that is aligned with and furthers the objectives of the National Security Strategy of the United States of America issued in December 2017, or any subsequent strategy issued not later than 18 months after December 27, 2021, which shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance The dataset required under subsection (a)(1) shall be maintained and updated on a regular basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation The Secretary shall lead the development of the plan required under subsection (a) but may consult or partner with private sector entities with expertise in labor economics, management, or human resources, as well as organizations familiar with the demands and needs of the Department’s workforce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2734f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 120 days after December 27, 2021, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding root causes of Foreign Service and civil service shortages, the effect of such shortages on national security objectives, and the Department’s plan to implement recommendations described in GAO–19–220.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>