<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2735"><akn:num>2735</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign relations exchange programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2735. Foreign relations exchange programs(a) AuthorityThe Secretary may establish exchange programs under which officers or employees of the Department of State, including individuals appointed under title 5 and members of the Foreign Service (as defined in section 3903 of this title), may be assigned, for not more than 1 year, to a position with any foreign government or international entity that permits an employee to be assigned to a position with the Department of State.


(b) Salary and benefits(1) Members of Foreign ServiceDuring a period in which a member of the Foreign Service is participating in an exchange program authorized pursuant to subsection (a), such member shall be entitled to the salary and benefits to which such member would receive but for the assignment under this section.


(2) Non-Foreign Service employees of DepartmentAn employee of the Department of State other than a member of the Foreign Service participating in an exchange program authorized pursuant to subsection (a) shall be treated in all respects as if detailed to an international organization pursuant to section 3343(c) of title 5.


(3) Foreign participantsThe salary and benefits of an employee of a foreign government or international entity participating in an exchange program authorized pursuant to subsection (a) shall be paid by such government or entity during the period in which such employee is participating in such program, and shall not be reimbursed by the Department of State.



(c) Non-reciprocal assignmentThe Secretary may authorize a non-reciprocal assignment of personnel pursuant to this section, with or without reimbursement from the foreign government or international entity for all or part of the salary and other expenses payable during such assignment, if such is in the interests of the United States.


(d) Rule of constructionNothing in this section may be construed to authorize the appointment as an officer or employee of the United States of—(1) an individual</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Secretary may establish exchange programs under which officers or employees of the Department of State, including individuals appointed under title 5 and members of the Foreign Service (as defined in section 3903 of this title), may be assigned, for not more than 1 year, to a position with any foreign government or international entity that permits an employee to be assigned to a position with the Department of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary and benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Salary and benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-reciprocal assignment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Non-reciprocal assignment The Secretary may authorize a non-reciprocal assignment of personnel pursuant to this section, with or without reimbursement from the foreign government or international entity for all or part of the salary and other expenses payable during such assignment, if such is in the interests of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize the appointment as an officer or employee of the United States of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>