<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2735b"><akn:num>2735b</akn:num><akn:heading>National Museum of American Diplomacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2735b. National Museum of American Diplomacy(a) Activities(1) Support authorizedThe Secretary is authorized to provide, by contract, grant, or otherwise, for the performance of appropriate museum visitor and educational outreach services and related events, including—(A) organizing programs and conference activities;

(B) creating, designing, and installing exhibits; and

(C) conducting museum shop services and food services in the public exhibition and related physical and virtual space utilized by the National Museum of American Diplomacy.


(2) Recovery of costsThe Secretary of State is authorized to retain the proceeds obtained from customary and appropriate fees charged for the use of facilities, including venue rental for events consistent with the activities described in subsection (a)(1) and museum shop services and food services at the National Museum of American Diplomacy. Such proceeds shall be retained as a recovery of the costs of operating the Museum, credited to a designated Department account that exists for the purpose of funding the Museum and its programs and activities, and shall remain available until expended.



(b) Disposition of documents, artifacts, and other articles(1) PropertyAll historic documents, artifacts, or other articles acquired by the Department of State for the permanent museum collection and determined by the Secretary of State to be suitable for display by the National Museum of American Diplomacy shall be considered to be the property of the United States Government and shall be subject to disposition solely in accordance with this subsection.


(2) Sale, trade, or transferWhenever the Secretary of State makes a determination described in paragraph (3) with respect to a document, artifact, or other article described in paragraph (1), taking into account considerations such as the Museum’s collections management policy and best professional museum practice, the Secretary may sell at fair market value, trade, or transfer suc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of documents, artifacts, and other articles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disposition of documents, artifacts, and other articles</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>