<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2735a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2735a"><akn:num>2735a</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Integration and Normalization F</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2735a. Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Integration and Normalization Fora and Agreements(a) OfficeThere is established within the Department of State the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Integration and Normalization Fora and Agreements (referred to in this section as the “Regional Integration Office”).


(b) Leadership(1)1 Special EnvoyThe Regional Integration Office shall be headed by the Special Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Normalization Agreements, who shall—(A) be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate; and

(B) report directly to the Secretary of State.



(c) Rank and status of ambassadorThe Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.


(d) DutiesThe Special Envoy shall—(1) lead diplomatic engagement—(A) to strengthen and expand the Negev Forum, the Abraham Accords, and related normalization agreements with Israel, including promoting initiatives that benefit the people of key partners in regional integration or other regional actors in order to encourage such expansion; and

(B) to support the work of regional integration;


(2) implement the policy of the United States to expand normalization and support greater regional integration—(A) within the Middle East and North Africa; and

(B) between the Middle East and North Africa and other key regions, including sub-Saharan Africa, the Indo-Pacific region, and beyond;


(3) work to deliver tangible economic and security benefits for the citizens of Abraham Accords countries, Negev Forum countries, and countries that are members of other related normalization agreements;

(4) serve as the ministerial liaison for the United States to the Negev Forum and other emerging normalization and integration fora, as necessary, and provide senior representation at events, steering committee meetings, and other relevant diplomatic engage</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office There is established within the Department of State the Office of the Special Presidential Envoy for the Abraham Accords, Negev Forum, and Related Integration and Normalization Fora and Agreements (referred to in this section as the “Regional Integration Office”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leadership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Leadership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rank and status of ambassador</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rank and status of ambassador The Special Envoy shall have the rank and status of ambassador.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties The Special Envoy shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation The Special Envoy shall not be a dual-hatted official with other responsibilities within the Department of State or the executive branch.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that whole-of-government resources should be harnessed to ensure the successful performance by the Special Envoy of the duties described in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Strategy Not later than 180 days after December 22, 2023, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives an interagency strategy to use the economic tools of the Federal Government to promote regional integration through targeted investment as described in subsection (d)(12).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Termination This section shall terminate on the date that is 6 years after December 22, 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2735a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rule of construction If, on December 22, 2023, an individual has already been designated, consistent with the requirements and responsibilities described in subsections (b), (c), and (d) and section 2651a of this title, the requirements under subsection (b) shall be considered to be satisfied with respect to such individual until the date on which such individual no longer serves as the Special Envoy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>