<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2736b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2736b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2736b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2736b"><akn:num>2736b</akn:num><akn:heading>Leadership engagement and accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2736b. Leadership engagement and accountability(a) Reward and recognize efforts to promote diversity and inclusion(1) In generalThe Secretary shall implement performance and advancement requirements that reward and recognize the efforts of individuals in senior positions and supervisors in the Department in fostering an inclusive environment and cultivating talent consistent with merit system principles, such as through participation in mentoring programs or sponsorship initiatives, recruitment events, and other similar opportunities.


(2) Outreach eventsThe Secretary shall create opportunities for individuals in senior positions and supervisors in the Department to participate in outreach events and to discuss issues relating to diversity and inclusion with the workforce on a regular basis, including with employee resource groups.



(b) External advisory committees and boardsFor each external advisory committee or board to which individuals in senior positions in the Department appoint members, the Secretary is strongly encouraged by Congress to ensure such external advisory committee or board is developed, reviewed, and carried out by qualified teams that represent the diversity of the organization.


(Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LIV, § 5404, Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2373.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definitions of “Secretary” and “Department” as used in this section, see section 5002 of Pub. L. 117–81, set out as a note under section 263c of this title.
For definitions of “diversity” and “workforce” as used in this section, see section 5401 of Pub. L. 117–81, set out as a note under section 2736 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2736b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reward and recognize efforts to promote diversity and inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reward and recognize efforts to promote diversity and inclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2736b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>External advisory committees and boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) External advisory committees and boards For each external advisory committee or board to which individuals in senior positions in the Department appoint members, the Secretary is strongly encouraged by Congress to ensure such external advisory committee or board is developed, reviewed, and carried out by qualified teams that represent the diversity of the organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>