<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2766" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2766/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2766/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2766"><akn:num>2766</akn:num><akn:heading>Security assistance surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2766. Security assistance surveys(a) Statement of findings and policyThe Congress finds that security assistance surveys prepared by the United States for foreign countries have had a significant impact on subsequent military procurement decisions of those countries. It is the policy of the United States that the results of security assistance surveys conducted by the United States clearly do not represent a commitment by the United States to provide any military equipment to any foreign country. Further, recommendations in such surveys should be consistent with the arms export control policy provided for in this chapter.


(b) Reporting requirementsAs part of the quarterly report required by section 2776(a) of this title, the President shall include a list of all security assistance surveys authorized during the preceding calendar quarter, specifying the country with respect to which the survey was or will be conducted, the purpose of the survey, and the number of United States Government personnel who participated or will participate in the survey.


(c) Submission of surveys to CongressUpon a request of the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives or the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the President shall submit to that committee copies of security assistance surveys conducted by United States Government personnel.


(d) “Security assistance surveys” definedAs used in this section, the term “security assistance surveys” means any survey or study conducted in a foreign country by United States Government personnel for the purpose of assessing the needs of that country for security assistance, and includes defense requirement surveys, site surveys, general surveys or studies, and engineering assessment surveys.


(Pub. L. 90–629, ch. 2, § 26, as added Pub. L. 95–384, § 19, Sept. 26, 1978, 92 Stat. 740; amended Pub. L. 99–83, title I, § 114, Aug. 8, 1985, 99 Stat. 198; Pub. L. 103–437, § 9(a)(7), No</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of findings and policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Statement of findings and policy The Congress finds that security assistance surveys prepared by the United States for foreign countries have had a significant impact on subsequent military procurement decisions of those countries. It is the policy of the United States that the results of security assistance surveys conducted by the United States clearly do not represent a commitment by the United States to provide any military equipment to any foreign country. Further, recommendations in such surveys should be consistent with the arms export control policy provided for in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reporting requirements As part of the quarterly report required by section 2776(a) of this title, the President shall include a list of all security assistance surveys authorized during the preceding calendar quarter, specifying the country with respect to which the survey was or will be conducted, the purpose of the survey, and the number of United States Government personnel who participated or will participate in the survey.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of surveys to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission of surveys to Congress Upon a request of the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives or the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the President shall submit to that committee copies of security assistance surveys conducted by United States Government personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2766_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Security assistance surveys” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Security assistance surveys” defined As used in this section, the term “security assistance surveys” means any survey or study conducted in a foreign country by United States Government personnel for the purpose of assessing the needs of that country for security assistance, and includes defense requirement surveys, site surveys, general surveys or studies, and engineering assessment surveys.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>