<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2767" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2767/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2767/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2767"><akn:num>2767</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of President to enter into cooperative projects with friendly foreign countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2767. Authority of President to enter into cooperative projects with friendly foreign countries(a) Authority of PresidentThe President may enter into a cooperative project agreement with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or with one or more member countries of that Organization.


(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) the term “cooperative project”, in the case of an agreement with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or with one or more member countries of that Organization, means a jointly managed arrangement, described in a written agreement among the parties, which is undertaken in order to further the objectives of standardization, rationalization, and interoperability of the armed forces of North Atlantic Treaty Organization member countries and which provides—(A) for one or more of the other participants to share with the United States the costs of research on and development, testing, evaluation, or joint production (including follow-on support) of certain defense articles;

(B) for concurrent production in the United States and in another member country of a defense article jointly developed in accordance with subparagraph (A); or

(C) for procurement by the United States of a defense article or defense service from another member country or for procurement by the United States of munitions from the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or a subsidiary of such organization;


(2) the term “cooperative project”, in the case of an agreement entered into under subsection (j), means a jointly managed arrangement, described in a written agreement among the parties, which is undertaken in order to enhance the ongoing multinational effort of the participants to improve the conventional defense capabilities of the participants and which provides—(A) for one or more of the other participants to share with the United States the costs of research on and development, testing, evaluation, or joint production (including follow-on support) of certain defense ar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of President The President may enter into a cooperative project agreement with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or with one or more member countries of that Organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements for equitable share of costs; limiting nature of agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements for equitable share of costs; limiting nature of agreements Each agreement for a cooperative project shall provide that the United States and each of the other participants will contribute to the cooperative project its equitable share of the full cost of such cooperative project and will receive an equitable share of the results of such cooperative project. The full costs of such cooperative project shall include overhead costs, administrative costs, and costs of claims. The United States and the other participants may contribute their equitable shares of the full cost of such cooperative project in funds or in defense articles or defense services needed for such cooperative project. Military assistance and financing received from the United States Government may not be used by any other participant to provide its share of the cost of such cooperative project. Such agreements shall provide that no requirement shall be imposed by a participant for worksharing or other in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contractual or other obligation; preconditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contractual or other obligation; preconditions The President may enter into contracts or incur other obligations for a cooperative project on behalf of the other participants, without charge to any appropriation or contract authorization, if each of the other participants in the cooperative project agrees (1) to pay its equitable share of the contract or other obligation, and (2) to make such funds available in such amounts and at such times as may be required by the contract or other obligation and to pay any damages and costs that may accrue from the performance of or cancellation of the contract or other obligation in advance of the time such payments, damages, or costs are due.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of charges; administrative surcharges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver of charges; administrative surcharges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmission of numbered certification to Congress respecting proposed agreement; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transmission of numbered certification to Congress respecting proposed agreement; contents Not less than 30 days before a cooperative project agreement is signed on behalf of the United States, the President shall transmit to the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the chairman of the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, a numbered certification with respect to such proposed agreement, setting forth—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting and certification requirements applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting and certification requirements applicable In the case of a cooperative project with a North Atlantic Treaty Organization country, section,33 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. 2776(b) of this title shall not apply to sales made under section 2761 or 2762 of this title and to production and exports made pursuant to cooperative projects under this section, and section 2776(c) of this title shall not apply to the issuance of licenses or other approvals under section 2778 of this title, if such sales are made, such production and exports ensue, or such licenses or approvals are issued, as part of a cooperative project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory provisions applicable to sales</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Statutory provisions applicable to sales The authority under this section is in addition to the authority under sections 2761 and 2762 of this title and under any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements entered into before October 1, 1985</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Agreements entered into before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2767_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative project agreements with friendly foreign countries not members of NATO</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative project agreements with friendly foreign countries not members of NATO</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>