<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_276bb"><akn:num>276bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of funds and property from Mrs. Kermit Roosevelt; purpose and use; disbursement and inves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 276bb. Acceptance of funds and property from Mrs. Kermit Roosevelt; purpose and use; disbursement and investment of fund
The board is authorized to accept from Mrs. Kermit Roosevelt such money and property as she may tender, to receipt therefor on behalf of the United States, and to deposit the funds so received in the Treasury of the United States as the original corpus of a trust fund, to be known as the Kermit Roosevelt fund, which shall be used for the purpose of fostering a better understanding and a closer relationship between the military forces of the United States and those of the United Kingdom by sponsoring lectures or courses of instruction to be delivered by officers of the British Army at the United States Military Academy and elsewhere in the United States and by officers of the United States Army at Sandhurst Royal Military College and elsewhere in the United Kingdom or, should such exchange lectures prove or become impracticable or unnecessary for any reason, by such other application of the funds as the board, with the approval of the Secretary of the Army may determine. The original corpus of the fund and the income therefrom may be disbursed at the discretion of the board in furtherance of the stated purpose, and shall be subject to investment and reinvestment as provided in section 276cc of this title.
(July 2, 1945, ch. 228, § 2, 59 Stat. 316; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 225 of Title 5 prior to the general revision and enactment of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, by Pub. L. 89–554, § 1, Sept. 6, 1966, 80 Stat. 378.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Department of War designated Department of the Army and title of Secretary of War changed to Secretary of the Army by section 205(a) of act July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, 61 Stat. 501. Section 205(a) of act July 26, 1947, was repealed by section 53 of ac</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>