<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276c–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276c–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/276c–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_276c_2"><akn:num>276c–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee benefits for United States citizen-representatives to international financial institutions;</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 276c–2. Employee benefits for United States citizen-representatives to international financial institutions; Treasury Department as collecting, accounting, and depositing agency for employee payments; contributions from appropriated funds
Notwithstanding the provisions of any other law, the Executive Directors and Directors and their alternates, representing the United States in the International Monetary Fund, the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development, the Inter-American Development Bank, the Bank for Economic Cooperation and Development in the Middle East and North Africa, the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Fund, the African Development Bank, and the Inter-American Investment Corporation, shall, if they are citizens of the United States, in the discretion of the Secretary of the Treasury, each be eligible on the basis of such service and the total compensation received therefor, for all employee benefits afforded employees in the civil service of the United States. The Treasury Department shall serve as the employing office for collecting, accounting for, and depositing in the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund, Employees Life Insurance Fund, and Employees Health Benefits Fund, all retirement and health insurance benefits payments made by these employees, and shall make any necessary agency contributions from funds appropriated to the Department of the Treasury.
(Pub. L. 91–599, ch. 5, § 51, Dec. 30, 1970, 84 Stat. 1659; Pub. L. 95–612, § 4, Nov. 8, 1978, 92 Stat. 3092; Pub. L. 97–35, title XIII, § 1342(d), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 743; Pub. L. 98–473, title I, § 101(1) [title I], Oct. 12, 1984, 98 Stat. 1884, 1885; Pub. L. 101–513, title V, § 562(c)(10)(C), Nov. 5, 1990, 104 Stat. 2036; Pub. L. 104–208, div. A, title I, § 101(c) [title VII, § 710(c)], Sept. 30, 1996, 110 Stat. 3009–121, 3009–181.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Amendment by Pub. L. 98–473 is based on </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>