<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/277d–45" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/277d–45/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/277d–45/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_277d_45"><akn:num>277d–45</akn:num><akn:heading>New Treaty Minute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 277d–45. New Treaty Minute(a) Congressional statementIn light of the existing threat to the environment and to public health and safety within the United States as a result of the river and ocean pollution in the San Diego-Tijuana border region, the Secretary is requested to give the highest priority to the negotiation and execution of a new Treaty Minute, or a modification of Treaty Minute 283, consistent with the provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title, in order that the other provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title to address such pollution may be implemented as soon as possible.


(b) Negotiation(1) InitiationThe Secretary is requested to initiate negotiations with Mexico, within 60 days after November 7, 2000, for a new Treaty Minute or a modification of Treaty Minute 283 consistent with the provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title.


(2) ImplementationImplementation of a new Treaty Minute or of a modification of Treaty Minute 283 under sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title shall be subject to the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(3) Matters to be addressedA new Treaty Minute or a modification of Treaty Minute 283 under paragraph (1) should address, at a minimum, the following:(A) The siting of treatment facilities in Mexico and in the United States.

(B) Provision for the secondary treatment of effluent from the IWTP at a Mexican facility if such treatment is not provided for at a facility in the United States.

(C) Provision for additional capacity for advanced primary and secondary treatment of additional sewage emanating from the Tijuana River area, Mexico, in addition to the treatment capacity for the advanced primary effluent from the IWTP at the Mexican facility.

(D) Provision for any and all approvals from Mexican authorities necessary to facilitate water quality verification and enforcement at the Mexican facility.

(E) Any terms and conditions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_277d_45_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional statement In light of the existing threat to the environment and to public health and safety within the United States as a result of the river and ocean pollution in the San Diego-Tijuana border region, the Secretary is requested to give the highest priority to the negotiation and execution of a new Treaty Minute, or a modification of Treaty Minute 283, consistent with the provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title, in order that the other provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title to address such pollution may be implemented as soon as possible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_277d_45_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Negotiation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_277d_45_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation In light of the continuing threat to the environment and to public health and safety within the United States as a result of the river and ocean pollution in the San Diego-Tijuana border region, the Commission is requested to give the highest priority to the implementation of Treaty Minute 311 to the Treaty for the Utilization of Waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, dated February 3, 1944, which establishes a framework for the siting of a treatment facility in Mexico to provide for the secondary treatment of effluent from the IWTP at the Mexican facility, to provide for additional capacity for advanced primary and secondary treatment of additional sewage emanating from the Tijuana River area, Mexico, and to meet the water quality standards of Mexico, the United States, and the State of California consistent with the provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of this title, in order that the other provisions of sections 277d–43 to 277d–46 of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>