<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2795a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2795a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2795a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2795a"><akn:num>2795a</akn:num><akn:heading>Use and transfer of items procured by Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2795a. Use and transfer of items procured by Fund(a) AuthorizationNo defense article or defense service acquired by the Secretary of Defense under this subchapter may be transferred to any foreign country or international organization unless such transfer is authorized by this chapter, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.], or other law.


(b) Temporary useThe President may authorize the temporary use by the United States Armed Forces of defense articles and defense services acquired under this subchapter prior to their transfer to a foreign country or international organization, if such is necessary to meet national defense requirements and the United States Armed Forces bear the costs of operation and maintenance of such articles or services while in their use and the costs of restoration or replacement upon the termination of such use.


(c) Storage, maintenance and other costsExcept as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Fund may be used to pay for storage, maintenance, and other costs related to the preservation and preparation for transfer of defense articles and defense services acquired under this subchapter prior to their transfer, as well as the administrative costs of the Department of Defense incurred in the acquisition of such items to the extent not reimbursed pursuant to section 2792(b) of this title.


(Pub. L. 90–629, ch. 5, § 52, as added Pub. L. 97–113, title I, § 108(a), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1523.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 90–629, Oct. 22, 1968, 82 Stat. 1321, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2751 of this title and Tables.
The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 87–195, Sept. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 424, which is classified principally to chapter 32 (§ 2151 et seq.) of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2795a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization No defense article or defense service acquired by the Secretary of Defense under this subchapter may be transferred to any foreign country or international organization unless such transfer is authorized by this chapter, the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.], or other law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2795a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Temporary use The President may authorize the temporary use by the United States Armed Forces of defense articles and defense services acquired under this subchapter prior to their transfer to a foreign country or international organization, if such is necessary to meet national defense requirements and the United States Armed Forces bear the costs of operation and maintenance of such articles or services while in their use and the costs of restoration or replacement upon the termination of such use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2795a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Storage, maintenance and other costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Storage, maintenance and other costs Except as provided in subsection (b) of this section, the Fund may be used to pay for storage, maintenance, and other costs related to the preservation and preparation for transfer of defense articles and defense services acquired under this subchapter prior to their transfer, as well as the administrative costs of the Department of Defense incurred in the acquisition of such items to the extent not reimbursed pursuant to section 2792(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>