<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2797a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2797a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2797a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2797a"><akn:num>2797a</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of transfer of missile equipment or technology by United States persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2797a. Denial of transfer of missile equipment or technology by United States persons(a) Sanctions(1) If the President determines that a United States person knowingly—(A) exports, transfers, or otherwise engages in the trade of any item on the MTCR Annex, in violation of the provisions of section 2778 of this title, section 4604 or 4605 11 See References in Text note below. of title 50 or any regulations or orders issued under any such provisions,

(B) conspires to or attempts to engage in such export, transfer, or trade, or

(C) facilitates such export, transfer, or trade by any other person,


then the President shall impose the applicable sanctions described in paragraph (2).

(2) The sanctions which apply to a United States person under paragraph (1) are the following:(A) If the item on the MTCR Annex involved in the export, transfer, or trade is missile equipment or technology within category II of the MTCR Annex, then the President shall deny to such United States person for a period of 2 years—(i) United States Government contracts relating to missile equipment or technology; and

(ii) licenses for the transfer of missile equipment or technology controlled under this chapter.


(B) If the item on the MTCR Annex involved in the export, transfer, or trade is missile equipment or technology within category I of the MTCR, then the President shall deny to such United States person for a period of not less than 2 years—(i) all United States Government contracts, and

(ii) all export licenses and agreements for items on the United States Munitions List.




(b) Discretionary sanctionsIn the case of any determination made pursuant to subsection (a), the President may pursue any penalty provided in section 2778(c) of this title.


(c) PresumptionIn determining whether to apply sanctions under subsection (a) to a United States person involved in the export, transfer, or trade of an item on the MTCR Annex, it should be a rebuttable presumption that such item is desig</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2797a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2797a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discretionary sanctions In the case of any determination made pursuant to subsection (a), the President may pursue any penalty provided in section 2778(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2797a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presumption In determining whether to apply sanctions under subsection (a) to a United States person involved in the export, transfer, or trade of an item on the MTCR Annex, it should be a rebuttable presumption that such item is designed for use in a missile listed in the MTCR Annex if the President determines that the final destination of the item is a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined, for purposes of 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by “section”. 4605(j)(1)(A) 1 of title 50, has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2797a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under subsection (a) with respect to a product or service if the President certifies to the Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>