<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/2803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2803"><akn:num>2803</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2803. Federal participation(a) Congressional authorization; proposalsThe Federal Government may participate in an international exposition proposed to be held in the United States only upon the authorization of the Congress. If the President finds that Federal participation is in the national interest, he shall transmit to the Congress his proposal for such participation, which proposal shall include—(1) evidence that the international exposition has met the criteria for Federal recognition and, pursuant to section 2802 of this title, it has been so recognized;

(2) a statement that the international exposition has been registered by the BIE; and

(3) a plan prepared by the Secretary of Commerce in cooperation with other interested departments and agencies of the Federal Government for Federal participation in the exposition. The Secretary of Commerce shall include in such plan any documentation described in subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section, a rendering of any design described in subsection (b)(1)(B) of this section, and any recommendation based on the determination under subsection (b)(1)(C) of this section.


(b) Construction of Federal pavilion(1) In developing a plan under subsection (a)(3) of this section the Secretary of Commerce shall consider whether the plan should include the construction of a Federal pavilion. If the Secretary of Commerce determines that a Federal pavilion should be constructed, he shall request the Administrator of General Services (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Administrator”) to determine, in consultation with such Secretary, whether there is a federally endorsed need for a permanent structure in the area of the exposition. If the Administrator determines that any such need exists—(A) the Administrator shall fully document such determination, including the identification of the need, and shall transmit such documentation to the Secretary of Commerce;

(B) the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Admin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional authorization; proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional authorization; proposals The Federal Government may participate in an international exposition proposed to be held in the United States only upon the authorization of the Congress. If the President finds that Federal participation is in the national interest, he shall transmit to the Congress his proposal for such participation, which proposal shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction of Federal pavilion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction of Federal pavilion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for Federal pavilion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations for Federal pavilion The enactment of a specific authorization of appropriations shall be required—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisites and temporary nature of Federal pavilion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requisites and temporary nature of Federal pavilion For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>