<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/284w" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/284w/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/284w/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284w"><akn:num>284w</akn:num><akn:heading>Multilateral debt relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284w. Multilateral debt relief(a) Authorization of contributionThe Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to contribute, on behalf of the United States, not more than $356,000,000 to the International Development Association for the purpose of funding debt relief under the Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative in the period governed by the fifteenth replenishment of resources of the International Development Association, subject to obtaining the necessary appropriations and without prejudice to any funding arrangements in existence on June 24, 2009.


(b) AppropriationsIn order to pay for the United States contribution provided for in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated, without fiscal year limitation, not more than $356,000,000 for payment by the Secretary of the Treasury.


(c) Multilateral Debt Relief InitiativeIn this section, the term “Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative” means the proposal set out in the G8 Finance Ministers’ Communique entitled “Conclusions on Development,” done at London, June 11, 2005, and reaffirmed by G8 Heads of State at the Gleneagles Summit on July 8, 2005.


(Pub. L. 86–565, § 25, as added Pub. L. 111–32, title XI, § 1109(a), June 24, 2009, 123 Stat. 1901.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284w_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of contribution The Secretary of the Treasury is authorized to contribute, on behalf of the United States, not more than $356,000,000 to the International Development Association for the purpose of funding debt relief under the Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative in the period governed by the fifteenth replenishment of resources of the International Development Association, subject to obtaining the necessary appropriations and without prejudice to any funding arrangements in existence on June 24, 2009.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284w_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriations In order to pay for the United States contribution provided for in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated, without fiscal year limitation, not more than $356,000,000 for payment by the Secretary of the Treasury.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284w_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative In this section, the term “Multilateral Debt Relief Initiative” means the proposal set out in the G8 Finance Ministers’ Communique entitled “Conclusions on Development,” done at London, June 11, 2005, and reaffirmed by G8 Heads of State at the Gleneagles Summit on July 8, 2005.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>