<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290h–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290h–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290h–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290h_5"><akn:num>290h–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290h–5. Management of Foundation(a) Board of directors; membership; designation of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson; appointment considerations; term; vacancies(1) The management of the Foundation shall be vested in a board of directors (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”) composed of seven members appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The President shall designate one member of the Board to serve as Chairperson of the Board and one member to serve as Vice Chairperson of the Board. Five members of the Board shall be appointed from private life. Two members of the Board shall be appointed from among officers and employees of agencies of the United States concerned with African affairs. All members of the Board shall be appointed on the basis of their understanding of and sensitivity to community level development processes. Members of the Board shall be appointed so that no more than four members of the Board are members of any one political party.

(2) Members of the Board shall be appointed for terms of six years, except that of the members first appointed, as designated by the President at the time of their appointment, two shall be appointed for terms of two years and two shall be appointed for terms of four years. A member of the Board appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which that member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term. Upon the expiration of his or her term a member shall continue to serve until a successor is appointed and shall have qualified.


(b) Compensation, actual, necessary, and transportation expensesMembers of the Board shall serve without additional compensation, but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses not exceeding $100 per day, and for transportation expenses, while engaged in their duties on behalf of the Foundation.


(c) QuorumA majority of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290h_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of directors; membership; designation of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson; appointment considerations; term; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Board of directors; membership; designation of Chairperson and Vice Chairperson; appointment considerations; term; vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290h_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation, actual, necessary, and transportation expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation, actual, necessary, and transportation expenses Members of the Board shall serve without additional compensation, but may be reimbursed for actual and necessary expenses not exceeding $100 per day, and for transportation expenses, while engaged in their duties on behalf of the Foundation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290h_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Quorum A majority of the Board shall constitute a quorum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290h_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>President of Foundation; appointment and compensation; employment of experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) President of Foundation; appointment and compensation; employment of experts and consultants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290h_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory council; membership; appointment considerations; consultations with council; compensation, travel, and other expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advisory council; membership; appointment considerations; consultations with council; compensation, travel, and other expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>