<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290j"><akn:num>290j</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290j. Establishment of the Fund(a) Agreement with Government of India; program purposesThe President is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Government of India for the establishment of a fund (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Fund”) which would provide grants and other assistance for cultural, educational, and scientific programs of mutual interest. Such programs may include exchanges of persons, exchanges of information, and other programs of study, research, and scholarly cooperation. The agreement may also provide for the establishment of an endowment, a foundation, or other means to carry out the purposes of the agreement.


(b) United States representativesThe United States representatives on any board or other entity created in accordance with the agreement to administer the Fund shall be designated by the President predominately from among representatives of United States Government agencies, including those administering programs which may be supported in whole or in part by the Fund.


(c) Funding of programsUnited States Government agencies carrying out programs of the types specified in subsection (a) may receive amounts directly from the Fund for use in carrying out those programs.


(Pub. L. 98–164, title IX, § 902, Nov. 22, 1983, 97 Stat. 1051.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 98–164, title IX, § 901, Nov. 22, 1983, 97 Stat. 1051, provided that: “This title [enacting this subchapter] may be cited as the ‘United States-India Fund for Cultural, Educational, and Scientific Cooperation Act’.”


Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 12517. Delegation Concerning United States-India Fund for Cultural, Educational, and Scientific Cooperation
Ex. Ord. No. 12517, May 29, 1985, 50 F.R. 23105, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and statutes of the United States of America, including section 301 of Title 3 of the United States Code, and in order to delegate certain functions</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement with Government of India; program purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agreement with Government of India; program purposes The President is authorized to enter into an agreement with the Government of India for the establishment of a fund (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Fund”) which would provide grants and other assistance for cultural, educational, and scientific programs of mutual interest. Such programs may include exchanges of persons, exchanges of information, and other programs of study, research, and scholarly cooperation. The agreement may also provide for the establishment of an endowment, a foundation, or other means to carry out the purposes of the agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United States representatives The United States representatives on any board or other entity created in accordance with the agreement to administer the Fund shall be designated by the President predominately from among representatives of United States Government agencies, including those administering programs which may be supported in whole or in part by the Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding of programs United States Government agencies carrying out programs of the types specified in subsection (a) may receive amounts directly from the Fund for use in carrying out those programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>