<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/290m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290m"><akn:num>290m</akn:num><akn:heading>North American Development Bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290m. North American Development Bank(a) Acceptance of membershipThe President is hereby authorized to accept membership for the United States in the North American Development Bank (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Bank”) provided for in Chapter II of the Border Environment Cooperation Agreement (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Cooperation Agreement”).


(b) Subscription of stock(1) Subscription authority(A) In generalThe Secretary of the Treasury may subscribe on behalf of the United States up to 150,000 shares of the capital stock of the Bank.


(B) Effectiveness of subscriptionExcept as provided in paragraph (3), any such subscription shall be effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriations Acts.



(2) Limitations on authorization of appropriationsFor payment by the Secretary of the Treasury of the subscription of the United States for shares described in paragraph (1), there are authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000,000 ($225,000,000 of which may be used for paid-in capital and $1,275,000,000 of which may be used for callable capital) without fiscal year limitation.


(3) Funding; limitation on callable capital subscriptions(A) FundingFor fiscal year 1995, the Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to the Bank out of any sums in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated the sum of $56,250,000 for the paid-in portion of the United States share of the capital stock of the Bank, 10 percent of which may be transferred by the Bank to the President pursuant to section 290m–2 of this title to pay for the cost of direct and guaranteed Federal loans.


(B) Limitation on callable capital subscriptionsFor fiscal year 1995, the Secretary of the Treasury shall subscribe to the callable capital portion of the United States share of the capital stock of the Bank in an amount not to exceed $318,750,000.



(4) Disposition of net income distributed by the facilityAny payment made to the United State</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptance of membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Acceptance of membership The President is hereby authorized to accept membership for the United States in the North American Development Bank (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Bank”) provided for in Chapter II of the Border Environment Cooperation Agreement (hereafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Cooperation Agreement”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subscription of stock</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subscription of stock</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of Board members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation of Board members No person shall be entitled to receive any salary or other compensation from the Bank or the United States for services as a Board member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Bretton Woods Agreements Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of Bretton Woods Agreements Act The provisions of section 4 of the Bretton Woods Agreements Act [22 U.S.C. 286b] shall apply with respect to the Bank to the same extent as with respect to the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Monetary Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions Unless authorized by law, neither the President nor any person or agency shall, on behalf of the United States—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Reserve banks as depositories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal Reserve banks as depositories Any Federal Reserve bank that is requested to do so by the Bank shall act as its depository or as its fiscal agent, and the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall supervise and direct the carrying out of these functions by the Federal Reserve banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of United States courts and enforcement of arbitral awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Jurisdiction of United States courts and enforcement of arbitral awards For the purpose of any civil action which may be brought within the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, by or against the Bank in accordance with the Cooperation Agreement, including an action brought to enforce an arbitral award against the Bank, the Bank shall be deemed to be an inhabitant of the Federal judicial district in which its principal office within the United States or its agency appointed for the purpose of accepting service or notice of service is located, and any such action to which the Bank shall be a party shall be deemed to arise under the laws of the United States, and the district courts of the United States, including the courts enumerated in section 460 of title 28, shall have original jurisdiction of any such action. When the Bank is a defendant in any action in a State court, it may at any time before trial remove the action into the approp</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290m_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from securities laws for certain securities issued by Bank; reports required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exemption from securities laws for certain securities issued by Bank; reports required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>