<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/294b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/294b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/294b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294b"><akn:num>294b</akn:num><akn:heading>Support co-location with allied partner nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294b. Support co-location with allied partner nations
The Secretary, following consultation which occurs a reasonable time in advance of the exercise of the authority and includes details on costs and purposes with the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives may alter, repair, and furnish United States Government-owned and leased space for use by the government of a foreign country to facilitate co-location of such government in such space, on such terms and conditions as the Secretary may determine, including with respect to reimbursement of all or part of the costs of such alteration, repair, or furnishing. Reimbursements or advances of funds pursuant to this section may be credited to the currently applicable appropriation and shall be available for the purposes for which such appropriation is authorized.
(Pub. L. 118–159, div. G, title LXXII, § 7213, Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2535.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Definitions
For definitions of “Secretary” and “appropriate congressional committees” as used in this section, see section 7002 of Pub. L. 118–159, set out as a note under section 2651 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>