<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3142"><akn:num>3142</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by Secretary of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3142. Report by Secretary of Commerce(a) Annual report on foreign direct investment in United StatesNot later than 6 months after November 7, 1990, and not later than the end of each 1-year period occurring thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and to the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress a report on the role and significance of foreign direct investment in the United States. Such report shall address the history, scope, trends, market concentrations, and effects on the United States economy of such investment. In addition, the Secretary of Commerce shall, if requested by any such committee, appear before that committee to provide testimony with respect to any report under this subsection.


(b) Sources of dataIn preparing each report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary’s designees, shall consider information collected by—(1) the Bureau of Economic Analysis under the International Investment and Trade in Services Survey Act (22 U.S.C. 3101 and following);

(2) the Bureau of the Census on industry, manufacturing, research and development, and trade, under title 13;

(3) the Bureau of Labor Statistics pertaining to information collected under the International Investment and Trade in Services Survey Act, but only to the extent that such information is in a form that cannot be associated with, or otherwise identify, directly or indirectly, a person, including any enterprise or establishment;

(4) the Secretary of Commerce or the Secretary’s designee pursuant to section 2 11 See References in Text note below. of Executive Order 11858 of May 7, 1975;

(5) the United States Department of Agriculture under the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (7 U.S.C. 3501 and following);

(6) the Depar</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on foreign direct investment in United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report on foreign direct investment in United States Not later than 6 months after November 7, 1990, and not later than the end of each 1-year period occurring thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and to the Joint Economic Committee of the Congress a report on the role and significance of foreign direct investment in the United States. Such report shall address the history, scope, trends, market concentrations, and effects on the United States economy of such investment. In addition, the Secretary of Commerce shall, if requested by any such committee, appear before that committee to provide testimony with respect to any report under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sources of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sources of data In preparing each report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Commerce, or the Secretary’s designees, shall consider information collected by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analyses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Analyses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>