<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3262" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3262/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3262/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3262"><akn:num>3262</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3262. Programs(a) Energy development programsThe United States shall initiate a program, consistent with the aims of section 3261 of this title, to cooperate with developing countries for the purpose of—(1) meeting the energy needs required for the development of such countries;

(2) reducing the dependence of such countries on petroleum fuels, with emphasis given to utilizing solar and other renewable energy resources; and

(3) expanding the energy alternatives available to such countries.


(b) Energy assessments and cooperative projectsSuch program shall include cooperation in evaluating the energy alternatives of developing countries, facilitating international trade in energy commodities, developing energy resources, and applying suitable energy technologies. The program shall include both general and country-specific energy assessments and cooperative projects in resource exploration and production, training, research and development.


(c) Exchange of scientists, technicians, and energy expertsAs an integral part of such program, the Department of Energy, under the general policy guidance of the Department of State and in cooperation with the Agency for International Development and other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall initiate, as soon as practicable, a program for the exchange of United States scientists, technicians, and energy experts with those of developing countries to implement the purposes of this section.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsFor the purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are contained in annual authorization Acts for the Department of Energy, including such sums which have been authorized for such purposes under previous legislation.


(e) Coordination with related United States activities abroadUnder the direction of the President, the Secretary of State shall ensure the coordination of the activities authorized by this subchapter with other related activities of the Uni</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3262_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy development programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Energy development programs The United States shall initiate a program, consistent with the aims of section 3261 of this title, to cooperate with developing countries for the purpose of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3262_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy assessments and cooperative projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Energy assessments and cooperative projects Such program shall include cooperation in evaluating the energy alternatives of developing countries, facilitating international trade in energy commodities, developing energy resources, and applying suitable energy technologies. The program shall include both general and country-specific energy assessments and cooperative projects in resource exploration and production, training, research and development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3262_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of scientists, technicians, and energy experts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exchange of scientists, technicians, and energy experts As an integral part of such program, the Department of Energy, under the general policy guidance of the Department of State and in cooperation with the Agency for International Development and other Federal agencies as appropriate, shall initiate, as soon as practicable, a program for the exchange of United States scientists, technicians, and energy experts with those of developing countries to implement the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3262_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations For the purposes of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are contained in annual authorization Acts for the Department of Energy, including such sums which have been authorized for such purposes under previous legislation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3262_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with related United States activities abroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with related United States activities abroad Under the direction of the President, the Secretary of State shall ensure the coordination of the activities authorized by this subchapter with other related activities of the United States conducted abroad, including the programs authorized by sections 2151a(c), 2151d(a)(2),11 See References in Text note below. and 2151q 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>