<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3351" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3351/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3351/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3351"><akn:num>3351</akn:num><akn:heading>Modernizing Taiwan’s security capabilities to deter and, if necessary, defeat aggression by the Peop</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3351. Modernizing Taiwan’s security capabilities to deter and, if necessary, defeat aggression by the People’s Republic of China(a) Appropriate congressional committees definedIn this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(1) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(2) the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;

(3) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(4) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives;

(5) the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and

(6) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(b) Taiwan security programsThe Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall use the authorities under this section to strengthen the United States-Taiwan defense relationship, and to support the acceleration of the modernization of Taiwan’s defense capabilities, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (Public Law 96–8) [22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.].


(c) PurposeIn addition to the purposes otherwise authorized for Foreign Military Financing programs under the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.), a purpose of the Foreign Military Financing Program should be to provide assistance, including equipment, training, and other support, to build the civilian and defensive military capabilities of Taiwan—(1) to accelerate the modernization of capabilities that will enable Taiwan to delay, degrade, and deny attempts by People’s Liberation Army forces—(A) to conduct coercive or grey zone activities;

(B) to blockade Taiwan; or

(C) to secure a lodgment on any islands administered by Taiwan and expand or otherwise use such lodgment to seize control of a population center or other key territory in Taiwan; and


(2) to prevent the People’s Republic of China from decapitating, seizing control of, or otherwise neutralizing or rendering ineffective Taiwan’s civilian and defense leadership.


(d) Regional contingency stockpileOf the am</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriate congressional committees defined In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taiwan security programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Taiwan security programs The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall use the authorities under this section to strengthen the United States-Taiwan defense relationship, and to support the acceleration of the modernization of Taiwan’s defense capabilities, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (Public Law 96–8) [22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose In addition to the purposes otherwise authorized for Foreign Military Financing programs under the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.), a purpose of the Foreign Military Financing Program should be to provide assistance, including equipment, training, and other support, to build the civilian and defensive military capabilities of Taiwan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regional contingency stockpile</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regional contingency stockpile Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to subsection (h), not more than $100,000,000 may be used during each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2032 to maintain a stockpile (if established pursuant to section 3352 of this title), in accordance with section 2321h of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on advancing the defense of Taiwan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report on advancing the defense of Taiwan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign military financing loan and loan guarantee authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Foreign military financing loan and loan guarantee authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3351_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Sunset provision Assistance may not be provided under this section after September 30, 2032.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>