<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3384" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3384/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3384/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3384"><akn:num>3384</akn:num><akn:heading>Taiwan Fellowship Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3384. Taiwan Fellowship Program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of State shall establish the Taiwan Fellowship Program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) to provide a fellowship opportunity in Taiwan of up to 2 years for eligible United States citizens. The Department of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and the implementing partner, may modify the name of the Program.


(b) Cooperative agreement(1) In generalThe American Institute in Taiwan should use amounts appropriated pursuant to section 3387(a) of this title to enter into an annual or multi-year cooperative agreement with an appropriate implementing partner.


(2) FellowshipsThe Department of State or the American Institute in Taiwan, in consultation with, as appropriate, the implementing partner, should award to eligible United States citizens, subject to available funding—(A) approximately 5 fellowships during the first 2 years of the Program; and

(B) approximately 10 fellowships during each of the remaining years of the Program.



(c) American Institution 11 So in original. Probably should be “Institute”. in Taiwan agreement; implementing partnerNot later than 30 days after December 23, 2022, the American Institute in Taiwan, in consultation with the Department of State, should—(1) begin negotiations with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office, or with another appropriate entity, for the purpose of entering into an agreement to facilitate the placement of fellows in an agency of Taiwan; and

(2) begin the process of selecting an implementing partner, which—(A) shall agree to meet all of the legal requirements required to operate in Taiwan; and

(B) shall be composed of staff who demonstrate significant experience managing exchange programs in the Indo-Pacific region.



(d) Curriculum(1) First yearDuring the first year of each fellowship under this section, each fellow should study—(A) the Mandarin Chinese language;

(B) the people, history, and polit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of State shall establish the Taiwan Fellowship Program (referred to in this section as the “Program”) to provide a fellowship opportunity in Taiwan of up to 2 years for eligible United States citizens. The Department of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and the implementing partner, may modify the name of the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperative agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>American Institution 11 So in original. Probably should be “Institute”. in Taiwan agreement; implementing partner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) American Institution Not later than 30 days after December 23, 2022, the American Institute in Taiwan, in consultation with the Department of State, should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Curriculum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Curriculum</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexible fellowship duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Flexible fellowship duration Notwithstanding any requirement under this section, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and, as appropriate, the implementing partner, may award fellowships that have a duration of less than 2 years, and may alter the curriculum requirements under subsection (d) for such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3384_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sunset The fellowship program under this subchapter shall terminate 7 years after December 23, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>