<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3388" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3388/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3388/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3388"><akn:num>3388</akn:num><akn:heading>Supporting United States educational and exchange programs with Taiwan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3388. Supporting United States educational and exchange programs with Taiwan(a) Establishment of the United States-Taiwan cultural exchange foundationThe Secretary of State should consider establishing an independent nonprofit entity that—(1) is dedicated to deepening ties between the future leaders of Taiwan and the future leaders of the United States; and

(2) works with State and local school districts and educational institutions to send high school and university students to Taiwan to study the Chinese language, culture, history, politics, and other relevant subjects.


(b) PartnerState and local school districts and educational institutions, including public universities, are encouraged to partner with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States to establish programs to promote more educational and cultural exchanges.


(Pub. L. 117–263, div. E, title LV, § 5535, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3332.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3388_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the United States-Taiwan cultural exchange foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of the United States-Taiwan cultural exchange foundation The Secretary of State should consider establishing an independent nonprofit entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3388_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Partner State and local school districts and educational institutions, including public universities, are encouraged to partner with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States to establish programs to promote more educational and cultural exchanges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>