<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3401"><akn:num>3401</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings and declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3401. Congressional findings and declaration of policy(a) Policy of support for peace treatyIt is the policy of the United States to support the peace treaty concluded between the Government of Egypt and the Government of Israel on March 26, 1979. This treaty is a significant step toward a full and comprehensive peace in the Middle East. The Congress urges the President to continue to exert every effort to bring about a comprehensive peace and to seek an end by all parties to the violence which could jeopardize this peace.


(b) FindingsThe peace treaty between Egypt and Israel having been ratified, the Congress finds that the national interests of the United States are served—(1) by authorizing the President to construct air bases in Israel to replace the Israeli air bases on the Sinai peninsula that are to be evacuated;

(2) by authorizing additional funds to finance procurements by Egypt and Israel through the fiscal year 1982 of defense articles and defense services for their respective security requirements; and

(3) by authorizing additional funds for economic assistance for Egypt in order to promote the economic stability and development of that country and to support the peace process in the Middle East.


(c) Other agreements, understandings, or commitmentsThe authorities contained in this subchapter to implement certain arrangements in support of the peace treaty between Egypt and Israel do not signify approval by the Congress of any other agreement, understanding, or commitment made by the executive branch.


(Pub. L. 96–35, § 2, July 20, 1979, 93 Stat. 89.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subchapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 96–35, July 20, 1979, 93 Stat. 89, known as the Special International Security Assistance Act of 1979, which enacted this subchapter and sections 2349, 2349a, and 2349b of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Table</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy of support for peace treaty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Policy of support for peace treaty It is the policy of the United States to support the peace treaty concluded between the Government of Egypt and the Government of Israel on March 26, 1979. This treaty is a significant step toward a full and comprehensive peace in the Middle East. The Congress urges the President to continue to exert every effort to bring about a comprehensive peace and to seek an end by all parties to the violence which could jeopardize this peace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings The peace treaty between Egypt and Israel having been ratified, the Congress finds that the national interests of the United States are served—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other agreements, understandings, or commitments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other agreements, understandings, or commitments The authorities contained in this subchapter to implement certain arrangements in support of the peace treaty between Egypt and Israel do not signify approval by the Congress of any other agreement, understanding, or commitment made by the executive branch.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>