<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3507" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3507/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3507/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3507"><akn:num>3507</akn:num><akn:heading>Council on International Scientific and Technological Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3507. Council on International Scientific and Technological Cooperation(a) EstablishmentIn order to further the purposes of the Institute, the President is authorized to establish a Council on International Scientific and Technological Cooperation (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).


(b) Functions(1) The Council shall—(A) advise the Director with respect to the policies, programs, planning, and procedures of the Institute;

(B) make recommendations to the Director on the use of the resources available to the Institute; and

(C) advise the Director on matters involving the activities of the Institute overseas and appropriate relationships with the private sector, within and outside the United States.


(2) The Council shall prepare an annual report setting forth the major recommendations made and advice given pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.


(c) Advice to Director concerning selection, termination, or change in activities, and transfer of government programs and projects to Institute; review and recommendations respecting new programs and initiativesThe Director shall seek the advice of the Council before making any decision with respect to the selection or termination of, or any significant change in, the areas and issues in which the Institute conducts its activities, and with respect to the transfer of specific programs and projects from any other Government agency to the Institute. The Council shall have the authority to review all new programs and initiatives before their implementation and to make recommendations with regard to the approval or disapproval of new programs and initiatives having a cost in excess of $500,000 or a duration greater than two years.


(d) Composition; Chairman; appointment, terms, etc., of membersThe Council shall consist of up to twenty-five members appointed by the President, one of whom the President shall designate as Chairman. The members of the Council shall be appointed for terms of four </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment In order to further the purposes of the Institute, the President is authorized to establish a Council on International Scientific and Technological Cooperation (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice to Director concerning selection, termination, or change in activities, and transfer of government programs and projects to Institute; review and recommendations respecting new programs and initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advice to Director concerning selection, termination, or change in activities, and transfer of government programs and projects to Institute; review and recommendations respecting new programs and initiatives The Director shall seek the advice of the Council before making any decision with respect to the selection or termination of, or any significant change in, the areas and issues in which the Institute conducts its activities, and with respect to the transfer of specific programs and projects from any other Government agency to the Institute. The Council shall have the authority to review all new programs and initiatives before their implementation and to make recommendations with regard to the approval or disapproval of new programs and initiatives having a cost in excess of $500,000 or a duration greater than two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition; Chairman; appointment, terms, etc., of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Composition; Chairman; appointment, terms, etc., of members The Council shall consist of up to twenty-five members appointed by the President, one of whom the President shall designate as Chairman. The members of the Council shall be appointed for terms of four years, except that the members first appointed shall be appointed for terms of one, two, three, or four years, as designated by the President at the time of their appointment, so that the terms of approximately one-fourth of the members of the Council expire in any year. The members of the Council shall be selected from among—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation, reimbursement, status, etc., of nongovernmental members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Compensation, reimbursement, status, etc., of nongovernmental members Members of the Council who are not officials of the United States Government shall be entitled to compensation, not to exceed the daily equivalent of the highest rate which may be paid to an employee under the General Schedule established by section 5332 of title 5, while in the performance of their duties under this chapter, and to reimbursement for expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence while away from their homes or regular places of business in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5. Members of the Council who are not officials of the United States Government shall not be deemed officers, employees, or otherwise in the service or employment of the United States Government for any purpose, except that members of the Council who are United States citizens shall be deemed Government employees for the purposes of sections 2</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3507_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive and additional committees; membership, powers, etc., of Executive Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Executive and additional committees; membership, powers, etc., of Executive Committee The Council may appoint from among its members an Executive Committee, and such other committees it deems necessary, to assist it in exercising its powers and functions. The Executive Committee shall consist of seven members, one of whom shall be the Chairman of the Council and not more than three of whom shall be employees of the United States Government. The Executive Committee shall exercise such powers and functions as are delegated to it by the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>