<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3622"><akn:num>3622</akn:num><akn:heading>Code of conduct for Commission personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3622. Code of conduct for Commission personnel(a) Oath; compliance with laws of United States regarding duties and responsibilities of Federal employeesBefore assuming the duties of his office or employment, each member of the Board of the Commission and each officer and employee of the Commission shall take an oath to discharge faithfully the duties of his office or employment. All employees of the Commission shall be subject to the laws of the United States regarding duties and responsibilities of Federal employees.


(b) Adoption of code of conduct; time limit; contentsNot later than 60 days after all the members of the Board of the Commission have been appointed, the Board shall adopt a code of conduct applicable to the persons referred to in subsection (a) of this section. The code of conduct shall contain provisions substantially equivalent to those contained in part 735 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations on October 1, 1979. The code of conduct shall, at a minimum, contain provisions substantially equivalent to the following provisions of law:(1) the provisions of chapter 11 of title 18, relating to bribery, graft, or conflicts of interest, as appropriate to the employees concerned;

(2) section 7352 of title 5;

(3) sections 207, 208, 285, 508, 641, 645, 1001, 1917, and 2071 of title 18;

(4) section 1343, 1344, and 1349(b) of title 31;

(5) chapter 131 of title 5; and

(6) those provisions of the laws and regulations of the Republic of Panama which are substantially equivalent to those of the United States set forth in this subsection.


(c) Investigations by Commission respecting violations; recommendations for suspensionThe Commission shall investigate any allegations regarding the violation of the code of conduct adopted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. The Commission may recommend that the President suspend from the performance of his duties any member of the Board of the Commission or any officer or employee of the Commission, pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oath; compliance with laws of United States regarding duties and responsibilities of Federal employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Oath; compliance with laws of United States regarding duties and responsibilities of Federal employees Before assuming the duties of his office or employment, each member of the Board of the Commission and each officer and employee of the Commission shall take an oath to discharge faithfully the duties of his office or employment. All employees of the Commission shall be subject to the laws of the United States regarding duties and responsibilities of Federal employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of code of conduct; time limit; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adoption of code of conduct; time limit; contents Not later than 60 days after all the members of the Board of the Commission have been appointed, the Board shall adopt a code of conduct applicable to the persons referred to in subsection (a) of this section. The code of conduct shall contain provisions substantially equivalent to those contained in part 735 of title 5 of the Code of Federal Regulations on October 1, 1979. The code of conduct shall, at a minimum, contain provisions substantially equivalent to the following provisions of law:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigations by Commission respecting violations; recommendations for suspension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investigations by Commission respecting violations; recommendations for suspension The Commission shall investigate any allegations regarding the violation of the code of conduct adopted pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. The Commission may recommend that the President suspend from the performance of his duties any member of the Board of the Commission or any officer or employee of the Commission, pending judicial proceedings by appropriate authorities concerning such allegations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measures to insure compliance with code of conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Measures to insure compliance with code of conduct The President shall negotiate suitable arrangements with the Republic of Panama whereby each nation shall agree to take all measures within its legal authority to assure that members of the Board of the Commission comply with the code of conduct established pursuant to subsection (b) of this section. Without prejudice to such jurisdiction as the United States may have with respect to members of the Board, the provisions of law enumerated in subsection (b) of this section shall be enforced with respect to members of the Board only in accordance with such arrangements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of post-employment restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver of post-employment restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3622_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consent for acceptance of employment by Panama Canal Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consent for acceptance of employment by Panama Canal Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>