<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3642" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3642/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3642/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3642"><akn:num>3642</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and compensation; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3642. Appointment and compensation; duties(a) Officers and employeesIn accordance with this part, the Commission may appoint, fix the compensation of, and define the authority and duties of officers and employees (other than the Administrator and Deputy Administrator) necessary for the management, operation, and maintenance of the Panama Canal and its complementary works, installations, and equipment.


(b) Eligibility to serve as officer or employee of CommissionIndividuals serving in any Executive agency (other than the Commission) or the Smithsonian Institution, including individuals in the uniformed services, may, if appointed under this section or section 3614 of this title, serve as officers or employees of the Commission.


(c) Salary protectionIn the case of an individual who is an officer or employee of the Commission on November 17, 1997, and who has not had a break in service with the Commission since that date, the rate of basic pay for that officer or employee may not be less than the rate in effect for that officer or employee on that date except—(1) as provided in a collective bargaining agreement;

(2) as a result of an adverse action against the officer or employee; or

(3) pursuant to a voluntary demotion.


(Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1202, Sept. 27, 1979, 93 Stat. 461; Pub. L. 104–201, div. C, title XXXV, § 3526, Sept. 23, 1996, 110 Stat. 2861; Pub. L. 105–85, div. C, title XXXV, § 3523(b), Nov. 18, 1997, 111 Stat. 2065; Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXV, § 3512(a)(1), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2271.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 105–261, § 3512(a)(1)(C), which directed substitution of “that date” for “the day before the date of enactment”, was executed by making the substitution for “the day before that date of enactment” before “except” in introductory provisions to reflect the probable intent of Congress.
Pub. L. 105–261, § 3512(a)(1)(A), (B), in introductory provisions, substituted “November 17, 1997,” for “the day b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3642_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Officers and employees In accordance with this part, the Commission may appoint, fix the compensation of, and define the authority and duties of officers and employees (other than the Administrator and Deputy Administrator) necessary for the management, operation, and maintenance of the Panama Canal and its complementary works, installations, and equipment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3642_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility to serve as officer or employee of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility to serve as officer or employee of Commission Individuals serving in any Executive agency (other than the Commission) or the Smithsonian Institution, including individuals in the uniformed services, may, if appointed under this section or section 3614 of this title, serve as officers or employees of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3642_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary protection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Salary protection In the case of an individual who is an officer or employee of the Commission on November 17, 1997, and who has not had a break in service with the Commission since that date, the rate of basic pay for that officer or employee may not be less than the rate in effect for that officer or employee on that date except—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>