<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3657" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3657/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3657/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3657"><akn:num>3657</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment and retention remuneration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3657. Recruitment and retention remuneration(a) Repealed. Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2269

(b) RestrictionAny employee described in more than one paragraph of subsection (a) of this section may qualify for a recruitment or retention differential under only one of those paragraphs.


(c) Recruitment and relocation bonuses(1) The Commission may pay a recruitment bonus to an individual who is newly appointed to a position with the Commission, or a relocation bonus to an employee of the Commission who must relocate to accept a position, if the Commission determines that the Commission would be likely, in the absence of such a bonus, to have difficulty in filling the position.

(2) A recruitment or relocation bonus may be paid to an employee under this subsection only if the employee enters into an agreement with the Commission to complete a period of employment established in the agreement. If the employee voluntarily fails to complete such period of employment or is separated from service in such employment as a result of an adverse action before the completion of such period, the employee shall repay the entire amount of the bonus.

(3) A recruitment or relocation bonus under this subsection may be paid as a lump sum. A bonus under this subsection may not be considered to be part of the basic pay of an employee.


(d) Retention bonuses(1) The Commission may pay a retention bonus to an employee of the Commission if the Commission determines that—(A) the employee has unusually high or unique qualifications and those qualifications make it essential for the Commission to retain the employee for a period specified by the Commission ending not later than the Canal Transfer Date, or the Commission otherwise has a special need for the services of the employee making it essential for the Commission to retain the employee for a period specified by the Commission ending not later than the Canal Transfer Date; and

(B) the employee</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3657_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–261, div. C, title XXXV, § 3507(a), Oct. 17, 1998, 112 Stat. 2269</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3657_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restriction Any employee described in more than one paragraph of subsection (a) of this section may qualify for a recruitment or retention differential under only one of those paragraphs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3657_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment and relocation bonuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recruitment and relocation bonuses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3657_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention bonuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Retention bonuses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3657_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limit on compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limit on compensation Additional compensation provided under this section may not exceed 25 percent of the rate of basic pay of the individual to whom the compensation is paid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>