<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3715c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3715c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3715c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3715c"><akn:num>3715c</akn:num><akn:heading>Final evaluation of Fund; deficiency or surplus in Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3715c. Final evaluation of Fund; deficiency or surplus in Fund(a) Final evaluation of FundBy March 31, 1998, the Secretary of Labor shall, on the basis of an actuarial study conducted by experts or consultants whose services are procured by the Secretary of Labor by contract, make a final determination of the amounts estimated to be necessary to meet expenditures for workers’ compensation benefits and other payments described in section 3715a(a) of this title, as calculated in accordance with the second sentence of section 3715a(b) of this title. Amounts in the Fund shall be used to pay for the final determination under this subsection.


(b) Deficiency or surplus in FundIf amounts in the Fund are not sufficient to meet expenditures as determined by the Secretary of Labor under subsection (a) for workers’ compensation benefits and other payments described in section 3715a(a) of this title, then amounts in the Panama Canal Revolving Fund not otherwise obligated shall be transferred to the Fund to make up the deficiency. Any amounts remaining in the Fund in excess of the final determination amount as described in subsection (a) shall be transferred to the Panama Canal Revolving Fund, and may be used to satisfy lawful obligations of the Revolving Fund arising on or before December 31, 1999.


(c) Continuity of Fund(1) Amounts in the Fund (including amounts transferred as a result of the final determination made under subsection (a)) shall be maintained by the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be made available for transfer to the Employees’ Compensation Fund in such amounts as are requested by the Secretary of Labor pursuant to section 3715b of this title, and may be discontinued only in accordance with paragraph (2).

(2) At such time as the Secretary of Labor certifies that no further liability exists for workers compensation benefits or other payments described in section 3715a(a) of this title, the Secretary of the Treasury may discontinue the Fund in the manner p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3715c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final evaluation of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Final evaluation of Fund By March 31, 1998, the Secretary of Labor shall, on the basis of an actuarial study conducted by experts or consultants whose services are procured by the Secretary of Labor by contract, make a final determination of the amounts estimated to be necessary to meet expenditures for workers’ compensation benefits and other payments described in section 3715a(a) of this title, as calculated in accordance with the second sentence of section 3715a(b) of this title. Amounts in the Fund shall be used to pay for the final determination under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3715c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deficiency or surplus in Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deficiency or surplus in Fund If amounts in the Fund are not sufficient to meet expenditures as determined by the Secretary of Labor under subsection (a) for workers’ compensation benefits and other payments described in section 3715a(a) of this title, then amounts in the Panama Canal Revolving Fund not otherwise obligated shall be transferred to the Fund to make up the deficiency. Any amounts remaining in the Fund in excess of the final determination amount as described in subsection (a) shall be transferred to the Panama Canal Revolving Fund, and may be used to satisfy lawful obligations of the Revolving Fund arising on or before December 31, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3715c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuity of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continuity of Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>