<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3784" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3784/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3784/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3784"><akn:num>3784</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of property to Republic of Panama</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3784. Transfer of property to Republic of Panama(a) Conveyance of Panama Railroad(1) On October 1, 1979, the Secretary of State may convey to the Republic of Panama the Panama Railroad and such property located in the area which, immediately before such date, comprised the Canal Zone and which is not within the land and water areas the use of which is made available to the United States pursuant to the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements.

(2) Property transferred pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection may not include buildings and other facilities, except housing, located outside such areas, the use of which is retained by the United States pursuant to the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements.


(b) Transfer of certain property pursuant to Panama Canal Treaty of 1977; report to CongressWith respect to the transfer of all other property (not described in subsection (a)(1) of this section) to be transferred in accordance with the terms of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements, the Secretary of State may convey such property from time to time in accordance with the terms of such Treaty and related agreements. Before the transfer of any such property, the President must submit a written report to the Congress—(1) precisely identifying and describing the particular property to be transferred;

(2) certifying the state of compliance by the Republic of Panama with such Treaty and related agreements; and

(3) setting forth the reasons for the conveyance being made at the particular time.


(c) Restriction on transfer of Panama Canal and certain other propertyThe Panama Canal, and such other property referred to in paragraph 2(d) of Article XIII of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 that has not been previously transferred in accordance with paragraphs 2(a), 2(b), and 2(c) of such Article, shall not be transferred to the Republic of Panama prior to December 31, 1999.


(Pub. L. 96–70, title I, § 1504, Sept. 27, 1979, 93 Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3784_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conveyance of Panama Railroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conveyance of Panama Railroad</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3784_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain property pursuant to Panama Canal Treaty of 1977; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of certain property pursuant to Panama Canal Treaty of 1977; report to Congress With respect to the transfer of all other property (not described in subsection (a)(1) of this section) to be transferred in accordance with the terms of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 and related agreements, the Secretary of State may convey such property from time to time in accordance with the terms of such Treaty and related agreements. Before the transfer of any such property, the President must submit a written report to the Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3784_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on transfer of Panama Canal and certain other property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on transfer of Panama Canal and certain other property The Panama Canal, and such other property referred to in paragraph 2(d) of Article XIII of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977 that has not been previously transferred in accordance with paragraphs 2(a), 2(b), and 2(c) of such Article, shall not be transferred to the Republic of Panama prior to December 31, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>