<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3972" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3972/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/3972/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3972"><akn:num>3972</akn:num><akn:heading>Special differentials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3972. Special differentials(a) Additional work requirementsThe Secretary may pay special differentials, in addition to compensation otherwise authorized, to Foreign Service officers who are required because of the nature of their assignments to perform additional work on a regular basis in substantial excess of normal requirements.


(b) Salary limitationsThe Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) shall limit the payment of special differentials to USAID Foreign Service criminal investigators to levels at which the aggregate of basic pay and special differential for any pay period would equal, for such criminal investigators, the bi-weekly pay limitations on premium pay regularly placed on other criminal investigators within the Federal law enforcement community. This provision shall be retroactive to January 1, 2013.


(c) Compensatory time offNothing in this chapter, or in subchapter V of chapter 55 of title 5 shall preclude the granting of compensatory time off for Foreign Service officers.


(Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 412, Oct. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 2092; Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(6), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 398; Pub. L. 114–323, title II, § 206, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1917.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2016—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 114–323 added subsec. (b).
1994—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 103–236 struck out subsec. (b) which read as follows: “Before implementing any proposal to limit either the number of Foreign Service officers who may receive a special differential under subsection (a) of this section or the amounts of such special differentials, the Secretary shall submit such proposal to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3972_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional work requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Additional work requirements The Secretary may pay special differentials, in addition to compensation otherwise authorized, to Foreign Service officers who are required because of the nature of their assignments to perform additional work on a regular basis in substantial excess of normal requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3972_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Salary limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Salary limitations The Inspector General of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) shall limit the payment of special differentials to USAID Foreign Service criminal investigators to levels at which the aggregate of basic pay and special differential for any pay period would equal, for such criminal investigators, the bi-weekly pay limitations on premium pay regularly placed on other criminal investigators within the Federal law enforcement community. This provision shall be retroactive to January 1, 2013.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3972_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensatory time off</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensatory time off Nothing in this chapter, or in subchapter V of chapter 55 of title 5 shall preclude the granting of compensatory time off for Foreign Service officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>