<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4013"><akn:num>4013</akn:num><akn:heading>Department awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4013. Department awards
The President shall establish a system of awards to confer appropriate recognition of outstanding contributions to the Nation by members of the Service or Civil Service. The awards system established under this section shall provide for presentation by the President and by the Secretary of medals or other suitable commendations for performance in the course of or beyond the call of duty which involves distinguished, meritorious service to the Nation, including extraordinary valor in the face of danger to life or health. Distinguished, meritorious service in the promotion of internationally recognized human rights, including the right to freedom of religion, shall serve as a basis for granting awards under this section.
(Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 614, formerly § 613, Oct. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 2099; renumbered § 614, Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 181(a)(1), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 416; amended Pub. L. 105–292, title V, § 504(b), Oct. 27, 1998, 112 Stat. 2811; Pub. L. 117–81, div. E, title LIII, § 5308(a), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2362.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2021—Pub. L. 117–81, § 5308(a)(1), amended section catchline generally, substituting “Department awards” for “Foreign Service awards”.
Pub. L. 117–81, § 5308(a)(2), inserted “or Civil Service” after “the Service” before period at end of first sentence.
1998—Pub. L. 105–292 inserted at end “Distinguished, meritorious service in the promotion of internationally recognized human rights, including the right to freedom of religion, shall serve as a basis for granting awards under this section.”

Executive Documents

Delegation of Functions
Functions of President under this section delegated to Secretary of State, see section 1 of Ex. Ord. No. 12293, Feb. 23, 1981, 46 F.R. 13969, set out under section 3901 of this title.


The Richard C. Holbrooke Award for Diplomacy
Memorandum of President of the United States, Dec. 22, 2010, 77 F.R. 75507, provided:
Memorandum for the Secretary of State
To</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>