<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4027" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4027/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4027/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4027"><akn:num>4027</akn:num><akn:heading>Visiting Scholars Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4027. Visiting Scholars Program(a) Establishment of programThere is authorized to be established at the institution a program whereby selected scholars would participate fully in the educational and training activities of the institution. This program may be referred to as the “Visiting Scholars Program”.


(b) Selection and appointment of scholars(1) Scholars participating in the Visiting Scholars Program shall be selected by a five-member board described in subsection (c).

(2) Each visiting scholar shall serve a term of one year, except that such term may be extended for one additional one-year period.


(c) Establishment of selection boardThe board referred to in subsection (b) shall be composed of the Director of the institution, who shall serve as chairperson, and four other members appointed by the Secretary of State.


(Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 707, as added Pub. L. 101–246, title I, § 144(a), Feb. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 36; amended Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 126(3), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 394.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1994—Subsecs. (a), (c). Pub. L. 103–236 substituted “institution” for “Foreign Service Institute” and “Institute” in subsec. (a) and “institution” for “Foreign Service Institute” in subsec. (c).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program There is authorized to be established at the institution a program whereby selected scholars would participate fully in the educational and training activities of the institution. This program may be referred to as the “Visiting Scholars Program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection and appointment of scholars</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection and appointment of scholars</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4027_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of selection board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of selection board The board referred to in subsection (b) shall be composed of the Director of the institution, who shall serve as chairperson, and four other members appointed by the Secretary of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>