<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4046" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4046/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4046/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4046"><akn:num>4046</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of annuities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4046. Computation of annuities(a) 11 See Amendment of Section note below. Measurements; reduction for special contributions; Foreign Service investigator/inspectors(1) The annuity of a participant shall be equal to 2 percent of his or her average basic salary for the highest 3 consecutive years of service multiplied by the number of years, not exceeding 35, of service credit obtained in accordance with sections 4056 and 4057 of this title, except that the highest 3 years of service shall be used in computing the annuity of any participant who serves an assignment in a position, as described in section 3942(b) of this title, to which the participant was appointed by the President and whose continuity of service in that position is interrupted prior to retirement by appointment or assignment to any other position determined by the Secretary of State to be of comparable importance. In determining the aggregate period of service upon which the annuity is to be based, the fractional part of a month, if any, shall not be counted. The annuity shall be reduced by 10 percent of any special contribution described in section 4045(d) of this title which is due for service for which no contributions were made and which remains unpaid unless the participant elects to eliminate the service involved for purposes of annuity computation.

(2) Notwithstanding the percentage limitation contained in paragraph (1) of this subsection—(A) utilizing the definition of average pay contained in section 8331(4) of title 5, the annuity of a Foreign Service criminal investigator/inspector of the Office of the Inspector General, Agency for International Development, who was appointed to a law enforcement position, as defined in section 8331(20) of title 5, prior to January 1, 1984, and would have been eligible to retire pursuant to section 8336(c) of that title, after attaining 50 years of age and completing 20 years as a law enforcement officer had the employee remained in the civil service sha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 See Amendment of Section note below. Measurements; reduction for special contributions; Foreign Service investigator/inspectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Married participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Married participants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surviving children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Surviving children</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recomputation for remaining children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recomputation for remaining children On the death of the surviving spouse or former spouse or termination of the annuity of a child, the annuity of any other child or children shall be recomputed and paid as though the spouse, former spouse, or child had not survived the participant. If the annuity to a surviving child who has not been receiving an annuity is initiated or resumed, the annuities of any other children shall be recomputed and paid from that date as though the annuities to all currently eligible children in the family were then being initiated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment period for child</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment period for child The annuity payable to a child under subsection (c) or (d) shall begin on the day after the participant dies, or if the child is not then qualified, on the first day of the month in which the child becomes eligible. The annuity of a child shall terminate on the last day of the month which precedes the month in which eligibility ceases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unmarried participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Unmarried participants At the time of retirement an unmarried participant who does not have a former spouse for whose benefit a reduction is made under subsection (b) may elect to receive a reduced annuity and to provide for an annuity equal to 55 percent of the reduced annuity payable after his or her death to a beneficiary whose name is designated in writing to the Secretary of State. The annuity payable to a participant making such election shall be reduced by 10 percent of an annuity computed under subsection (a) and by 5 percent of an annuity so computed for each full 5 years the designated beneficiary is younger than the retiring participant, but such total reduction shall not exceed 40 percent. No such election of a reduced annuity payable to a beneficiary shall be valid until the participant has satisfactorily passed a physical examination as prescribed by the Secretary of State. The annuity payable to a beneficiary under this subsection shall begin on the day after the ann</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Marriage after retirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Marriage after retirement A participant or former participant who was unmarried at retirement and who later marries may, within one year after such marriage, irrevocably elect in writing to receive a reduced annuity and to provide a survivor annuity for the spouse (if such spouse qualifies as a surviving spouse under section 4044(13) of this title). Receipt by the Secretary of State of notice of an election under this subsection voids prospectively any election previously made under subsection (f). The reduction in annuity required by an election under this subsection shall be computed and the amount of the survivor annuity shall be determined in accordance with subsections (b)(2) and (3). The annuity reduction or recomputation shall be effective the first day of the month beginning one year after the date of marriage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Election of benefits A surviving spouse or surviving former spouse of any participant or former participant shall not become entitled to a survivor annuity or to the restoration of a survivor annuity payable from the Fund under this part unless the survivor elects to receive it instead of any other survivor annuity to which he or she may be entitled under this or any other retirement system for Government employees on the basis of a marriage to someone other than that participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reversion to retired status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reversion to retired status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4046_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recomputation upon dissolution of marriage; election after remarriage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Recomputation upon dissolution of marriage; election after remarriage An annuity which is reduced under this section or any similar prior provision of law to provide a survivor benefit for a spouse shall, if the marriage of the participant to such spouse is dissolved, be recomputed and paid for each full month during which an annuitant is not married (or is remarried if there is no election in effect under the following sentence) as if the annuity had not been so reduced, subject to any reduction required to provide a survivor benefit under section 4054(b) or (c) of this title. Upon remarriage the retired participant may irrevocably elect, by means of a signed writing received by the Secretary within one year after such remarriage, to receive during such marriage a reduction in annuity for the purpose of allowing an annuity for the new spouse of the annuitant in the event such spouse survives the annuitant. Such reduction shall be equal to the reduction in effect immediately before</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>