<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4055" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4055/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4055/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4055"><akn:num>4055</akn:num><akn:heading>Lump-sum payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4055. Lump-sum payments(a) Requirements for payment(1) A participant is entitled to be paid a lump-sum credit if the participant—(A) is separated from the Service for at least 31 consecutive days, or is transferred to a position in which the participant is not subject to this subchapter and remains in such a position for at least 31 consecutive days;

(B) files an application with the Secretary of State for payment of the lump-sum credit;

(C) is not reemployed in a position in which the participant is subject to this subchapter at the time the participant files the application;

(D) will not become eligible to receive an annuity under this part within 31 days after filing the application; and

(E) has notified any spouse or former spouse the participant may have of the application for payment in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary of State.


Such regulations may provide for waiver of subparagraph (E) under circumstances described in section 4046(b)(1)(D) of this title.

(2) Such lump-sum credit shall be paid to the participant and to any former spouse of the participant in accordance with subsection (i).


(b) Recall service; return of contributionsWhenever an annuitant becomes separated from the Service following a period of recall service without becoming eligible for a supplemental or recomputed annuity under section 4063 of this title, the compulsory contributions of the annuitant to the Fund for such service, together with any special contributions the annuitant may have made for other service performed after the date of separation from the Service which forms the basis for annuity, shall be returned to the annuitant (and any former spouse of the annuitant who was married to the participant during the period of recall service, in accordance with subsection (i)).


(c) Difference between annuity and lump-sum creditIf all annuity rights under this part based on the service of a deceased participant or annuitant terminate before the total a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements for payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recall service; return of contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recall service; return of contributions Whenever an annuitant becomes separated from the Service following a period of recall service without becoming eligible for a supplemental or recomputed annuity under section 4063 of this title, the compulsory contributions of the annuitant to the Fund for such service, together with any special contributions the annuitant may have made for other service performed after the date of separation from the Service which forms the basis for annuity, shall be returned to the annuitant (and any former spouse of the annuitant who was married to the participant during the period of recall service, in accordance with subsection (i)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Difference between annuity and lump-sum credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Difference between annuity and lump-sum credit If all annuity rights under this part based on the service of a deceased participant or annuitant terminate before the total annuity paid equals the lump-sum credit to which the participant or annuitant is entitled, the difference shall be paid in accordance with subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lack of eligible survivors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Lack of eligible survivors If a participant or former participant dies and is not survived by an individual eligible for an annuity under this part or by such an individual or individuals all of whose annuity rights terminate before a claim for survivor annuity is filed, the lump-sum credit to which the participant or annuitant is entitled shall be paid in accordance with subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death of annuitant who was former participant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Death of annuitant who was former participant If an annuitant who was a former participant dies, any annuity accrued and unpaid shall be paid in accordance with subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Order of precedence for payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Order of precedence for payments Payments under subsections (c) through (e) shall be paid in the following order of precedence to individuals surviving the participant and alive on the date entitlement to the payment arises, upon the establishment of a valid claim therefor, and such payment shall be a bar to recovery by any other person:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death of survivor annuitant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Death of survivor annuitant Annuity accrued and unpaid on the death of a survivor annuitant shall be paid in the following order of precedence, and the payment bars recovery by any other person:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Amount of credit 11 See Amendment of Section note below. Amounts deducted and withheld from basic salary of a participant under section 4045 of this title from the beginning of the first pay period after the participant has completed 35 years of service computed under section 4056 of this title (excluding service credit for unused sick leave under section 4056(b) of this title), together with interest on the amounts at the rate of 3 percent a year compounded annually from the date of the deduction to the date of retirement or death, shall be applied toward any special contribution due under section 4045(d) of this title), and any balance not so required shall be refunded in a lump sum to the participant after separation or, in the event of a death in service, to a beneficiary in the order of precedence specified in subsection (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4055_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Former spouses Unless otherwise expressly provided by any spousal agreement or court order under section 4060(b)(1) of this title, the amount of a participant’s or former participant’s lump-sum credit payable to a former spouse of that participant shall be— The lump-sum credit of the participant shall be reduced by the amount of the lump-sum credit payable to the former spouse. For the purposes of this subsection, the term “creditable service” means service which is creditable under part I or II.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>