<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4060" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4060/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4060/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4060"><akn:num>4060</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment and attachment of moneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4060. Assignment and attachment of moneys(a) Annuities and severance pay benefits(1) An individual entitled to an annuity from the Fund may make allotments or assignments of amounts from such annuity for such purposes as the Secretary of State in his or her sole discretion considers appropriate.

(2) Notwithstanding section 3727 of title 31 or any other law, a member of the Service who is entitled to receive benefits under section 4009(b)(1) of this title may assign to any person the whole or any part of those benefits. Any such assignment shall be on a form approved by the Secretary of the Treasury and a copy of such assignment form shall be deposited with the Secretary of the Treasury by the member executing the assignment.


(b) Participants or annuitants having former spouses(1)(A) In the case of any participant or annuitant who has a former spouse who is covered by a court order or who is a party to a spousal agreement—(i) any right of the former spouse to any annuity under section 4054(a) of this title in connection with any retirement or disability annuity of the participant, and the amount of any such annuity;

(ii) any right of the former spouse to a survivor annuity under section 4054(b) or (c) of this title, and the amount of any such annuity; and

(iii) any right of the former spouse to any payment of a lump-sum credit under section 4055(a) or (b) of this title;


shall be determined in accordance with that spousal agreement or court order, if and to the extent expressly provided for in the terms of that spousal agreement or court order.

(B) This paragraph shall not apply in the case of any spousal agreement or court order which, as determined by the Secretary of State—(i) would provide for a survivor annuity for a spouse or any former spouse of a participant with respect to which there has not been an annuity reduction (or a salary reduction or payment under section 4054(c)(3) of this title); or

(ii) is otherwise inconsistent with the requirements o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4060_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuities and severance pay benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annuities and severance pay benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4060_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants or annuitants having former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participants or annuitants having former spouses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4060_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of other provisions of law or remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicability of other provisions of law or remedies None of the moneys mentioned in this part shall be assignable either in law or equity, except under subsection (a) or (b) of this section, or subject to execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, except as otherwise may be provided by Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>