<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4062" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4062/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4062/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4062"><akn:num>4062</akn:num><akn:heading>Unfunded liability obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4062. Unfunded liability obligations(a) Notice of interest and military service creditAt the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of State shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amount equivalent to—(1) interest on the unfunded liability computed for that year at the interest rate used in the then most recent valuation of the System, and

(2) that portion of disbursement for annuities for that year which the Secretary of State estimates is attributable to credit allowed for military and naval service, less an amount determined by the Secretary of State to be appropriate to reflect the value of the deposits made to the credit of the Fund under section 4045(e) of this title.


(b) Credit to FundBefore closing the accounts for each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall credit such amounts to the Fund, as a Government contribution, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated.


(c) Reports to CongressRequests for appropriations to the Fund under section 4061(b) of this title shall include reports to the Congress on the sums credited to the Fund under this section.


(Pub. L. 96–465, title I, § 822, Oct. 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 2121; Ex. Ord. No. 12446, § 4(d), Oct. 17, 1983, 48 F.R. 48445.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1983—Subsec. (a)(2). Ex. Ord. No. 12446 inserted “, less an amount determined by the Secretary of State to be appropriate to reflect the value of the deposits made to the credit of the Fund under section 4045(e) of this title”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1983 AmendmentAmendment by Ex. Ord. No. 12446 effective Oct. 17, 1983, see section 4(e) of Ex. Ord. No. 12446, set out under section 4067 of this title.

Termination of Reporting RequirementsFor termination, effective May 15, 2000, of provisions of law requiring submittal to Congress of any annual, semiannual, or other regular periodic report listed in House Document No. 103–7 (in which a report required under subsec.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of interest and military service credit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice of interest and military service credit At the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of State shall notify the Secretary of the Treasury of the amount equivalent to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credit to Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Credit to Fund Before closing the accounts for each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall credit such amounts to the Fund, as a Government contribution, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4062_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports to Congress Requests for appropriations to the Fund under section 4061(b) of this title shall include reports to the Congress on the sums credited to the Fund under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>