<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4071j"><akn:num>4071j</akn:num><akn:heading>Former spouses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4071j. Former spouses(a) Entitlement to share in benefits; conditions; remarriage; payments as income to former spouse; disability annuitants; election regarding method of payment; maximum amount payable(1)(A) Unless otherwise expressly provided by any spousal agreement or court order governing disposition of benefits under this part, a former spouse of a participant or former participant is entitled, during the period described in subparagraph (B), to a share (determined under paragraph (2)) of all benefits otherwise payable to such participant under this part if such former spouse was married to the participant for at least 10 years during service of the participant which is creditable under this subchapter with at least 5 of such years occurring while the participant was a member of the Foreign Service.

(B) The period referred to in subparagraph (A) is the period which begins on the first day of the month following the month in which the divorce or annulment becomes final and ends on the last day of the month before the former spouse dies or remarries before 55 years of age.


(2) The share referred to in paragraph (1) equals—(A) 50 percent, if such former spouse was married to the participant throughout the actual years of service of the participant which are creditable under this subchapter; or

(B) a pro rata share of 50 percent, if such former spouse was not married to the participant throughout such creditable service.


(3) A former spouse shall not be qualified for any benefit under this subsection if, before the commencement of any benefit, the former spouse remarries before becoming 55 years of age.

(4)(A) For purposes of title 26, payments to a former spouse under this section shall be treated as income to the former spouse and not to the participant.

(B) Any reduction in payments to a participant or former participant as a result of payments to a former spouse under this subsection shall be disregarded in calculating—(i) the survivor annuity for a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to share in benefits; conditions; remarriage; payments as income to former spouse; disability annuitants; election regarding method of payment; maximum amount payable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Entitlement to share in benefits; conditions; remarriage; payments as income to former spouse; disability annuitants; election regarding method of payment; maximum amount payable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to survivor benefits; determination of share; disqualification upon remarriage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Entitlement to survivor benefits; determination of share; disqualification upon remarriage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diminution of entitlement of former spouse prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Diminution of entitlement of former spouse prohibited A participant or former participant may not make any election or modification of election under section 8417, 8418, or 8433 of title 5 or other section relating to the participant’s account in the Thrift Savings Plan or annuity under the basic plan that would diminish the entitlement of a former spouse to any benefit granted to the former spouse by this section or in a current spousal agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of participant from Foreign Service Retirement and Disability System; determination of benefit share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of participant from Foreign Service Retirement and Disability System; determination of benefit share If a member becomes a participant under this part after qualifying for benefits under part I and, at the time of transfer, has a former spouse entitled to benefits under part I which are determined under section 4054 or 4055 of this title (as determined by the Secretary of State) and are similar in amount to a pro rata share division under section 4054 or 4055 of this title and the service of the member as a participant under this part is not recognized in determining that pro rata share, then subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall not apply to such former spouse. Otherwise, subsections (a) and (b) of this section shall apply.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death of participant entitled to deferred annuity; spousal agreement; payment of survivor annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Death of participant entitled to deferred annuity; spousal agreement; payment of survivor annuity If a participant dies after completing at least 18 months of service or a former participant dies entitled to a deferred annuity, but before becoming eligible to receive the annuity, and such participant or former participant has left with the Secretary of State a spousal agreement promising a share of a survivor annuity under subchapter IV, chapter 84, title 5, to a former spouse, such survivor annuity shall be paid under the terms of this part as if the survivor annuity had been ordered by a court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>