<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4071d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4071d"><akn:num>4071d</akn:num><akn:heading>Entitlement to annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4071d. Entitlement to annuity(a) Retirement conditions; definitions(1) Any participant may be retired under the conditions specified in section 4051 of this title and shall be retired under the conditions specified in sections 4052 and 4053 of this title and receive benefits under this part.

(2) For the purposes of this subsection—(A) the term “participant”, as used in the sections referred to in paragraph (1), means a participant in the Foreign Service Pension System; and

(B) the term “System”, as used in those sections, means the Foreign Service Pension System.


(3) For purposes of any annuity computation under this subsection, the average pay (as used in section 8414 11 See References in Text note below. of title 5) of any member of the Service whose official duty station is outside the continental United States shall be considered to be the salary that would have been paid to the member had the member’s official duty station been Washington, D.C., including locality-based comparability payments under section 5304 of title 5 that would have been payable to the member if the member’s official duty station had been Washington, D.C.


(b) Voluntary or mandatory retirement with authorization for immediate annuity; computation of annuity(1) Any participant who retires voluntarily or mandatorily under section 4007, 4008, 4010a, 4051, 4052, or 4053 of this title under conditions authorizing an immediate annuity for participants in the Foreign Service Retirement and Disability System or for participants in the Foreign Service Pension System, and who has completed at least 5 years as a member of the Foreign Service, shall be entitled to an immediate annuity computed under paragraph (2).

(2) An annuity under paragraph (1) shall be computed—(A) in accordance with section 8415(e)(1) of title 5 for all service while a participant in this System and for prior service creditable under this part not otherwise counted as—(i) a member of the Service,

(ii) an employee of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retirement conditions; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Retirement conditions; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary or mandatory retirement with authorization for immediate annuity; computation of annuity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Voluntary or mandatory retirement with authorization for immediate annuity; computation of annuity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annuity supplement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annuity supplement A participant who is entitled to an immediate annuity under subsection (b) shall be entitled to receive an annuity supplement while the annuitant is under 62 years of age. The annuity supplement shall be based on the total creditable service of the annuitant and shall be computed in accordance with sections 8421(b) and 8421a of title 5 as if the participant were a law enforcement officer retired under section 8412(d) 1 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4071d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation for cause based on disloyalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Separation for cause based on disloyalty Any participant who is separated for cause under section 4010 of this title shall not be entitled to an annuity under this System when the Secretary determines that the separation was based in whole or in part on disloyalty to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>