<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4135"><akn:num>4135</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign Service Grievance Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4135. Foreign Service Grievance Board(a) Establishment; compositionThere is established the Foreign Service Grievance Board (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”). The Board shall consist of no fewer than 5 members who shall be independent, distinguished citizens of the United States, well known for their integrity, who are not employees of the Department or members of the Service.


(b) Appointment and selection of nominees; length of terms; vacanciesThe Chairperson and other members of the Board shall be appointed by the Secretary of State, from nominees approved in writing by the agencies to which this subchapter applies and the exclusive representative (if any) for each such agency. Each member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, subject to renewal with the same written approvals required for initial appointment. In the event of a vacancy on the Board, an appointment for the unexpired term may be made by the Secretary of State in accordance with the procedures specified in this section. In the event of inability to obtain agreement on a nominee, each such agency and exclusive representative shall select 2 nominees and shall, in an order determined by lot, in turn strike a name from a list of such nominees until only one name remains. For purposes of this section, the nominee whose name remains shall be deemed to be approved in writing by each such agency head and exclusive representative.


(c) CompensationMembers of the Board who are not employees of the Government shall be paid for each day they are performing their duties (including traveltime) at the daily equivalent of the maximum rate payable for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5.


(d) RemovalThe Secretary of State may, upon written notice, remove a Board member for corruption, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or demonstrated incapacity to perform his or her functions, established at a hearing (unless the right to a hearing is waived i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; composition There is established the Foreign Service Grievance Board (hereinafter in this subchapter referred to as the “Board”). The Board shall consist of no fewer than 5 members who shall be independent, distinguished citizens of the United States, well known for their integrity, who are not employees of the Department or members of the Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and selection of nominees; length of terms; vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment and selection of nominees; length of terms; vacancies The Chairperson and other members of the Board shall be appointed by the Secretary of State, from nominees approved in writing by the agencies to which this subchapter applies and the exclusive representative (if any) for each such agency. Each member of the Board shall be appointed for a term of 2 years, subject to renewal with the same written approvals required for initial appointment. In the event of a vacancy on the Board, an appointment for the unexpired term may be made by the Secretary of State in accordance with the procedures specified in this section. In the event of inability to obtain agreement on a nominee, each such agency and exclusive representative shall select 2 nominees and shall, in an order determined by lot, in turn strike a name from a list of such nominees until only one name remains. For purposes of this section, the nominee whose name remains shall be deemed to be approved in writing by eac</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation Members of the Board who are not employees of the Government shall be paid for each day they are performing their duties (including traveltime) at the daily equivalent of the maximum rate payable for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Removal The Secretary of State may, upon written notice, remove a Board member for corruption, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or demonstrated incapacity to perform his or her functions, established at a hearing (unless the right to a hearing is waived in writing by the Board member).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative services; payment of expenses; assignment as staff employees of Board; performance evaluation reports; records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative services; payment of expenses; assignment as staff employees of Board; performance evaluation reports; records The Board may obtain facilities, services, and supplies through the general administrative services of the Department of State. All expenses of the Board, including necessary costs of the travel and travel-related expenses of a grievant, shall be paid out of funds appropriated to the Department for obligation and expenditure by the Board. At the request of the Board, employees of the Department and members of the Service may be assigned as staff employees for the Board. Within the limits of appropriated funds, the Board may appoint and fix the compensation of such other employees as the Board considers necessary to carry out its functions. The individuals so appointed or assigned shall be responsible solely to the Board, and the Board shall prepare the performance evaluation reports for such individuals. The records of the Board shall be maintained by the Bo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>