<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4137" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4137/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4137/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4137"><akn:num>4137</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign Service Grievance Board decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4137. Foreign Service Grievance Board decisions(a) Record; findings of fact and statement of reasonsUpon completion of its proceedings, the Board shall expeditiously decide the grievance on the basis of the record of proceedings. In each case the decision of the Board shall be in writing, and shall include findings of fact and a statement of the reasons for the decision of the Board.


(b) Authority of Department upon finding of meritorious grievanceIf the Board finds that the grievance is meritorious, the Board shall have the authority to direct the Department—(1) to correct any official personnel record relating to the grievant which the Board finds to be inaccurate or erroneous, to have an omission, or to contain information of a falsely prejudicial character;

(2) to reverse a decision denying the grievant compensation or any other perquisite of employment authorized by laws or regulations when the Board finds that such decision was arbitrary, capricious, or contrary to laws or regulations;

(3) to retain in the Service a member whose separation would be in consequence of the matter by which the member is aggrieved;

(4) to reinstate the grievant, and to grant the grievant back pay in accordance with section 5596(b)(1) of title 5;

(5) to pay reasonable attorney fees to the grievant to the same extent and in the same manner as such fees may be required by the Merit Systems Protection Board under section 7701(g) of title 5; and

(6) to take such other remedial action as may be appropriate under procedures agreed to by the Department and the exclusive representative (if any).


(c) Finality of decisions; judicial reviewExcept as provided in subsection (d), decisions of the Board under this subchapter shall be final, subject only to judicial review as provided in section 4140 of this title.


(d) Recommendations(1) If the Board finds that the grievance is meritorious and that remedial action should be taken that relates directly to promotion, tenure or assignment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record; findings of fact and statement of reasons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Record; findings of fact and statement of reasons Upon completion of its proceedings, the Board shall expeditiously decide the grievance on the basis of the record of proceedings. In each case the decision of the Board shall be in writing, and shall include findings of fact and a statement of the reasons for the decision of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Department upon finding of meritorious grievance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Department upon finding of meritorious grievance If the Board finds that the grievance is meritorious, the Board shall have the authority to direct the Department—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of decisions; judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Finality of decisions; judicial review Except as provided in subsection (d), decisions of the Board under this subchapter shall be final, subject only to judicial review as provided in section 4140 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record of grievances; copy to committee of Congress; right of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Record of grievances; copy to committee of Congress; right of review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4137_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alleged discrimination; substantive law to be applied</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Alleged discrimination; substantive law to be applied The Board shall, with respect to any grievance based on an alleged violation of a law, rule, regulation, or policy directive referred to in section 4131(a)(1)(H) of this title, apply the substantive law that would be applied by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission if a charge or claim alleging discrimination under such law, rule, regulation, or policy directive had been filed with the commission.1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>