<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4306"><akn:num>4306</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of foreign missions in the District of Columbia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4306. Location of foreign missions in the District of Columbia(a) Section as governing location, replacement, or expansionThe location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries in the District of Columbia shall be subject to this section.


(b) Acceptable areas; limitations and conditions(1) A chancery shall be permitted to locate as a matter of right in any area which is zoned commercial, industrial, waterfront, or mixed-use (CR).

(2) A chancery shall also be permitted to locate—(A) in any area which is zoned medium-high or high density residential, and

(B) in any other area, determined on the basis of existing uses, which includes office or institutional uses, including but not limited to any area zoned mixed-use diplomatic or special purpose,


subject to disapproval by the District of Columbia Board of Zoning Adjustment in accordance with this section.

(3) In each of the areas described in paragraphs (1) and (2), the limitations and conditions applicable to chanceries shall not exceed those applicable to other office or institutional uses in that area.


(c) Filing of application with Board of Zoning Adjustment; publication of notice; public participation; final determination(1) If a foreign mission wishes to locate a chancery in an area described in subsection (b)(2), or wishes to appeal an administrative decision relating to a chancery based in whole or in part upon any zoning map or regulation, it shall file an application with the Board of Zoning Adjustment which shall publish notice of that application in the District of Columbia Register.

(2) Regulations issued to carry out this section shall provide appropriate opportunities for participation by the public in proceedings concerning the location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries.

(3) A final determination concerning the location, replacement, or expansion of a chancery shall be made not later than six months after the date of the filing of an application with respect to such location, replacem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Section as governing location, replacement, or expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Section as governing location, replacement, or expansion The location, replacement, or expansion of chanceries in the District of Columbia shall be subject to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Acceptable areas; limitations and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Acceptable areas; limitations and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filing of application with Board of Zoning Adjustment; publication of notice; public participation; final determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Filing of application with Board of Zoning Adjustment; publication of notice; public participation; final determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for determination Any determination concerning the location of a chancery under subsection (b)(2), or concerning an appeal of an administrative decision with respect to a chancery based in whole or in part upon any zoning regulation or map, shall be based solely on the following criteria:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency of regulations, proceedings, and other actions; review and comment by National Planning Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consistency of regulations, proceedings, and other actions; review and comment by National Planning Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule-making nature of proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule-making nature of proceedings Regulations issued to carry out this section shall provide for proceedings of a rule-making and not of an adjudicatory nature.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with District of Columbia building and related codes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compliance with District of Columbia building and related codes The Secretary shall require foreign missions to comply substantially with District of Columbia building and related codes in a manner determined by the Secretary to be not inconsistent with the international obligations of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Board of Zoning Adjustment or Zoning Commission not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Approval of Board of Zoning Adjustment or Zoning Commission not required Approval by the Board of Zoning Adjustment or the Zoning Commission or, except as provided in section 4305 of this title, by any other agency or official is not required—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership on Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Membership on Zoning Commission and Board of Zoning Adjustment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4306_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Application of other laws Provisions of law (other than this chapter) applicable with respect to the location, replacement, or expansion of real property in the District of Columbia shall apply with respect to chanceries only to the extent that they are consistent with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>