<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4315" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4315/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4315/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4315"><akn:num>4315</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of foreign mission in manner incompatible with its status as foreign mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4315. Use of foreign mission in manner incompatible with its status as foreign mission(a) Establishment of limitation on certain usesA foreign mission may not allow an unaffiliated alien the use of any premise of that foreign mission which is inviolable under United States law (including any treaty) for any purpose which is incompatible with its status as a foreign mission, including use as a residence.


(b) Temporary lodgingFor the purposes of this section, the term “residence” does not include such temporary lodging as may be permitted under regulations issued by the Secretary.


(c) WaiverThe Secretary may waive subsection (a) with respect to all foreign missions of a country (and may revoke such a waiver) 30 days after providing written notification of such a waiver, together with the reasons for such waiver (or revocation of such a waiver), to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.


(d) ReportNot later than 180 days after December 22, 1987, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Congress concerning the implementation of this section and shall submit such other reports to the Congress concerning changes in implementation as may be necessary.


(e) DefinitionsFor the purposes of this section—(1) the term “foreign mission” includes any international organization as defined in section 4309(b) of this title; and

(2) the term “unaffiliated alien” means, with respect to a foreign country, an alien who—(A) is admitted to the United States as a nonimmigrant, and

(B) is not a member, or a family member of a member, of a foreign mission of that foreign country.



(Aug. 1, 1956, ch. 841, title II, § 215, as added Pub. L. 100–204, title I, § 128(a), Dec. 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 1343.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
December 22, 1987, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “the date of the enactment of this Act”, which was translated as meaning the date of enactment of Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4315_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of limitation on certain uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of limitation on certain uses A foreign mission may not allow an unaffiliated alien the use of any premise of that foreign mission which is inviolable under United States law (including any treaty) for any purpose which is incompatible with its status as a foreign mission, including use as a residence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4315_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary lodging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Temporary lodging For the purposes of this section, the term “residence” does not include such temporary lodging as may be permitted under regulations issued by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4315_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver The Secretary may waive subsection (a) with respect to all foreign missions of a country (and may revoke such a waiver) 30 days after providing written notification of such a waiver, together with the reasons for such waiver (or revocation of such a waiver), to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4315_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 180 days after December 22, 1987, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the Congress concerning the implementation of this section and shall submit such other reports to the Congress concerning changes in implementation as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4315_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For the purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>