<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4316" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4316/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4316/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4316"><akn:num>4316</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of travel restrictions to personnel of certain countries and organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4316. Application of travel restrictions to personnel of certain countries and organizations(a) Requirement for restrictionsThe Secretary shall apply the same generally applicable restrictions to the travel while in the United States of the individuals described in subsection (b) as are applied under this chapter to the members of the missions of the Soviet Union in the United States.


(b) Individuals subject to restrictionsThe restrictions required by subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to those individuals who (as determined by the Secretary) are—(1) the personnel of an international organization, if the individual is a national of any foreign country whose government engages in intelligence activities in the United States that are harmful to the national security of the United States;

(2) the personnel of a mission to an international organization, if that mission is the mission of a foreign government that engages in intelligence activities in the United States that are harmful to the national security of the United States; or

(3) the family members or dependents of an individual described in paragraphs (1) and (2);


and who are not nationals or permanent resident aliens of the United States.

(c) WaiversThe Secretary, after consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, may waive application of the restrictions required by subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States so require.


(d) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(3), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 397

(e) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “generally applicable restrictions” means any limitations on the radius within which unrestricted travel is permitted and obtaining travel services through the auspices of the Office of Foreign Missions for travel elsewhere, and does not include any restrictions which unconditionally prohibit the m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement for restrictions The Secretary shall apply the same generally applicable restrictions to the travel while in the United States of the individuals described in subsection (b) as are applied under this chapter to the members of the missions of the Soviet Union in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals subject to restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Individuals subject to restrictions The restrictions required by subsection (a) shall be applied with respect to those individuals who (as determined by the Secretary) are— and who are not nationals or permanent resident aliens of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waivers The Secretary, after consultation with the Director of Central Intelligence and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, may waive application of the restrictions required by subsection (a) if the Secretary determines that the national security and foreign policy interests of the United States so require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 139(3), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 397</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4316_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>