<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4356" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4356/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4356/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4356"><akn:num>4356</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4356. Advisory Committee(a) Establishment(1) There is established on a permanent basis the Advisory Committee on Historical Diplomatic Documentation for the Department of State. The activities of the Advisory Committee shall be coordinated by the Office of the Historian of the Department of State.

(2) The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 9 members and an executive secretary. The Historian shall serve as executive secretary.

(3)(A) The members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed by the Secretary of State from among distinguished historians, political scientists, archivists, international lawyers, and other social scientists who have a demonstrable record of substantial research pertaining to the foreign relations of the United States. No officer or employee of the United States Government shall be appointed to the Advisory Committee.

(B)(i) Six members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed from lists of individuals nominated by the American Historical Association, the Organization of American Historians, the American Political Science Association, Society of American Archivists, the American Society of International Law, and the Society for Historians of American Foreign Relations. One member shall be appointed from each list.

(ii) If an organization does not submit a list of nominees under clause (i) in a timely fashion, the Secretary of State shall make an appointment from among the nominees on other lists.




(b) Terms of service for appointments(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), members of the Advisory Committee shall be appointed for terms of three years.

(2) Of the members first appointed, as designated by the Secretary of State at the time of their appointment (after consultation with the appropriate organizations) three shall be appointed for terms of one year, three shall be appointed for terms of two years, and three shall be appointed for terms of three years.

(3) Each term of service under paragraph (1) shall begin on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of service for appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of service for appointments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection of chairperson The Advisory Committee shall select, from among its members, a chairperson to serve a term of 1 year. A chairperson may be reelected upon expiration of his or her term as chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings A majority of the members of the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum. The Advisory Committee shall meet at least quarterly or as frequently as may be necessary to carry out its duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security clearances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Security clearances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4356_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>