<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4413"><akn:num>4413</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of the Endowment for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4413. Eligibility of the Endowment for grants(a) Compliance with statutory requirementsGrants may be made to the Endowment under this subchapter only if the Endowment agrees to comply with the requirements specified in this section and elsewhere in this subchapter.


(b) Funding for private sector groups and covered programs only(1) The Endowment may only provide funding for programs of private sector groups and may not carry out programs directly.

(2) The Endowment may provide funding only for programs which are consistent with the purposes set forth in section 4411(b) of this title.


(c) Compensation, etc., for officers and employees of Endowment(1) Officers of the Endowment may not receive any salary or other compensation from any source, other than the Endowment, for services rendered during the period of their employment by the Endowment.

(2) If an individual who is an officer or employee of the United States Government serves as a member of the Board of Directors or as an officer or employee of the Endowment, that individual may not receive any compensation or travel expenses in connection with services performed for the Endowment.


(d) Prohibitions respecting financial matters(1) The Endowment shall not issue any shares of stock or declare or pay any dividends.

(2) No part of the assets of the Endowment shall inure to the benefit of any member of the Board, any officer or employee of the Endowment, or any other individual, except as salary or reasonable compensation for services.


(e) Audit of accounts; reporting requirements(1) The accounts of the Endowment shall be audited annually in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants or independent licensed public accountants certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State or other political subdivision of the United States. The audits shall be conducted at the place or places where the accounts of the Endowment are normally kept. All books,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with statutory requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with statutory requirements Grants may be made to the Endowment under this subchapter only if the Endowment agrees to comply with the requirements specified in this section and elsewhere in this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for private sector groups and covered programs only</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding for private sector groups and covered programs only</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation, etc., for officers and employees of Endowment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation, etc., for officers and employees of Endowment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions respecting financial matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibitions respecting financial matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of accounts; reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Audit of accounts; reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of financial transactions; reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Audit of financial transactions; reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits by United States Information Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Audits by United States Information Agency The financial transactions of the Endowment for each fiscal year shall be audited by the United States Information Agency under the conditions set forth in subsection (f)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping requirements; audit and examination of books, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Recordkeeping requirements; audit and examination of books, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report; contents; testimony respecting report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual report; contents; testimony respecting report Not later than February 1 of each year, the Endowment shall submit an annual report for the preceding fiscal year to the President for transmittal to the Congress. The report shall include a comprehensive and detailed report of the Endowment’s operations, activities, financial condition, and accomplishments under this subchapter and may include such recommendations as the Endowment deems appropriate. The Board members and officers of the Endowment shall be available to testify before appropriate committees of the Congress with respect to such report, the report of any audit made by the Comptroller General pursuant to subsection (f), or any other matter which any such committee may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4413_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grantee; conflict of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Grantee; conflict of interest After January 31, 1993, no member of the Board of the Endowment may be a member of the board of directors or an officer of any grantee of the National Endowment for Democracy which receives more than 5 percent of the funds of the Endowment for any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>