<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4803"><akn:num>4803</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of high risk, high threat posts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4803. Designation of high risk, high threat posts(a) Initial designationNot later than 30 days after December 16, 2016, the Department of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report, in classified form, that contains a list of diplomatic and consular posts designated as high risk, high threat posts.


(b) Designations before opening or reopening postsBefore opening or reopening a diplomatic or consular post, the Secretary shall determine if such post should be designated as a high risk, high threat post.


(c) Designating existing postsThe Secretary shall regularly review existing diplomatic and consular posts to determine if any such post should be designated as a high risk, high threat post if conditions at such post or the surrounding security environment require such a designation.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.


(2) High risk, high threat postThe term “high risk, high threat post” means a United States diplomatic or consular post or other United States mission abroad, as determined by the Secretary, that, among other factors—(A) is located in a country—(i) with high to critical levels of political violence and terrorism; and

(ii) the government of which lacks the ability or willingness to provide adequate security; and


(B) has mission physical security platforms that fall below the Department of State’s established standards.



(Pub. L. 99–399, title I, § 104, as added Pub. L. 114–323, title I, § 101(a), Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1907; amended Pub. L. 115–94, § 2(a), Dec. 18, 2017, 131 Stat. 2038.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 4803, Pub. L. 99–399, title I, § 104(a), Aug. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 856, established Bureau</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial designation Not later than 30 days after December 16, 2016, the Department of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report, in classified form, that contains a list of diplomatic and consular posts designated as high risk, high threat posts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designations before opening or reopening posts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designations before opening or reopening posts Before opening or reopening a diplomatic or consular post, the Secretary shall determine if such post should be designated as a high risk, high threat post.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designating existing posts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designating existing posts The Secretary shall regularly review existing diplomatic and consular posts to determine if any such post should be designated as a high risk, high threat post if conditions at such post or the surrounding security environment require such a designation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>