<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4851" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4851/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4851/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4851"><akn:num>4851</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4851. Authorization(a) Diplomatic security program(1) In generalIn addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, the following amounts are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 1986 and 1987, for the Department of State to carry out diplomatic security construction, acquisition, and operations pursuant to the Department of State’s Supplemental Diplomatic Security Program, as justified to the Congress for the respective fiscal year for “Administration of Foreign Affairs”, as follows:(A) For “Salaries and Expenses”, $308,104,000.

(B) For “Acquisition and Maintenance of Buildings Abroad”, $857,806,000.

(C) For “Counterterrorism Research and Development”, $15,000,000.


(2) Omitted

(3) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 101(c), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 388

(4) Allocation of amounts authorized to be appropriatedAmounts authorized to be appropriated by this subsection, and by the amendment made by paragraph (2), shall be allocated as provided in the table entitled “Diplomatic Security Program” relating to this section which appears in the Joint Explanatory Statement of the Committee of Conference to accompany H.R. 4151 of the 99th Congress (the Omnibus Diplomatic Security and Antiterrorism Act of 1986).



(b) Notification to authorizing Committees of requests for appropriationsIn any fiscal year, whenever the Secretary of State submits to the Congress a request for appropriations to carry out the program described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of such request, together with a justification of each item listed in such request.


(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 122(b), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 392

(d) Prohibition on reallocations of authorizationsSection 2696(d) of this title shall not apply with respect to any amounts authorized to be appropriated under this section.


(e) Security requirements of o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diplomatic security program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Diplomatic security program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to authorizing Committees of requests for appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification to authorizing Committees of requests for appropriations In any fiscal year, whenever the Secretary of State submits to the Congress a request for appropriations to carry out the program described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate of such request, together with a justification of each item listed in such request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–236, title I, § 122(b), Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 392</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on reallocations of authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition on reallocations of authorizations Section 2696(d) of this title shall not apply with respect to any amounts authorized to be appropriated under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security requirements of other foreign affairs agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Security requirements of other foreign affairs agencies Based solely on security requirements and within the total amount of funds available for security, the Secretary of State shall ensure that an equitable level of funding is provided for the security requirements of other foreign affairs agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insufficiency of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Insufficiency of funds In the event that sufficient funds are not available in any fiscal year for all of the diplomatic security construction, acquisition, and operations pursuant to the Department of State’s Supplemental Diplomatic Security Program, as justified to the Congress for such fiscal year, the Secretary of State shall report to the Congress the effect that the insufficiency of funds will have with respect to the Department of State and each of the other foreign affairs agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds for certain security programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Allocation of funds for certain security programs Of the amount of funds authorized to be appropriated by subsection (a)(1)(A), $34,537,000 shall be available to the Secretary of State only for the protection of classified office equipment, the expansion of information systems security, and the hiring of American systems managers and operators for computers at high threat locations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Furniture, furnishings, and equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Furniture, furnishings, and equipment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>