<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4865"><akn:num>4865</akn:num><akn:heading>Security requirements for United States diplomatic facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4865. Security requirements for United States diplomatic facilities(a) In generalThe following security requirements shall apply with respect to United States diplomatic facilities and specified personnel:(1) Threat assessment(A) Emergency Action PlanThe Emergency Action Plan (EAP) of each United States mission shall address a range of threats, including that of large explosive attacks from vehicles and from complex attacks (as such term is defined in section 4866 of this title), and the safety of employees during such an explosive attack or such a complex attack. Such plan shall be reviewed and updated annually.


(B) Security Environment Threat ListThe Security Environment Threat List shall contain a section that addresses potential acts of international terrorism against United States diplomatic facilities based on threat identification criteria that emphasize the threat of transnational terrorism and include the local security environment, host government support, and other relevant factors such as cultural realities. Such plan shall be reviewed and updated every six months.



(2) Site selection(A) In generalIn selecting a site for any new United States diplomatic facility abroad in a location that has certain minimum ratings under the Security Environment Threat List as determined by the Secretary in his or her discretion, the Secretary shall ensure that all United States Government personnel at the post (except those under the command of an area military commander, personnel of the Peace Corps, and personnel of any other type or category of facility that the Secretary may identify) will be located on the site.


(B) Waiver authority(i) In generalSubject to clause (ii), the Secretary of State may waive subparagraph (A) if the Secretary, in consultation with, as appropriate, the head of each agency employing personnel that would not be located at the site, if applicable, determines that it is in the national interest of the United States after taking account </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The following security requirements shall apply with respect to United States diplomatic facilities and specified personnel:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Statutory construction Nothing in this section alters or amends existing security requirements not addressed by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>