<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4903" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4903/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/4903/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4903"><akn:num>4903</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4903. Fellowships(a) NumberUp to 100 fellowships may be provided under this chapter each year. Not less than 15 shall be provided during fiscal year 1993.


(b) Remuneration and periodThe Board shall determine, taking into consideration the position in which each Fellow will serve and his or her experience and expertise—(1) the amount of remuneration the Fellow will receive for his or her service under this chapter, and

(2) the period of the fellowship, which shall be between one and two years.


(c) TrainingEach Fellow may be given appropriate training at the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center or other appropriate institution.


(d) Housing and transportationThe Secretary of State shall, pursuant to regulations—(1) provide housing for each Fellow while the Fellow is serving abroad, including (where appropriate) housing for family members; and

(2) pay the costs and expenses incurred by each Fellow in traveling between the United States and the country in which the Fellow serves, including (where appropriate) travel for family members.


(e) Effective dateSubsection (d) of this section shall not take effect until October 1, 1986.


(Pub. L. 99–399, title X, § 1004, Aug. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 894; Pub. L. 102–511, title VIII, § 804(a), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3353; Pub. L. 107–132, § 1(b), Jan. 16, 2002, 115 Stat. 2412.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2002—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 107–132 substituted “George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center” for “Foreign Service Institute”.
1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–511 inserted at end “Not less than 15 shall be provided during fiscal year 1993.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
FundingPub. L. 102–511, title VIII, § 804(b), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3353, provided that: “In addition to the funds made available pursuant to section 1005(c) of that Act [22 U.S.C. 4904(c)], funds authorized to be appropriated by chapter 11 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2295 et se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4903_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Number Up to 100 fellowships may be provided under this chapter each year. Not less than 15 shall be provided during fiscal year 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4903_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remuneration and period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Remuneration and period The Board shall determine, taking into consideration the position in which each Fellow will serve and his or her experience and expertise—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4903_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Training Each Fellow may be given appropriate training at the George P. Shultz National Foreign Affairs Training Center or other appropriate institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4903_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing and transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Housing and transportation The Secretary of State shall, pursuant to regulations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4903_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date Subsection (d) of this section shall not take effect until October 1, 1986.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>