<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5421"><akn:num>5421</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise Funds for Poland and Hungary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5421. Enterprise Funds for Poland and Hungary(a) PurposesThe purposes of this section are to promote—(1) development of the Polish and Hungarian private sectors, including small businesses, the agricultural sector, and joint ventures with United States and host country participants, and

(2) policies and practices conducive to private sector development in Poland and Hungary,


through loans, grants, equity investments, feasibility studies, technical assistance, training, insurance, guarantees, and other measures.

(b) Authorization of appropriationsTo carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated to the President—(1) $240,000,000 to support the Polish-American Enterprise Fund; and

(2) $60,000,000 to support the Hungarian-American Enterprise Fund.


Such amounts are authorized to be made available until expended.

(c) Nonapplicability of other lawsThe funds appropriated under subsection (b) may be made available to the Polish-American Enterprise Fund and the Hungarian-American Enterprise Fund and used for the purposes of this section notwithstanding any other provision of law.


(d) Designation of Enterprise Funds(1) DesignationThe President is authorized to designate two private, nonprofit organizations as eligible to receive funds and support pursuant to this section upon determining that such organizations have been established for the purposes specified in subsection (a). For purposes of this chapter, the organizations so designated shall be referred to as the Polish-American Enterprise Fund and the Hungarian-American Enterprise Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Enterprise Funds”).


(2) Consultation with CongressThe President shall consult with the leadership of each House of Congress before designating an organization pursuant to paragraph (1).


(3) Board of Directors(A) Each Enterprise Fund shall be governed by a Board of Directors comprised of private citizens of the United States, and cit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purposes of this section are to promote— through loans, grants, equity investments, feasibility studies, technical assistance, training, insurance, guarantees, and other measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations To carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a), there are authorized to be appropriated to the President— Such amounts are authorized to be made available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nonapplicability of other laws The funds appropriated under subsection (b) may be made available to the Polish-American Enterprise Fund and the Hungarian-American Enterprise Fund and used for the purposes of this section notwithstanding any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Enterprise Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designation of Enterprise Funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to Enterprise Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grants to Enterprise Funds Funds appropriated to the President pursuant to subsection (b) shall be granted to the Enterprise Funds to carry out the purposes specified in subsection (a) and for the administrative expenses of each Enterprise Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible programs and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible programs and projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters to be considered by Enterprise Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Matters to be considered by Enterprise Funds In carrying out this section, each Enterprise Fund shall take into account such considerations as internationally recognized worker rights and other internationally recognized human rights, environmental factors, United States economic and employment effects, and the likelihood of commercial viability of the activity receiving assistance from the Enterprise Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Retention of interest An Enterprise Fund may hold funds granted to it pursuant to this section in interest-bearing accounts, prior to the disbursement of such funds for purposes specified in subsection (a), and may retain for such program purposes any interest earned on such deposits without returning such interest to the Treasury of the United States and without further appropriation by the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of United States private venture capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Use of United States private venture capital In order to maximize the effectiveness of the activities of the Enterprise Funds, each Enterprise Fund may conduct public offerings or private placements for the purpose of soliciting and accepting United States venture capital which may be used, separately or together with funds made available pursuant to this section, for any lawful investment purpose that the Board of Directors of the Enterprise Fund may determine in carrying out this section. Financial returns on Enterprise Fund investments that include a component of private venture capital may be distributed, at such times and in such amounts as the Board of Directors of the Enterprise Fund may determine, to the investors of such capital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5421_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial instruments for individual investment in Poland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Financial instruments for individual investment in Poland In order to maximize the effectiveness of the activities of the Polish-American Enterprise Fund, that Enterprise Fund should undertake all possible efforts to establish financial instruments that will enable individuals to invest in the private sectors of Poland and that will thereby have the effect of multiplying the impact of United States grants to that Enterprise Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>