<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5452" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5452/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5452/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5452"><akn:num>5452</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental initiatives for Poland and Hungary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5452. Environmental initiatives for Poland and Hungary(a) Priority for control of pollutionThe Congress recognizes the severe pollution problems affecting Poland and Hungary and the serious health problems which ensue from such pollution. The Congress therefore directs that a high priority be given in the implementation of assistance to Poland and Hungary to the control of pollution and the restoration of the natural resource base on which a sustainable, healthy economy depends.


(b) EPA activities generallyIn addition to specific authorities contained in any of the environmental statutes administered by the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of that Agency (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Administrator”) is authorized to undertake such educational, policy training, research, and technical and financial assistance, monitoring, coordinating, and other activities as the Administrator may deem appropriate, either alone or in cooperation with other United States or foreign agencies, governments, or public or private institutions, in protecting the environment in Poland and Hungary.


(c) EPA activities in PolandThe Administrator shall cooperate with Polish officials and experts to—(1) establish an air quality monitoring network in the Krakow metropolitan area as a part of Poland’s national air monitoring network; and

(2) improve both water quality and the availability of drinking water in the Krakow metropolitan area.


(d) EPA activities in HungaryThe Administrator shall work with other United States and Hungarian officials and private parties to establish and support a regional center in Budapest for facilitating cooperative environmental activities between governmental experts and public and private organizations from the United States and Eastern and Western Europe.


(e) Funding of EPA activitiesTo enable the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out subsections (b), (c), and (d), there are authorized to be appropriated $10,00</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for control of pollution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Priority for control of pollution The Congress recognizes the severe pollution problems affecting Poland and Hungary and the serious health problems which ensue from such pollution. The Congress therefore directs that a high priority be given in the implementation of assistance to Poland and Hungary to the control of pollution and the restoration of the natural resource base on which a sustainable, healthy economy depends.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPA activities generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) EPA activities generally In addition to specific authorities contained in any of the environmental statutes administered by the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of that Agency (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Administrator”) is authorized to undertake such educational, policy training, research, and technical and financial assistance, monitoring, coordinating, and other activities as the Administrator may deem appropriate, either alone or in cooperation with other United States or foreign agencies, governments, or public or private institutions, in protecting the environment in Poland and Hungary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPA activities in Poland</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) EPA activities in Poland The Administrator shall cooperate with Polish officials and experts to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPA activities in Hungary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) EPA activities in Hungary The Administrator shall work with other United States and Hungarian officials and private parties to establish and support a regional center in Budapest for facilitating cooperative environmental activities between governmental experts and public and private organizations from the United States and Eastern and Western Europe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding of EPA activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding of EPA activities To enable the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out subsections (b), (c), and (d), there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for the 3-year period beginning October 1, 1989, to carry out chapter 1 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2151 and following; relating to development assistance) or chapter 4 of Part 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. II of that Act (22 U.S.C. 2346 and following; relating to the economic support fund). These funds may be used to carry out those subsections notwithstanding any provision of law relating to the use of foreign assistance funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy activities relating to fossil fuels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Department of Energy activities relating to fossil fuels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for efficient energy use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priority for efficient energy use In view of the high energy usage per unit of output in Hungary and Poland, the Secretary of Energy shall give high priority to assisting officials of Poland and Hungary in improving the efficiency of their energy use, through emphasis on such measures as efficient motors, lights, gears, and appliances and improvements in building insulation and design.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5452_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative investments in energy in Hungary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Alternative investments in energy in Hungary It is the sense of the Congress that the Executive branch should work with the Government of Hungary to achieve environmentally safe alternative investments in energy efficiency, particularly with regard to projects along the Danube River.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>