<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5841" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5841/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/5841/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5841"><akn:num>5841</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for establishment of Democracy Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5841. Authorization for establishment of Democracy Corps(a) Establishment; purposeThe President is authorized to provide for the establishment of the Democracy Corps as a private nonprofit organization, incorporated in the District of Columbia, whose purpose shall be to maintain a presence in the independent states of the former Soviet Union as described in subsection (c).


(b) Board of DirectorsThe Board of Directors of the Democracy Corps shall have not more than 10 members, appointed by the President. Individuals appointed to the Board—(1) shall, individually or through the organizations they represent, have experience and expertise appropriate to carrying out the purpose of the Democracy Corps, including involvement either with activities of the type described in subsection (d) or in the independent states;

(2) shall be United States citizens; and

(3) may not be officers or employees of the United States Government or Members of Congress.


(c) Grants to Democracy Corps; purposeThe Administrator is authorized to make an annual grant to the Democracy Corps with the funds made available pursuant to this section. The purpose of such grants shall be to enable the Democracy Corps to maintain a presence in independent states of the former Soviet Union that will assist at the local level in the development of—(1) institutions of democratic governance (including judicial, electoral, legislative, and administrative processes), and

(2) the nongovernmental organizations of a civil society (including charitable, educational, trade union, business, professional, voluntary, community, and other civic organizations),


by mobilizing the expertise of the American people to provide practical assistance through “on the ground” person-to-person advice, technical assistance, and small grants to indigenous individuals and indigenous entities, in accordance with subsection (d).

(d) ActivitiesThe Democracy Corps shall be required to carry out its purpose through the placement w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; purpose The President is authorized to provide for the establishment of the Democracy Corps as a private nonprofit organization, incorporated in the District of Columbia, whose purpose shall be to maintain a presence in the independent states of the former Soviet Union as described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board of Directors The Board of Directors of the Democracy Corps shall have not more than 10 members, appointed by the President. Individuals appointed to the Board—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to Democracy Corps; purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants to Democracy Corps; purpose The Administrator is authorized to make an annual grant to the Democracy Corps with the funds made available pursuant to this section. The purpose of such grants shall be to enable the Democracy Corps to maintain a presence in independent states of the former Soviet Union that will assist at the local level in the development of— by mobilizing the expertise of the American people to provide practical assistance through “on the ground” person-to-person advice, technical assistance, and small grants to indigenous individuals and indigenous entities, in accordance with subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Activities The Democracy Corps shall be required to carry out its purpose through the placement within the independent states of teams of United States citizens with appropriate expertise and knowledge. Under guidelines developed by the Board, these teams shall assist indigenous individuals and entities in the independent states that are involved in the development of the institutions and organizations referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) by— These local centers may be designated as “Democracy Houses” or given another appropriate appellation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grant agreement Grants under this section shall be made pursuant to a grant agreement requiring the Democracy Corps to comply with the requirements specified in this section and with such other terms and conditions as the Administrator may require, which shall include requirements regarding consultation with the coordinator designated pursuant to section 5812(a) of this title, conflicts of interest, and accountability for funds, including a requirement for annual independent audits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination The Democracy Corps shall be required to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on campaign financing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition on campaign financing Funds made available to the Democracy Corps under this section may not be expended by the Democracy Corps, or any recipient of a grant from the Democracy Corps, to finance the campaigns of candidates for public office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Freedom of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Freedom of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Annual reports The Board shall be required to submit to the Administrator and the Congress, not later than January 31 each year, a comprehensive report on the activities of the Democracy Corps. Each such report shall list each grant made by the Democracy Corps under subsection (d)(2) during the preceding fiscal year, specifying the grantee and the amount of the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5841_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations Of the amount authorized to be appropriated to carry out chapter 11 of part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2295 et seq.], up to $15,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 are authorized to be appropriated for grants to the Democracy Corps under this section, in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>