<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6021"><akn:num>6021</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6021. Findings
The Congress makes the following findings:(1) The economy of Cuba has experienced a decline of at least 60 percent in the last 5 years as a result of—(A) the end of its subsidization by the former Soviet Union of between 5 billion and 6 billion dollars annually;

(B) 36 years of communist tyranny and economic mismanagement by the Castro government;

(C) the extreme decline in trade between Cuba and the countries of the former Soviet bloc; and

(D) the stated policy of the Russian Government and the countries of the former Soviet bloc to conduct economic relations with Cuba on strictly commercial terms.


(2) At the same time, the welfare and health of the Cuban people have substantially deteriorated as a result of this economic decline and the refusal of the Castro regime to permit free and fair democratic elections in Cuba.

(3) The Castro regime has made it abundantly clear that it will not engage in any substantive political reforms that would lead to democracy, a market economy, or an economic recovery.

(4) The repression of the Cuban people, including a ban on free and fair democratic elections, and continuing violations of fundamental human rights, have isolated the Cuban regime as the only completely nondemocratic government in the Western Hemisphere.

(5) As long as free elections are not held in Cuba, the economic condition of the country and the welfare of the Cuban people will not improve in any significant way.

(6) The totalitarian nature of the Castro regime has deprived the Cuban people of any peaceful means to improve their condition and has led thousands of Cuban citizens to risk or lose their lives in dangerous attempts to escape from Cuba to freedom.

(7) Radio Marti and Television Marti have both been effective vehicles for providing the people of Cuba with news and information and have helped to bolster the morale of the people of Cuba living under tyranny.

(8) The consistent policy of the United States towards Cuba since the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The economy of Cuba has experienced a decline of at least 60 percent in the last 5 years as a result of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) At the same time, the welfare and health of the Cuban people have substantially deteriorated as a result of this economic decline and the refusal of the Castro regime to permit free and fair democratic elections in Cuba.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The Castro regime has made it abundantly clear that it will not engage in any substantive political reforms that would lead to democracy, a market economy, or an economic recovery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The repression of the Cuban people, including a ban on free and fair democratic elections, and continuing violations of fundamental human rights, have isolated the Cuban regime as the only completely nondemocratic government in the Western Hemisphere.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) As long as free elections are not held in Cuba, the economic condition of the country and the welfare of the Cuban people will not improve in any significant way.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The totalitarian nature of the Castro regime has deprived the Cuban people of any peaceful means to improve their condition and has led thousands of Cuban citizens to risk or lose their lives in dangerous attempts to escape from Cuba to freedom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Radio Marti and Television Marti have both been effective vehicles for providing the people of Cuba with news and information and have helped to bolster the morale of the people of Cuba living under tyranny.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The consistent policy of the United States towards Cuba since the beginning of the Castro regime, carried out by both Democratic and Republican administrations, has sought to keep faith with the people of Cuba, and has been effective in sanctioning the totalitarian Castro regime.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The United States has shown a deep commitment, and considers it a moral obligation, to promote and protect human rights and fundamental freedoms as expressed in the Charter of the United Nations and in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6021_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The Congress has historically and consistently manifested its solidarity and the solidarity of the American people with the democratic aspirations of the Cuban people.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>