<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6033" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6033/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6033/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6033"><akn:num>6033</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against indirect financing of Cuba</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6033. Prohibition against indirect financing of Cuba(a) ProhibitionNotwithstanding any other provision of law, no loan, credit, or other financing may be extended knowingly by a United States national, a permanent resident alien, or a United States agency to any person for the purpose of financing transactions involving any confiscated property the claim to which is owned by a United States national as of March 12, 1996, except for financing by the United States national owning such claim for a transaction permitted under United States law.


(b) Suspension and termination of prohibition(1) SuspensionThe President is authorized to suspend the prohibition contained in subsection (a) upon a determination made under section 6063(c)(1) of this title that a transition government in Cuba is in power.


(2) TerminationThe prohibition contained in subsection (a) shall cease to apply on the date on which the economic embargo of Cuba terminates as provided in section 6064 of this title.



(c) PenaltiesViolations of subsection (a) shall be punishable by such civil penalties as are applicable to violations of the Cuban Assets Control Regulations set forth in part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.


(d) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) the term “permanent resident alien” means an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence into the United States; and

(2) the term “United States agency” has the meaning given the term “agency” in section 551(1) of title 5.


(Pub. L. 104–114, title I, § 103, Mar. 12, 1996, 110 Stat. 794.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6033_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no loan, credit, or other financing may be extended knowingly by a United States national, a permanent resident alien, or a United States agency to any person for the purpose of financing transactions involving any confiscated property the claim to which is owned by a United States national as of March 12, 1996, except for financing by the United States national owning such claim for a transaction permitted under United States law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6033_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension and termination of prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Suspension and termination of prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6033_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalties Violations of subsection (a) shall be punishable by such civil penalties as are applicable to violations of the Cuban Assets Control Regulations set forth in part 515 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6033_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>