<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6083" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6083/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6083/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6083"><akn:num>6083</akn:num><akn:heading>Proof of ownership of claims to confiscated property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6083. Proof of ownership of claims to confiscated property(a) Evidence of ownership(1) Conclusiveness of certified claimsIn any action brought under this subchapter, the court shall accept as conclusive proof of ownership of an interest in property a certification of a claim to ownership of that interest that has been made by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 (22 U.S.C. 1643 and following).


(2) Claims not certifiedIf in an action under this subchapter a claim has not been so certified by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, the court may appoint a special master, including the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission, to make determinations regarding the amount and ownership of the claim. Such determinations are only for evidentiary purposes in civil actions brought under this subchapter and do not constitute certifications under title V of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949.


(3) Effect of determinations of foreign or international entitiesIn determining the amount or ownership of a claim in an action under this subchapter, the court shall not accept as conclusive evidence any findings, orders, judgments, or decrees from administrative agencies or courts of foreign countries or international organizations that declare the value of or invalidate the claim, unless the declaration of value or invalidation was found pursuant to binding international arbitration to which the United States or the claimant submitted the claim.



(b) Omitted

(c) Rule of constructionNothing in this chapter or in section 514 of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [22 U.S.C. 1643l], as added by subsection (b), shall be construed—(1) to require or otherwise authorize the claims of Cuban nationals who became United States citizens after their property was confiscated to be included in the claims certified to the Secretary of State by the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission for purposes of f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence of ownership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evidence of ownership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6083_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction Nothing in this chapter or in section 514 of the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 [22 U.S.C. 1643l], as added by subsection (b), shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>