<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6102"><akn:num>6102</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6102. Program requirements
The program established under this chapter shall comply with the following requirements:(1) United States citizens who are eligible for fellowships under this chapter shall be employees of the Federal Government having at least two years experience in any branch of the Government, a strong career interest in United States-Japan relations, and a demonstrated commitment to further service in the Federal Government, and such other qualifications as are determined by the Center.

(2) Not more than 10 fellowships may be awarded each year of which not more than 3 shall be awarded to individuals who are not detailed employees of the Government.

(3)(A) Fellows shall agree to maintain satisfactory progress in language training and appropriate behavior in Japan, as determined by the Center, as a condition of continued receipt of Federal funds.

(B) Fellows who are not detailees shall agree to return to the Federal Government for further employment for a period of at least 2 years following the end of their fellowships, unless, in the determination of the Center, the fellow is unable (for reasons beyond the fellow’s control and after receiving assistance from the Center as provided in paragraph (8)) to find reemployment for such period.


(4) During the period of the fellowship, the Center shall provide—(A) to each fellow who is not a detailee a stipend at a rate of pay equal to the rate of pay that individual was receiving when he or she entered the program, plus a cost-of-living adjustment calculated at the same rate of pay, and for the same period of time, for which such adjustments were made to the salaries of individuals occupying competitive positions in the civil service during the same period as the fellowship; and

(B) to each fellow (including detailees) certain allowances and benefits as that individual would have been entitled to, but for his or her separation from Government service, as a United States Government civilian employee ove</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) United States citizens who are eligible for fellowships under this chapter shall be employees of the Federal Government having at least two years experience in any branch of the Government, a strong career interest in United States-Japan relations, and a demonstrated commitment to further service in the Federal Government, and such other qualifications as are determined by the Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Not more than 10 fellowships may be awarded each year of which not more than 3 shall be awarded to individuals who are not detailed employees of the Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) During the period of the fellowship, the Center shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Any fellow who is not a detailee who does not comply with the requirements of this section shall reimburse the United States Information Agency for the Federal funds expended for the Fellow’s participation in the fellowship, together with interest on such funds (calculated at the prevailing rate), as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The Center shall select fellows based solely on merit. The Center shall make positive efforts to recruit candidates reflecting the cultural, racial, and ethnic diversity of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The Center shall assist, to the extent possible, any fellow who is not a detailee in finding employment in the Federal Government if such fellow was not able, at the end of the fellowship, to be reemployed in the agency from which he or she separated to become a fellow.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) No fellow may engage in any intelligence or intelligence-related activity on behalf of the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6102_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The financial records of the Center shall be audited annually in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants or independent licensed public accountants, certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State or other political subdivision of the United States. The audit shall be conducted at the place or places where the financial records of the Center are normally kept. All books, financial records, files, and other papers, things, and property belonging to or in use by the Center and necessary to facilitate the audit shall be made available to the person or persons conducting the audit, and full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians shall be afforded to such person or persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>