<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6203" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6203/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6203/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6203"><akn:num>6203</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6203. Establishment of the Chief Executive Officer of the United States Agency for Global Media(a) Continued existence within Executive branchThe United States Agency for Global Media shall continue to exist within the Executive branch of Government as an entity described in section 104 of title 5.


(b) Chief Executive Officer(1) In generalThe head of the United States Agency for Global Media shall be a Chief Executive Officer, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, until such time as a Chief Executive Officer is appointed and has qualified, the current or acting Chief Executive Officer appointed by the Board may continue to serve and exercise the authorities and powers under this chapter.


(2) TermThe first Chief Executive Officer appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall serve for an initial term of three years.


(3) CompensationA Chief Executive Officer appointed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be compensated at the annual rate of basic pay for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.



(c) Termination of Director of International Broadcasting BureauEffective on December 23, 2016, the position of the Director of the International Broadcasting Bureau shall be terminated, and all of the responsibilities, offices, authorities, and immunities of the Director or the Agency under this chapter or any other Act or authority before such date shall be transferred or available to, assumed by, or overseen by the Chief Executive Officer, as head of the Agency.


(d) Immunity from civil liabilityNotwithstanding any other provision of law, all limitations on liability that apply to the Chief Executive Officer shall also apply to members of the boards of directors of RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, or any organization that consolidates such entities when such members are acting in their off</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6203_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued existence within Executive branch</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Continued existence within Executive branch The United States Agency for Global Media shall continue to exist within the Executive branch of Government as an entity described in section 104 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6203_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Executive Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chief Executive Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6203_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Director of International Broadcasting Bureau</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination of Director of International Broadcasting Bureau Effective on December 23, 2016, the position of the Director of the International Broadcasting Bureau shall be terminated, and all of the responsibilities, offices, authorities, and immunities of the Director or the Agency under this chapter or any other Act or authority before such date shall be transferred or available to, assumed by, or overseen by the Chief Executive Officer, as head of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6203_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Immunity from civil liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Immunity from civil liability Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all limitations on liability that apply to the Chief Executive Officer shall also apply to members of the boards of directors of RFE/RL, Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, or any organization that consolidates such entities when such members are acting in their official capacities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>