<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6204" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6204/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6204/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6204"><akn:num>6204</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities of Chief Executive Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6204. Authorities of Chief Executive Officer(a) AuthoritiesThe Chief Executive Officer shall have the following authorities:(1) To supervise all broadcasting activities conducted pursuant to this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [22 U.S.C. 1465 et seq.],,11 So in original. the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [22 U.S.C. 1465aa et seq.], and Worldnet Television, except as provided in section 6205(b) of this title.

(2) To review and evaluate the mission and operation of, and to assess the quality, effectiveness, and professional integrity of, all such activities within the context of the broad foreign policy objectives of the United States.

(3) To ensure that United States international broadcasting is conducted in accordance with the standards and principles contained in section 6202 of this title.

(4) To review, evaluate, and determine, at least annually, after consultation with the Secretary of State, the addition or deletion of language services.

(5) To make and supervise grants and cooperative agreements for broadcasting and related activities in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter and on behalf of other agencies, accordingly.

(6) To allocate funds appropriated for international broadcasting activities among the various elements of the Agency and grantees, subject to reprogramming notification requirements in law for the reallocation of funds.

(7) To review engineering activities to ensure that all broadcasting elements receive the highest quality and cost-effective delivery services.

(8) To undertake such studies as may be necessary to identify areas in which broadcasting activities under its authority could be made more efficient and economical.

(9) To submit to the President and the Congress an annual report which summarizes and evaluates activities under this chapter, the Radio Broadcasting to Cuba Act [22 U.S.C. 1465 et seq.], and the Television Broadcasting to Cuba Act [22 U.S.C. 1465aa et seq.]. Each annual report shall plac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6204_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorities The Chief Executive Officer shall have the following authorities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6204_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Professional independence of broadcasters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Professional independence of broadcasters The Secretary of State and the Chief Executive Officer, in carrying out their functions, shall respect the professional independence and integrity of the Agency, its broadcasting services, and the grantees of the Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6204_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on corporate leadership of grantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on corporate leadership of grantees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>