<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6207" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6207/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6207/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6207"><akn:num>6207</akn:num><akn:heading>Limits on grants for Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6207. Limits on grants for Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty(a) Board of RFE/RL, IncorporatedThe Agency may not make any grant to RFE/RL, Incorporated, unless the certificate of incorporation of RFE/RL, Incorporated, has been amended to provide that—(1) the Board of Directors of RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall consist of the members authorized under section 6204(a)(20) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title; and

(2) such Board of Directors shall make all major policy determinations governing the operation of RFE/RL, Incorporated, and shall appoint and fix the compensation of such managerial officers and employees of RFE/RL, Incorporated, as it considers necessary to carry out the purposes of the grant provided under this chapter.


(b) Location of principal place of business(1) The Agency may not make any grant to RFE/RL, Incorporated unless the headquarters of RFE/RL, Incorporated and its senior administrative and managerial staff are in a location which ensures economy, operational effectiveness, and accountability to the Agency.

(2) Not later than 90 days after confirmation of all members of the Agency, the Agency shall provide a report to Congress on the number of administrative, managerial, and technical staff of RFE/RL, Incorporated who will be located within the metropolitan area of Washington, D.C., and the number of employees whose principal place of business will be located outside the metropolitan area of Washington, D.C.


(c) Limitation on grant amountsThe total amount of grants made for the operating costs of RFE/RL, Incorporated, may not exceed $85,000,000 in fiscal year 2003.


(d) Alternative granteeIf the Chief Executive Officer determines at any time that RFE/RL, Incorporated is not carrying out the functions described in this section in an effective and economical manner, the Agency may award the grant to carry out such functions to another entity.


(e) Not a Federal agency or instrumentalityNothing in this chapter may be construe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of RFE/RL, Incorporated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Board of RFE/RL, Incorporated The Agency may not make any grant to RFE/RL, Incorporated, unless the certificate of incorporation of RFE/RL, Incorporated, has been amended to provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location of principal place of business</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Location of principal place of business</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on grant amounts The total amount of grants made for the operating costs of RFE/RL, Incorporated, may not exceed $85,000,000 in fiscal year 2003.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative grantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Alternative grantee If the Chief Executive Officer determines at any time that RFE/RL, Incorporated is not carrying out the functions described in this section in an effective and economical manner, the Agency may award the grant to carry out such functions to another entity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Not a Federal agency or instrumentality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Not a Federal agency or instrumentality Nothing in this chapter may be construed to make RFE/RL, Incorporated a Federal agency or instrumentality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority Grants authorized under section 6204 of this title for RFE/RL, Incorporated, shall be available to make annual grants for the purpose of carrying out similar functions as were carried out by RFE/RL, Incorporated, on the day before April 30, 1994, with respect to Radio Free Europe and Radio Liberty, consistent with section 2 of the Board for International Broadcasting Act of 1973 [22 U.S.C. 2871], as in effect on such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Grant agreement Grants to RFE/RL, Incorporated, by the Agency shall only be made in compliance with a grant agreement. The grant agreement shall establish guidelines for such grants. The grant agreement shall include the following provisions—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited uses of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prohibited uses of grant funds No grant funds provided under this section may be used for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on management practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report on management practices Effective not later than March 31 and September 30 of each calendar year, the Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall submit to the Agency and the Congress a report on management practices of RFE/RL, Incorporated, under this section. The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall establish a special unit within the Inspector General’s office to monitor and audit the activities of RFE/RL, Incorporated, and shall provide for on-site monitoring of such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6207_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Audit authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>