<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6209a"><akn:num>6209a</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6209a. Inspector General authorities(a) In generalThe Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall exercise the same authorities with respect to the United States Agency for Global Media as the Inspector General exercises under the Inspector General Act of 1978 and section 3929 of this title with respect to the Department of State.


(b) Respect for journalistic integrity of broadcastersThe Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall respect the journalistic integrity of all the broadcasters covered by this chapter and may not evaluate the philosophical or political perspectives reflected in the content of broadcasts.


(Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 310A, as added Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(7), Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2554; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(6), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4025.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Inspector General Act of 1978, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 95–452, Oct. 12, 1978, 92 Stat. 1101, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was substantially repealed and restated in chapter 4 (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 5 by Pub. L. 117–286, §§ 3(b), 7, Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4206, 4361. For disposition of sections of the Act into chapter 4 of Title 5, see Disposition Table preceding section 101 of Title 5.
This chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, and was translated as reading “this title”, meaning title III of Pub. L. 103–236, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 432, known as the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994, which is classified principally to this chapter, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 6201 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(6), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4025, which amended this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall exercise the same authorities with respect to the United States Agency for Global Media as the Inspector General exercises under the Inspector General Act of 1978 and section 3929 of this title with respect to the Department of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Respect for journalistic integrity of broadcasters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Respect for journalistic integrity of broadcasters The Inspector General of the Department of State and the Foreign Service shall respect the journalistic integrity of all the broadcasters covered by this chapter and may not evaluate the philosophical or political perspectives reflected in the content of broadcasts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>