<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6209/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6209"><akn:num>6209</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation and non-Federal status of broadcasting entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6209. Incorporation and non-Federal status of broadcasting entities(a) Defined termIn this chapter—(1) the term “grant” includes agreements under section 6305 of title 31; and

(2) the term “grantee” includes recipients of an agreement described in paragraph (1).


(b) IncorporationThe Chief Executive Officer is authorized to incorporate grantees in accordance with the regular notification procedures of—(1) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(2) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(3) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and

(4) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.


(c) Federal statusNothing in this chapter or in any other Act, and no action taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act, may be construed to make a grantee incorporated pursuant to subsection (b), or any other grantee or entity provided funding by the Agency, a Federal agency or instrumentality.


(d) Leadership of grantee organizationsThe chief executive officer or the equivalent official of RFE/RL Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, and the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, and any other organization that is established or authorized under this chapter, shall serve at the pleasure of, and may be named by, the Chief Executive Officer of the Agency, with the concurrence of the Grantee Board and subject to the approval of the Advisory Board pursuant to section 6205 of this title.


(Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 310, as added Pub. L. 114–328, div. A, title XII, § 1288(7), Dec. 23, 2016, 130 Stat. 2553; amended Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, §§ 1299P(c)(2), (3), 1299Q(e)(5), (f), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4020, 4025, 4026; Pub. L. 117–263, div. I, title XCVII, § 9705, Dec. 23, 2022, 136 Stat. 3915.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a), (c), and (d), was so in the original, but probably should have been a reference to “this title”, meaning title III of Pub.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Defined term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Defined term In this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Incorporation The Chief Executive Officer is authorized to incorporate grantees in accordance with the regular notification procedures of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal status Nothing in this chapter or in any other Act, and no action taken pursuant to this chapter or any other Act, may be construed to make a grantee incorporated pursuant to subsection (b), or any other grantee or entity provided funding by the Agency, a Federal agency or instrumentality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6209_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leadership of grantee organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Leadership of grantee organizations The chief executive officer or the equivalent official of RFE/RL Inc., Radio Free Asia, the Open Technology Fund, and the Middle East Broadcasting Networks, and any other organization that is established or authorized under this chapter, shall serve at the pleasure of, and may be named by, the Chief Executive Officer of the Agency, with the concurrence of the Grantee Board and subject to the approval of the Advisory Board pursuant to section 6205 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>