<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6212" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6212/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6212/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6212"><akn:num>6212</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6212. Requirement for authorization of appropriations(a) Limitation on obligation and expenditure of fundsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, for the fiscal year 1994 and for each subsequent fiscal year, any funds appropriated for the purposes of broadcasting subject to supervision of the Agency shall not be available for obligation or expenditure—(1) unless such funds are appropriated pursuant to an authorization of appropriations; or

(2) in excess of the authorized level of appropriations.


(b) Subsequent authorizationThe limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply to the extent that an authorization of appropriations is enacted after such funds are appropriated.


(c) ApplicationThe provisions of this section—(1) may not be superseded, except by a provision of law which specifically repeals, modifies, or supersedes the provisions of this section; and

(2) shall not apply to, or affect in any manner, permanent appropriations, trust funds, and other similar accounts which are authorized by law and administered under or pursuant to this chapter.


(Pub. L. 103–236, title III, § 313, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 444; Pub. L. 107–228, div. A, title V, § 507(2), Sept. 30, 2002, 116 Stat. 1394; Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(9), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4025.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (c)(2), was in the original “this title”, meaning title III of Pub. L. 103–236, Apr. 30, 1994, 108 Stat. 432, known as the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title III to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 6201 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Pub. L. 116–283, div. A, title XII, § 1299Q(e)(9), Jan. 1, 2021, 134 Stat. 4025, which amended this section, was itself amended by Pub. L. 116–260, div. O, title XIII, § 1301, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2158, to make it effective 90 days after Jan. 1, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6212_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on obligation and expenditure of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on obligation and expenditure of funds Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the fiscal year 1994 and for each subsequent fiscal year, any funds appropriated for the purposes of broadcasting subject to supervision of the Agency shall not be available for obligation or expenditure—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6212_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsequent authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Subsequent authorization The limitation under subsection (a) shall not apply to the extent that an authorization of appropriations is enacted after such funds are appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6212_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application The provisions of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>