<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6301"><akn:num>6301</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of procurement sanction on persons engaging in export activities that contribute to proli</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6301. Imposition of procurement sanction on persons engaging in export activities that contribute to proliferation(a) Determination by President(1) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b)(2), the President shall impose the sanction described in subsection (c) if the President determines in writing that, on or after the effective date of this subchapter, a foreign person or a United States person has materially and with requisite knowledge contributed, through the export from the United States or any other country of any goods or technology (as defined in section 6305(2) of this title), to the efforts by any individual, group, or non-nuclear-weapon state to acquire unsafeguarded special nuclear material or to use, develop, produce, stockpile, or otherwise acquire any nuclear explosive device.


(2) Persons against which the sanction is to be imposedThe sanction shall be imposed pursuant to paragraph (1) on—(A) the foreign person or United States person with respect to which the President makes the determination described in that paragraph;

(B) any successor entity to that foreign person or United States person;

(C) any foreign person or United States person that is a parent or subsidiary of that person if that parent or subsidiary materially and with requisite knowledge assisted in the activities which were the basis of that determination; and

(D) any foreign person or United States person that is an affiliate of that person if that affiliate materially and with requisite knowledge assisted in the activities which were the basis of that determination and if that affiliate is controlled in fact by that person.


(3) Other sanctions availableThe sanction which is required to be imposed for activities described in this subsection is in addition to any other sanction which may be imposed for the same activities under any other provision of law.


(4) DefinitionFor purposes of this subsection, the term “requisite knowledge” means situations in which a person “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Determination by President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with and actions by foreign government of jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation with and actions by foreign government of jurisdiction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sanction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory opinions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advisory opinions Upon the request of any person, the Secretary of State may, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, issue in writing an advisory opinion to that person as to whether a proposed activity by that person would subject that person to the sanction under this section. Any person who relies in good faith on such an advisory opinion which states that the proposed activity would not subject a person to such sanction, and any person who thereafter engages in such activity, may not be made subject to such sanction on account of such activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of sanction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Termination of sanction The sanction imposed pursuant to this section shall apply for a period of at least 12 months following the imposition of the sanction and shall cease to apply thereafter only if the President determines and certifies in writing to the Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6301_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>