<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6402" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6402/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6402/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6402"><akn:num>6402</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6402. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Ambassador at LargeThe term “Ambassador at Large” means the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under section 6411(b) of this title.


(2) Annual ReportThe term “Annual Report” means the Annual Report on International Religious Freedom described in section 6412(b) of this title.


(3) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives; and

(B) in the case of any determination made with respect to the taking of President 11 So in original. Probably should be “Presidential”. action under paragraphs (9) through (15) of section 6445(a) of this title, the term includes the committees described in subparagraph (A) and, where appropriate, the Committee on Banking and Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.


(4) Commensurate actionThe term “commensurate action” means action taken by the President under section 6445(b) of this title.


(5) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established in section 6431(a) of this title.


(6) Country Reports on Human Rights PracticesThe term “Country Reports on Human Rights Practices” means the annual reports required to be submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n(d) and 2304(b) of this title.


(7) Executive SummaryThe term “Executive Summary” means the Executive Summary to the Annual Report, as described in section 6412(b)(1)(F) of this title.


(8) Government or foreign governmentThe term “government” or “foreign government” includes any agency or instrumentality of the government.


(9) Human Rights ReportsThe term “Human Rights Reports” means all reports submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ambassador at Large</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Ambassador at Large The term “Ambassador at Large” means the Ambassador at Large for International Religious Freedom appointed under section 6411(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Annual Report The term “Annual Report” means the Annual Report on International Religious Freedom described in section 6412(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commensurate action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Commensurate action The term “commensurate action” means action taken by the President under section 6445(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Commission The term “Commission” means the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom established in section 6431(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Country Reports on Human Rights Practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Country Reports on Human Rights Practices The term “Country Reports on Human Rights Practices” means the annual reports required to be submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n(d) and 2304(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Summary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Executive Summary The term “Executive Summary” means the Executive Summary to the Annual Report, as described in section 6412(b)(1)(F) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government or foreign government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Government or foreign government The term “government” or “foreign government” includes any agency or instrumentality of the government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Human Rights Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Human Rights Reports The term “Human Rights Reports” means all reports submitted by the Department of State to Congress under sections 2151n and 2304 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6402_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 1001 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>