<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6431" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6431/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6431/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6431"><akn:num>6431</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6431. Establishment and composition(a) In generalThere is established the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom.


(b) Membership(1) AppointmentThe Commission shall be composed of—(A) the Ambassador at Large, who shall serve ex officio as a nonvoting member of the Commission; and

(B) Nine 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. other members, who shall be United States citizens who are not being paid as officers or employees of the United States, and who shall be appointed as follows:(i) Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the President.

(ii) Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, of which two of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the Senate of the political party that is not the political party of the President, and of which one of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the Senate of the other political party.

(iii) Three members of the Commission shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, of which two of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the House of the political party that is not the political party of the President, and of which one of the members shall be appointed upon the recommendation of the leader in the House of the other political party.



(2) SelectionMembers of the Commission shall be selected among distinguished individuals noted for their knowledge and experience in fields relevant to the issue of international religious freedom, including foreign affairs, direct experience abroad, human rights, and international law.


(3) Time of appointmentThe appointments required by paragraph (1) shall be made not later than 120 days after October 27, 1998.



(c) Terms(1) In generalThe term of office of each member of the Commission shall be 2 years. An individual, including any member appointed to the Commission pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of Chair and Vice Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Election of Chair and Vice Chair At the first meeting of the Commission after May 30 of each year, a majority of the members of the Commission who are present and voting shall elect a Chair and a Vice Chair. The Vice Chair shall have been appointed by an officeholder from a different political party than the officeholder who appointed the member of the Commission who was elected Chair. The positions of Chair and Vice Chair shall be rotated annually between members who were appointed to the Commission by officeholders of different political parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Quorum Six voting members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum for purposes of transacting business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Meetings Each year, within 15 days, or as soon as practicable, after the issuance of the International Religious Freedom Report, the Commission shall convene. The Commission shall otherwise meet at the call of the Chair or, if no Chair has been elected for that calendar year, at the call of six voting members of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Vacancies Any vacancy of the Commission shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made. A member may serve after the expiration of that member’s term until a successor has taken office. Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of that term.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administrative support The Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission on a reimbursable basis (or, in the discretion of the Administrator, on a nonreimbursable basis) such administrative support services as the Commission may request to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding Members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5 while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Commission. Members of the Commission shall comply with the requirements set forth in chapters 300 through 304 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as the “Federal Travel Regulation”) and the Department of State Standardized Regulations governing authorized travel at government expense, including regulations concerning the mode of travel, lodging and per diem expenditures, reimbursement payments, and expense reporting and documentation requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6431_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Removal If a payment is made under section 415(a) of the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (2 U.S.C. 1415(a)) for an award or settlement in connection with a claim alleging a violation of unlawful harassment, intimidation, reprisal, or discrimination under the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 (2 U.S.C. 1301 et seq.) that was committed personally by an individual who, at the time of committing the violation, was a Member of the Commission, the Member shall be removed from the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>