<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6432a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6432a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6432a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6432a"><akn:num>6432a</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6432a. Powers of the Commission(a) Hearings and sessionsThe Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties under this subchapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places in the United States, take testimony and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Information from Federal agenciesThe Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission, subject to applicable law.


(c) Postal servicesThe Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.


(d) Administrative proceduresThe Commission may adopt such rules and regulations, relating to administrative procedure, as may be reasonably necessary to enable it to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.


(e) Views of the CommissionThe Members of the Commission may speak in their capacity as private citizens. Statements on behalf of the Commission shall be issued in writing over the names of the Members. The Commission shall in its written statements clearly describe its statutory authority, distinguishing that authority from that of appointed or elected officials of the United States Government. Oral statements, where practicable, shall include a similar description. If a Member of the Commission is invited to speak at an event in his or her capacity as a Commissioner, the Member shall provide notice of the request to all Commissioners and the Executive Director as soon as the Commissioner becomes aware of such invitation. Speeches and responses to questions at official events shall reflect the views of the Commission. Official speeches and other prepared materials shall be made availa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings and sessions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hearings and sessions The Commission may, for the purpose of carrying out its duties under this subchapter, hold hearings, sit and act at times and places in the United States, take testimony and receive evidence as the Commission considers advisable to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information from Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information from Federal agencies The Commission may secure directly from any Federal department or agency such information as the Commission considers necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Upon request of the Chairperson of the Commission, the head of such department or agency shall furnish such information to the Commission, subject to applicable law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Postal services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Postal services The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative procedures The Commission may adopt such rules and regulations, relating to administrative procedure, as may be reasonably necessary to enable it to carry out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Views of the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Views of the Commission The Members of the Commission may speak in their capacity as private citizens. Statements on behalf of the Commission shall be issued in writing over the names of the Members. The Commission shall in its written statements clearly describe its statutory authority, distinguishing that authority from that of appointed or elected officials of the United States Government. Oral statements, where practicable, shall include a similar description. If a Member of the Commission is invited to speak at an event in his or her capacity as a Commissioner, the Member shall provide notice of the request to all Commissioners and the Executive Director as soon as the Commissioner becomes aware of such invitation. Speeches and responses to questions at official events shall reflect the views of the Commission. Official speeches and other prepared materials shall be made available to all Commissioners in advance of the event. If a Commissioner is speaking in his or her private</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Travel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6432a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual disclosures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual disclosures Not later than March 1 of each year, each Member of the Commission shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees (as defined in section 6433a(a) of this title) with respect to the most recently concluded 12-month period, that discloses any travel by the Member outside of the United States that was paid for or reimbursed by a person or entity other than the Member, a relative of the Member, or the Federal Government, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>