<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6433" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6433/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6433/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6433"><akn:num>6433</akn:num><akn:heading>Report of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6433. Report of Commission(a) In generalNot later than May 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress setting forth its recommendations for United States policy options based on its evaluations under section 6432 of this title.


(b) Classified form of reportThe report may be submitted in classified form, together with a public summary of recommendations, if the classification of information would further the purposes of this chapter.


(c) Individual or dissenting viewsEach member of the Commission may include the individual or dissenting views of the member.


(Pub. L. 105–292, title II, § 205, formerly § 203, Oct. 27, 1998, 112 Stat. 2799; renumbered § 205, Pub. L. 106–55, § 1(b)(2), Aug. 17, 1999, 113 Stat. 401.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 105–292, Oct. 27, 1998, 112 Stat. 2787, known as the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 6401 of this title and Tables.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 205 of Pub. L. 105–292 was renumbered section 207 and is classified to section 6435 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than May 1 of each year, the Commission shall submit a report to the President, the Secretary of State, and Congress setting forth its recommendations for United States policy options based on its evaluations under section 6432 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified form of report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Classified form of report The report may be submitted in classified form, together with a public summary of recommendations, if the classification of information would further the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6433_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual or dissenting views</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Individual or dissenting views Each member of the Commission may include the individual or dissenting views of the member.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>