<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6449" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6449/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6449/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6449"><akn:num>6449</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of Presidential actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6449. Termination of Presidential actions
Any Presidential action taken under this chapter with respect to a foreign country shall terminate on the earlier of the following dates:(1) Termination dateWithin 2 years of the effective date of the Presidential action unless expressly reauthorized by law.


(2) Foreign government actionsUpon the determination by the President, in consultation with the Commission, and certification to Congress that the foreign government has ceased or taken substantial and verifiable steps to cease the particularly severe violations of religious freedom.


(Pub. L. 105–292, title IV, § 409, Oct. 27, 1998, 112 Stat. 2809.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 105–292, Oct. 27, 1998, 112 Stat. 2787, known as the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 6401 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6449_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Termination date Within 2 years of the effective date of the Presidential action unless expressly reauthorized by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6449_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign government actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Foreign government actions Upon the determination by the President, in consultation with the Commission, and certification to Congress that the foreign government has ceased or taken substantial and verifiable steps to cease the particularly severe violations of religious freedom.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>