<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6563" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6563/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6563/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6563"><akn:num>6563</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of AID</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6563. Status of AID(a) In generalUnless abolished pursuant to the reorganization plan submitted under section 6601 of this title, and except as provided in section 6562 of this title, there is within the Executive branch of Government the United States Agency for International Development as an entity described in section 104 of title 5.


(b) Retention of officersNothing in this section shall require the reappointment of any officer of the United States serving in the Agency for International Development of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 105–277, div. G, subdiv. A, title XIV, § 1413, Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–791.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFor the effective date of this subchapter, referred to in subsec. (b), meaning the effective date of title XIV of subdiv. A of div. G of Pub. L. 105–277, see section 1401 of Pub. L. 105–277, set out as a note under section 6561 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6563_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Unless abolished pursuant to the reorganization plan submitted under section 6601 of this title, and except as provided in section 6562 of this title, there is within the Executive branch of Government the United States Agency for International Development as an entity described in section 104 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6563_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Retention of officers Nothing in this section shall require the reappointment of any officer of the United States serving in the Agency for International Development of the United States International Development Cooperation Agency as of the day before the effective date of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>