<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6724" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6724/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6724/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6724"><akn:num>6724</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6724. Procedures for inspections(a) Types of inspectionsEach inspection of a plant, plant site, or other facility or location in the United States under the Convention shall be conducted in accordance with this section and section 6725 of this title, except where other procedures are provided in a facility agreement entered into under section 6722 of this title.


(b) Notice(1) In generalAn inspection referred to in subsection (a) may be made only upon issuance of an actual written notice by the United States National Authority to the owner and to the operator, occupant, or agent in charge of the premises to be inspected.


(2) Time of notificationThe notice for a routine inspection shall be submitted to the owner and to the operator, occupant, or agent in charge within six hours of receiving the notification of the inspection from the Technical Secretariat or as soon as possible thereafter. Notice for a challenge inspection shall be provided at any appropriate time determined by the United States National Authority. Notices may be posted prominently at the plant, plant site, or other facility or location if the United States is unable to provide actual written notice to the owner, operator, or agent in charge of the premises.


(3) Content of notice(A) In generalThe notice under paragraph (1) shall include all appropriate information supplied by the Technical Secretariat to the United States National Authority concerning—(i) the type of inspection;

(ii) the basis for the selection of the plant, plant site, or other facility or location for the type of inspection sought;

(iii) the time and date that the inspection will begin and the period covered by the inspection; and

(iv) the names and titles of the inspectors.


(B) Special rule for challenge inspectionsIn the case of a challenge inspection pursuant to Article IX of the Convention, the notice shall also include all appropriate evidence or reasons provided by the requesting state party to the Convention for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of inspections Each inspection of a plant, plant site, or other facility or location in the United States under the Convention shall be conducted in accordance with this section and section 6725 of this title, except where other procedures are provided in a facility agreement entered into under section 6722 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Credentials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Credentials The head of the inspection team of the Technical Secretariat and the accompanying employees of the Federal Government (and, in the case of an inspection of a United States Government facility, any accompanying contractor personnel) shall display appropriate identifying credentials to the owner, operator, occupant, or agent in charge of the premises before the inspection is commenced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timeframe for inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timeframe for inspections Consistent with the provisions of the Convention, each inspection shall be commenced and completed with reasonable promptness and shall be conducted at reasonable times, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Scope</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sampling and safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sampling and safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6724_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination The appropriate representatives of the United States, as designated, if present, shall assist the owner and the operator, occupant or agent in charge of the premises to be inspected in interacting with the members of the inspection team of the Technical Secretariat.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>