<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6965" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6965/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/6965/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6965"><akn:num>6965</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6965. Reports to Congress(a) Frequency of reportsNot later than the date that is 1 year after October 10, 2000, and not later than the end of each 1-year period thereafter, the Task Force shall submit to the Congress a report on the work of the Task Force during the preceding 1-year period.


(b) Contents of reportsEach report under subsection (a) shall set forth, at a minimum—(1) the number of allegations of violations of section 1307 of title 19 with respect to products of the Peoples’ 11 So in original. Probably should be “People’s”. Republic of China that were investigated during the preceding 1-year period;

(2) the number of actual violations of section 1307 of title 19 with respect to the products of the People’s Republic of China that were discovered during the preceding 1-year period;

(3) in the case of each attempted entry of products of the People’s Republic of China in violation of such section 1307 of title 19 discovered during the preceding 1-year period—(A) the identity of the exporter of the goods;

(B) the identity of the person or persons who attempted to sell the goods for export; and

(C) the identity of all parties involved in transshipment of the goods; and


(4) such other information as the Task Force considers useful in monitoring and enforcing compliance with section 1307 of title 19.


(Pub. L. 106–286, div. B, title V, § 505, Oct. 10, 2000, 114 Stat. 904.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6965_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Frequency of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Frequency of reports Not later than the date that is 1 year after October 10, 2000, and not later than the end of each 1-year period thereafter, the Task Force shall submit to the Congress a report on the work of the Task Force during the preceding 1-year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6965_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents of reports Each report under subsection (a) shall set forth, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>