<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7103b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7103b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7103b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7103b"><akn:num>7103b</akn:num><akn:heading>Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7103b. Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act”.


(b) EstablishmentThere is established the United States Advisory Council on Human Trafficking (referred to in this section as the “Council”), which shall provide advice and recommendations to the Senior Policy Operating Group established under section 7103(g) of this title (referred to in this section as the “Group”) and the President’s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking established under section 7103(a) of such title (referred to in this section as the “Task Force”).


(c) Membership(1) CompositionThe Council shall be composed of not less than 8 and not more than 14 individuals who are survivors of human trafficking.


(2) Representation of survivorsTo the extent practicable, members of the Council shall be survivors of trafficking, who shall accurately reflect the diverse backgrounds of survivors of trafficking, including—(A) survivors of sex trafficking and survivors of labor trafficking; and

(B) survivors who are United States citizens and survivors who are aliens lawfully present in the United States.


(3) AppointmentNot later than 180 days after May 29, 2015, the President shall appoint the members of the Council.


(4) Term; reappointmentEach member of the Council shall serve for a term of 2 years and may be reappointed by the President to serve 1 additional 2-year term.



(d) FunctionsThe Council shall—(1) be a nongovernmental advisory body to the Group;

(2) meet, at its own discretion or at the request of the Group, not less frequently than annually to review Federal Government policy and programs intended to combat human trafficking, including programs relating to the provision of services for victims and serve as a point of contact for Federal agencies reaching out to human trafficking survivors for input on programming and policies relating to human trafficking in the United S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Survivors of Human Trafficking Empowerment Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established the United States Advisory Council on Human Trafficking (referred to in this section as the “Council”), which shall provide advice and recommendations to the Senior Policy Operating Group established under section 7103(g) of this title (referred to in this section as the “Group”) and the President’s Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking established under section 7103(a) of such title (referred to in this section as the “Task Force”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports Not later than 1 year after May 29, 2015, and each year thereafter until the date described in subsection (h),11 See References in Text note below. the Council shall submit a report that contains the findings derived from the reviews conducted pursuant to subsection (d)(2) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employee status Members of the Council—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7103b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of FACA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nonapplicability of FACA The Council shall not be subject to the requirements under the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>