<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7104b"><akn:num>7104b</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and investigation of trafficking in persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7104b. Monitoring and investigation of trafficking in persons(a) Referral and investigation(1) ReferralIf the contracting or grant officer of an executive agency for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement receives credible information that a recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subgrantee or subcontractor, has engaged in an activity described in section 7104(g) of this title, as amended by section 1702, including a report from a contracting officer representative, an auditor, an alleged victim or victim’s representative, or any other credible source, the contracting or grant officer shall promptly refer the matter to the agency’s Office of Inspector General for investigation. The contracting officer may also direct the contractor to take specific steps to abate an alleged violation or enforce the requirements of a compliance plan implemented pursuant to section 7104a of this title.


(2) InvestigationAn Inspector General who receives a referral under paragraph (1) or otherwise receives credible information that a recipient of the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subgrantee or subcontractor of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subgrantee or subcontractor, has engaged in an activity described in section 7104(g) of this title, as amended by section 1702, shall promptly review the referral or information and determine whether to initiate an investigation of the matter. In the event that an Inspector General does not initiate an investigation, the Inspector General shall document the rationale for the decision not to investigate.


(3) Criminal investigationIf the matter is referred to the Department of Justice for criminal prosecution, the Inspector General may suspend any investigation under this subsection pending the outcome of the criminal prosecution. The Inspector General shall notify the head of the execu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral and investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Referral and investigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report Upon completion of an investigation under subsection (a), the Inspector General shall submit a report on the investigation to the head of the executive agency that awarded the contract, grant, or cooperative agreement. The report shall include the Inspector General’s conclusions regarding whether or not any allegations that the recipient of a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement; any subcontractor or subgrantee of the recipient; or any agent of the recipient or of such a subcontractor or subgrantee, engaged in any of the activities described in section 7104(g) of this title, as amended by section 1702, are substantiated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedial actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Remedial actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of report conclusions in FAPIIS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusion of report conclusions in FAPIIS</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>