<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7104d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7104d"><akn:num>7104d</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction; effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7104d. Rules of construction; effective date(a) LiabilityExcluding section 1706, nothing in this title shall be construed to supersede, enlarge, or diminish the common law or statutory liabilities of any grantee, subgrantee, contractor, subcontractor, or other party covered by section 106(g) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. 7104(g)), as amended by section 1702.


(b) Authority of Department of JusticeNothing in this title shall be construed as diminishing or otherwise modifying the authority of the Attorney General to investigate activities covered by this title.


(c) Implementation and effective dates(1) Contracting requirements(A) Not later than 270 days after January 2, 2013, the Federal Acquisition Regulation shall be amended to carry out the requirements of sections 1702, 1703, and 1704(c), and the second sentence of section 1704(a)(1), of this title.

(B) The requirements of sections 1702, 1703, and 1704(c), and the second sentence of section 1704(a)(1), of this title, shall apply to grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements entered into on or after the date that is 270 days after January 2, 2013, and to task and delivery orders awarded on or after such date pursuant to contracts entered before, on, or after such date.


(2) Investigative and procedural requirementsFederal agencies shall implement the requirements of sections 1704, 1705, and 1707 (other than subsection (c) of section 1704) not later than 90 days after January 2, 2013.


(3) Criminal law changesThe amendments made by section 1706 shall take effect upon the date of enactment and shall apply to conduct taking place on or after such date.



(Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XVII, § 1708, Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2098.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis title, referred to in text, is title XVII of div. A of Pub. L. 112–239, which enacted this section and sections 7104a to 7104c of this title, amended sections 7103 and 7104 of this title, section 1351 of Title</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability Excluding section 1706, nothing in this title shall be construed to supersede, enlarge, or diminish the common law or statutory liabilities of any grantee, subgrantee, contractor, subcontractor, or other party covered by section 106(g) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. 7104(g)), as amended by section 1702.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Department of Justice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority of Department of Justice Nothing in this title shall be construed as diminishing or otherwise modifying the authority of the Attorney General to investigate activities covered by this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7104d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation and effective dates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation and effective dates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>