<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7108" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7108/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7108/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7108"><akn:num>7108</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions against significant traffickers in persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7108. Actions against significant traffickers in persons(a) Authority to sanction significant traffickers in persons(1) In generalThe President may exercise the authorities set forth in section 1702 of title 50 without regard to section 1701 of title 50, or section 10102 of this title, in the case of any of the following persons:(A) Any foreign person that plays a significant role in a severe form of trafficking in persons, directly or indirectly in the United States.

(B) Foreign persons that materially assist in, or provide financial or technological support for or to, or provide goods or services in support of, activities of a significant foreign trafficker in persons identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).

(C) Foreign persons that are owned, controlled, or directed by, or acting for or on behalf of, a significant foreign trafficker identified pursuant to subparagraph (A).

(D) Officials of a foreign government who participate in, facilitate, or condone severe forms of trafficking in persons for significant financial gain.


(2) PenaltiesThe penalties set forth in section 1705 of title 50 apply to violations of any license, order, or regulation issued under this section.



(b) Report to Congress on identification and sanctioning of significant traffickers in persons(1) In generalUpon exercising the authority of subsection (a), the President shall report to the appropriate congressional committees—(A) identifying publicly the foreign persons that the President determines are appropriate for sanctions pursuant to this section and the basis for such determination; and

(B) detailing publicly the sanctions imposed pursuant to this section.


(2) Removal of sanctionsUpon suspending or terminating any action imposed under the authority of subsection (a), the President shall report to the committees described in paragraph (1) on such suspension or termination.


(3) Submission of classified informationReports submitted under this subsection may include an annex wit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to sanction significant traffickers in persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to sanction significant traffickers in persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress on identification and sanctioning of significant traffickers in persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report to Congress on identification and sanctioning of significant traffickers in persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement and intelligence activities not affected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Law enforcement and intelligence activities not affected Nothing in this section prohibits or otherwise limits the authorized law enforcement or intelligence activities of the United States, or the law enforcement activities of any State or subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of foreign persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition of foreign persons In this section, the term “foreign person” means any citizen or national of a foreign state or any entity not organized under the laws of the United States, including a foreign government official, but does not include a foreign state.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7108_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as precluding judicial review of the exercise of the authority described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>