<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7109b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7109b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7109b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7109b"><akn:num>7109b</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7109b. Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons(a) Establishment of awardThe President is authorized to establish an award, to be known as the “Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons”, for extraordinary efforts to combat trafficking in persons. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of State shall present the award annually to not more than 5 individuals or organizations, including—(1) individuals who are United States citizens or foreign nationals; and

(2) United States or foreign nongovernmental organizations.


(b) SelectionThe President shall establish procedures for selecting recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a).


(c) CeremonyThe Secretary of State shall host an annual ceremony for recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a) as soon as practicable after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under section 7107(b)(1) of this title. The Secretary of State may pay the travel costs of each recipient and a guest of each recipient who attends the ceremony.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated, for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2027, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 106–386, div. A, § 112B, as added Pub. L. 110–457, title I, § 109, Dec. 23, 2008, 122 Stat. 5051; amended Pub. L. 117–347, title I, § 105(d)(2), Jan. 5, 2023, 136 Stat. 6204.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2023—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 117–347 substituted “2022 through 2027” for “2008 through 2011”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7109b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of award The President is authorized to establish an award, to be known as the “Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts To Combat Trafficking in Persons”, for extraordinary efforts to combat trafficking in persons. To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary of State shall present the award annually to not more than 5 individuals or organizations, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7109b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection The President shall establish procedures for selecting recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7109b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceremony</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ceremony The Secretary of State shall host an annual ceremony for recipients of the award authorized under subsection (a) as soon as practicable after the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress the report required under section 7107(b)(1) of this title. The Secretary of State may pay the travel costs of each recipient and a guest of each recipient who attends the ceremony.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7109b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated, for each of the fiscal years 2022 through 2027, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>