<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7110" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7110/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7110/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7110"><akn:num>7110</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7110. Authorizations of appropriations(a) Authorization of appropriations in support of the task forceThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $13,822,000 for Diplomatic and Consular Programs of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, which shall be used to carry out sections 7103(e), 7103(f),11 See References in Text note below. and 7107 of this title, including for additional personnel.


(b) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services(1) Eligibility for benefits and assistanceTo carry out the purposes of sections 7104(b) and 7105(b) of this title and section 628c of title 42, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Health and Human Services $19,500,000 for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, of which $3,500,000 is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year for the National Human Trafficking Hotline.


(2) Additional benefits for trafficking victimsTo carry out the purposes of section 7105(f) 1 of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated $8,000,000 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.


(3) Grants for State improvementsTo carry out the purposes of section 20705a of title 34, there are authorized to be appropriated $4,000,000 to the Secretary of Health and Human Services for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027.



(c) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of State(1) Assistance to combat traffickingThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $65,000,000, which shall be used—(A) to carry out sections 7104 and 7105(a) of this title;

(B) to carry out section 2152d of this title;

(C) to assist countries in meeting the minimum standards described in section 7106 of this title; and

(D) for programs and activities on prevention, protection, and prosecution </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations in support of the task force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations in support of the task force There are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State, for each of the fiscal years 2018 through 2021, $13,822,000 for Diplomatic and Consular Programs of the Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking in Persons, which shall be used to carry out sections 7103(e), 7103(f),11 See References in Text note below. and 7107 of this title, including for additional personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations to Attorney General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations to President</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Labor To carry out the purposes of section 7105(b) of this title, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Labor $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to Director of the FBI</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations to Director of the FBI There are authorized to be appropriated to the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation $15,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2011, to remain available until expended, to investigate severe forms of trafficking in persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7110_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Homeland Security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations to the Secretary of Homeland Security There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. $10,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028, to remain available until expended, of which $2,000,000 shall be made available each fiscal year for the establishment of a labor trafficking investigation team within the Department of Homeland Security Center for Countering Human Trafficking, and the remaining funds shall be used for investigations by the Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement of severe forms of trafficking in persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>