<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7113"><akn:num>7113</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7113. Accountability(a) In generalFor fiscal year 2013, and each fiscal year thereafter, all grants awarded by the Attorney General under this title or an Act amended by this title shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:(1) Audit requirement(A) DefinitionIn this paragraph, the term “unresolved audit finding” means an audit report finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the grantee has used grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved during the 12-month period beginning on the date on which the final audit report is issued 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(B) RequirementBeginning in the first fiscal year beginning after March 7, 2013, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of recipients of grants under this title or an Act amended by this title to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees. The Inspector General shall determine the appropriate number of grantees to be audited each year.


(C) Mandatory exclusionA recipient of grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title during the first 2 fiscal years beginning after the end of the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A).


(D) PriorityIn awarding grants under this title or an Act amended by this title, the Attorney General shall give priority to eligible applicants that did not have an unresolved audit finding during the 3 fiscal years before submitting an application for a grant under this title or an Act amended by this title.


(E) ReimbursementIf an entity is awarded grant funds under this title or an Act amended by this title during the 2-fiscal-year period during which the entity is barred from receiving gr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For fiscal year 2013, and each fiscal year thereafter, all grants awarded by the Attorney General under this title or an Act amended by this title shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to additional grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application to additional grants For purposes of subsection (a), for fiscal year 2018, and each fiscal year thereafter, the term “grant awarded by the Attorney General under this title or an Act amended by this title” includes a grant under any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>