<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7114" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7114/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7114/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7114"><akn:num>7114</akn:num><akn:heading>Efforts to end modern slavery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7114. Efforts to end modern slavery(a) Actions by the Secretary of Defense(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after December 23, 2016, the Secretary of Defense shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on the policies and guidance of the Department of Defense with respect to the education and training on human slavery and the appropriate role of the United States Armed Forces in combatting trafficking in persons that is received by personnel of the Armed Forces, including uniformed personnel and civilians engaged in partnership with foreign nations.


(2) ElementsThe briefing required under paragraph (1) shall address—(A) resources available for Armed Forces personnel who become aware of instances of human slavery or trafficking in persons while deployed overseas; and

(B) guidance on the requirement to make official reports through the chain of command, the roles and responsibilities of military and civilian officials of the United States Armed Forces and host nations, circumstances in which members of the Armed Forces are authorized to take immediate action to prevent loss of life or serious injury, and the authority to use appropriate force to stop or prevent sexual abuse or exploitation of children.



(b) Grant authorizationThe Secretary of State is authorized to make a grant or grants of funding to provide support for transformational programs and projects that seek to achieve a measurable and substantial reduction of the prevalence of modern slavery in targeted populations within partner countries (or jurisdictions thereof).


(c) Monitoring and evaluationAny grantee shall—(1) develop specific and detailed criteria for the monitoring and evaluation of supported projects;

(2) implement a system for measuring progress against baseline data that is rigorously designed based on international corporate and nongovernmental best practices;

(3) ensure that each supported project is regularly and rigorously monitored and evaluated, on a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by the Secretary of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Actions by the Secretary of Defense</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant authorization The Secretary of State is authorized to make a grant or grants of funding to provide support for transformational programs and projects that seek to achieve a measurable and substantial reduction of the prevalence of modern slavery in targeted populations within partner countries (or jurisdictions thereof).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Monitoring and evaluation Any grantee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Auditing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Auditing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report Any grant recipient shall submit a report to the Secretary of State annually and the Secretary shall transmit it to the appropriate congressional committees within 30 days. Such report shall include the names of each of the projects or sub-grantees receiving such funding pursuant to this section and the amount of funding provided for, along with a detailed description of, each such project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding availability of fiscal year 2016 appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction regarding availability of fiscal year 2016 appropriations The enactment of this section is deemed to meet the condition of the first proviso of paragraph (2) of section 7060(f) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Appropriations 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “Programs”. Act, 2016 (division K of Public Law 114–113), and the funds referred to in such paragraph shall be made available in accordance with, and for the purposes set forth in, such paragraph.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations; sunset</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Comptroller General review of existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Comptroller General review of existing programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7114_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Appropriate congressional committees defined In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>