<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7401"><akn:num>7401</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction relating to United States accession to the International Criminal Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7401. Restriction relating to United States accession to the International Criminal Court(a) ProhibitionThe United States shall not become a party to the International Criminal Court except pursuant to a treaty made under Article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States on or after November 29, 1999.


(b) Prohibition on use of fundsNone of the funds authorized to be appropriated by this or any other Act may be obligated for use by, or for support of, the International Criminal Court unless the United States has become a party to the Court pursuant to a treaty made under Article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States on or after November 29, 1999.


(c) International Criminal Court definedIn this section, the term “International Criminal Court” means the court established by the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court, adopted by the United Nations Diplomatic Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Establishment of an International Criminal Court on July 17, 1998.


(Pub. L. 106–113, div. B, § 1000(a)(7) [div. A, title VII, § 705], Nov. 29, 1999, 113 Stat. 1536, 1501A–460.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly set out as a note under section 262–1 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 107–206, title II, § 2001, Aug. 2, 2002, 116 Stat. 899, provided that: “This title [enacting subchapter II of this chapter] may be cited as the ‘American Servicemembers’ Protection Act of 2002’.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition The United States shall not become a party to the International Criminal Court except pursuant to a treaty made under Article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States on or after November 29, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on use of funds None of the funds authorized to be appropriated by this or any other Act may be obligated for use by, or for support of, the International Criminal Court unless the United States has become a party to the Court pursuant to a treaty made under Article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States on or after November 29, 1999.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7401_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Criminal Court defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) International Criminal Court defined In this section, the term “International Criminal Court” means the court established by the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court, adopted by the United Nations Diplomatic Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Establishment of an International Criminal Court on July 17, 1998.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>