<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7432" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7432/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7432/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7432"><akn:num>7432</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7432. Definitions
As used in this subchapter and in section 7402 of this title:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.


(2) Classified national security informationThe term “classified national security information” means information that is classified or classifiable under Executive Order 12958 or a successor Executive order.


(3) Covered allied personsThe term “covered allied persons” means military personnel, elected or appointed officials, and other persons employed by or working on behalf of the government of a NATO member country, a major non-NATO ally (including Australia, Egypt, Israel, Japan, Jordan, Argentina, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand), or Taiwan, for so long as that government is not a party to the International Criminal Court and wishes its officials and other persons working on its behalf to be exempted from the jurisdiction of the International Criminal Court.


(4) Covered United States personsThe term “covered United States persons” means members of the Armed Forces of the United States, elected or appointed officials of the United States Government, and other persons employed by or working on behalf of the United States Government, for so long as the United States is not a party to the International Criminal Court.


(5) ExtraditionThe terms “extradition” and “extradite” mean the extradition of a person in accordance with the provisions of chapter 209 of title 18 (including section 3181(b) of such title) and such terms include both extradition and surrender as those terms are defined in Article 102 of the Rome Statute.


(6) International Criminal CourtThe term “International Criminal Court” means the court established by the Rome Statute.


(7) Major non-NATO allyThe term “major non-NATO ally” means a country that has been so designated in accordance wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on International Relations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Classified national security information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Classified national security information The term “classified national security information” means information that is classified or classifiable under Executive Order 12958 or a successor Executive order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered allied persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Covered allied persons The term “covered allied persons” means military personnel, elected or appointed officials, and other persons employed by or working on behalf of the government of a NATO member country, a major non-NATO ally (including Australia, Egypt, Israel, Japan, Jordan, Argentina, the Republic of Korea, and New Zealand), or Taiwan, for so long as that government is not a party to the International Criminal Court and wishes its officials and other persons working on its behalf to be exempted from the jurisdiction of the International Criminal Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered United States persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Covered United States persons The term “covered United States persons” means members of the Armed Forces of the United States, elected or appointed officials of the United States Government, and other persons employed by or working on behalf of the United States Government, for so long as the United States is not a party to the International Criminal Court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extradition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Extradition The terms “extradition” and “extradite” mean the extradition of a person in accordance with the provisions of chapter 209 of title 18 (including section 3181(b) of such title) and such terms include both extradition and surrender as those terms are defined in Article 102 of the Rome Statute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>International Criminal Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) International Criminal Court The term “International Criminal Court” means the court established by the Rome Statute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major non-NATO ally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Major non-NATO ally The term “major non-NATO ally” means a country that has been so designated in accordance with section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2321k].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participate in any peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Participate in any peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations The term “participate in any peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations” means to assign members of the Armed Forces of the United States to a United Nations military command structure as part of a peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations in which those members of the Armed Forces of the United States are subject to the command or operational control of one or more foreign military officers not appointed in conformity with article II, section 2, clause 2 of the Constitution of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Party to the International Criminal Court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Party to the International Criminal Court The term “party to the International Criminal Court” means a government that has deposited an instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval, or accession to the Rome Statute, and has not withdrawn from the Rome Statute pursuant to Article 127 thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7432_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations The term “peacekeeping operation under chapter VI of the charter of the United Nations or peace enforcement operation under chapter VII of the charter of the United Nations” means any military operation to maintain or restore international peace and security that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>