<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7602" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7602/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7602/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7602"><akn:num>7602</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7602. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AIDSThe term “AIDS” means the acquired immune deficiency syndrome.


(2) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(3) Global AIDS CoordinatorThe term “Global AIDS Coordinator” means the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally.


(4) Global FundThe term “Global Fund” means the public-private partnership known as the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria established pursuant to Article 80 of the Swiss Civil Code.


(5) HIVThe term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus, the pathogen that causes AIDS.


(6) HIV/AIDSThe term “HIV/AIDS” means, with respect to an individual, an individual who is infected with HIV or living with AIDS.


(7) Impact evaluation researchThe term “impact evaluation research” means the application of research methods and statistical analysis to measure the extent to which change in a population-based outcome can be attributed to program intervention instead of other environmental factors.


(8) Operations researchThe term “operations research” means the application of social science research methods, statistical analysis, and other appropriate scientific methods to judge, compare, and improve policies and program outcomes, from the earliest stages of defining and designing programs through their development and implementation, with the objective of the rapid dissemination of conclusions and concrete impact on programming.


(9) ParaprofessionalThe term “paraprofessional” means an individual who is trained and employed as a health agent for the provision of basic assistance in the identification, prevention, or treatment of illness or disability.


(10) Partner governm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>AIDS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) AIDS The term “AIDS” means the acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Global AIDS Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Global AIDS Coordinator The term “Global AIDS Coordinator” means the Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Global Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Global Fund The term “Global Fund” means the public-private partnership known as the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria established pursuant to Article 80 of the Swiss Civil Code.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>HIV</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) HIV The term “HIV” means the human immunodeficiency virus, the pathogen that causes AIDS.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>HIV/AIDS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) HIV/AIDS The term “HIV/AIDS” means, with respect to an individual, an individual who is infected with HIV or living with AIDS.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact evaluation research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Impact evaluation research The term “impact evaluation research” means the application of research methods and statistical analysis to measure the extent to which change in a population-based outcome can be attributed to program intervention instead of other environmental factors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operations research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Operations research The term “operations research” means the application of social science research methods, statistical analysis, and other appropriate scientific methods to judge, compare, and improve policies and program outcomes, from the earliest stages of defining and designing programs through their development and implementation, with the objective of the rapid dissemination of conclusions and concrete impact on programming.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Paraprofessional</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Paraprofessional The term “paraprofessional” means an individual who is trained and employed as a health agent for the provision of basic assistance in the identification, prevention, or treatment of illness or disability.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7602_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partner government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Partner government The term “partner government” means a government with which the United States is working to provide assistance to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, or malaria on behalf of people living within the jurisdiction of such government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>