<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7622"><akn:num>7622</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7622. Participation in the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria(a) Findings; sense of Congress(1) FindingsCongress makes the following findings:(A) The establishment of the Global Fund in January 2002 is consistent with the general principles for an international AIDS trust fund first outlined by Congress in the Global AIDS and Tuberculosis Relief Act of 2000 (Public Law 106–264) [22 U.S.C. 6801 et seq.].

(B) The Global Fund is an innovative financing mechanism which—(i) has made progress in many areas in combating HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and

(ii) represents the multilateral component of this chapter, extending United States efforts to more than 130 countries around the world.


(C) The Global Fund and United States bilateral assistance programs—(i) are demonstrating increasingly effective coordination, with each possessing certain comparative advantages in the fight against HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria; and

(ii) often work most effectively in concert with each other.


(D) The United States Government—(i) is the largest supporter of the Global Fund in terms of resources and technical support;

(ii) made the founding contribution to the Global Fund; and

(iii) is fully committed to the success of the Global Fund as a multilateral public-private partnership.



(2) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(A) transparency and accountability are crucial to the long-term success and viability of the Global Fund;

(B) the Global Fund has made significant progress toward addressing concerns raised by the Government Accountability Office by—(i) improving risk assessment and risk management capabilities;

(ii) providing clearer guidance for and oversight of Local Fund Agents; and

(iii) strengthening the Office of the Inspector General for the Global Fund;


(C) the provision of sufficient resources and authority to the Office of the Inspector General for the Global Fund to ensure that office has the staff and independence n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings; sense of Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for United States participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority for United States participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports to Congress Not later than 1 year after May 27, 2003, and annually thereafter for the duration of the Global Fund, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the Global Fund, including contributions pledged to, contributions (including donations from the private sector) received by, and projects funded by the Global Fund, and the mechanisms established for transparency and accountability in the grant-making process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States financial participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) United States financial participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency technical review panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interagency technical review panel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring by Comptroller General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Monitoring by Comptroller General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Provision of information to Congress The Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat HIV/AIDS Globally shall make available to the Congress the following documents within 30 days of a request by the Congress for such documents:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7622_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of the Congress regarding encouragement of private contributions to the Global Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sense of the Congress regarding encouragement of private contributions to the Global Fund It is the sense of the Congress that the President should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>