<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7631"><akn:num>7631</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to combat HIV/AIDS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7631. Assistance to combat HIV/AIDS(a) Omitted

(b) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalIn addition to funds available under section 104(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2151b(c)) for such purpose or under any other provision of that Act [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.], there are authorized to be appropriated to the President, from amounts authorized to be appropriated under section 7671 of this title, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to carry out section 104A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as added by subsection (a) [22 U.S.C. 2151b–2].


(2) Availability of fundsAmounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.


(3) Allocation of fundsOf the amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) for the fiscal years 2009 through 2013, such sums as may be necessary are authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 104A(d)(4) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (as added by subsection (a)) [22 U.S.C. 2151b–2(d)(4)], relating to the procurement and distribution of HIV/AIDS pharmaceuticals.



(c) Food and nutritional support(1) In generalAs indicated in the report produced by the Institute of Medicine, entitled “PEPFAR Implementation: Progress and Promise”, inadequate caloric intake has been clearly identified as a principal reason for failure of clinical response to antiretroviral therapy. In recognition of the impact of malnutrition as a clinical health issue for many persons living with HIV/AIDS that is often associated with health and economic impacts on these individuals and their families, the Global AIDS Coordinator and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall—(A) follow World Health Organization guidelines for HIV/AIDS food and nutrition services;

(B) integrate nutrition programs with HIV/AIDS activities through effective linkages among the health, agricultural, and livelihood sectors and e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Food and nutritional support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Food and nutritional support</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligibility for assistance An organization, including a faith-based organization, that is otherwise eligible to receive assistance under section 104A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151b–2], under this chapter, or under any amendment made by this chapter or by the Tom Lantos and Henry J. Hyde United States Global Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Reauthorization Act of 2008, for HIV/AIDS prevention, treatment, or care—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to promote or advocate the legalization or practice of prostitution or sex trafficking. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to preclude the provision to individuals of palliative care, treatment, or post-exposure pharmaceutical prophylaxis, and necessary pharmaceuticals and commodities, including test kits, condoms, and, when proven effective, microbicides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation No funds made available to carry out this chapter, or any amendment made by this chapter, may be used to provide assistance to any group or organization that does not have a policy explicitly opposing prostitution and sex trafficking, except that this subsection shall not apply to the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis and Malaria, the World Health Organization, the International AIDS Vaccine Initiative or to any United Nations agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7631_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress relating to food assistance for individuals living with HIV/AIDS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sense of Congress relating to food assistance for individuals living with HIV/AIDS</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>