<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7634" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7634/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7634/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7634"><akn:num>7634</akn:num><akn:heading>Malaria response Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7634. Malaria response Coordinator(a) In generalThere is established within the United States Agency for International Development a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally (referred to in this section as the “Malaria Coordinator”), who shall be appointed by the President.


(b) AuthoritiesThe Malaria Coordinator, acting through nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country finance, health, and other relevant ministries, and relevant executive branch agencies as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out this section, is authorized to—(1) operate internationally to carry out prevention, care, treatment, support, capacity development, and other activities to reduce the prevalence, mortality, and incidence of malaria;

(2) provide grants to, and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with, nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based organizations) to carry out this section; and

(3) transfer and allocate executive branch agency funds that have been appropriated for the purposes described in paragraphs (1) and (2).


(c) Duties(1) In generalThe Malaria Coordinator has primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all resources and international activities of the United States Government relating to efforts to combat malaria.


(2) Specific dutiesThe Malaria Coordinator shall—(A) facilitate program and policy coordination of antimalarial efforts among relevant executive branch agencies and nongovernmental organizations by auditing, monitoring, and evaluating such programs;

(B) ensure that each relevant executive branch agency undertakes antimalarial programs primarily in those areas in which the agency has the greatest expertise, technical capability, and potential for success;

(C) coordinate relevant executive branch agency activities in the field of malaria prevention and treatment;

(D) coordinate planning, implementation, and evalu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established within the United States Agency for International Development a Coordinator of United States Government Activities to Combat Malaria Globally (referred to in this section as the “Malaria Coordinator”), who shall be appointed by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorities The Malaria Coordinator, acting through nongovernmental organizations (including faith-based and community-based organizations), partner country finance, health, and other relevant ministries, and relevant executive branch agencies as may be necessary and appropriate to carry out this section, is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for the World Health Organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance for the World Health Organization In carrying out this section, the President may provide financial assistance to the Roll Back Malaria Partnership of the World Health Organization to improve the capacity of countries with high rates of malaria and other affected countries to implement comprehensive malaria control programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of assistance efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of assistance efforts In carrying out this section and in accordance with section 2151b–4 of this title, the Malaria Coordinator shall coordinate the provision of assistance by working with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Research To carry out this section, the Malaria Coordinator, in accordance with section 2151b–4 of this title, shall ensure that operations and implementation research conducted under this chapter will closely complement the clinical and program research being undertaken by the National Institutes of Health. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention should advise the Malaria Coordinator on priorities for operations and implementation research and should be a key implementer of this research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Monitoring To ensure that adequate malaria controls are established and implemented, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention should advise the Malaria Coordinator on monitoring, surveillance, and evaluation activities and be a key implementer of such activities under this chapter. Such activities shall complement, rather than duplicate, the work of the World Health Organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7634_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>