<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7705" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7705/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7705/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7705"><akn:num>7705</akn:num><akn:heading>Candidate countries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7705. Candidate countries(a) In generalA country shall be a candidate country for purposes of eligibility to receive assistance under section 7704 of this title if—(1) the per capita income of the country in a fiscal year is equal to or less than the World Bank threshold for initiating the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development graduation process for the fiscal year; and

(2) subject to subsection (b), the country is not ineligible to receive United States economic assistance under part I of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.) by reason of the application of any provision of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 [22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.] or any other provision of law.


(b) Rule of constructionFor the purposes of determining whether a country is eligible, pursuant to subsection (a)(2), to receive assistance under section 7704 of this title, the exercise by the President, the Secretary of State, or any other officer or employee of the United States Government of any waiver or suspension of any provision of law referred to in subsection (a)(2), and notification to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such provision of law, shall be construed as satisfying the requirements under subsection (a).


(c) Determination by the BoardThe Board shall determine whether a country is a candidate country for purposes of this section.


(Pub. L. 108–199, div. D, title VI, § 606, Jan. 23, 2004, 118 Stat. 215; Pub. L. 115–167, title II, § 201, Apr. 23, 2018, 132 Stat. 1278; Pub. L. 118–159, div. E, title LI, § 5122(b), Dec. 23, 2024, 138 Stat. 2430.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), is Pub. L. 87–195, Sept. 4, 1961, 75 Stat. 424, which is classified principally to chapter 32 (§ 2151 et seq.) of this title. Part I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 2151 et seq.) of chapter 32 of this title. For provisions deeming references to subchapter I</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7705_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A country shall be a candidate country for purposes of eligibility to receive assistance under section 7704 of this title if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7705_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rule of construction For the purposes of determining whether a country is eligible, pursuant to subsection (a)(2), to receive assistance under section 7704 of this title, the exercise by the President, the Secretary of State, or any other officer or employee of the United States Government of any waiver or suspension of any provision of law referred to in subsection (a)(2), and notification to the appropriate congressional committees in accordance with such provision of law, shall be construed as satisfying the requirements under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7705_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by the Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination by the Board The Board shall determine whether a country is a candidate country for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>