<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7708" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7708/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7708/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7708"><akn:num>7708</akn:num><akn:heading>Millennium Challenge Compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7708. Millennium Challenge Compact(a) CompactThe Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation, may provide assistance for an eligible country only if the country enters into an agreement with the United States, to be known as a “Millennium Challenge Compact”, that establishes a multi-year plan for achieving shared development objectives in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.


(b) Elements(1) In generalThe Compact should take into account the national development strategy of the eligible country and shall contain—(A) the specific objectives that the country and the United States expect to achieve during the term of the Compact;

(B) the responsibilities of the country and the United States in the achievement of such objectives;

(C) regular benchmarks to measure, where appropriate, progress toward achieving such objectives;

(D) an identification of the intended beneficiaries, disaggregated by income level, gender, and age, to the maximum extent practicable;

(E) a multi-year financial plan, including the estimated amount of contributions by the Corporation and the country and proposed mechanisms to implement the plan and provide oversight, that describes how the requirements of subparagraphs (A) through (D) will be met, including identifying the role of civil society in the achievement of such requirements;

(F) where appropriate, a description of the current and potential participation of other donors in the achievement of such objectives;

(G) a plan to ensure appropriate fiscal accountability for the use of assistance provided under section 7704 of this title;

(H) where appropriate, a process or processes for consideration of solicited proposals under the Compact as well as a process for consideration of unsolicited proposals by the Corporation and national, regional, or local units of government;

(I) a requirement that open, fair, and competitive procedures are used in a transparent manner in the administration of grants or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compact The Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation, may provide assistance for an eligible country only if the country enters into an agreement with the United States, to be known as a “Millennium Challenge Compact”, that establishes a multi-year plan for achieving shared development objectives in furtherance of the purposes of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Elements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional provision relating to prohibition on taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional provision relating to prohibition on taxation In addition to the elements described in subsection (c), each Compact shall contain a provision that states that assistance provided by the United States under the Compact shall be exempt from taxation by the government of the eligible country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local input</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Local input In entering into a Compact, the United States shall seek to ensure that the government of an eligible country—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation During any discussions with a country for the purpose of entering into a Compact with the country, officials of the Corporation participating in such discussions shall, at a minimum, consult with appropriate officials of the United States Agency for International Development, particularly with those officials responsible for the appropriate region or country on development issues related to the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other donors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with other donors To the maximum extent feasible, activities undertaken to achieve the objectives of the Compact shall be undertaken in coordination with the assistance activities of other donors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for development of compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance for development of compact Notwithstanding subsection (a), the Chief Executive Officer may enter into contracts or make grants for any eligible country for the purpose of facilitating the development and implementation of the Compact between the United States and the country.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for approval by the Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Requirement for approval by the Board Each Compact shall be approved by the Board before the United States enters into the Compact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increase or extension of assistance under a Compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Increase or extension of assistance under a Compact Not later than 15 days after making a determination to increase or extend assistance under a Compact with an eligible country, the Board, acting through the Chief Executive Officer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7708_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of Compact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Duration of Compact The duration of a Compact shall not exceed 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>