<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7713" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7713/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7713/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7713"><akn:num>7713</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of the Corporation; related provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7713. Powers of the Corporation; related provisions(a) PowersThe Corporation—(1) shall have perpetual succession unless dissolved by a law enacted after January 23, 2004;

(2) may adopt, alter, and use a seal, which shall be judicially noticed;

(3) may make and perform such contracts, grants, and other agreements with any person or government however designated and wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation;

(4) may determine and prescribe the manner in which its obligations shall be incurred and its expenses allowed and paid, including expenses for representation;

(5) may lease, purchase, or otherwise acquire, improve, and use such real property wherever situated, as may be necessary for carrying out the functions of the Corporation;

(6) may accept cash gifts or donations of services or of property (real, personal, or mixed), tangible or intangible, for the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter;

(7) may use the United States mails in the same manner and on the same conditions as the executive departments;

(8) may contract with individuals for personal services, who shall not be considered Federal employees for any provision of law administered by the Office of Personnel Management;

(9) may hire or obtain passenger motor vehicles; and

(10) shall have such other powers as may be necessary and incident to carrying out this chapter.


(b) Principal officeThe Corporation shall maintain its principal office in the metropolitan area of Washington, District of Columbia.


(c) Positions with foreign governmentsWhen approved by the Chief Executive Officer, for purposes of implementing a Compact, employees of the Corporation (including individuals detailed to the Corporation) may accept and hold offices or positions to which no compensation is attached with governments or governmental agencies of foreign countries or with international organizations.


(d) Other authoritiesExcept to the extent inconsiste</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers The Corporation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Principal office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Principal office The Corporation shall maintain its principal office in the metropolitan area of Washington, District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Positions with foreign governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Positions with foreign governments When approved by the Chief Executive Officer, for purposes of implementing a Compact, employees of the Corporation (including individuals detailed to the Corporation) may accept and hold offices or positions to which no compensation is attached with governments or governmental agencies of foreign countries or with international organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other authorities Except to the extent inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter, the administrative authorities contained in the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (22 U.S.C. 2651a et seq.) and the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.) shall apply to the implementation of this chapter to the same extent and in the same manner as such authorities apply to the implementation of those Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of Government Corporation Control Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability of Government Corporation Control Act</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspector General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Inspector General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7713_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>