<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7812" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7812/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/7812/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7812"><akn:num>7812</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for human rights and democracy programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7812. Support for human rights and democracy programs(a) SupportThe President is authorized to provide grants to private, nonprofit organizations to support programs that promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea. Such programs may include appropriate educational and cultural exchange programs with North Korean participants, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law. The President is also authorized to provide grants to entities to undertake research on North Korea’s denial of human rights, including on the political and military chains of command responsible for authorizing and implementing systemic human rights abuses, including at prison camps and detention facilities where political prisoners are held.


(b) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated to the President $2,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2008 and $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2009 through 2022 to carry out this section.


(2) AvailabilityAmounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under paragraph (1) are authorized to remain available until expended.



(Pub. L. 108–333, title I, § 102, Oct. 18, 2004, 118 Stat. 1290; Pub. L. 110–346, § 5, Oct. 7, 2008, 122 Stat. 3941; Pub. L. 112–172, § 4, Aug. 16, 2012, 126 Stat. 1308; Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(a), July 20, 2018, 132 Stat. 1523.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(a)(1), inserted at end “The President is also authorized to provide grants to entities to undertake research on North Korea’s denial of human rights, including on the political and military chains of command responsible for authorizing and implementing systemic human rights abuses, including at prison camps and detention facilities where political prisoners are held.”
Subsec. (b)(1). Pub. L. 115–198, § 7(a)(2), substituted “2022” for “2017”.
2012—Subsec. (b)(1). Pub. L. 112–172 substituted “2017” for “2012”.
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7812_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Support The President is authorized to provide grants to private, nonprofit organizations to support programs that promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea. Such programs may include appropriate educational and cultural exchange programs with North Korean participants, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law. The President is also authorized to provide grants to entities to undertake research on North Korea’s denial of human rights, including on the political and military chains of command responsible for authorizing and implementing systemic human rights abuses, including at prison camps and detention facilities where political prisoners are held.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7812_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>