<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8003" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8003/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8003/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8003"><akn:num>8003</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority and congressional approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8003. Waiver authority and congressional approval(a) In generalIf the President makes the determination described in subsection (b), the President may—(1) exempt a proposed agreement for cooperation with India arranged pursuant to section 2153 of title 42 from the requirement of subsection (a)(2) of such section;

(2) waive the application of section 2157 of title 42 with respect to exports to India; and

(3) waive with respect to India the application of—(A) section 2158(a)(1)(D) of title 42; and

(B) section 2158 of title 42 regarding any actions that occurred before July 18, 2005.



(b) Determination by the PresidentThe determination referred to in subsection (a) is a determination by the President that the following actions have occurred:(1) India has provided the United States and the IAEA with a credible plan to separate civil and military nuclear facilities, materials, and programs, and has filed a declaration regarding its civil facilities and materials with the IAEA.

(2) India and the IAEA have concluded all legal steps required prior to signature by the parties of an agreement requiring the application of IAEA safeguards in perpetuity in accordance with IAEA standards, principles, and practices (including IAEA Board of Governors Document GOV/1621 (1973)) to India’s civil nuclear facilities, materials, and programs as declared in the plan described in paragraph (1), including materials used in or produced through the use of India’s civil nuclear facilities.

(3) India and the IAEA are making substantial progress toward concluding an Additional Protocol consistent with IAEA principles, practices, and policies that would apply to India’s civil nuclear program.

(4) India is working actively with the United States for the early conclusion of a multilateral treaty on the cessation of the production of fissile materials for use in nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices.

(5) India is working with and supporting United States and international eff</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the President makes the determination described in subsection (b), the President may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination by the President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination by the President The determination referred to in subsection (a) is a determination by the President that the following actions have occurred:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on nuclear transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Restrictions on nuclear transfers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sunset The authority provided under subsection (a)(1) to exempt an agreement shall terminate upon October 8, 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8003_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reporting to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>