<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8102"><akn:num>8102</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8102. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Additional protocolThe term “Additional Protocol”, when used in the singular form, means the Protocol Additional to the Agreement between the United States of America and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in the United States of America, with Annexes, signed at Vienna June 12, 1998 (T. Doc. 107–7).


(2) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on International Relations, the Committee on Science, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.


(3) Complementary accessThe term “complementary access” means the exercise of the IAEA’s access rights as set forth in Articles 4 to 6 of the Additional Protocol.


(4) Executive agencyThe term “executive agency” has the meaning given such term in section 105 of title 5.


(5) FacilityThe term “facility” has the meaning set forth in Article 18i. of the Additional Protocol.


(6) IAEAThe term “IAEA” means the International Atomic Energy Agency.


(7) Judge of the United StatesThe term “judge of the United States” means a United States district judge, or a United States magistrate judge appointed under the authority of chapter 43 of title 28.


(8) LocationThe term “location” means any geographic point or area declared or identified by the United States or specified by the International Atomic Energy Agency.


(9) Nuclear Non-Proliferation TreatyThe term “Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty” means the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, done at Washington, London, and Moscow July 1, 1968, and entered into force March 5, 1970 (21 UST 483).


(10) Nuclear-weapon State Party and non-nuclear-weapon State PartyThe terms “nuclear-weapon State Party” and “non-nuclear-weapon State Party” have the meanings gi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional protocol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Additional protocol The term “Additional Protocol”, when used in the singular form, means the Protocol Additional to the Agreement between the United States of America and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards in the United States of America, with Annexes, signed at Vienna June 12, 1998 (T. Doc. 107–7).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on International Relations, the Committee on Science, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complementary access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Complementary access The term “complementary access” means the exercise of the IAEA’s access rights as set forth in Articles 4 to 6 of the Additional Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Executive agency The term “executive agency” has the meaning given such term in section 105 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Facility The term “facility” has the meaning set forth in Article 18i. of the Additional Protocol.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>IAEA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) IAEA The term “IAEA” means the International Atomic Energy Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judge of the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Judge of the United States The term “judge of the United States” means a United States district judge, or a United States magistrate judge appointed under the authority of chapter 43 of title 28.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Location The term “location” means any geographic point or area declared or identified by the United States or specified by the International Atomic Energy Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty The term “Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty” means the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons, done at Washington, London, and Moscow July 1, 1968, and entered into force March 5, 1970 (21 UST 483).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8102_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear-weapon State Party and non-nuclear-weapon State Party</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Nuclear-weapon State Party and non-nuclear-weapon State Party The terms “nuclear-weapon State Party” and “non-nuclear-weapon State Party” have the meanings given such terms in the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>