<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8303" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8303/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8303/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8303"><akn:num>8303</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Volunteers for Prosperity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8303. Office of Volunteers for Prosperity(a) FunctionsThe VfP Office shall pursue the objectives of the VfP Program described in subsection (b) by—(1) implementing the VfPServe Program to provide eligible skilled professionals with matching grants to offset the travel and living expenses of volunteering abroad with nonprofit organizations;

(2) otherwise promoting short- and long-term international volunteer service by skilled American professionals, including connecting such professionals with nonprofit organizations, to achieve such objectives;

(3) helping nonprofit organizations in the United States recruit and effectively manage additional skilled American professionals for volunteer assignments throughout the developing world;

(4) providing recognition for skilled American volunteers and the organizations deploying them;

(5) helping nonprofit organizations and corporations in the United States to identify resources and opportunities in international volunteer service utilizing skilled Americans;

(6) encouraging the establishment of international volunteer programs for employees of United States corporations; and

(7) encouraging international voluntary service by highly skilled Americans to promote health and prosperity throughout the world.


(b) VfP Program objectivesThe objectives of the VfP Program should include—(1) eliminating extreme poverty;

(2) reducing world hunger and malnutrition;

(3) increasing access to safe potable water;

(4) enacting universal education;

(5) reducing child mortality and childhood diseases;

(6) combating the spread of preventable diseases, including HIV, malaria, and tuberculosis;

(7) providing educational and work skill support for girls and empowering women to achieve independence;

(8) creating sustainable business and entrepreneurial opportunities; and

(9) increasing access to information technology.


(c) Volunteers for Prosperity Service Incentive Program(1) In generalThe VfP Office may provide matching grants </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Functions The VfP Office shall pursue the objectives of the VfP Program described in subsection (b) by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>VfP Program objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) VfP Program objectives The objectives of the VfP Program should include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteers for Prosperity Service Incentive Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Volunteers for Prosperity Service Incentive Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination The VfP Office shall coordinate its efforts with other public and private efforts that aim to send skilled professionals to serve in developing nations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8303_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report The VfP Office shall submit an annual report to Congress on the activities of the VfP Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>