<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8562" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8562/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8562/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8562"><akn:num>8562</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8562. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Admission; admitted; alienThe terms “admission”, “admitted”, and “alien” have the meanings given those terms in section 1101 of title 8.


(2) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Financial Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.


(3) Correspondent account; payable-through accountThe terms “correspondent account” and “payable-through account” have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31.


(4) Foreign financial institutionThe term “foreign financial institution” has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 8513(i) of this title.


(5) Foreign personThe term “foreign person” means any individual or entity that is not a United States person.


(6) United States personThe term “United States person” means—(A) a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or

(B) an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.


(Pub. L. 117–328, div. AA, title II, § 203, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5532.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Masih Alinejad Harassment and Unlawful Targeting Act of 2022, also known as the Masih Alinejad HUNT Act of 2022, and not as part of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission; admitted; alien</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Admission; admitted; alien The terms “admission”, “admitted”, and “alien” have the meanings given those terms in section 1101 of title 8.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Correspondent account; payable-through account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Correspondent account; payable-through account The terms “correspondent account” and “payable-through account” have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign financial institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Foreign financial institution The term “foreign financial institution” has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 8513(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Foreign person The term “foreign person” means any individual or entity that is not a United States person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8562_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) United States person The term “United States person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>