<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8726" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8726/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8726/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8726"><akn:num>8726</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports on, and authorization of imposition of sanctions with respect to, the provision of specializ</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8726. Reports on, and authorization of imposition of sanctions with respect to, the provision of specialized financial messaging services to the Central Bank of Iran and other sanctioned Iranian financial institutions(a) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(1) providers of specialized financial messaging services are a critical link to the international financial system;

(2) the European Union is to be commended for strengthening the multilateral sanctions regime against Iran by deciding that specialized financial messaging services may not be provided to the Central Bank of Iran and other sanctioned Iranian financial institutions by persons subject to the jurisdiction of the European Union; and

(3) the loss of access by sanctioned Iranian financial institutions to specialized financial messaging services must be maintained.


(b) Reports required(1) In generalNot later than 60 days after August 10, 2012, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that contains—(A) a list of all persons that the Secretary has identified that directly provide specialized financial messaging services to, or enable or facilitate direct or indirect access to such messaging services for, the Central Bank of Iran or a financial institution described in section 104(c)(2)(E)(ii) of the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (22 U.S.C. 8513(c)(2)(E)(ii)); and

(B) a detailed assessment of the status of efforts by the Secretary to end the direct provision of such messaging services to, and the enabling or facilitation of direct or indirect access to such messaging services for, the Central Bank of Iran or a financial institution described in that section.


(2) Enabling or facilitation of access to specialized financial messaging services through intermediary financial institutionsFor purposes of paragraph (1) and subsection (c), enabling or facilitating direc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8726_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8726_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reports required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8726_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of imposition of sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of imposition of sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8726_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the authority of the President pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) or the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 (22 U.S.C. 8501 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>