<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8754a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8754a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8754a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8754a"><akn:num>8754a</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy and grant program to promote internet freedom in Iran</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8754a. Strategy and grant program to promote internet freedom in Iran(a) Strategy(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after December 23, 2024, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall develop a strategy to support and enhance access to information by civil society in Iran.


(2) ElementsThe strategy required in subparagraph (A) 11 So in original. Probably should be “paragraph (1)”. shall include the following elements:(A) An evaluation of the use of virtual private networks by civil society in Iran.

(B) An assessment of the level of internet access for Iranians who do not use virtual private networks, including levels of reliable connectivity, bandwidth, and coverage, as well as censorship, surveillance, and other limitations on internet access.

(C) A strategy to increase the accessibility of virtual private networks in Iran.

(D) An assessment of alternatives to virtual private networks that are capable of circumventing restrictions on open internet access imposed by the Government of Iran.

(E) An assessment of how companies providing Iranian civilians with technology and other tools to overcome technical and political obstacles are able to access the open internet.

(F) An assessment of the ability of the Government of Iran to cut off all access to the internet in Iran.

(G) A strategy to circumvent internet blackouts for Iranian civil society.


(3) Initial updateNot later than 120 days after December 23, 2024, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate an updated version of the strategy required in paragraph (1).


(4) Periodic review and updatesThe Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate, shall—(A) not less frequently than twice each year, review the strategy required in par</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8754a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8754a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program and contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant program and contract authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>