<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/8802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_8802"><akn:num>8802</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress relating to violations of human rights by Iran</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 8802. Sense of Congress relating to violations of human rights by Iran(a) FindingCongress finds that the interests of the United States and international peace are threatened by the ongoing and destabilizing actions of the Government of Iran, including its massive, systematic, and extraordinary violations of the human rights of its own citizens.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that the United States should—(1) deny the Government of Iran the ability to continue to oppress the people of Iran and to use violence and executions against pro-democracy protestors and regime opponents;

(2) fully and publicly support efforts made by the people of Iran to promote the establishment of basic freedoms that build the foundation for the emergence of a freely elected, open, and democratic political system;

(3) help the people of Iran produce, access, and share information freely and safely via the Internet and through other media; and

(4) defeat all attempts by the Government of Iran to jam or otherwise obstruct international satellite broadcast signals.


(Pub. L. 112–239, div. A, title XII, § 1243, Jan. 2, 2013, 126 Stat. 2005.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Finding Congress finds that the interests of the United States and international peace are threatened by the ongoing and destabilizing actions of the Government of Iran, including its massive, systematic, and extraordinary violations of the human rights of its own citizens.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_8802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that the United States should—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>