<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9202" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9202/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9202/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9202"><akn:num>9202</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9202. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Applicable Executive orderThe term “applicable Executive order” means—(A) Executive Order 13382 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to blocking property of weapons of mass destruction proliferators and their supporters), Executive Order 13466 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to continuing certain restrictions with respect to North Korea and North Korean nationals), Executive Order 13551 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to blocking property of certain persons with respect to North Korea), Executive Order 13570 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to prohibiting certain transactions with respect to North Korea), Executive Order 13619 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to blocking property of persons threatening the peace, security, or stability of Burma), Executive Order 13687 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to imposing additional sanctions with respect to North Korea), Executive Order No. 13694 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to blocking the property of certain persons engaging in significant malicious cyber-enabled activities), or Executive Order No. 13722 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note; relating to blocking the property of the Government of North Korea and the Workers’ Party of Korea, and Prohibiting Certain Transactions With Respect to North Korea), to the extent that such Executive order—(i) authorizes the imposition of sanctions on persons for conduct with respect to North Korea;

(ii) prohibits transactions or activities involving the Government of North Korea; or

(iii) otherwise imposes sanctions with respect to North Korea; and


(B) any Executive order adopted on or after February 18, 2016, to the extent that such Executive order—(i) authorizes the imposition of sanctions on persons for conduct with respect to North Korea;

(ii) prohibits transactions or activities involving the Government of North Korea; or

(iii) otherwise imposes sanctions with respect to North Korea.



(2) Applicable United Nations Security Council resolutionThe term “applicab</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable Executive order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Applicable Executive order The term “applicable Executive order” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable United Nations Security Council resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Applicable United Nations Security Council resolution The term “applicable United Nations Security Council resolution” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Designated person The term “designated person” means a person designated under subsection (a), (b), or (g) of section 9214 of this title for purposes of applying 1 or more of the sanctions described in subchapter I or II with respect to the person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Foreign person The term “foreign person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government of North Korea</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Government of North Korea The term “Government of North Korea” means the Government of North Korea and its agencies, instrumentalities, and controlled entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Humanitarian assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Humanitarian assistance The term “humanitarian assistance” means assistance to meet humanitarian needs, including needs for food, medicine, medical supplies, clothing, and shelter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intelligence community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Intelligence community The term “intelligence community” has the meaning given such term in section 3003(4) of title 50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Luxury goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Luxury goods The term “luxury goods”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9202_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monetary instruments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Monetary instruments The term “monetary instruments” has the meaning given such term in section 5312(a) of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>