<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9221a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9221a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9221a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9221a"><akn:num>9221a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on indirect correspondent accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9221a. Prohibition on indirect correspondent accounts(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b), if a United States financial institution has or obtains knowledge that a correspondent account established, maintained, administered, or managed by that institution for a foreign financial institution is being used by the foreign financial institution to provide significant financial services indirectly to any person, foreign government, or financial institution designated under section 9214 of this title, the United States financial institution shall ensure that such correspondent account is no longer used to provide such services.


(b) ExceptionA United States financial institution is authorized to process transfers of funds to or from North Korea, or for the direct or indirect benefit of any person, foreign government, or financial institution that is designated under section 9214 of this title, only if the transfer—(1) arises from, and is ordinarily incident and necessary to give effect to, an underlying transaction that has been authorized by a specific or general license issued by the Secretary of the Treasury; and

(2) does not involve debiting or crediting a North Korean account.


(c) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Correspondent accountThe term “correspondent account” has the meaning given that term in section 5318A of title 31.


(2) United States financial institutionThe term “United States financial institution” means 11 So in original. has the meaning given that term in section 510.310 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on August 2, 2017.


(3) Foreign financial institutionThe term “foreign financial institution” has the meaning given that term in section 1010.605 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on August 2, 2017.



(Pub. L. 114–122, title II, § 201A, as added Pub. L. 115–44, title III, § 312(a), Aug. 2, 2017, 131 Stat. 945.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9221a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (b), if a United States financial institution has or obtains knowledge that a correspondent account established, maintained, administered, or managed by that institution for a foreign financial institution is being used by the foreign financial institution to provide significant financial services indirectly to any person, foreign government, or financial institution designated under section 9214 of this title, the United States financial institution shall ensure that such correspondent account is no longer used to provide such services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9221a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception A United States financial institution is authorized to process transfers of funds to or from North Korea, or for the direct or indirect benefit of any person, foreign government, or financial institution that is designated under section 9214 of this title, only if the transfer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9221a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>