<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9223" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9223/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9223/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9223"><akn:num>9223</akn:num><akn:heading>Proliferation prevention sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9223. Proliferation prevention sanctions(a) Export of certain goods or technologyA validated license shall be required for the export to North Korea of any goods or technology otherwise covered under section 4605(j) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 50. No defense exports may be approved for the Government of North Korea.


(b) Transactions in defense articles or defense services(1) In generalThe President shall withhold assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.) to the government of any country that provides to or receives from the Government of North Korea a defense article or defense service, as such terms are defined in section 2794 of this title, if the President determines that a significant type or amount of such article or service has been so provided or received.


(2) ApplicabilityThe prohibition under paragraph (1) with respect to a government shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the prohibition under paragraph (1) is applied to that government.



(c) WaiverNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of State may waive the prohibitions under this section with respect to a country if the Secretary—(1) determines that such waiver is in the national interest of the United States; and

(2) submits a written report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes—(A) the steps that the relevant agencies are taking to curtail the trade described in subsection (b)(1); and

(B) why such waiver is in the national interest of the United States.



(d) ExceptionThe prohibitions under this section shall not apply to the provision of assistance for human rights, democracy, rule of law, maternal and child health, disease prevention and response, or humanitarian purposes.


(e) Report on arms trafficking involving North Korea(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after August 2, 2017, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9223_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Export of certain goods or technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Export of certain goods or technology A validated license shall be required for the export to North Korea of any goods or technology otherwise covered under section 4605(j) 11 See References in Text note below. of title 50. No defense exports may be approved for the Government of North Korea.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9223_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transactions in defense articles or defense services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transactions in defense articles or defense services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9223_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of State may waive the prohibitions under this section with respect to a country if the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9223_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception The prohibitions under this section shall not apply to the provision of assistance for human rights, democracy, rule of law, maternal and child health, disease prevention and response, or humanitarian purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9223_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on arms trafficking involving North Korea</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on arms trafficking involving North Korea</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>