<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9241b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9241b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9241b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9241b"><akn:num>9241b</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions on foreign persons employing North Korean labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9241b. Sanctions on foreign persons employing North Korean labor(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (c), the President shall designate any person identified under section 9241(b)(3) of this title for the imposition of sanctions under subsection (b).


(b) Imposition of sanctions(1) In generalThe President shall impose the sanctions described in paragraph (2) with respect to any person designated under subsection (a).


(2) Sanctions describedThe sanctions described in this paragraph are sanctions pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.) to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a person designated under subsection (a), if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.



(c) Exception(1) In generalA person may not be designated under subsection (a) if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the President has received reliable assurances from such person that—(A) the employment of North Korean laborers does not result in the direct or indirect transfer of convertible currency, luxury goods, or other stores of value to the Government of North Korea;

(B) all wages and benefits are provided directly to the laborers, and are held, as applicable, in accounts within the jurisdiction in which they reside in locally denominated currency; and

(C) the laborers are subject to working conditions consistent with international standards.


(2) RecertificationNot later than 180 days after the date on which the President transmits to the appropriate congressional committees an initial certification under paragraph (1), and every 180 days thereafter, the President shall—(A) transmit a recertification stating that the conditions described in such paragraph continue to be met; or

(B) if such recertification cannot be transmitted, impo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9241b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (c), the President shall designate any person identified under section 9241(b)(3) of this title for the imposition of sanctions under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9241b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Imposition of sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9241b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>