<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9424" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9424/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9424/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9424"><akn:num>9424</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9424. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) Appropriate congressional committeesThe term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and

(B) the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.


(2) Foreign personThe term “foreign person”—(A) means an individual or entity that is not a United States person; and

(B) includes a foreign state (as such term is defined in section 1603 of title 28).


(3) Government of IranThe term “Government of Iran” has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2021.


(4) United States personThe terms “United States person” means—(A) a United States citizen;

(B) a permanent resident alien of the United States;

(C) an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or

(D) a person in the United States.


(5) Iran-aligned entityThe term “Iran-aligned entity” means a foreign person that—(A) is controlled or significantly influenced by the Government of Iran; and

(B) knowingly receives material or financial support from the Government of Iran, including Hezbollah, the Houthis, or any other proxy group that furthers Iran’s national security objectives.


(6) Covered technologyThe term “covered technology” means—(A) any goods, technology, software, or related material specified in the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, as in effect on the day before April 24, 2024; and

(B) any additional goods, technology, software, or related material added to the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex after the day before April 24, 2024.


(7) Family memberThe term “family member” means—(A) a child, grandchild, parent, grandparent</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Appropriate congressional committees The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Foreign person The term “foreign person”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government of Iran</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Government of Iran The term “Government of Iran” has the meaning given such term in section 560.304 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, as such section was in effect on January 1, 2021.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) United States person The terms “United States person” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Iran-aligned entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Iran-aligned entity The term “Iran-aligned entity” means a foreign person that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Covered technology The term “covered technology” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family member</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Family member The term “family member” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Knowingly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Knowingly The term “knowingly” has the meaning given that term in section 14 of the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996 (50 U.S.C. 1701 note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missile Technology Control Regime</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Missile Technology Control Regime The term “Missile Technology Control Regime” means the policy statement, between the United States, the United Kingdom, the Federal Republic of Germany, France, Italy, Canada, and Japan, announced on April 16, 1987, to restrict sensitive missile-relevant transfers based on the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex, and any amendments thereto or expansions thereof, as in effect on the day before April 24, 2024.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9424_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Missile Technology Control Regime Annex</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Missile Technology Control Regime Annex The term “Missile Technology Control Regime Annex” means the Guidelines and Equipment and Technology Annex of the Missile Technology Control Regime, and any amendments thereto or updates thereof, as in effect on the day before April 24, 2024.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>