<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9529" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9529/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9529/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9529"><akn:num>9529</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9529. Sanctions described(a) Sanctions describedThe sanctions to be imposed with respect to a person under section 9524(a)(2), 9525(b), 9526(a), or 9527(a) of this title are the following:(1) Export-Import Bank assistance for exports to sanctioned personsThe President may direct the Export-Import Bank of the United States not to give approval to the issuance of any guarantee, insurance, extension of credit, or participation in the extension of credit in connection with the export of any goods or services to the sanctioned person.


(2) Export sanctionThe President may order the United States Government not to issue any specific license and not to grant any other specific permission or authority to export any goods or technology to the sanctioned person under—(A) the Export Administration Act of 1979 (50 U.S.C. 4601 et seq.) (as continued in effect pursuant to the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.));

(B) the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.);

(C) the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.); or

(D) any other statute that requires the prior review and approval of the United States Government as a condition for the export or reexport of goods or services.


(3) Loans from United States financial institutionsThe President may prohibit any United States financial institution from making loans or providing credits to the sanctioned person totaling more than $10,000,000 in any 12-month period unless the person is engaged in activities to relieve human suffering and the loans or credits are provided for such activities.


(4) Loans from international financial institutionsThe President may direct the United States executive director to each international financial institution to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose any loan from the international financial institution that would benefit the sanctioned person.


(5) Prohibitions on financial institutionsThe following prohibitions may be imposed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9529_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Sanctions described The sanctions to be imposed with respect to a person under section 9524(a)(2), 9525(b), 9526(a), or 9527(a) of this title are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9529_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctioned person defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sanctioned person defined In this section, the term “sanctioned person” means a person subject to sanctions under section 9524(a)(2), 9525(b), 9526(a), or 9527(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>