<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9530" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9530/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9530/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9530"><akn:num>9530</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions, waiver, and termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9530. Exceptions, waiver, and termination(a) ExceptionsThe provisions of this part and amendments made by this part shall not apply with respect to the following:(1) Activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.), or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.

(2) The admission of an alien to the United States if such admission is necessary to comply with United States obligations under the Agreement between the United Nations and the United States of America regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, under the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or under other international agreements.


(b) Waiver of sanctions that are imposedSubject to section 9511 of this title, if the President imposes sanctions with respect to a person under this part or the amendments made by this part, the President may waive the application of those sanctions if the President determines that such a waiver is in the national security interest of the United States.


(c) TerminationSubject to section 9511 of this title, the President may terminate the application of sanctions under section 9524, 9525, 9526, 9527, or 9528 of this title with respect to a person if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees—(1) a notice of and justification for the termination; and

(2) a notice that—(A) the person is not engaging in the activity that was the basis for the sanctions or has taken significant verifiable steps toward stopping the activity; and

(B) the President has received reliable assurances that the person will not knowingly engage in activity subject to sanctions under this part in the future.



(Pub. L. 115–44, title II, § 236, Aug. 2, 2017, 131 Stat. 921.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis part, referred to in te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9530_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Exceptions The provisions of this part and amendments made by this part shall not apply with respect to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9530_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of sanctions that are imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver of sanctions that are imposed Subject to section 9511 of this title, if the President imposes sanctions with respect to a person under this part or the amendments made by this part, the President may waive the application of those sanctions if the President determines that such a waiver is in the national security interest of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9530_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Termination Subject to section 9511 of this title, the President may terminate the application of sanctions under section 9524, 9525, 9526, 9527, or 9528 of this title with respect to a person if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>