<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9564" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9564/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9564/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9564"><akn:num>9564</akn:num><akn:heading>Progress reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9564. Progress reports
Not later than one year after December 20, 2019, and annually thereafter, the President shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on progress made in providing assistance for projects under section 9563 of this title that includes—(1) a description of the energy infrastructure projects the United States has identified for such assistance; and

(2) for each such project—(A) a description of the role of the United States in the project, including in early-stage project support and late-stage project support;

(B) the amount and form of any debt financing and insurance provided by the United States Government for the project;

(C) the amount and form of any early-stage project support; and

(D) an update on the progress made on the project as of the date of the report.


(Pub. L. 116–94, div. P, title XX, § 2005, Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 3226.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the European Energy Security and Diversification Act of 2019, and also as part of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020, and not as part of the Countering Russian Influence in Europe and Eurasia Act of 2017 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) a description of the energy infrastructure projects the United States has identified for such assistance; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9564_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) for each such project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>