<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9613"><akn:num>9613</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9613. Management of Corporation(a) Structure of CorporationThere shall be in the Corporation a Board of Directors (in this chapter referred to as the “Board”), a Chief Executive Officer, a Deputy Chief Executive Officer, a Chief Risk Officer, a Chief Development Officer, and such other officers as the Board may determine.


(b) Board of Directors(1) DutiesAll powers of the Corporation shall vest in and be exercised by or under the authority of the Board. The Board—(A) shall perform the functions specified to be carried out by the Board in this chapter;

(B) may prescribe, amend, and repeal bylaws, rules, regulations, policies, and procedures governing the manner in which the business of the Corporation may be conducted and in which the powers granted to the Corporation by law may be exercised; and

(C) shall develop, in consultation with stakeholders, other interested parties, and the appropriate congressional committees, a publicly available policy with respect to consultations, hearings, and other forms of engagement in order to provide for meaningful public participation in the Board’s activities.


(2) Membership of Board(A) In generalThe Board shall consist of—(i) the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation;

(ii) the officers specified in subparagraph (B); and

(iii) four other individuals who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, of which—(I) one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least 5 individuals submitted by the majority leader of the Senate after consultation with the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(II) one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least 5 individuals submitted by the minority leader of the Senate after consultation with the ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(III) one individual should be appointed from among a list of at least 5 individuals submitted by the Speaker of the House of Rep</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Structure of Corporation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Structure of Corporation There shall be in the Corporation a Board of Directors (in this chapter referred to as the “Board”), a Chief Executive Officer, a Deputy Chief Executive Officer, a Chief Risk Officer, a Chief Development Officer, and such other officers as the Board may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board of Directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public hearings The Board shall hold at least 2 public hearings each year in order to afford an opportunity for any person to present views with respect to whether—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Executive Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chief Executive Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Chief Executive Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deputy Chief Executive Officer There shall be in the Corporation a Deputy Chief Executive Officer, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall serve at the pleasure of the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Risk Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chief Risk Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Development Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Chief Development Officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Officers and employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9613_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Development Advisory Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>