<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9671" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9671/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9671/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9671"><akn:num>9671</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations and preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9671. Limitations and preferences(a) Limitation on support for single entityNo entity receiving support from the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter may receive more than an amount equal to 5 percent of the Corporation’s maximum contingent liability authorized under section 9633 of this title.


(b) Preference for support for projects sponsored by United States persons(1) In generalThe Corporation should give preferential consideration to projects sponsored by or involving private sector entities that are United States persons.


(2) United States person definedIn this subsection, the term “United States person” means—(A) a United States citizen; or

(B) an entity owned or controlled by an individual or individuals described in subparagraph (A).



(c) Preference for support in countries in compliance with international trade obligations(1) Consultations with United States Trade RepresentativeNot less frequently than annually, the Corporation shall consult with the United States Trade Representative with respect to the status of countries eligible to receive support from the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter and the compliance of those countries with their international trade obligations.


(2) Preferential considerationThe Corporation shall give preferential consideration to providing support under subchapter II of this chapter for projects in countries in compliance with or making substantial progress coming into compliance with their international trade obligations.



(d) Worker rights(1) In generalThe Corporation shall only support projects under subchapter II of this chapter in countries that are taking steps to adopt and implement laws that extend internationally recognized worker rights (as defined in section 2467 of title 19) to workers in that country, including any designated zone in that country.


(2) Required contract languageThe Corporation shall also include the following language, in substantially the following form, in a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on support for single entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on support for single entity No entity receiving support from the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter may receive more than an amount equal to 5 percent of the Corporation’s maximum contingent liability authorized under section 9633 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for support for projects sponsored by United States persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preference for support for projects sponsored by United States persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for support in countries in compliance with international trade obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preference for support in countries in compliance with international trade obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Worker rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Worker rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Impact notification The Board shall not vote in favor of any project proposed to be supported by the Corporation under subchapter II of this chapter that is likely to have significant adverse environmental or social impacts that are sensitive, diverse, or unprecedented, unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Women’s economic empowerment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Women’s economic empowerment In utilizing its authorities under subchapter II of this chapter, the Corporation shall consider the impacts of its support on women’s economic opportunities and outcomes and shall prioritize the reduction of gender gaps and maximize development impact by working to improve women’s economic opportunities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for provision of support in countries embracing private enterprise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preference for provision of support in countries embracing private enterprise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of foreign boycott participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consideration of foreign boycott participation In providing support for projects under subchapter II of this chapter, the Corporation shall consider, using information readily available, whether the project is sponsored by or substantially affiliated with any person taking or knowingly agreeing to take actions, or having taken or knowingly agreed to take actions within the past 3 years, which demonstrate or otherwise evidence intent to comply with, further, or support any boycott described in section 4842(a) of title 50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9671_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring opportunities for small businesses in foreign development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Ensuring opportunities for small businesses in foreign development The Corporation shall, using broad criteria, make, to the maximum extent possible consistent with this chapter, efforts—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>