<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9686" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9686/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9686/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9686"><akn:num>9686</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9686. Savings provisions(a) Completed administrative actions(1) In generalCompleted administrative actions of an agency shall not be affected by the enactment of this Act or the transfer of such agency to the Corporation under section 9683 of this title, but shall continue in effect according to their terms until amended, modified, superseded, terminated, set aside, or revoked in accordance with law by an officer of the United States or a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.


(2) Completed administrative action definedIn this subsection, the term “completed administrative action” includes orders, determinations, rules, regulations, personnel actions, permits, agreements, grants, contracts, certificates, policies, licenses, registrations, and privileges.



(b) Pending proceedings(1) In generalPending proceedings in an agency, including notices of proposed rulemaking, and applications for licenses, permits, certificates, grants, and financial assistance, shall continue notwithstanding the enactment of this Act or the transfer of the agency to the Corporation, unless discontinued or modified under the same terms and conditions and to the same extent that such discontinuance could have occurred if such enactment or transfer had not occurred.


(2) OrdersOrders issued in proceedings described in paragraph (1), and appeals therefrom, and payments made pursuant to such orders, shall issue in the same manner and on the same terms as if this chapter had not been enacted or the agency had not been transferred, and any such orders shall continue in effect until amended, modified, superseded, terminated, set aside, or revoked by an officer of the United States or a court of competent jurisdiction, or by operation of law.



(c) Pending civil actionsPending civil actions shall continue notwithstanding the enactment of this Act or the transfer of an agency to the Corporation, and in such civil actions, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Completed administrative actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Completed administrative actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pending proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pending civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pending civil actions Pending civil actions shall continue notwithstanding the enactment of this Act or the transfer of an agency to the Corporation, and in such civil actions, proceedings shall be had, appeals taken, and judgments rendered and enforced in the same manner and with the same effect as if such enactment or transfer had not occurred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>References</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) References References relating to an agency that is transferred to the Corporation under section 9683 of this title in statutes, Executive orders, rules, regulations, directives, or delegations of authority that precede such transfer or October 5, 2018, shall be deemed to refer, as appropriate, to the Corporation, to its officers, employees, or agents, or to its corresponding organizational units or functions. Statutory reporting requirements that applied in relation to such an agency immediately before the effective date of this chapter shall continue to apply following such transfer if they refer to the agency by name.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employment provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9686_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statutory reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Statutory reporting requirements Any statutory reporting requirement that applied to an agency transferred to the Corporation under this subchapter immediately before October 5, 2018, shall continue to apply following that transfer if the statutory requirement refers to the agency by name.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>