<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9753" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9753/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9753/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9753"><akn:num>9753</akn:num><akn:heading>Countering Russian influence in Venezuela</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9753. Countering Russian influence in Venezuela(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Russian-Venezuelan Threat Mitigation Act”.


(b) Threat assessment and strategy to counter Russian influence in Venezuela(1) Defined termIn this subsection, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.


(2) Threat assessmentNot later than 120 days after December 20, 2019, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding—(A) an assessment of Russian-Venezuelan security cooperation;

(B) the potential threat such cooperation poses to the United States and countries in the Western Hemisphere; and

(C) a strategy to counter threats identified in subparagraphs (A) and (B).



(c) Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole(1) Aliens describedAn alien described in this paragraph is an alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of either Secretary) knows, or has reason to believe, is acting or has acted on behalf of the Government of Russia in direct support of the security forces of the Maduro regime.


(2) Visas, admission, or paroleAn alien described in paragraph (1) is—(A) inadmissible to the United States;

(B) ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and

(C) otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.).


(3) Current visas revoked(A) In generalAn alien described in paragraph (1) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.


(B) Immediate effectA revocation under subparagraph (A) shall—(i) take effect immediately; and

(ii) automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9753_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Russian-Venezuelan Threat Mitigation Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9753_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Threat assessment and strategy to counter Russian influence in Venezuela</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Threat assessment and strategy to counter Russian influence in Venezuela</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9753_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>