<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9761" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9761/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9761/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9761"><akn:num>9761</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional briefings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9761. Congressional briefings(a) Humanitarian assistance; sanctions coordination(1) In generalNot later than 15 days after any of the congressional committees listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation—(A) of section 9711 of this title, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall provide such briefing to such committee; and

(B) of section 9751 of this title, the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.


(2) Congressional committeesThe committees listed in this paragraph are—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(B) the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate;

(C) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and

(D) the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.



(b) United Nations; negotiated solution; crimes against humanity(1) In generalNot later than 15 days after any congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 9703 of this title, 9712 of this title, or 142,11 See References in Text note below. the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.


(2) Congressional committeesThe congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.



(c) Regime cohesion(1) In generalNot later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in paragraph (2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 131,1 the Secretary of State and the Director of National Intelligence shall provide such briefing to such committee.


(2) Congressional committeesThe congressional committees listed in this paragraph are—(A) the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;

(B) the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;

(C) the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Repres</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Humanitarian assistance; sanctions coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Humanitarian assistance; sanctions coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>United Nations; negotiated solution; crimes against humanity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) United Nations; negotiated solution; crimes against humanity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regime cohesion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regime cohesion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>International election observation; democratic civil society</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) International election observation; democratic civil society Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in subsection (a)(2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 9731 of this title, the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall provide such briefing to such committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Visa restrictions; sanctions waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Visa restrictions; sanctions waiver Not later than 15 days after a congressional committee listed in subsection (b)(2) requests a briefing regarding the implementation of section 9721 or 9722 of this title, the Secretary of State shall provide such briefing to such committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of stolen assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recovery of stolen assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9761_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>PDVSA transactions with Rosneft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) PDVSA transactions with Rosneft</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>