<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/22/9905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_9905"><akn:num>9905</akn:num><akn:heading>Private sector consultation and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 9905. Private sector consultation and coordination(a) Consultation with private sector by embassyIn developing the priorities for trade expansion initiatives described in section 9904(d) of this title, embassy mission teams shall convene local representatives of the United States private sector and the private sector of host countries to consult on issues affecting trade at the borders of such countries and take into account the private sector’s operational expertise and experience confronting the trade barriers in such countries as well as its recommendations for reform and best practices.


(b) Inclusion of private-sector comments in mission plansWritten comments from local United States private sector representatives shall be included in the trade expansion component of mission plans submitted by the chief of mission to the Secretary of State, with recommendations and comments from the mission team, for the purpose of informing the development of the joint strategic plan on trade expansion priorities required pursuant to section 9904(c)(4) of this title and recommended funding for the implementation of such plan.


(c) Designated embassy point of contact for private sector consultationEach chief of mission shall designate an appropriate point of contact within the embassy who shall receive recommendations from appropriate private sector representatives regarding the implementation of the strategic plan required under section 9904(c)(4) of this title and ongoing trade barriers negatively impacting priority trade expansion. The chief of mission shall ensure that the designated point of contact shall be reasonably available for consultations with appropriate private sector representatives and to receive recommendations with respect to country-specific issues that may arise that will foreseeably disrupt trade.


(d) Requirement to protect business confidential information(1) In generalThe Secretary of State, Secretary of Commerce, and United States Trade Representa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with private sector by embassy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consultation with private sector by embassy In developing the priorities for trade expansion initiatives described in section 9904(d) of this title, embassy mission teams shall convene local representatives of the United States private sector and the private sector of host countries to consult on issues affecting trade at the borders of such countries and take into account the private sector’s operational expertise and experience confronting the trade barriers in such countries as well as its recommendations for reform and best practices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of private-sector comments in mission plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inclusion of private-sector comments in mission plans Written comments from local United States private sector representatives shall be included in the trade expansion component of mission plans submitted by the chief of mission to the Secretary of State, with recommendations and comments from the mission team, for the purpose of informing the development of the joint strategic plan on trade expansion priorities required pursuant to section 9904(c)(4) of this title and recommended funding for the implementation of such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated embassy point of contact for private sector consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designated embassy point of contact for private sector consultation Each chief of mission shall designate an appropriate point of contact within the embassy who shall receive recommendations from appropriate private sector representatives regarding the implementation of the strategic plan required under section 9904(c)(4) of this title and ongoing trade barriers negatively impacting priority trade expansion. The chief of mission shall ensure that the designated point of contact shall be reasonably available for consultations with appropriate private sector representatives and to receive recommendations with respect to country-specific issues that may arise that will foreseeably disrupt trade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_9905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement to protect business confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement to protect business confidential information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>