<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1007" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1007/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1007/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1007"><akn:num>1007</akn:num><akn:heading>Representative payees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1007. Representative payees(a) In generalIf the Commissioner of Social Security determines that the interest of any qualified individual under this subchapter would be served thereby, payment of the qualified individual’s benefit under this subchapter may be made, regardless of the legal competency or incompetency of the qualified individual, either directly to the qualified individual, or for his or her use and benefit, to another person (the meaning of which term, for purposes of this section, includes an organization) with respect to whom the requirements of subsection (b) have been met (in this section referred to as the qualified individual’s “representative payee”). If the Commissioner of Social Security determines that a representative payee has misused any benefit paid to the representative payee pursuant to this section, 405(j) of this title, or section 1383(a)(2) of this title, the Commissioner of Social Security shall promptly revoke the person’s designation as the qualified individual’s representative payee under this subsection, and shall make payment to an alternative representative payee or, if the interest of the qualified individual under this subchapter would be served thereby, to the qualified individual.


(b) Examination of fitness of prospective representative payee(1) Any determination under subsection (a) to pay the benefits of a qualified individual to a representative payee shall be made on the basis of—(A) an investigation by the Commissioner of Social Security of the person to serve as representative payee, which shall be conducted in advance of the determination and shall, to the extent practicable, include a face-to-face interview with the person (or, in the case of an organization, a representative of the organization); and

(B) adequate evidence that the arrangement is in the interest of the qualified individual.


(2) As part of the investigation referred to in paragraph (1), the Commissioner of Social Security shall—(A) require th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Commissioner of Social Security determines that the interest of any qualified individual under this subchapter would be served thereby, payment of the qualified individual’s benefit under this subchapter may be made, regardless of the legal competency or incompetency of the qualified individual, either directly to the qualified individual, or for his or her use and benefit, to another person (the meaning of which term, for purposes of this section, includes an organization) with respect to whom the requirements of subsection (b) have been met (in this section referred to as the qualified individual’s “representative payee”). If the Commissioner of Social Security determines that a representative payee has misused any benefit paid to the representative payee pursuant to this section, 405(j) of this title, or section 1383(a)(2) of this title, the Commissioner of Social Security shall promptly revoke the person’s designation as the qualified individual’s representati</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of fitness of prospective representative payee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Examination of fitness of prospective representative payee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for maintaining lists of undesirable payees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement for maintaining lists of undesirable payees The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish and maintain lists which shall be updated periodically and which shall be in a form that renders such lists available to the servicing offices of the Social Security Administration. The lists shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons ineligible to serve as representative payees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Persons ineligible to serve as representative payees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deferral of payment pending appointment of representative payee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deferral of payment pending appointment of representative payee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hearing Any qualified individual who is dissatisfied with a determination by the Commissioner of Social Security to make payment of the qualified individual’s benefit to a representative payee under subsection (a) of this section or with the designation of a particular person to serve as representative payee shall be entitled to a hearing by the Commissioner of Social Security to the same extent as is provided in section 1009(a) of this title, and to judicial review of the Commissioner of Social Security’s final decision as is provided in section 1009(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notice requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Accountability monitoring</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restitution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Restitution In any case where the negligent failure of the Commissioner of Social Security to investigate or monitor a representative payee results in misuse of benefits by the representative payee, the Commissioner of Social Security shall make payment to the qualified individual or the individual’s alternative representative payee of an amount equal to the misused benefits. In any case in which a representative payee that— misuses all or part of an individual’s benefit paid to such representative payee, the Commissioner of Social Security shall pay to the beneficiary or the beneficiary’s alternative representative payee an amount equal to the amount of such benefit so misused. The provisions of this paragraph are subject to the limitations of subsection (l)(2). The Commissioner of Social Security shall make a good faith effort to obtain restitution from the terminated representative payee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1007_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Misuse of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Misuse of benefits For purposes of this subchapter, misuse of benefits by a representative payee occurs in any case in which the representative payee receives payment under this subchapter for the use and benefit of another person under this subchapter and converts such payment, or any part thereof, to a use other than for the use and benefit of such person. The Commissioner of Social Security may prescribe by regulation the meaning of the term “use and benefit” for purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>