<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10134"><akn:num>10134</akn:num><akn:heading>Site approval and construction authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10134. Site approval and construction authorization(a) Hearings and Presidential recommendation(1) The Secretary shall hold public hearings in the vicinity of the Yucca Mountain site, for the purposes of informing the residents of the area of such consideration and receiving their comments regarding the possible recommendation of such site. If, upon completion of such hearings and completion of site characterization activities at the Yucca Mountain site, under section 10133 of this title, the Secretary decides to recommend approval of such site to the President, the Secretary shall notify the Governor and legislature of the State of Nevada, of such decision. No sooner than the expiration of the 30-day period following such notification, the Secretary shall submit to the President a recommendation that the President approve such site for the development of a repository. Any such recommendation by the Secretary shall be based on the record of information developed by the Secretary under section 10133 of this title and this section, including the information described in subparagraph (A) through subparagraph (G). Together with any recommendation of a site under this paragraph, the Secretary shall make available to the public, and submit to the President, a comprehensive statement of the basis of such recommendation, including the following:(A) a description of the proposed repository, including preliminary engineering specifications for the facility;

(B) a description of the waste form or packaging proposed for use at such repository, and an explanation of the relationship between such waste form or packaging and the geologic medium of such site;

(C) a discussion of data, obtained in site characterization activities, relating to the safety of such site;

(D) a final environmental impact statement prepared for the Yucca Mountain site pursuant to subsection (f) and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), together with comments made con</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings and Presidential recommendation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hearings and Presidential recommendation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission of application If the President recommends to the Congress the Yucca Mountain site under subsection (a) and the site designation is permitted to take effect under section 10135 of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Commission an application for a construction authorization for a repository at such site not later than 90 days after the date on which the recommendation of the site designation is effective under such section and shall provide to the Governor and legislature of the State of Nevada a copy of such application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status report on application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status report on application Not later than 1 year after the date on which an application for a construction authorization is submitted under subsection (b), and annually thereafter until the date on which such authorization is granted, the Commission shall submit a report to the Congress describing the proceedings undertaken through the date of such report with regard to such application, including a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Commission action The Commission shall consider an application for a construction authorization for all or part of a repository in accordance with the laws applicable to such applications, except that the Commission shall issue a final decision approving or disapproving the issuance of a construction authorization not later than the expiration of 3 years after the date of the submission of such application, except that the Commission may extend such deadline by not more than 12 months if, not less than 30 days before such deadline, the Commission complies with the reporting requirements established in subsection (e)(2). The Commission decision approving the first such application shall prohibit the emplacement in the first repository of a quantity of spent fuel containing in excess of 70,000 metric tons of heavy metal or a quantity of solidified high-level radioactive waste resulting from the reprocessing of such a quantity of spent fuel until such time as a second repository is in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project decision schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Project decision schedule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10134_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Environmental impact statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>