<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10156" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10156/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10156/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10156"><akn:num>10156</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim Storage Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10156. Interim Storage Fund(a) Contracts(1) During the period following January 7, 1983, but not later than January 1, 1990, the Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts with persons who generate or own spent nuclear fuel resulting from civilian nuclear activities for the storage of such spent nuclear fuel in any storage capacity provided under this part: Provided, however, That the Secretary shall not enter into contracts for spent nuclear fuel in amounts in excess of the available storage capacity specified in section 10155(a) of this title. Those contracts shall provide that the Federal Government will (1) take title at the civilian nuclear power reactor site, to such amounts of spent nuclear fuel from the civilian nuclear power reactor as the Commission determines cannot be stored onsite, (2) transport the spent nuclear fuel to a federally owned and operated interim away-from-reactor storage facility, and (3) store such fuel in the facility pending further processing, storage, or disposal. Each such contract shall (A) provide for payment to the Secretary of fees determined in accordance with the provisions of this section; and (B) specify the amount of storage capacity to be provided for the person involved.

(2) The Secretary shall undertake a study and, not later than 180 days after January 7, 1983, submit to the Congress a report, establishing payment charges that shall be calculated on an annual basis, commencing on or before January 1, 1984. Such payment charges and the calculation thereof shall be published in the Federal Register, and shall become effective not less than 30 days after publication. Each payment charge published in the Federal Register under this paragraph shall remain effective for a period of 12 months from the effective date as the charge for the cost of the interim storage of any spent nuclear fuel. The report of the Secretary shall specify the method and manner of collection (including the rates and manner of payment) and any </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation No spent nuclear fuel generated or owned by any department of the United States referred to in section 101 or 102 of title 5 may be stored by the Secretary in any storage capacity provided under this part unless such department transfers to the Secretary, for deposit in the Interim Storage Fund, amounts equivalent to the fees that would be paid to the Secretary under the contracts referred to in this section if such spent nuclear fuel were generated by any other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Interim Storage Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Establishment of Interim Storage Fund There hereby is established in the Treasury of the United States a separate fund, to be known as the Interim Storage Fund. The Storage Fund shall consist of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Storage Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of Storage Fund The Secretary may make expenditures from the Storage Fund, subject to subsection (e), for any purpose necessary or appropriate to the conduct of the functions and activities of the Secretary, or the provision or anticipated provision of services, under this part, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Impact assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10156_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of Storage Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administration of Storage Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>