<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10161" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10161/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10161/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10161"><akn:num>10161</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitored retrievable storage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10161. Monitored retrievable storage(a) FindingsThe Congress finds that—(1) long-term storage of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel in monitored retrievable storage facilities is an option for providing safe and reliable management of such waste or spent fuel;

(2) the executive branch and the Congress should proceed as expeditiously as possible to consider fully a proposal for construction of one or more monitored retrievable storage facilities to provide such long-term storage;

(3) the Federal Government has the responsibility to ensure that site-specific designs for such facilities are available as provided in this section;

(4) the generators and owners of the high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel to be stored in such facilities have the responsibility to pay the costs of the long-term storage of such waste and spent fuel; and

(5) disposal of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel in a repository developed under this chapter should proceed regardless of any construction of a monitored retrievable storage facility pursuant to this section.


(b) Submission of proposal by Secretary(1) On or before June 1, 1985, the Secretary shall complete a detailed study of the need for and feasibility of, and shall submit to the Congress a proposal for, the construction of one or more monitored retrievable storage facilities for high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel. Each such facility shall be designed—(A) to accommodate spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste resulting from civilian nuclear activities;

(B) to permit continuous monitoring, management, and maintenance of such spent fuel and waste for the foreseeable future;

(C) to provide for the ready retrieval of such spent fuel and waste for further processing or disposal; and

(D) to safely store such spent fuel and waste as long as may be necessary by maintaining such facility through appropriate means, including any required replacement of such fac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of proposal by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission of proposal by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Environmental impact statements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Licensing Any facility authorized pursuant to this section shall be subject to licensing under section 5842(3) of this title. In reviewing the application filed by the Secretary for licensing of the first such facility, the Commission may not consider the need for such facility or any alternative to the design criteria for such facility set forth in subsection (b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Clarification Nothing in this section limits the consideration of alternative facility designs consistent with the criteria of paragraph (b)(1) in any environmental impact statement, or in any licensing procedure of the Commission, with respect to any monitored, retrievable facility authorized pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impact assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Impact assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation No monitored retrievable storage facility developed pursuant to this section may be constructed in any State in which there is located any site approved for site characterization under section 10132 of this title. The restriction in the preceding sentence shall only apply until such time as the Secretary decides that such candidate site is no longer a candidate site under consideration for development as a repository. Such restriction shall continue to apply to any site selected for construction as a repository.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10161_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of States and Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Participation of States and Indian tribes Any facility authorized pursuant to this section shall be subject to the provisions of sections 10135, 10136(a), 10136(b), 10136(d), 10137, and 10138 of this title. For purposes of carrying out the provisions of this subsection, any reference in sections 10135 through 10138 of this title to a repository shall be considered to refer to a monitored retrievable storage facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>