<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10168" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10168/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10168/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10168"><akn:num>10168</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10168. Construction authorization(a) Environmental impact statement(1) Once the selection of a site is effective under section 10166 of this title, the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.) shall apply with respect to construction of a monitored retrievable storage facility, except that any environmental impact statement prepared with respect to such facility shall not be required to consider the need for such facility or any alternative to the design criteria for such facility set forth in section 10161(b)(1) of this title.

(2) Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the consideration of alternative facility designs consistent with the criteria described in section 10161(b)(1) of this title in any environmental impact statement, or in any licensing procedure of the Commission, with respect to any monitored retrievable storage facility authorized under section 10162(b) of this title.


(b) Application for construction licenseOnce the selection of a site for a monitored retrievable storage facility is effective under section 10166 of this title, the Secretary may submit an application to the Commission for a license to construct such a facility as part of an integrated nuclear waste management system and in accordance with the provisions of this section and applicable agreements under this chapter affecting such facility.


(c) LicensingAny monitored retrievable storage facility authorized pursuant to section 10162(b) of this title shall be subject to licensing under section 5842(3) of this title. In reviewing the application filed by the Secretary for licensing of such facility, the Commission may not consider the need for such facility or any alternative to the design criteria for such facility set forth in section 10161(b)(1) of this title.


(d) Licensing conditionsAny license issued by the Commission for a monitored retrievable storage facility under this section shall provide that—(1) construction </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10168_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental impact statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10168_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for construction license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application for construction license Once the selection of a site for a monitored retrievable storage facility is effective under section 10166 of this title, the Secretary may submit an application to the Commission for a license to construct such a facility as part of an integrated nuclear waste management system and in accordance with the provisions of this section and applicable agreements under this chapter affecting such facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10168_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Licensing Any monitored retrievable storage facility authorized pursuant to section 10162(b) of this title shall be subject to licensing under section 5842(3) of this title. In reviewing the application filed by the Secretary for licensing of such facility, the Commission may not consider the need for such facility or any alternative to the design criteria for such facility set forth in section 10161(b)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10168_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Licensing conditions Any license issued by the Commission for a monitored retrievable storage facility under this section shall provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>