<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10163" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10163/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10163/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10163"><akn:num>10163</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitored Retrievable Storage Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10163. Monitored Retrievable Storage Commission(a) 11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. Establishment(1)(A) There is established a Monitored Retrievable Storage Review Commission (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “MRS Commission”), that shall consist of 3 members who shall be appointed by and serve at the pleasure of the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives.

(B) Members of the MRS Commission shall be appointed not later than 30 days after December 22, 1987, from among persons who as a result of training, experience and attainments are exceptionally well qualified to evaluate the need for a monitored retrievable storage facility as a part of the Nation’s nuclear waste management system.

(C) The MRS Commission shall prepare a report on the need for a monitored retrievable storage facility as a part of a national nuclear waste management system that achieves the purposes of this chapter. In preparing the report under this subparagraph, the MRS Commission shall—(i) review the status and adequacy of the Secretary’s evaluation of the systems advantages and disadvantages of bringing such a facility into the national nuclear waste disposal system;

(ii) obtain comment and available data on monitored retrievable storage from affected parties, including States containing potentially acceptable sites;

(iii) evaluate the utility of a monitored retrievable storage facility from a technical perspective; and

(iv) make a recommendation to Congress as to whether such a facility should be included in the national nuclear waste management system in order to achieve the purposes of this chapter, including meeting needs for packaging and handling of spent nuclear fuel, improving the flexibility of the repository development schedule, and providing temporary storage of spent nuclear fuel accepted for disposal.



(2) In preparing the report and making its recommendation under paragraph (1) the MRS Commissio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10163_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>