<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10173b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10173b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10173b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10173b"><akn:num>10173b</akn:num><akn:heading>Review Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10173b. Review Panel(a) In generalThe Review Panel required to be established by section 10173a(b)(1) of this title shall consist of a Chairman selected by the Secretary in consultation with the Governor of the State or governing body of the Indian tribe, as appropriate, that is party to such agreement and 6 other members as follows:(1) 2 members selected by the Governor of such State or governing body of such Indian tribe;

(2) 2 members selected by units of local government affected by the repository or monitored retrievable storage facility;

(3) 1 member to represent persons making payments into the Waste Fund, to be selected by the Secretary; and

(4) 1 member to represent other public interests, to be selected by the Secretary.


(b) Terms(1) The members of the Review Panel shall serve for terms of 4 years each.

(2) Members of the Review Panel who are not full-time employees of the Federal Government, shall receive a per diem compensation for each day spent conducting work of the Review Panel, including their necessary travel or other expenses while engaged in the work of the Review Panel.

(3) Expenses of the Panel shall be paid by the Secretary from the Waste Fund.


(c) DutiesThe Review Panel shall—(1) advise the Secretary on matters relating to the proposed repository or monitored retrievable storage facility, including issues relating to design, construction, operation, and decommissioning of the facility;

(2) evaluate performance of the repository or monitored retrievable storage facility, as it considers appropriate;

(3) recommend corrective actions to the Secretary;

(4) assist in the presentation of State or affected Indian tribe and local perspectives to the Secretary; and

(5) participate in the planning for and the review of preoperational data on environmental, demographic, and socioeconomic conditions of the site and the local community.


(d) InformationThe Secretary shall promptly 11 So in original. make available promptly 1 any informatio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10173b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Review Panel required to be established by section 10173a(b)(1) of this title shall consist of a Chairman selected by the Secretary in consultation with the Governor of the State or governing body of the Indian tribe, as appropriate, that is party to such agreement and 6 other members as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10173b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10173b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Review Panel shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10173b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information The Secretary shall promptly 11 So in original. make available promptly 1 any information in the Secretary’s possession requested by the Panel or its Chairman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10173b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chapter 10 of title 5 The requirements of chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to a Review Panel established under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>