<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10174a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10174a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10174a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10174a"><akn:num>10174a</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10174a. Report(a) In generalWithin one year of December 22, 1987, the Secretary shall report to Congress on the potential impacts of locating a repository at the Yucca Mountain site, including the recommendations of the Secretary for mitigation of such impacts and a statement of which impacts should be dealt with by the Federal Government, which should be dealt with by the State with State resources, including the benefits payments under section 10173a of this title, and which should be a joint Federal-State responsibility. The report under this subsection shall include the analysis of the Secretary of the authorities available to mitigate these impacts and the appropriate sources of funds for such mitigation.


(b) Impacts to be consideredPotential impacts to be addressed in the report under this 11 So in original. The word “this” probably should not appear. subsection (a) shall include impacts on—(1) education, including facilities and personnel for elementary and secondary schools, community colleges, vocational and technical schools and universities;

(2) public health, including the facilities and personnel for treatment and distribution of water, the treatment of sewage, the control of pests and the disposal of solid waste;

(3) law enforcement, including facilities and personnel for the courts, police and sheriff’s departments, district attorneys and public defenders and prisons;

(4) fire protection, including personnel, the construction of fire stations, and the acquisition of equipment;

(5) medical care, including emergency services and hospitals;

(6) cultural and recreational needs, including facilities and personnel for libraries and museums and the acquisition and expansion of parks;

(7) distribution of public lands to allow for the timely expansion of existing, or creation of new, communities and the construction of necessary residential and commercial facilities;

(8) vocational training and employment services;

(9) social services, including pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10174a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Within one year of December 22, 1987, the Secretary shall report to Congress on the potential impacts of locating a repository at the Yucca Mountain site, including the recommendations of the Secretary for mitigation of such impacts and a statement of which impacts should be dealt with by the Federal Government, which should be dealt with by the State with State resources, including the benefits payments under section 10173a of this title, and which should be a joint Federal-State responsibility. The report under this subsection shall include the analysis of the Secretary of the authorities available to mitigate these impacts and the appropriate sources of funds for such mitigation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10174a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Impacts to be considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Impacts to be considered Potential impacts to be addressed in the report under this 11 So in original. The word “this” probably should not appear. subsection (a) shall include impacts on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>