<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10197" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10197/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10197/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10197"><akn:num>10197</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development on disposal of high-level radioactive waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10197. Research and development on disposal of high-level radioactive waste(a) PurposeNot later than 64 months after January 7, 1983, the Secretary is authorized to, to the extent practicable, begin at a site evaluated under section 10194 of this title, as part of and as an extension of siting research activities of such site under such section, the mining and construction of a test and evaluation facility. Prior to the mining and construction of such facility, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment. The purpose of such facility shall be—(1) to supplement and focus the repository site characterization process;

(2) to provide the conditions under which known technological components can be integrated to demonstrate a functioning repository-like system;

(3) to provide a means of identifying, evaluating, and resolving potential repository licensing issues that could not be resolved during the siting research program conducted under section 10192 11 So in original. Probably should be “10194”. of this title;

(4) to validate, under actual conditions, the scientific models used in the design of a repository;

(5) to refine the design and engineering of repository components and systems and to confirm the predicted behavior of such components and systems;

(6) to supplement the siting data, the generic and specific geological characteristics developed under section 10194 of this title relating to isolating disposal materials in the physical environment of a repository;

(7) to evaluate the design concepts for packaging, handling, and emplacement of high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel at the design rate; and

(8) to establish operating capability without exposing workers to excessive radiation.


(b) DesignThe Secretary shall design each test and evaluation facility—(1) to be capable of receiving not more than 100 full-sized canisters of solidified high-level radioactive waste (which canisters shall not exceed an aggregate weight of 100 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose Not later than 64 months after January 7, 1983, the Secretary is authorized to, to the extent practicable, begin at a site evaluated under section 10194 of this title, as part of and as an extension of siting research activities of such site under such section, the mining and construction of a test and evaluation facility. Prior to the mining and construction of such facility, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment. The purpose of such facility shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Design The Secretary shall design each test and evaluation facility—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of existing Department facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of existing Department facilities During the conducting of siting research activities under section 10194 of this title and for such period thereafter as the Secretary considers appropriate, the Secretary shall use Department facilities owned by the Federal Government on January 7, 1983, for the conducting of generically applicable tests regarding packaging, handling, and emplacement technology for solidified high-level radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel from civilian nuclear activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Engineered barriers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Engineered barriers The system of engineered barriers and selected geology used in a test and evaluation facility shall have a design life at least as long as that which the Commission requires by regulations issued under this chapter, or under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), for repositories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Role of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Role of Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental review The Secretary shall prepare an environmental impact statement under section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(2)(C)) prior to conducting tests with radioactive materials at the test and evaluation facility. Such environmental impact statement shall incorporate, to the extent practicable, the environmental assessment prepared under subsection (a). Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit siting research activities conducted under section 10194 of this title. This subsection shall apply only to activities performed exclusively for a test and evaluation facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10197_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>