<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10198" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10198/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10198/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10198"><akn:num>10198</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development on spent nuclear fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10198. Research and development on spent nuclear fuel(a) Demonstration and cooperative programsThe Secretary shall establish a demonstration program, in cooperation with the private sector, for the dry storage of spent nuclear fuel at civilian nuclear power reactor sites, with the objective of establishing one or more technologies that the Commission may, by rule, approve for use at the sites of civilian nuclear power reactors without, to the maximum extent practicable, the need for additional site-specific approvals by the Commission. Not later than 1 year after January 7, 1983, the Secretary shall select at least 1, but not more than 3, sites evaluated under section 10194 of this title at such power reactors. In selecting such site or sites, the Secretary shall give preference to civilian nuclear power reactors that will soon have a shortage of interim storage capacity for spent nuclear fuel. Subject to reaching agreement as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary shall undertake activities to assist such power reactors with demonstration projects at such sites, which may use one of the following types of alternate storage technologies: spent nuclear fuel storage casks, caissons, or silos. The Secretary shall also undertake a cooperative program with civilian nuclear power reactors to encourage the development of the technology for spent nuclear fuel rod consolidation in existing power reactor water storage basins.


(b) Cooperative agreementsTo carry out the programs described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with each utility involved that specifies, at a minimum, that—(1) such utility shall select the alternate storage technique to be used, make the land and spent nuclear fuel available for the dry storage demonstration, submit and provide site-specific documentation for a license application to the Commission, obtain a license relating to the facility involved, construct such facility, operate such facility after li</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10198_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration and cooperative programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Demonstration and cooperative programs The Secretary shall establish a demonstration program, in cooperation with the private sector, for the dry storage of spent nuclear fuel at civilian nuclear power reactor sites, with the objective of establishing one or more technologies that the Commission may, by rule, approve for use at the sites of civilian nuclear power reactors without, to the maximum extent practicable, the need for additional site-specific approvals by the Commission. Not later than 1 year after January 7, 1983, the Secretary shall select at least 1, but not more than 3, sites evaluated under section 10194 of this title at such power reactors. In selecting such site or sites, the Secretary shall give preference to civilian nuclear power reactors that will soon have a shortage of interim storage capacity for spent nuclear fuel. Subject to reaching agreement as provided in subsection (b), the Secretary shall undertake activities to assist such power reactors with demonst</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10198_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cooperative agreements To carry out the programs described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement with each utility involved that specifies, at a minimum, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10198_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dry storage research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dry storage research and development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10198_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding The total contribution from the Secretary from Federal funds and the use of Federal facilities or services shall not exceed 25 percent of the total costs of the demonstration program authorized in subsection (a), as estimated by the Secretary. All remaining costs of such program shall be paid by the utilities involved or shall be provided by the Secretary from the Interim Storage Fund established in section 10156 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10198_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to spent nuclear fuel storage program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relation to spent nuclear fuel storage program The spent nuclear fuel storage program authorized in section 10155 of this title shall not be construed to authorize the use of research development or demonstration facilities owned by the Department unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>