<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10244" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10244/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10244/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10244"><akn:num>10244</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessment of sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10244. Environmental assessment of sites(a) In generalUpon the request of the Negotiator, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment of any site that is the subject of negotiations under section 10243(a) of this title.


(b) Contents(1) Each environmental assessment prepared for a repository site shall include a detailed statement of the probable impacts of characterizing such site and the construction and operation of a repository at such site.

(2) Each environmental assessment prepared for a monitored retrievable storage facility site shall include a detailed statement of the probable impacts of construction and operation of such a facility at such site.


(c) Judicial reviewThe issuance of an environmental assessment under subsection (a) shall be considered to be a final agency action subject to judicial review in accordance with the provisions of chapter 7 of title 5 and section 10139 of this title.


(d) Public hearings(1) In preparing an environmental assessment for any repository or monitored retrievable storage facility site, the Secretary shall hold public hearings in the vicinity of such site to inform the residents of the area in which such site is located that such site is being considered and to receive their comments.

(2) At such hearings, the Secretary shall solicit and receive any recommendations of such residents with respect to issues that should be addressed in the environmental assessment required under subsection (a) and the site characterization plan described in section 10133(b)(1) of this title.


(e) Public availabilityEach environmental assessment prepared under subsection (a) shall be made available to the public.


(f) Evaluation of sites(1) In preparing an environmental assessment under subsection (a), the Secretary shall use available geophysical, geologic, geochemical and hydrologic, and other information and shall not conduct any preliminary borings or excavations at any site that is the subject of such assessment unl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Upon the request of the Negotiator, the Secretary shall prepare an environmental assessment of any site that is the subject of negotiations under section 10243(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Judicial review The issuance of an environmental assessment under subsection (a) shall be considered to be a final agency action subject to judicial review in accordance with the provisions of chapter 7 of title 5 and section 10139 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public availability Each environmental assessment prepared under subsection (a) shall be made available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10244_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of sites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluation of sites</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>