<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10364" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10364/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10364/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10364"><akn:num>10364</akn:num><akn:heading>Water management improvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10364. Water management improvement(a) Authorization of grants and cooperative agreements(1) Authority of SecretaryThe Secretary may provide any grant to, or enter into an agreement with, any eligible applicant to assist the eligible applicant in planning, designing, or constructing any improvement or carrying out any activity—(A) to conserve water;

(B) to increase water use efficiency;

(C) to facilitate water markets;

(D) to enhance water management, including increasing the use of renewable energy in the management and delivery of water;

(E) to accelerate the adoption and use of advanced water treatment technologies to increase water supply;

(F) to assist States and water users in complying with interstate compacts or reducing basin water supply-demand imbalances;

(G) to achieve the prevention of the decline of species that the United States Fish and Wildlife Service and National Marine Fisheries Service have proposed for listing under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.) (or candidate species that are being considered by those agencies for such listing but are not yet the subject of a proposed rule);

(H) to achieve the acceleration of the recovery of threatened species, endangered species, and designated critical habitats that are adversely affected by Federal reclamation projects or are subject to a recovery plan or conservation plan under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.) under which the Commissioner of Reclamation has implementation responsibilities;

(I) to improve the condition of a natural feature; or

(J) to carry out any other activity—(i) to address any climate-related impact to the water supply of the United States that increases ecological resiliency to the impacts of climate change;

(ii) to prevent any water-related crisis or conflict at any watershed that has a nexus to a Federal reclamation project located in a service area; or

(iii) to plan for or address the impacts of drought.



(2) App</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10364_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of grants and cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10364_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10364_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mutual benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mutual benefit Grants or other agreements made under this section may be for the mutual benefit of the United States and the entity that is provided the grant or enters into the cooperative agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10364_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to project-specific authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to project-specific authority This section shall not supersede any existing project-specific funding authority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10364_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $920,000,000, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>