<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10408" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10408/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10408/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10408"><akn:num>10408</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants and uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10408. Subgrants and uses of funds(a) SubgrantsA State that receives a grant under section 10406(a) of this title shall use grant funds described in section 10406(b)(2) of this title to provide subgrants to eligible entities for programs and projects within such State, that is 11 So in original. Probably should be “are”. designed to prevent incidents of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence by providing immediate shelter and supportive services for adult and youth victims of family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence (and their dependents), and that may provide prevention services to prevent future incidents of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence.


(b) Use of funds(1) In generalFunds awarded to eligible entities under subsection (a) shall be used to provide shelter, supportive services, or prevention services to adult and youth victims of family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence, and their dependents, which may include—(A) provision, on a regular basis, of immediate shelter and related supportive services to adult and youth victims of family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence, and their dependents, including paying for the operating and administrative expenses of the facilities for such shelter;

(B) assistance in developing safety plans, and supporting efforts of victims of family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence to make decisions related to their ongoing safety and well-being;

(C) provision of individual and group counseling, peer support groups, and referral to community-based services to assist family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence victims, and their dependents, in recovering from the effects of the violence;

(D) provision of services, training, technical assistance, and outreach to increase awareness of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence and increase the accessibility of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10408_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subgrants A State that receives a grant under section 10406(a) of this title shall use grant funds described in section 10406(b)(2) of this title to provide subgrants to eligible entities for programs and projects within such State, that is 11 So in original. Probably should be “are”. designed to prevent incidents of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence by providing immediate shelter and supportive services for adult and youth victims of family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence (and their dependents), and that may provide prevention services to prevent future incidents of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10408_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10408_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities To be eligible to receive a subgrant from a State under this section, an entity shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10408_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>