<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10403"><akn:num>10403</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10403. Authorization of appropriations(a) Formula grants to States(1) In generalThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out sections 10401 through 10412 of this title, $175,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015.


(2) Allocations(A) Formula grants to States(i) Reservation of fundsFor any fiscal year for which the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) exceed $130,000,000, not less than 25 percent of such excess funds shall be made available to carry out section 10412 of this title.


(ii) Formula grantsOf the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and not reserved under clause (i), not less than 70 percent shall be used for making grants under section 10406(a) of this title.



(B) Grants to tribesOf the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and not reserved under subparagraph (A)(i), not less than 10 percent shall be used to carry out section 10409 of this title.


(C) Technical assistance and training centersOf the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and not reserved under subparagraph (A)(i), not less than 6 percent shall be used by the Secretary for making grants under section 10410 of this title.


(D) Grants for State Domestic Violence CoalitionsOf the amounts appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and not reserved under subparagraph (A)(i), not less than 10 percent of such amounts shall be used by the Secretary for making grants under section 10411 of this title.


(E) Administration, evaluation and monitoringOf the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year and not reserved under subparagraph (A)(i), not more than 2.5 percent shall be used by the Secretary for evaluation, monitoring, and other administrative costs under this chapter.




(b) National domestic violence hotlineThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 10413 of this title $3,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015.


(c) Domestic Violence Prevention En</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula grants to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Formula grants to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National domestic violence hotline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National domestic violence hotline There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 10413 of this title $3,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic Violence Prevention Enhancement and Leadership Through Alliances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Domestic Violence Prevention Enhancement and Leadership Through Alliances There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out section 10414 of this title $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional funding For the purposes of carrying out this chapter, in addition to amounts otherwise made available for such purposes, there are appropriated, out of any amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for fiscal year 2021, to remain available until expended except as otherwise provided in this subsection, each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>