<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10410" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10410/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10410/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10410"><akn:num>10410</akn:num><akn:heading>National resource centers and training and technical assistance centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10410. National resource centers and training and technical assistance centers(a) Purpose and grants authorized(1) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide resource information, training, and technical assistance relating to the objectives of this chapter to improve the capacity of individuals, organizations, governmental entities, and communities to prevent family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence and to provide effective intervention services.


(2) Grants authorizedFrom the amounts appropriated under this chapter and reserved under section 10403(a)(2)(C) of this title, the Secretary—(A) shall award grants to eligible entities for the establishment and maintenance of—(i) 2 national resource centers (as provided for in subsection (b)(1)); and

(ii) at least 7 special issue resource centers addressing key areas of domestic violence, and intervention and prevention (as provided for in subsection (b)(2)); and


(B) may award grants, to—(i) State resource centers to reduce disparities in domestic violence in States with high proportions of Indian (including Alaska Native) or Native Hawaiian populations (as provided for in subsection (b)(3)); and

(ii) support training and technical assistance that address emerging issues related to family violence, domestic violence, or dating violence, to entities demonstrating related expertise.




(b) Domestic violence resource centers(1) National resource centersIn accordance with subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities for—(A) a National Resource Center on Domestic Violence, which shall—(i) offer a comprehensive array of technical assistance and training resources to Federal, State, and local governmental agencies, domestic violence service providers, community-based organizations, and other professionals and interested parties, related to domestic violence service programs and research, including programs and research related to victims and their children who are exposed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10410_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose and grants authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10410_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic violence resource centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Domestic violence resource centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10410_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10410_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports and evaluation Each entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit a performance report to the Secretary annually and in such manner as shall be reasonably required by the Secretary. Such performance report shall describe the activities that have been carried out with such grant funds, contain an evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities, and provide such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>