<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10411" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10411/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10411/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10411"><akn:num>10411</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to State Domestic Violence Coalitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10411. Grants to State Domestic Violence Coalitions(a) GrantsThe Secretary shall award grants for the funding of State Domestic Violence Coalitions.


(b) Allotment of funds(1) In generalFrom the amount appropriated under section 10403(a)(2)(D) of this title for each fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each of the covered territories an amount equal to 1⁄56 of the amount so appropriated for such fiscal year.


(2) DefinitionFor purposes of this subsection, the term “covered territories” means Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.



(c) ApplicationEach State Domestic Violence Coalition desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be essential to carry out the objectives of this section. The application submitted by the coalition for the grant shall provide documentation of the coalition’s work, satisfactory to the Secretary, demonstrating that the coalition—(1) meets all of the applicable requirements set forth in this chapter; and

(2) demonstrates the ability to conduct appropriately all activities described in this section, as indicated by—(A) documented experience in administering Federal grants to conduct the activities described in subsection (d); or

(B) a documented history of active participation in the activities described in paragraphs (1), (3), (4), and (5) of subsection (d) and a demonstrated capacity to conduct the activities described in subsection (d)(2).



(d) Use of fundsA coalition that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds for administration and operations to further the purposes of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence intervention and prevention, through activities that shall include—(1) working with local family</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants The Secretary shall award grants for the funding of State Domestic Violence Coalitions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allotment of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application Each State Domestic Violence Coalition desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be essential to carry out the objectives of this section. The application submitted by the coalition for the grant shall provide documentation of the coalition’s work, satisfactory to the Secretary, demonstrating that the coalition—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds A coalition that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds for administration and operations to further the purposes of family violence, domestic violence, and dating violence intervention and prevention, through activities that shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on use of funds A coalition that receives a grant under this section shall not be required to use funds received under this chapter for the purposes described in paragraph (5) or (6) of subsection (d) if the coalition provides an annual assurance to the Secretary that the coalition is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on lobbying</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibition on lobbying No funds made available to entities under this section shall be used, directly or indirectly, to influence the issuance, amendment, or revocation of any executive order or similar promulgation by any Federal, State, or local agency, or to undertake to influence the passage or defeat of any legislation by Congress, or by any State or local legislative body, or State proposals by initiative petition, except that the representatives of the entity may testify or make other appropriate communication—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports and evaluation Each entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit a performance report to the Secretary at such time as shall be reasonably required by the Secretary. Such performance report shall describe the activities that have been carried out with such grant funds, contain an evaluation of the effectiveness of such activities, and provide such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10411_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Indian representatives For purposes of this section, a State Domestic Violence Coalition may include representatives of Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>