<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10710" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10710/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10710/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10710"><akn:num>10710</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10710. Records and reports(a) ReportsThe Institute is authorized to require such reports as it deems necessary from any recipient with respect to activities carried out pursuant to this chapter.


(b) RecordsThe Institute is authorized to prescribe the keeping of records with respect to funds provided by any grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this chapter and shall have access to such records at all reasonable times for the purpose of ensuring compliance with such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract or the terms and conditions upon which financial assistance was provided.


(c) Submission of copies of reports to recipients; maintenance in principal office of Institute; availability for public inspection; furnishing of copies to interested partiesCopies of all reports pertinent to the evaluation, inspection, or monitoring of any recipient shall be submitted on a timely basis to such recipient, and shall be maintained in the principal office of the Institute for a period of at least five years after such evaluation, inspection, or monitoring. Such reports shall be available for public inspection during regular business hours, and copies shall be furnished, upon request, to interested parties upon payment of such reasonable fees as the Institute may establish.


(d) Funds accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal fundsNon-Federal funds received by the Institute, and funds received for projects funded in part by the Institute or by any recipient from a source other than the Institute, shall be accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds.


(Pub. L. 98–620, title II, § 211, Nov. 8, 1984, 98 Stat. 3344.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 98–620, Nov. 8, 1984, 98 Stat. 3336, known as the State Justice Institute Act of 1984, which is clas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10710_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reports The Institute is authorized to require such reports as it deems necessary from any recipient with respect to activities carried out pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10710_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Records The Institute is authorized to prescribe the keeping of records with respect to funds provided by any grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under this chapter and shall have access to such records at all reasonable times for the purpose of ensuring compliance with such grant, cooperative agreement, or contract or the terms and conditions upon which financial assistance was provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10710_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of copies of reports to recipients; maintenance in principal office of Institute; availability for public inspection; furnishing of copies to interested parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission of copies of reports to recipients; maintenance in principal office of Institute; availability for public inspection; furnishing of copies to interested parties Copies of all reports pertinent to the evaluation, inspection, or monitoring of any recipient shall be submitted on a timely basis to such recipient, and shall be maintained in the principal office of the Institute for a period of at least five years after such evaluation, inspection, or monitoring. Such reports shall be available for public inspection during regular business hours, and copies shall be furnished, upon request, to interested parties upon payment of such reasonable fees as the Institute may establish.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10710_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funds accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds Non-Federal funds received by the Institute, and funds received for projects funded in part by the Institute or by any recipient from a source other than the Institute, shall be accounted for and reported as receipts and disbursements separate and distinct from Federal funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>