<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/10802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_10802"><akn:num>10802</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 10802. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) The term “abuse” means any act or failure to act by an employee of a facility rendering care or treatment which was performed, or which was failed to be performed, knowingly, recklessly, or intentionally, and which caused, or may have caused, injury or death to a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. individual with mental illness, and includes acts such as—(A) the rape or sexual assault of a 1 individual with mental illness;

(B) the striking of a 1 individual with mental illness;

(C) the use of excessive force when placing a 1 individual with mental illness in bodily restraints; and

(D) the use of bodily or chemical restraints on a 1 individual with mental illness which is not in compliance with Federal and State laws and regulations.


(2) The term “eligible system” means the system established in a State to protect and advocate the rights of persons with developmental disabilities under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.].

(3) The term “facilities” may include, but need not be limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, community facilities for individuals with mental illness, board and care homes, homeless shelters, and jails and prisons.

(4) The term “individual with mental illness” means, except as provided in section 10804(d) of this title, an individual—(A) who has a significant mental illness or emotional impairment, as determined by a mental health professional qualified under the laws and regulations of the State; and

(B)(i)(I) who is an inpatient or resident in a facility rendering care or treatment, even if the whereabouts of such inpatient or resident are unknown;

(II) who is in the process of being admitted to a facility rendering care or treatment, including persons being transported to such a facility; or”; 22 So in original.

(III) who is involuntarily confined in a municipal detention facility for reasons oth</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “abuse” means any act or failure to act by an employee of a facility rendering care or treatment which was performed, or which was failed to be performed, knowingly, recklessly, or intentionally, and which caused, or may have caused, injury or death to a 11 So in original. Probably should be “an”. individual with mental illness, and includes acts such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “eligible system” means the system established in a State to protect and advocate the rights of persons with developmental disabilities under subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “facilities” may include, but need not be limited to, hospitals, nursing homes, community facilities for individuals with mental illness, board and care homes, homeless shelters, and jails and prisons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “individual with mental illness” means, except as provided in section 10804(d) of this title, an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “neglect” means a negligent act or omission by any individual responsible for providing services in a facility rendering care or treatment which caused or may have caused injury or death to a 1 individual with mental illness or which placed a 1 individual with mental illness at risk of injury or death, and includes an act or omission such as the failure to establish or carry out an appropriate individual program plan or treatment plan for a 1 individual with mental illness, the failure to provide adequate nutrition, clothing, or health care to a 1 individual with mental illness, or the failure to provide a safe environment for a 1 individual with mental illness, including the failure to maintain adequate numbers of appropriately trained staff.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_10802_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “American Indian consortium” means a consortium established under part C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act 33 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 6042 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>