<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11002" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11002/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11002/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11002"><akn:num>11002</akn:num><akn:heading>Substances and facilities covered and notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11002. Substances and facilities covered and notification(a) Substances covered(1) In generalA substance is subject to the requirements of this subchapter if the substance is on the list published under paragraph (2).


(2) List of extremely hazardous substancesWithin 30 days after October 17, 1986, the Administrator shall publish a list of extremely hazardous substances. The list shall be the same as the list of substances published in November 1985 by the Administrator in Appendix A of the “Chemical Emergency Preparedness Program Interim Guidance”.


(3) Thresholds(A) At the time the list referred to in paragraph (2) is published the Administrator shall—(i) publish an interim final regulation establishing a threshold planning quantity for each substance on the list, taking into account the criteria described in paragraph (4), and

(ii) initiate a rulemaking in order to publish final regulations establishing a threshold planning quantity for each substance on the list.


(B) The threshold planning quantities may, at the Administrator’s discretion, be based on classes of chemicals or categories of facilities.

(C) If the Administrator fails to publish an interim final regulation establishing a threshold planning quantity for a substance within 30 days after October 17, 1986, the threshold planning quantity for the substance shall be 2 pounds until such time as the Administrator publishes regulations establishing a threshold for the substance.


(4) RevisionsThe Administrator may revise the list and thresholds under paragraphs (2) and (3) from time to time. Any revisions to the list shall take into account the toxicity, reactivity, volatility, dispersability, combustability, or flammability of a substance. For purposes of the preceding sentence, the term “toxicity” shall include any short- or long-term health effect which may result from a short-term exposure to the substance.



(b) Facilities covered(1) Except as provided in section 11004 of this title, a facilit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11002_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substances covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Substances covered</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11002_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facilities covered</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11002_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency planning notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Emergency planning notification Not later than seven months after October 17, 1986, the owner or operator of each facility subject to the requirements of this subchapter by reason of subsection (b)(1) shall notify the State emergency response commission for the State in which such facility is located that such facility is subject to the requirements of this subchapter. Thereafter, if a substance on the list of extremely hazardous substances referred to in subsection (a) first becomes present at such facility in excess of the threshold planning quantity established for such substance, or if there is a revision of such list and the facility has present a substance on the revised list in excess of the threshold planning quantity established for such substance, the owner or operator of the facility shall notify the State emergency response commission and the local emergency planning committee within 60 days after such acquisition or revision that such facility is subject to the require</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11002_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notification of Administrator The State emergency response commission shall notify the Administrator of facilities subject to the requirements of this subchapter by notifying the Administrator of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>