<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11004"><akn:num>11004</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11004. Emergency notification(a) Types of releases(1) 11002(a) substance which requires CERCLA noticeIf a release of an extremely hazardous substance referred to in section 11002(a) of this title occurs from a facility at which a hazardous chemical is produced, used, or stored, and such release requires a notification under section 103(a) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 [42 U.S.C. 9603(a)] (hereafter in this section referred to as “CERCLA”) (42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.), the owner or operator of the facility shall immediately provide notice as described in subsection (b).


(2) Other 11002(a) substanceIf a release of an extremely hazardous substance referred to in section 11002(a) of this title occurs from a facility at which a hazardous chemical is produced, used, or stored, and such release is not subject to the notification requirements under section 103(a) of CERCLA [42 U.S.C. 9603(a)], the owner or operator of the facility shall immediately provide notice as described in subsection (b), but only if the release—(A) is not a federally permitted release as defined in section 101(10) of CERCLA [42 U.S.C. 9601(10)],

(B) is in an amount in excess of a quantity which the Administrator has determined (by regulation) requires notice, and

(C) occurs in a manner which would require notification under section 103(a) of CERCLA [42 U.S.C. 9603(a)].


Unless and until superseded by regulations establishing a quantity for an extremely hazardous substance described in this paragraph, a quantity of 1 pound shall be deemed that quantity the release of which requires notice as described in subsection (b).

(3) Non-11002(a) substance which requires CERCLA noticeIf a release of a substance which is not on the list referred to in section 11002(a) of this title occurs at a facility at which a hazardous chemical is produced, used, or stored, and such release requires notification under section 103(a) of CERCLA [42 U.S.C. 9603(a)], the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of releases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of releases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11004_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Followup emergency notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Followup emergency notice As soon as practicable after a release which requires notice under subsection (a), such owner or operator shall provide a written followup emergency notice (or notices, as more information becomes available) setting forth and updating the information required under subsection (b), and including additional information with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11004_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation exemption not applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transportation exemption not applicable The exemption provided in section 11047 of this title (relating to transportation) does not apply to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11004_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Addressing source water used for drinking water</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Addressing source water used for drinking water</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>