<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11021"><akn:num>11021</akn:num><akn:heading>Material safety data sheets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11021. Material safety data sheets(a) Basic requirement(1) Submission of MSDS or listThe owner or operator of any facility which is required to prepare or have available a material safety data sheet for a hazardous chemical under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act shall submit a material safety data sheet for each such chemical, or a list of such chemicals as described in paragraph (2), to each of the following:(A) The appropriate local emergency planning committee.

(B) The State emergency response commission.

(C) The fire department with jurisdiction over the facility.


(2) Contents of list(A) The list of chemicals referred to in paragraph (1) shall include each of the following:(i) A list of the hazardous chemicals for which a material safety data sheet is required under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act, grouped in categories of health and physical hazards as set forth under such Act and regulations promulgated under such Act, or in such other categories as the Administrator may prescribe under subparagraph (B).

(ii) The chemical name or the common name of each such chemical as provided on the material safety data sheet.

(iii) Any hazardous component of each such chemical as provided on the material safety data sheet.


(B) For purposes of the list under this paragraph, the Administrator may modify the categories of health and physical hazards as set forth under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act by requiring information to be reported in terms of groups of hazardous chemicals which present similar hazards in an emergency.


(3) Treatment of mixturesAn owner or operator may meet the requirements of this section with respect to a hazardous chemical which is a mixture by doing one of the following:(A) Submitting a material s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basic requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Thresholds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Thresholds The Administrator may establish threshold quantities for hazardous chemicals below which no facility shall be subject to the provisions of this section. The threshold quantities may, in the Administrator’s discretion, be based on classes of chemicals or categories of facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of MSDS on request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of MSDS on request</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial submission and updating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Initial submission and updating</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Hazardous chemical” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Hazardous chemical” defined For purposes of this section, the term “hazardous chemical” has the meaning given such term by section 1910.1200(c) of title 29 of the Code of Federal Regulations, except that such term does not include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>