<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11022" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11022/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11022/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11022"><akn:num>11022</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency and hazardous chemical inven­tory forms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11022. Emergency and hazardous chemical inven­tory forms(a) Basic requirement(1) The owner or operator of any facility which is required to prepare or have available a material safety data sheet for a hazardous chemical under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 [29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.] and regulations promulgated under that Act shall prepare and submit an emergency and hazardous chemical inventory form (hereafter in this chapter referred to as an “inventory form”) to each of the following:(A) The appropriate local emergency planning committee.

(B) The State emergency response commission.

(C) The fire department with jurisdiction over the facility.


(2) The inventory form containing tier I information (as described in subsection (d)(1)) shall be submitted on or before March 1, 1988, and annually thereafter on March 1, and shall contain data with respect to the preceding calendar year. The preceding sentence does not apply if an owner or operator provides, by the same deadline and with respect to the same calendar year, tier II information (as described in subsection (d)(2)) to the recipients described in paragraph (1).

(3) An owner or operator may meet the requirements of this section with respect to a hazardous chemical which is a mixture by doing one of the following:(A) Providing information on the inventory form on each element or compound in the mixture which is a hazardous chemical. If more than one mixture has the same element or compound, only one listing on the inventory form for the element or compound at the facility is necessary.

(B) Providing information on the inventory form on the mixture itself.



(b) ThresholdsThe Administrator may establish threshold quantities for hazardous chemicals covered by this section below which no facility shall be subject to the provisions of this section. The threshold quantities may, in the Administrator’s discretion, be based on classes of chemicals or categories of facilities.


(c) Hazardous chemical</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basic requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Thresholds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Thresholds The Administrator may establish threshold quantities for hazardous chemicals covered by this section below which no facility shall be subject to the provisions of this section. The threshold quantities may, in the Administrator’s discretion, be based on classes of chemicals or categories of facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous chemicals covered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hazardous chemicals covered A hazardous chemical subject to the requirements of this section is any hazardous chemical for which a material safety data sheet or a listing is required under section 11021 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contents of form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of tier II information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of tier II information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire department access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fire department access Upon request to an owner or operator of a facility which files an inventory form under this section by the fire department with jurisdiction over the facility, the owner or operator of the facility shall allow the fire department to conduct an on-site inspection of the facility and shall provide to the fire department specific location information on hazardous chemicals at the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11022_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Format of forms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Format of forms The Administrator shall publish a uniform format for inventory forms within three months after October 17, 1986. If the Administrator does not publish such forms, owners and operators of facilities subject to the requirements of this section shall provide the information required under this section by letter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>