<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11042" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11042/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11042/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11042"><akn:num>11042</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade secrets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11042. Trade secrets(a) Authority to withhold information(1) General authority(A) With regard to a hazardous chemical, an extremely hazardous substance, or a toxic chemical, any person required under section 11003(d)(2), 11003(d)(3), 11021, 11022, or 11023 of this title to submit information to any other person may withhold from such submittal the specific chemical identity (including the chemical name and other specific identification), as defined in regulations prescribed by the Administrator under subsection (c), if the person complies with paragraph (2).

(B) Any person withholding the specific chemical identity shall, in the place on the submittal where the chemical identity would normally be included, include the generic class or category of the hazardous chemical, extremely hazardous substance, or toxic chemical (as the case may be).


(2) Requirements(A) A person is entitled to withhold information under paragraph (1) if such person—(i) claims that such information is a trade secret, on the basis of the factors enumerated in subsection (b),

(ii) includes in the submittal referred to in paragraph (1) an explanation of the reasons why such information is claimed to be a trade secret, based on the factors enumerated in subsection (b), including a specific description of why such factors apply, and

(iii) submits to the Administrator a copy of such submittal, and the information withheld from such submittal.


(B) In submitting to the Administrator the information required by subparagraph (A)(iii), a person withholding information under this subsection may—(i) designate, in writing and in such manner as the Administrator may prescribe by regulation, the information which such person believes is entitled to be withheld under paragraph (1), and

(ii) submit such designated information separately from other information submitted under this subsection.



(3) LimitationThe authority under this subsection to withhold information shall not apply to information whic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to withhold information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to withhold information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade secret factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Trade secret factors No person required to provide information under this chapter may claim that the information is entitled to protection as a trade secret under subsection (a) unless such person shows each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trade secret regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Trade secret regulations As soon as practicable after October 17, 1986, the Administrator shall prescribe regulations to implement this section. With respect to subsection (b)(4), such regulations shall be equivalent to comparable provisions in the Occupational Safety and Health Administration Hazard Communication Standard (29 C.F.R. 1910.1200) and any revisions of such standard prescribed by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with the final ruling of the courts of the United States in United Steelworkers of America, AFL–CIO–CLC v. Thorne G. Auchter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition for review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Petition for review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for information provided to health professionals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exception for information provided to health professionals Nothing in this section, or regulations adopted pursuant to this section, shall authorize any person to withhold information which is required to be provided to a health professional, a doctor, or a nurse in accordance with section 11043 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providing information to Administrator; availability to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Providing information to Administrator; availability to public Any information submitted to the Administrator under subsection (a)(2) or subsection (d)(3) (except a specific chemical identity) shall be available to the public, except that upon a showing satisfactory to the Administrator by any person that the information (or a particular part thereof) to which the Administrator has access under this section if made public would divulge information entitled to protection under section 1905 of title 18, such information or part shall be considered confidential in accordance with the purposes of that section, except that such information or part may be disclosed to other officers, employees, or authorized representatives of the United States concerned with carrying out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information provided to State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Information provided to State Upon request by a State, acting through the Governor of the State, the Administrator shall provide to the State any information obtained under subsection (a)(2) and subsection (d)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on adverse effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Information on adverse effects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11042_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information provided to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Information provided to Congress Notwithstanding any limitatio 22 So in original. Probably should be “limitation”. contained in this section or any other provision of law, all information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Administrator (or any representative of the Administrator) under this chapter shall be made available to a duly authorized committee of the Congress upon written request by such a committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>