<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11046" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11046/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11046/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11046"><akn:num>11046</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11046. Civil actions(a) Authority to bring civil actions(1) Citizen suitsExcept as provided in subsection (e), any person may commence a civil action on his own behalf against the following:(A) An owner or operator of a facility for failure to do any of the following:(i) Submit a followup emergency notice under section 11004(c) of this title.

(ii) Submit a material safety data sheet or a list under section 11021(a) of this title.

(iii) Complete and submit an inventory form under section 11022(a) of this title containing tier I information as described in section 11022(d)(1) of this title unless such requirement does not apply by reason of the second sentence of section 11022(a)(2) of this title.

(iv) Complete and submit a toxic chemical release form under section 11023(a) of this title.


(B) The Administrator for failure to do any of the following:(i) Publish inventory forms under section 11022(g) of this title.

(ii) Respond to a petition to add or delete a chemical under section 11023(e)(1) of this title within 180 days after receipt of the petition.

(iii) Publish a toxic chemical release form under 11023(g) 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of this title.

(iv) Establish a computer database in accordance with section 11023(j) of this title.

(v) Promulgate trade secret regulations under section 11042(c) of this title.

(vi) Render a decision in response to a petition under section 11042(d) of this title within 9 months after receipt of the petition.


(C) The Administrator, a State Governor, or a State emergency response commission, for failure to provide a mechanism for public availability of information in accordance with section 11044(a) of this title.

(D) A State Governor or a State emergency response commission for failure to respond to a request for tier II information under section 11022(e)(3) of this title within 120 days after the date of receipt of the request.


(2) State or local suits(A) Any State or local governmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to bring civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to bring civil actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Venue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Venue</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Relief The district court shall have jurisdiction in actions brought under subsection (a) against an owner or operator of a facility to enforce the requirement concerned and to impose any civil penalty provided for violation of that requirement. The district court shall have jurisdiction in actions brought under subsection (a) against the Administrator to order the Administrator to perform the act or duty concerned.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation No action may be commenced under subsection (a) against an owner or operator of a facility if the Administrator has commenced and is diligently pursuing an administrative order or civil action to enforce the requirement concerned or to impose a civil penalty under this Act with respect to the violation of the requirement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Costs The court, in issuing any final order in any action brought pursuant to this section, may award costs of litigation (including reasonable attorney and expert witness fees) to the prevailing or the substantially prevailing party whenever the court determines such an award is appropriate. The court may, if a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction is sought, require the filing of a bond or equivalent security in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other rights Nothing in this section shall restrict or expand any right which any person (or class of persons) may have under any Federal or State statute or common law to seek enforcement of any requirement or to seek any other relief (including relief against the Administrator or a State agency).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11046_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intervention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Intervention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>