<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11261" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11261/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11261/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11261"><akn:num>11261</akn:num><akn:heading>Research program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11261. Research program(a) Grants for researchThe Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall conduct, or make grants for the conduct of, research relevant to appropriate services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families.


(b) Research subjectsThe Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall ensure that research conducted under subsection (a) shall include research—(1) concerning improving the organization, delivery, and financing of services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families, including research on—(A) the design, staffing, and operation of special care units for the individuals in institutional settings, as well as individuals in institutional settings,11 So in original. The words “as well as individuals in institutional settings,” probably should not appear. as well as individuals in home care, day care, and respite care; and

(B) the exploration and enhancement of services such as home care, day care, and respite care, that provide alternatives to institutional care;


(2) concerning the costs incurred by individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and by their families in obtaining services, particularly services that are essential to the individuals and that are not generally required by other patients under long-term care programs;

(3) concerning the costs, cost-effectiveness, and effectiveness of various interventions to provide services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families;

(4) conducted in consultation with the Director of the National Institute on Aging and the Commissioner of the Administration on Aging, concerning the role of physicians in caring for persons with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families, including the role of a physician in connecting such persons with appropriate health care and supportive services, including </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11261_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants for research The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall conduct, or make grants for the conduct of, research relevant to appropriate services for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias and for their families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11261_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research subjects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research subjects The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality shall ensure that research conducted under subsection (a) shall include research—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>