<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11292" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11292/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11292/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11292"><akn:num>11292</akn:num><akn:heading>Education of public, individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and their families, and health and long-te</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11292. Education of public, individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and their families, and health and long-term care providers(a) Training models grants(1) GrantsThe Director of the National Institute on Aging may award grants to eligible entities to assist the entities in developing and evaluating model training programs—(A) for—(i) health care professionals, including mental health professionals;

(ii) health care paraprofessionals;

(iii) personnel, including information and referral, case management, and in-home services personnel (including personnel receiving support under the Older Americans Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.)), providing supportive services to the elderly and the families of the elderly;

(iv) family caregivers providing care and treatment for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related disorders; and

(v) personnel of local organizations (including community groups, business and labor groups, and religious, educational, and charitable organizations) that have traditionally not been involved in planning and developing long-term care services; and


(B) with attention to such variables as—(i) curricula development for training and continuing education programs;

(ii) care setting; and

(iii) intervention technique.



(2) Eligible entityTo be eligible to receive grants under this subsection, an entity shall be—(A) an educational institution providing training and education in medicine, psychology, nursing, social work, gerontology, or health care administration;

(B) an educational institution providing preparatory training and education of personnel for nursing homes, hospitals, and home or community settings; or

(C) an Alzheimer’s Disease Research Center described in section 285e–2(a) of this title.



(b) Educational grantsThe Director of the National Institute on Aging is authorized to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to assist such entities in establishing programs, for educating health care providers and the f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11292_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training models grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Training models grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11292_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Educational grants The Director of the National Institute on Aging is authorized to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to assist such entities in establishing programs, for educating health care providers and the families of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease or related disorders, regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11292_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award of grants In awarding grants under this section, the Director of the National Institute on Aging shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11292_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Director of the National Institute on Aging at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information, as the Director may reasonably require, including, at a minimum, an assurance that the entity will coordinate programs provided under this section with the State agency designated under section 305(a)(1) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 [42 U.S.C. 3025(a)(1)], in the State in which the entity will provide such programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11292_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination The Director of the National Institute on Aging shall coordinate the award of grants under this section with the heads of other appropriate agencies, including the Commissioner of the Administration on Aging.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>