<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11316" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11316/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11316/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11316"><akn:num>11316</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11316. Transfer of functions(a) Transfers from HHS Task ForceThe Council shall be the successor to the Federal Task Force on the Homeless of the Department of Health and Human Services. The property, records, and undistributed program funds of the Task Force shall be transferred to the Council.


(b) Termination of HHS Task ForceThe Secretary of Health and Human Services shall terminate the Federal Task Force on the Homeless of the Department of Health and Human Services as soon as practicable following the first meeting of the Council.


(Pub. L. 100–77, title II, § 206, July 22, 1987, 101 Stat. 489.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11316_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers from HHS Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfers from HHS Task Force The Council shall be the successor to the Federal Task Force on the Homeless of the Department of Health and Human Services. The property, records, and undistributed program funds of the Task Force shall be transferred to the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11316_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of HHS Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Termination of HHS Task Force The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall terminate the Federal Task Force on the Homeless of the Department of Health and Human Services as soon as practicable following the first meeting of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>