<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11320" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11320/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11320/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11320"><akn:num>11320</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement of State involvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11320. Encouragement of State involvement(a) State contact personsEach State shall designate an individual to serve as a State contact person for the purpose of receiving and disseminating information and communications received from the Council, including the bimonthly bulletin described in section 11313(a)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(b) State interagency councils and lead agenciesEach State is encouraged to establish a State interagency council on the homeless or designate a lead agency for the State for the purpose of assuming primary responsibility for coordinating and interacting with the Council and State and local agencies as necessary.


(Pub. L. 100–77, title II, § 210, as added Pub. L. 100–628, title II, § 206(a), Nov. 7, 1988, 102 Stat. 3229.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextPar. (7) of section 11313(a) of this title, referred to in subsec. (a), was redesignated par. (11) of section 11313(a) by Pub. L. 111–22, div. B, § 1004(a)(3)(A), May 20, 2009, 123 Stat. 1667.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11320_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State contact persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State contact persons Each State shall designate an individual to serve as a State contact person for the purpose of receiving and disseminating information and communications received from the Council, including the bimonthly bulletin described in section 11313(a)(7) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11320_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State interagency councils and lead agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State interagency councils and lead agencies Each State is encouraged to establish a State interagency council on the homeless or designate a lead agency for the State for the purpose of assuming primary responsibility for coordinating and interacting with the Council and State and local agencies as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>