<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11364a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11364a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11364a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11364a"><akn:num>11364a</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of amounts recaptured from appropriated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11364a. Availability of amounts recaptured from appropriated funds(a) Amounts recaptured from funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year under the heading “Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Homeless Assistance Grants” shall become available until expended not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available and shall be available, in addition to rental assistance amounts that were recaptured and made available until expended under such heading by any prior Act, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for the following purposes:(1) For grants under the Continuum of Care program under subtitle C of title IV of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 11381 et seq.);

(2) For grants under the Emergency Solutions Grant program under subtitle B of title IV of such Act (42 U.S.C. 11371 et seq.);

(3) Not less than 10 percent of the amounts shall be used only for grants in rural areas under the Continuum of Care program, to include activities eligible under the Rural Housing Stability Assistance program under section 491 of such Act (42 U.S.C. 11408) that are not otherwise eligible under the Continuum of Care program; and

(4) Not less than 10 percent of the amounts shall be for emergency solutions grants for disaster areas as authorized by subsection (c).


(b) Prior to the use of any recaptured amounts referred to in subsection (a), including competing, awarding, or obligating such amounts, the Secretary shall submit a plan in accordance with subsection (a) that specifies the planned use of any such amounts to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and receive prior written approval of such plan, except that use of amounts in the plan for the purposes specified in subsection (a)(4) may begin once such plan is submitted to such Committees.

(c)(1) The Secretary may m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11364a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts recaptured from funds appropriated for this or any succeeding fiscal year under the heading “Department of Housing and Urban Development—Community Planning and Development—Homeless Assistance Grants” shall become available until expended not later than the end of the fifth fiscal year after the last fiscal year for which such funds are available and shall be available, in addition to rental assistance amounts that were recaptured and made available until expended under such heading by any prior Act, and in addition to such other funds as may be available for such purposes, for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11364a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prior to the use of any recaptured amounts referred to in subsection (a), including competing, awarding, or obligating such amounts, the Secretary shall submit a plan in accordance with subsection (a) that specifies the planned use of any such amounts to the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate, and receive prior written approval of such plan, except that use of amounts in the plan for the purposes specified in subsection (a)(4) may begin once such plan is submitted to such Committees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11364a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>