<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11360" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11360/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11360/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11360"><akn:num>11360</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11360. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) At risk of homelessnessThe term “at risk of homelessness” means, with respect to an individual or family, that the individual or family—(A) has income below 30 percent of median income for the geographic area;

(B) has insufficient resources immediately available to attain housing stability; and

(C)(i) has moved frequently because of economic reasons;

(ii) is living in the home of another because of economic hardship;

(iii) has been notified that their right to occupy their current housing or living situation will be terminated;

(iv) lives in a hotel or motel;

(v) lives in severely overcrowded housing;

(vi) is exiting an institution; or

(vii) otherwise lives in housing that has characteristics associated with instability and an increased risk of homelessness.



Such term includes all families with children and youth defined as homeless under other Federal statutes.

(2) Chronically homeless(A) In generalThe term “chronically homeless” means, with respect to an individual or family, that the individual or family—(i) is homeless and lives or resides in a place not meant for human habitation, a safe haven, or in an emergency shelter;

(ii) has been homeless and living or residing in a place not meant for human habitation, a safe haven, or in an emergency shelter continuously for at least 1 year or on at least 4 separate occasions in the last 3 years; and

(iii) has an adult head of household (or a minor head of household if no adult is present in the household) with a diagnosable substance use disorder, serious mental illness, developmental disability (as defined in section 15002 of this title), post traumatic stress disorder, cognitive impairments resulting from a brain injury, or chronic physical illness or disability, including the co-occurrence of 2 or more of those conditions.


(B) Rule of constructionA person who currently lives or resides in an institutional care facility, including a jail, substa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>At risk of homelessness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) At risk of homelessness The term “at risk of homelessness” means, with respect to an individual or family, that the individual or family— Such term includes all families with children and youth defined as homeless under other Federal statutes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chronically homeless</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Chronically homeless</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative applicant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Collaborative applicant The term “collaborative applicant” means an entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Collaborative application The term “collaborative application” means an application for a grant under part C that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consolidated Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Consolidated Plan The term “Consolidated Plan” means a comprehensive housing affordability strategy and community development plan required in part 91 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Eligible entity The term “eligible entity” means, with respect to a part, a public entity, a private entity, or an entity that is a combination of public and private entities, that is eligible to directly receive grant amounts under such part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Families with children and youth defined as homeless under other Federal statutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Families with children and youth defined as homeless under other Federal statutes The term “families with children and youth defined as homeless under other Federal statutes” means any children or youth that are defined as “homeless” under any Federal statute other than this part, but are not defined as homeless under section 11302 of this title, and shall also include the parent, parents, or guardian of such children or youth under part B of subchapter VI this 11 So in original. Probably should be “of this”. chapter (42 U.S.C. 11431 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Formula area The term “formula area” has the meaning given the term in section 1000.302 of title 24, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Geographic area The term “geographic area” means a State, metropolitan city, urban county, town, village, or other nonentitlement area, a formula area, or a combination or consortia of such, in the United States, as described in section 5306 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11360_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeless individual with a disability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Homeless individual with a disability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>