<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11374" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11374/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11374/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11374"><akn:num>11374</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11374. Eligible activities(a) In generalAssistance provided under section 11372 of this title may be used for the following activities:(1) The renovation, major rehabilitation, or conversion of buildings to be used as emergency shelters.

(2) The provision of essential services related to emergency shelter or street outreach, including services concerned with employment, health, education, family support services for homeless youth, substance abuse services, victim services, or mental health services, if—(A) such essential services have not been provided by the local government during any part of the immediately preceding 12-month period or the Secretary determines that the local government is in a severe financial deficit; or

(B) the use of assistance under this part would complement the provision of those essential services.


(3) Maintenance, operation, insurance, provision of utilities, and provision of furnishings related to emergency shelter.

(4) Provision of rental assistance to provide short-term or medium-term housing to homeless individuals or families or individuals or families at risk of homelessness. Such rental assistance may include tenant-based or project-based rental assistance.

(5) Housing relocation or stabilization services for homeless individuals or families or individuals or families at risk of homelessness, including housing search, mediation or outreach to property owners, legal services, credit repair, providing security or utility deposits, utility payments, rental assistance for a final month at a location, assistance with moving costs, or other activities that are effective at—(A) stabilizing individuals and families in their current housing; or

(B) quickly moving such individuals and families to other permanent housing.



(b) Maximum allocation for emergency shelter activitiesA grantee of assistance provided under section 11372 of this title for any fiscal year may not use an amount of such assistance for activities described in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11374_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Assistance provided under section 11372 of this title may be used for the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11374_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum allocation for emergency shelter activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maximum allocation for emergency shelter activities A grantee of assistance provided under section 11372 of this title for any fiscal year may not use an amount of such assistance for activities described in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (a) that exceeds the greater of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>