<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11373" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11373/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11373/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11373"><akn:num>11373</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation and distribution of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11373. Allocation and distribution of assistance(a) In generalThe Secretary shall allocate assistance under this part to metropolitan cities, urban counties, and States (for distribution to local governments and private nonprofit organizations in the States) in a manner that ensures that the percentage of the total amount available under this part for any fiscal year that is allocated to any State, metropolitan city, or urban county is equal to the percentage of the total amount available for section 5306 of this title for such prior fiscal year that is allocated to such State, metropolitan city, or urban county.


(b) Minimum allocation requirementIf, under the allocation provisions applicable under this part, any metropolitan city or urban county would receive a grant of less than 0.05 percent of the amounts appropriated under section 11364 of this title and made available to carry out this part for any fiscal year, such amount shall instead be reallocated to the State, except that any city that is located in a State that does not have counties as local governments, that has a population greater than 40,000 but less than 50,000 as used in determining the fiscal year 1987 community development block grant program allocation, and that was allocated in excess of $1,000,000 in community development block grant funds in fiscal year 1987, shall receive directly the amount allocated to such city under subsection (a).


(c) Distributions to nonprofit organizations, public housing agencies, and local redevelopment authoritiesAny local government receiving assistance under this part may distribute all or a portion of such assistance to private nonprofit organizations providing assistance to homeless individuals, to public housing agencies (as defined under section 1437a(b)(6) of this title), or to local redevelopment authorities (as defined under State law). Any State receiving assistance under this part may distribute all or a portion of such assistance to private nonpro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11373_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall allocate assistance under this part to metropolitan cities, urban counties, and States (for distribution to local governments and private nonprofit organizations in the States) in a manner that ensures that the percentage of the total amount available under this part for any fiscal year that is allocated to any State, metropolitan city, or urban county is equal to the percentage of the total amount available for section 5306 of this title for such prior fiscal year that is allocated to such State, metropolitan city, or urban county.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11373_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allocation requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimum allocation requirement If, under the allocation provisions applicable under this part, any metropolitan city or urban county would receive a grant of less than 0.05 percent of the amounts appropriated under section 11364 of this title and made available to carry out this part for any fiscal year, such amount shall instead be reallocated to the State, except that any city that is located in a State that does not have counties as local governments, that has a population greater than 40,000 but less than 50,000 as used in determining the fiscal year 1987 community development block grant program allocation, and that was allocated in excess of $1,000,000 in community development block grant funds in fiscal year 1987, shall receive directly the amount allocated to such city under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11373_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions to nonprofit organizations, public housing agencies, and local redevelopment authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distributions to nonprofit organizations, public housing agencies, and local redevelopment authorities Any local government receiving assistance under this part may distribute all or a portion of such assistance to private nonprofit organizations providing assistance to homeless individuals, to public housing agencies (as defined under section 1437a(b)(6) of this title), or to local redevelopment authorities (as defined under State law). Any State receiving assistance under this part may distribute all or a portion of such assistance to private nonprofit organizations providing assistance to homeless individuals, if the local government for the locality in which the project is located certifies that it approves of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11373_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11373_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations to territories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allocations to territories In addition to the other allocations required in this section, the Secretary shall (for amounts appropriated after July 22, 1987) allocate assistance under this part to the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States, in accordance with an allocation formula established by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>