<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11384" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11384/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11384/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11384"><akn:num>11384</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for high-performing communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11384. Incentives for high-performing communities(a) Designation as a high-performing community(1) In generalThe Secretary shall designate, on an annual basis, which collaborative applicants represent high-performing communities.


(2) ConsiderationIn determining whether to designate a collaborative applicant as a high-performing community under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall establish criteria to ensure that the requirements described under paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B) of subsection (d) are measured by comparing homeless individuals and families under similar circumstances, in order to encourage projects in the geographic area to serve homeless individuals and families with more severe barriers to housing stability.


(3) 2-year phase inIn each of the first 2 years after the effective date under section 1503 of the Homeless Emergency Assistance and Rapid Transition to Housing Act of 2009, the Secretary shall designate not more than 10 collaborative applicants as high-performing communities.


(4) Excess of qualified applicantsIf, during the 2-year period described under paragraph (2), more than 10 collaborative applicants could qualify to be designated as high-performing communities, the Secretary shall designate the 10 that have, in the discretion of the Secretary, the best performance based on the criteria described under subsection (d).


(5) Time limit on designationThe designation of any collaborative applicant as a high-performing community under this subsection shall be effective only for the year in which such designation is made. The Secretary, on an annual basis, may renew any such designation.



(b) Application(1) In generalA collaborative applicant seeking designation as a high-performing community under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, and in such manner as the Secretary may require.


(2) Content of applicationIn any application submitted under paragraph (1), a collaborative applicant shall include in su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11384_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation as a high-performing community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation as a high-performing community</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11384_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11384_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds Funds awarded under section 11382(a) of this title to a project sponsor who is located in a high-performing community may be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11384_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of high-performing community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition of high-performing community For purposes of this section, the term “high-performing community” means a geographic area that demonstrates through reliable data that all five of the following requirements are met for that geographic area:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11384_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation among entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cooperation among entities A collaborative applicant designated as a high-performing community under this section shall cooperate with the Secretary in distributing information about successful efforts within the geographic area represented by the collaborative applicant to reduce homelessness.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>