<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11386b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11386b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11386b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11386b"><akn:num>11386b</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of amounts and incentives for specific eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11386b. Allocation of amounts and incentives for specific eligible activities(a) Minimum allocation for permanent housing for homeless individuals and families with disabilities(1) In generalFrom the amounts made available to carry out this part for a fiscal year, a portion equal to not less than 30 percent of the sums made available to carry out part B and this part, shall be used for permanent housing for homeless individuals with disabilities and homeless families that include such an individual who is an adult or a minor head of household if no adult is present in the household.


(2) CalculationIn calculating the portion of the amount described in paragraph (1) that is used for activities that are described in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall not count funds made available to renew contracts for existing projects under section 11386c of this title.


(3) AdjustmentThe 30 percent figure in paragraph (1) shall be reduced proportionately based on need under section 11386a(b)(2) of this title in geographic areas for which subsection (e) applies in regard to subsection (d)(2)(A).


(4) SuspensionThe requirement established in paragraph (1) shall be suspended for any year in which funding available for grants under this part after making the allocation established in paragraph (1) would not be sufficient to renew for 1 year all existing grants that would otherwise be fully funded under this part.


(5) TerminationThe requirement established in paragraph (1) shall terminate upon a finding by the Secretary that since the beginning of 2001 at least 150,000 new units of permanent housing for homeless individuals and families with disabilities have been funded under this part.



(b) Set-aside for permanent housing for homeless families with childrenFrom the amounts made available to carry out this part for a fiscal year, a portion equal to not less than 10 percent of the sums made available to carry out part B and this part for that fiscal year shall be used to provi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11386b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum allocation for permanent housing for homeless individuals and families with disabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Minimum allocation for permanent housing for homeless individuals and families with disabilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11386b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set-aside for permanent housing for homeless families with children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Set-aside for permanent housing for homeless families with children From the amounts made available to carry out this part for a fiscal year, a portion equal to not less than 10 percent of the sums made available to carry out part B and this part for that fiscal year shall be used to provide or secure permanent housing for homeless families with children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11386b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of amounts for permanent or transitional housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of amounts for permanent or transitional housing Nothing in this chapter may be construed to establish a limit on the amount of funding that an applicant may request under this part for acquisition, construction, or rehabilitation activities for the development of permanent housing or transitional housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11386b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for proven strategies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Incentives for proven strategies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11386b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for successful implementation of proven strategies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Incentives for successful implementation of proven strategies If any geographic area demonstrates that it has fully implemented any of the activities described in subsection (d) for all homeless individuals and families or for all members of subpopulations for whom such activities are targeted, that geographic area shall receive the bonus or incentive provided under subsection (d), but may use such bonus or incentive for any eligible activity under either section 11383 of this title or paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 11374(a) of this title for homeless people generally or for the relevant subpopulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>