<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11385" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11385/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11385/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11385"><akn:num>11385</akn:num><akn:heading>Supportive services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11385. Supportive services(a) In generalTo the extent practicable, each project shall provide supportive services for residents of the project and homeless persons using the project, which may be designed by the recipient or participants.


(b) RequirementsSupportive services provided in connection with a project shall address the special needs of individuals (such as homeless persons with disabilities and homeless families with children) intended to be served by a project.


(c) ServicesSupportive services may include such activities as (A) establishing and operating a child care services program for homeless families, (B) establishing and operating an employment assistance program, (C) providing outpatient health services, food, and case management, (D) providing assistance in obtaining permanent housing, employment counseling, and nutritional counseling, (E) providing security arrangements necessary for the protection of residents of supportive housing and for homeless persons using the housing or project, (F) providing assistance in obtaining other Federal, State, and local assistance available for such residents (including mental health benefits, employment counseling, and medical assistance, but not including major medical equipment), and (G) providing other appropriate services.


(d) Provision of servicesServices provided pursuant to this section may be provided directly by the recipient or by contract with other public or private service providers. Such services may be provided to homeless individuals who do not reside in supportive housing.


(e) Coordination with Secretary of Health and Human Services(1) ApprovalPromptly upon receipt of any application for assistance under this part that includes the provision of outpatient health services, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall consult with the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the proposed outpatient health services. If, within 45 days of such consultation, the Secre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11385_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To the extent practicable, each project shall provide supportive services for residents of the project and homeless persons using the project, which may be designed by the recipient or participants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11385_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements Supportive services provided in connection with a project shall address the special needs of individuals (such as homeless persons with disabilities and homeless families with children) intended to be served by a project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11385_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services Supportive services may include such activities as (A) establishing and operating a child care services program for homeless families, (B) establishing and operating an employment assistance program, (C) providing outpatient health services, food, and case management, (D) providing assistance in obtaining permanent housing, employment counseling, and nutritional counseling, (E) providing security arrangements necessary for the protection of residents of supportive housing and for homeless persons using the housing or project, (F) providing assistance in obtaining other Federal, State, and local assistance available for such residents (including mental health benefits, employment counseling, and medical assistance, but not including major medical equipment), and (G) providing other appropriate services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11385_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of services Services provided pursuant to this section may be provided directly by the recipient or by contract with other public or private service providers. Such services may be provided to homeless individuals who do not reside in supportive housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11385_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>