<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11382" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11382/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11382/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11382"><akn:num>11382</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuum of care applications and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11382. Continuum of care applications and grants(a) ProjectsThe Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, and using the selection criteria described in section 11386a of this title, to carry out eligible activities under this part for projects that meet the program requirements under section 11386 of this title, either by directly awarding funds to project sponsors or by awarding funds to unified funding agencies.


(b) Notification of funding availabilityThe Secretary shall release a notification of funding availability for grants awarded under this part for a fiscal year not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of the appropriate Act making appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development for such fiscal year.


(c) Applications(1) Submission to the SecretaryTo be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), a project sponsor or unified funding agency in a geographic area shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, and containing such information as the Secretary determines necessary—(A) to determine compliance with the program requirements and selection criteria under this part; and

(B) to establish priorities for funding projects in the geographic area.


(2) Announcement of awards(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall announce, within 5 months after the last date for the submission of applications described in this subsection for a fiscal year, the grants conditionally awarded under subsection (a) for that fiscal year.


(B) TransitionFor a period of up to 2 years beginning after the effective date under section 1503 of the Homeless Emergency Assistance and Rapid Transition to Housing Act of 2009, the Secretary shall announce, within 6 months after the last date for the submission of applications described in this subsection for a fiscal year, the grants conditionally awarded under subsection (a) for that fiscal </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Projects The Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, and using the selection criteria described in section 11386a of this title, to carry out eligible activities under this part for projects that meet the program requirements under section 11386 of this title, either by directly awarding funds to project sponsors or by awarding funds to unified funding agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of funding availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of funding availability The Secretary shall release a notification of funding availability for grants awarded under this part for a fiscal year not later than 3 months after the date of the enactment of the appropriate Act making appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development for such fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligation, distribution, and utilization of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Obligation, distribution, and utilization of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewal funding for unsuccessful applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Renewal funding for unsuccessful applicants The Secretary may renew funding for a specific project previously funded under this part that the Secretary determines meets the purposes of this part, and was included as part of a total application that met the criteria of subsection (c), even if the application was not selected to receive grant assistance. The Secretary may renew the funding for a period of not more than 1 year, and under such conditions as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in determining renewal funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Considerations in determining renewal funding When providing renewal funding for leasing, operating costs, or rental assistance for permanent housing, the Secretary shall make adjustments proportional to increases in the fair market rents in the geographic area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>More than 1 application for a geographic area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) More than 1 application for a geographic area If more than 1 collaborative applicant applies for funds for a geographic area, the Secretary shall award funds to the collaborative applicant with the highest score based on the selection criteria set forth in section 11386a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solo applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Solo applicants A solo applicant may submit an application to the Secretary for a grant under subsection (a) and be awarded such grant on the same basis as such grants are awarded to other applicants based on the criteria described in section 11386a of this title, but only if the Secretary determines that the solo applicant has attempted to participate in the continuum of care process but was not permitted to participate in a reasonable manner. The Secretary may award such grants directly to such applicants in a manner determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11382_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibility to serve persons defined as homeless under other Federal laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Flexibility to serve persons defined as homeless under other Federal laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>