<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11408" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11408/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11408/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11408"><akn:num>11408</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural housing stability grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11408. Rural housing stability grant program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish and carry out a rural housing stability grant program. In carrying out the program, the Secretary may award grants to eligible organizations in lieu of grants under part C in order to pay for the Federal share of the cost of—(1) rehousing or improving the housing situations of individuals and families who are homeless or in the worst housing situations in the geographic area;

(2) stabilizing the housing of individuals and families who are in imminent danger of losing housing; and

(3) improving the ability of the lowest-income residents of the community to afford stable housing.


(b) Use of funds(1) In generalAn eligible organization may use a grant awarded under subsection (a) to provide, in rural areas—(A) rent, mortgage, or utility assistance after 2 months of nonpayment in order to prevent eviction, foreclosure, or loss of utility service;

(B) security deposits, rent for the first month of residence at a new location, and relocation assistance;

(C) short-term emergency lodging in motels or shelters, either directly or through vouchers;

(D) construction of new housing units to provide transitional or permanent housing to homeless individuals and families and individuals and families at risk of homelessness;

(E) acquisition or rehabilitation of a structure to provide supportive services or to provide transitional or permanent housing, other than emergency shelter, to homeless individuals and families and individuals and families at risk of homelessness;

(F) leasing of property, or portions of property, not owned by the recipient or project sponsor involved, for use in providing transitional or permanent housing to homeless individuals and families and individuals and families at risk of homelessness, or providing supportive services to such homeless and at-risk individuals and families;

(G) provision of rental assistance to provide </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish and carry out a rural housing stability grant program. In carrying out the program, the Secretary may award grants to eligible organizations in lieu of grants under part C in order to pay for the Federal share of the cost of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Award of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application In order to be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), an organization shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The application shall include, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligible organizations Organizations eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a) shall include private nonprofit entities and county and local governments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Selection criteria The Secretary shall establish criteria for selecting recipients of grants under subsection (a), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to eligible organizations in developing programs in accordance with this section, and in gaining access to other Federal resources that may be used to assist homeless persons in rural areas. Such assistance may be provided through regional workshops, and may be provided directly or through grants to, or contracts with, nongovernmental entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11408_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Termination of assistance If an individual or family who receives assistance under this section violates requirements of the assistance program provided by the organization receiving a grant under this section, the organization may terminate assistance in accordance with a formal process established by the organization that recognizes the rights of individuals receiving such assistance to due process of law, which may include a hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>