<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11904"><akn:num>11904</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11904. Applications(a) In generalTo receive a grant under this subchapter, a public housing agency, a public housing resident management corporation, an Indian tribe 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. a recipient of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.], or an owner of federally assisted low-income housing shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require. Such application shall include a plan for addressing the problem of drug-related or violent crime in and around of 22 So in original. the housing administered or owned by the applicant for which the application is being submitted, which plan shall be coordinated with and may be included in the public housing agency plan submitted to the Secretary pursuant to section 1437c–1 of this title.


(b) One-year renewable grants(1) In generalAn eligible applicant that is a public housing agency may apply for a 1-year grant under this subchapter that, subject to the availability of appropriated amounts, shall be renewed annually for a period of not more than 4 additional years, except that such renewal shall be contingent upon the Secretary finding, upon an annual or more frequent review, that the grantee agency is performing under the terms of the grant and applicable laws in a satisfactory manner and meets such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe. The Secretary may adjust the amount of any grant received or renewed under this paragraph to take into account increases or decreases in amounts appropriated for these purposes or such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.


(2) Eligibility and preferenceThe Secretary may not provide assistance under this subchapter to an applicant that is a public housing agency unless—(A) the agency will use the grants to continue or expand act</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To receive a grant under this subchapter, a public housing agency, a public housing resident management corporation, an Indian tribe 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. a recipient of assistance under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.], or an owner of federally assisted low-income housing shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such additional information as the Secretary may reasonably require. Such application shall include a plan for addressing the problem of drug-related or violent crime in and around of 22 So in original. the housing administered or owned by the applicant for which the application is being submitted, which plan shall be coordinated with and may be included in the public housing agency plan submitted to the Secretary pursuant to section 1437c–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>One-year renewable grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) One-year renewable grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria The Secretary shall approve applications under subsection (b) that are not subject to a preference under subsection (b)(2)(A) on the basis of thresholds or criteria such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally assisted low-income housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federally assisted low-income housing In addition to the selection criteria specified in subsection (c), the Secretary may establish other criteria for the evaluation of applications submitted by owners of federally assisted low-income housing, except that such additional criteria shall be designed only to reflect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11904_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>High intensity drug trafficking areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) High intensity drug trafficking areas In evaluating the extent of the drug-related crime problem pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary may consider whether housing projects proposed for assistance are located in a high intensity drug trafficking area designated pursuant to section 1504 33 See References in Text note below. of title 21.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>