<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11907" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11907/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/11907/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_11907"><akn:num>11907</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 11907. Monitoring(a) In generalThe Secretary shall audit and monitor the programs funded under this subchapter to ensure that assistance provided under this subchapter is administered in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.


(b) Prohibition of funding baseline services(1) In generalAmounts provided under this subchapter may not be used to reimburse or support any local law enforcement agency or unit of general local government for the provision of services that are included in the baseline of services required to be provided by any such entity pursuant to a local cooperation agreement under section 1437c(e)(2) of this title or any provision of an annual contributions contract for payments in lieu of taxation pursuant to section 1437d(d) of this title.


(2) DescriptionEach public housing agency that receives grant amounts under this subchapter shall describe, in the report under section 11906(a) of this title, such baseline of services for the unit of general local government in which the jurisdiction of the agency is located.



(c) EnforcementThe Secretary shall provide for the effective enforcement of this section, which may include the use of on-site monitoring, independent public audit requirements, certification by local law enforcement or local government officials regarding the performance of baseline services referred to in subsection (b), and entering into agreements with the Attorney General to achieve compliance, and verification of compliance, with the provisions of this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5128, as added Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 586(g), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2649.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 11907, Pub. L. 100–690, title V, § 5128, Nov. 18, 1988, 102 Stat. 4303; Pub. L. 101–625, title V, § 581(a), Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4248, related to provision of periodic reports by grantees, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–276, title V, §§ 503, 586(g), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2521, 2649, effectiv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11907_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall audit and monitor the programs funded under this subchapter to ensure that assistance provided under this subchapter is administered in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11907_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of funding baseline services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition of funding baseline services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_11907_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement The Secretary shall provide for the effective enforcement of this section, which may include the use of on-site monitoring, independent public audit requirements, certification by local law enforcement or local government officials regarding the performance of baseline services referred to in subsection (b), and entering into agreements with the Attorney General to achieve compliance, and verification of compliance, with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>