<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12005"><akn:num>12005</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration and commercial application projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12005. Demonstration and commercial application projects(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to direct the Secretary to further the commercialization of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies through a five-year program.


(b) Demonstration and commercial application projects(1) Establishment(A) The Secretary shall solicit proposals for demonstration and commercial application projects for renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies pursuant to subsection (c). Such projects may include projects for—(i) the production and sale of electricity, thermal energy, or other forms of energy using a renewable energy technology;

(ii) increasing the efficiency of energy use; and

(iii) improvements in, or expansion of, facilities for the manufacture of renewable energy or energy efficiency technologies.


(B) Requirements.—Each project selected under this section shall include at least one for-profit business. Activities supported under this section shall be performed in the United States. Each project under this section shall require the manufacture and reproduction substantially within the United States for commercial sale of any invention or product that may result from the project.


(2) Forms of financial assistance(A) In supporting projects selected under subsection (c), the Secretary may choose from among the forms of agreements described in section 13541 of this title.

(B) In supporting projects selected under subsection (c), the Secretary may also enter into agreements with private lenders to pay a portion of the interest on loans made for such projects.


(3) Cost sharingCost sharing for projects under this section shall be conducted according to the procedures described in section 13542(b) and (c) of this title.


(4) Advisory Committee(A) The Secretary shall establish an Advisory Committee on Demonstration and Commercial Application of Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Technologies (in this chapter referred to as the “Advisory Comm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12005_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to direct the Secretary to further the commercialization of renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies through a five-year program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12005_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration and commercial application projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Demonstration and commercial application projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12005_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection of projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12005_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1994.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>