<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12006" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12006/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12006/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12006"><akn:num>12006</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12006. Reports(a) Report by SecretaryOne year after December 11, 1989, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall report to Congress on the programs and projects supported under this chapter and the progress being made toward accomplishing the goals and purposes set forth in this chapter.


(b) National renewable energy and energy efficiency management plan(1) The Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Committee, shall prepare a three-year management plan to be administered and carried out by the Secretary in the conduct of activities under this chapter.

(2) After opportunity for public comment and consideration, as appropriate, of such comment, the Secretary shall publish the plan.

(3) In addition to describing the Secretary’s intentions for administering this chapter, the plan shall include a comprehensive strategy for assisting the private sector—(A) in commercializing the renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies developed under this chapter; and

(B) in meeting competition from foreign suppliers of products derived from renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies.


(4) The plan shall address the role of federally-assisted research, development, and demonstration in the achievement of applicable national policy goals of the National Energy Policy Plan required under section 7321 of this title and the plan developed under section 5905 of this title.

(5) In addition, the Plan 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. shall—(A) contain a detailed assessment of program needs, objectives, and priorities for each of the programs authorized under section 12005 of this title;

(B) use a uniform prioritization methodology to facilitate cost-benefit analyses of proposals in various program areas;

(C) establish milestones for setting forth specific technology transfer activities under each program area;

(D) include annual and five-year cost estimates for individual programs under this chapter; and

(E) identify program areas f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12006_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Report by Secretary One year after December 11, 1989, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall report to Congress on the programs and projects supported under this chapter and the progress being made toward accomplishing the goals and purposes set forth in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12006_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National renewable energy and energy efficiency management plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National renewable energy and energy efficiency management plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12006_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on options</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report on options As part of the first report submitted under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report analyzing options available to the Secretary under existing law to assist the private sector with the timely commercialization of wind, photovoltaic, solar thermal, biofuels, hydrogen, solar buildings, marine, geothermal, low-head hydro, and energy storage renewable energy technologies and energy efficiency technologies through emphasis on development and demonstration assistance to specific technologies in the research, development, and demonstration programs of the Department of Energy that are near commercial application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>