<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12103" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12103/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12103/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12103"><akn:num>12103</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12103. Additional definitions
As used in this chapter:(1) Auxiliary aids and servicesThe term “auxiliary aids and services” includes—(A) qualified interpreters or other effective methods of making aurally delivered materials available to individuals with hearing impairments;

(B) qualified readers, taped texts, or other effective methods of making visually delivered materials available to individuals with visual impairments;

(C) acquisition or modification of equipment or devices; and

(D) other similar services and actions.


(2) StateThe term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.”.


(Pub. L. 101–336, § 4, as added Pub. L. 110–325, § 4(b), Sept. 25, 2008, 122 Stat. 3556.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 101–336, July 26, 1990, 104 Stat. 327, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 12101 of this title and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Jan. 1, 2009, see section 8 of Pub. L. 110–325, set out as an Effective Date of 2008 Amendment note under section 705 of Title 29, Labor.

Executive Documents

Termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands
For termination of Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, see note set out preceding section 1681 of Title 48, Territories and Insular Possessions.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12103_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Auxiliary aids and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Auxiliary aids and services The term “auxiliary aids and services” includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12103_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) State The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>