<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12113"><akn:num>12113</akn:num><akn:heading>Defenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12113. Defenses(a) In generalIt may be a defense to a charge of discrimination under this chapter that an alleged application of qualification standards, tests, or selection criteria that screen out or tend to screen out or otherwise deny a job or benefit to an individual with a disability has been shown to be job-related and consistent with business necessity, and such performance cannot be accomplished by reasonable accommodation, as required under this subchapter.


(b) Qualification standardsThe term “qualification standards” may include a requirement that an individual shall not pose a direct threat to the health or safety of other individuals in the workplace.


(c) Qualification standards and tests related to uncorrected visionNotwithstanding section 12102(4)(E)(ii) of this title, a covered entity shall not use qualification standards, employment tests, or other selection criteria based on an individual’s uncorrected vision unless the standard, test, or other selection criteria, as used by the covered entity, is shown to be job-related for the position in question and consistent with business necessity.


(d) Religious entities(1) In generalThis subchapter shall not prohibit a religious corporation, association, educational institution, or society from giving preference in employment to individuals of a particular religion to perform work connected with the carrying on by such corporation, association, educational institution, or society of its activities.


(2) Religious tenets requirementUnder this subchapter, a religious organization may require that all applicants and employees conform to the religious tenets of such organization.



(e) List of infectious and communicable diseases(1) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services, not later than 6 months after July 26, 1990, shall—(A) review all infectious and communicable diseases which may be transmitted through handling the food supply;

(B) publish a list of infectious and communicable diseas</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general It may be a defense to a charge of discrimination under this chapter that an alleged application of qualification standards, tests, or selection criteria that screen out or tend to screen out or otherwise deny a job or benefit to an individual with a disability has been shown to be job-related and consistent with business necessity, and such performance cannot be accomplished by reasonable accommodation, as required under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualification standards The term “qualification standards” may include a requirement that an individual shall not pose a direct threat to the health or safety of other individuals in the workplace.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification standards and tests related to uncorrected vision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualification standards and tests related to uncorrected vision Notwithstanding section 12102(4)(E)(ii) of this title, a covered entity shall not use qualification standards, employment tests, or other selection criteria based on an individual’s uncorrected vision unless the standard, test, or other selection criteria, as used by the covered entity, is shown to be job-related for the position in question and consistent with business necessity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Religious entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of infectious and communicable diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) List of infectious and communicable diseases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>