<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12181" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12181/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12181/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12181"><akn:num>12181</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12181. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) CommerceThe term “commerce” means travel, trade, traffic, commerce, transportation, or communication—(A) among the several States;

(B) between any foreign country or any territory or possession and any State; or

(C) between points in the same State but through another State or foreign country.


(2) Commercial facilitiesThe term “commercial facilities” means facilities—(A) that are intended for nonresidential use; and

(B) whose operations will affect commerce.


Such term shall not include railroad locomotives, railroad freight cars, railroad cabooses, railroad cars described in section 12162 of this title or covered under this subchapter, railroad rights-of-way, or facilities that are covered or expressly exempted from coverage under the Fair Housing Act of 1968 11 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.).

(3) Demand responsive systemThe term “demand responsive system” means any system of providing transportation of individuals by a vehicle, other than a system which is a fixed route system.


(4) Fixed route systemThe term “fixed route system” means a system of providing transportation of individuals (other than by aircraft) on which a vehicle is operated along a prescribed route according to a fixed schedule.


(5) Over-the-road busThe term “over-the-road bus” means a bus characterized by an elevated passenger deck located over a baggage compartment.


(6) Private entityThe term “private entity” means any entity other than a public entity (as defined in section 12131(1) of this title).


(7) Public accommodationThe following private entities are considered public accommodations for purposes of this subchapter, if the operations of such entities affect commerce—(A) an inn, hotel, motel, or other place of lodging, except for an establishment located within a building that contains not more than five rooms for rent or hire and that is actually occupied by the proprietor of such establishment </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Commerce The term “commerce” means travel, trade, traffic, commerce, transportation, or communication—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Commercial facilities The term “commercial facilities” means facilities— Such term shall not include railroad locomotives, railroad freight cars, railroad cabooses, railroad cars described in section 12162 of this title or covered under this subchapter, railroad rights-of-way, or facilities that are covered or expressly exempted from coverage under the Fair Housing Act of 1968 11 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demand responsive system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Demand responsive system The term “demand responsive system” means any system of providing transportation of individuals by a vehicle, other than a system which is a fixed route system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fixed route system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Fixed route system The term “fixed route system” means a system of providing transportation of individuals (other than by aircraft) on which a vehicle is operated along a prescribed route according to a fixed schedule.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Over-the-road bus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Over-the-road bus The term “over-the-road bus” means a bus characterized by an elevated passenger deck located over a baggage compartment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Private entity The term “private entity” means any entity other than a public entity (as defined in section 12131(1) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public accommodation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Public accommodation The following private entities are considered public accommodations for purposes of this subchapter, if the operations of such entities affect commerce—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rail and railroad</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Rail and railroad The terms “rail” and “railroad” have the meaning given the term “railroad” in section 20102(1) 1 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Readily achievable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Readily achievable The term “readily achievable” means easily accomplishable and able to be carried out without much difficulty or expense. In determining whether an action is readily achievable, factors to be considered include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12181_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified public transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Specified public transportation The term “specified public transportation” means transportation by bus, rail, or any other conveyance (other than by aircraft) that provides the general public with general or special service (including charter service) on a regular and continuing basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>