<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12206"><akn:num>12206</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12206. Technical assistance(a) Plan for assistance(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after July 26, 1990, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Chair of the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chair of the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board, and the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, shall develop a plan to assist entities covered under this chapter, and other Federal agencies, in understanding the responsibility of such entities and agencies under this chapter.


(2) Publication of planThe Attorney General shall publish the plan referred to in paragraph (1) for public comment in accordance with subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 (commonly known as the Administrative Procedure Act).



(b) Agency and public assistanceThe Attorney General may obtain the assistance of other Federal agencies in carrying out subsection (a), including the National Council on Disability, the President’s Committee on Employment of People with Disabilities, the Small Business Administration, and the Department of Commerce.


(c) Implementation(1) Rendering assistanceEach Federal agency that has responsibility under paragraph (2) for implementing this chapter may render technical assistance to individuals and institutions that have rights or duties under the respective subchapter or subchapters of this chapter for which such agency has responsibility.


(2) Implementation of subchapters(A) Subchapter IThe Equal Employment Opportunity Commission and the Attorney General shall implement the plan for assistance developed under subsection (a), for subchapter I.


(B) Subchapter II(i) Part AThe Attorney General shall implement such plan for assistance for part A of subchapter II.


(ii) Part BThe Secretary of Transportation shall implement such plan for assistance for part B of subchapter II.



(C) Subchapter IIIThe Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation and the Chai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Plan for assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency and public assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agency and public assistance The Attorney General may obtain the assistance of other Federal agencies in carrying out subsection (a), including the National Council on Disability, the President’s Committee on Employment of People with Disabilities, the Small Business Administration, and the Department of Commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12206_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12206_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grants and contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12206_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to receive assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Failure to receive assistance An employer, public accommodation, or other entity covered under this chapter shall not be excused from compliance with the requirements of this chapter because of any failure to receive technical assistance under this section, including any failure in the development or dissemination of any technical assistance manual authorized by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>