<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12337" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12337/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12337/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12337"><akn:num>12337</akn:num><akn:heading>State coordination of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12337. State coordination of services(a) AuthorityThe Commissioner shall make grants under this section to States on a formula basis for the purpose of improving the coordination of services provided to children, youth, and families.


(b) ApplicationTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of a State shall prepare and submit to the Commissioner an application containing a plan providing assurances that—(1) the independent State body is committed to interagency planning that results in statewide policies promoting systematic collaboration among agencies on behalf of young individuals as demonstrated by joint planning, joint financing, joint service delivery, common intake and assessment, and other arrangements that reduce barriers to services and promote more effective local service delivery systems for young individuals;

(2) such plan will be based on needs as identified through an analysis of updated reports (such as “State of the Child” reports) prepared by the State, including detailed information gathered by the State, to the extent practicable, on young individuals and the families of such individuals concerning—(A) age, sex, race, and ethnicity;

(B) the residences of such individuals;

(C) the incidence of homelessness among such individuals;

(D) the composition of families of such individuals;

(E) the economic situations of such individuals;

(F) the incidence of poverty among such individuals;

(G) experiences in the care of such individuals away from home;

(H) the health of such individuals;

(I) violence in the homes or communities of such individuals;

(J) the nature of the attachment of such individuals to school and work;

(K) dropout rates of such individuals from school; and

(L) the character of the communities in which such individuals reside;


(3) the system to be used for the distribution of funds within the State will require that—(A) each area have an equal opportunity to apply for or receive fun</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12337_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority The Commissioner shall make grants under this section to States on a formula basis for the purpose of improving the coordination of services provided to children, youth, and families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12337_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, the chief executive officer of a State shall prepare and submit to the Commissioner an application containing a plan providing assurances that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12337_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grants to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of grants to States Notwithstanding section 12340(g) of this title, the amounts made available to each State under section 12340(a) of this title may be used to make grants to a State to enable such State to pay such percentages as the independent State body of such State determines to be appropriate, of the cost of administering the State plan of such State including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12337_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (d) has been enacted. Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amounts received by a State under this section and section 12338 of this title shall be used only to supplement, not to supplant, the amount of Federal, State, and local funds expended for the purposes for which grants are made under this section and section 12338 of this title. In no event shall such expenditures be used to satisfy the matching requirements of any other Federal program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12337_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to family resource and support program grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Relationship to family resource and support program grants If a State intends to apply for a grant under section 12339 22 See References in Text note below. of this title to be used for the same calendar year as the grant under this section, such State shall include in the application for a grant under this section a description of plans for family resource and support programs and for the coordination of the use of all funds received under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>