<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12340" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12340/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12340/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12340"><akn:num>12340</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriation and allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12340. Authorization of appropriation and allotment(a) Administration on Children, Youth, and Families; State coordination; supportive services(1) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out sections 12337 and 12338 of this title such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1995 through 1998.


(2) Availability of appropriationOf the amount appropriated under paragraph (1) for any fiscal year—(A) not more than 10 percent shall be available to carry out section 12315 of this title; and

(B) not less than 90 percent shall be available to carry out sections 12337 and 12338 of this title.


(3) Allotment formulaExcept as provided in paragraph (4), from the amount available under paragraph (2)(B) for each fiscal year, a State shall be allotted an amount that bears the same ratio to the amount appropriated for such fiscal year as the population of the State that is under the age of 21 bears to the population of all States that is under the age of 21.


(4) Exceptions(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B) and subject to the availability of appropriations under paragraph (1), no State shall be allotted less than $300,000 under the formula established under paragraph (3).


(B) Limitation on allotmentNotwithstanding subparagraph (A), Guam, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be allotted not less than $75,000 under the formula established under paragraph (2).




(b) Determination of ageThe number of individuals under the age of 21 in each State shall be determined by the Commissioner on the basis of the most recent data available to the Commissioner.


(c) Transfer of allotted fundsWhenever the Commissioner determines that—(1) any amount allotted to a State for a fiscal year under section 12337 or 12338 of this title will not be used by such State for carrying out the purpose for which such allotment</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration on Children, Youth, and Families; State coordination; supportive services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administration on Children, Youth, and Families; State coordination; supportive services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of age</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of age The number of individuals under the age of 21 in each State shall be determined by the Commissioner on the basis of the most recent data available to the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of allotted funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of allotted funds Whenever the Commissioner determines that— the Commissioner shall make such allotment available for carrying out such purposes to other participating States in a proportional manner based on the relative population of the State of individuals under the age of 21.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–252, title IV, § 402(b)(2), May 18, 1994, 108 Stat. 673</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation A State shall not use in excess of 10 percent of a grant awarded under section 12338 or 12339 11 See References in Text note below. of this title for administrative activities at the State level.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grants for Indians The Commissioner shall use 1 percent of the amount appropriated under this section for each fiscal year to make allotments to Indian tribes and tribal organizations (such terms having the same meaning given to such terms in section 5304(b) and (c) 1 of title 25) that submit to the Commissioner a plan that meets criteria consistent with the provisions of this part and that comply with other requirements established by the Commissioner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12340_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation Grants made under this subchapter may be used to pay not more than 80 percent of the cost of— The remaining 20 percent of such cost shall be paid by the State with funds from non-Federal sources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>