<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12374" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12374/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12374/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12374"><akn:num>12374</akn:num><akn:heading>Conference committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12374. Conference committees(a) Advisory committeeThe Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to the Conference which shall include representatives from the Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families, public agencies and nonprofit private organizations as appropriate.


(b) Other committeesThe Secretary may establish such other committees, including technical committees, as may be necessary to assist in the planning, conducting, and reviewing of the Conference.


(c) Composition of committeesEach committee established under this section shall be composed of professionals and public members, and shall include individuals from low-income families and from minority groups.


(d) CompensationMembers of any committee established under this section (other than any officers or employees of the Federal Government), while attending conferences or meetings of the committee or otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary, shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary, but not to exceed the daily rate payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 (including travel time). While away from their homes or regular places of business, such members may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under section 5703 of such title for persons employed intermittently in Federal Government service.


(Pub. L. 101–501, title IX, § 985, Nov. 3, 1990, 104 Stat. 1282.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1990, see section 1001(a) of Pub. L. 101–501, set out as an Effective Date of 1990 Amendment note under section 8621 of this title.

Termination of Advisory CommitteesAdvisory committees established after Jan. 5, 1973, to terminate not later than the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date of their establishment, unless, in the case of a committee established by the President or an officer of the Federal Governmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12374_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Advisory committee The Secretary shall establish an advisory committee to the Conference which shall include representatives from the Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families, public agencies and nonprofit private organizations as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12374_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other committees The Secretary may establish such other committees, including technical committees, as may be necessary to assist in the planning, conducting, and reviewing of the Conference.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12374_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition of committees Each committee established under this section shall be composed of professionals and public members, and shall include individuals from low-income families and from minority groups.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12374_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compensation Members of any committee established under this section (other than any officers or employees of the Federal Government), while attending conferences or meetings of the committee or otherwise serving at the request of the Secretary, shall be entitled to receive compensation at a rate to be fixed by the Secretary, but not to exceed the daily rate payable for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 (including travel time). While away from their homes or regular places of business, such members may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, as authorized under section 5703 of such title for persons employed intermittently in Federal Government service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>