<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12407"><akn:num>12407</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12407. Technical panel(a) EstablishmentThere is hereby established the Hydrogen Technical Advisory Panel (the “technical panel”), to advise the Secretary on the programs under this chapter.


(b) MembershipThe technical panel shall be appointed by the Secretary and shall be comprised of such representatives from domestic industry, universities, professional societies, Government laboratories, financial, environmental, and other organizations as the Secretary deems appropriate based on his assessment of the technical and other qualifications of such representatives. Appointments to the technical panel shall be made within 90 days after November 15, 1990. The technical panel shall have a chairman, who shall be elected by the members from among their number.


(c) CooperationThe heads of the departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Executive branch of the Federal Government shall cooperate with the technical panel in carrying out the requirements of this section and shall furnish to the technical panel such information as the technical panel deems necessary to carry out this section.


(d) ReviewThe technical panel shall review and make any necessary recommendations to the Secretary on the following items—(1) the implementation and conduct of programs under this chapter; and

(2) the economic, technological, and environmental consequences of the deployment of hydrogen production and use systems.


(e) SupportThe Secretary shall provide such staff, funds and other support as may be necessary to enable the technical panel to carry out the functions described in this section.


(Pub. L. 101–566, § 108, Nov. 15, 1990, 104 Stat. 2800; Pub. L. 104–271, title I, § 102(b), Oct. 9, 1996, 110 Stat. 3305.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1996—Subsec. (d)(3). Pub. L. 104–271 struck out par. (3) which read as follows: “comments on and recommendations for improvements in the comprehensive 5-year program management plan required under section 12402 of this title.”

Statutory </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is hereby established the Hydrogen Technical Advisory Panel (the “technical panel”), to advise the Secretary on the programs under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The technical panel shall be appointed by the Secretary and shall be comprised of such representatives from domestic industry, universities, professional societies, Government laboratories, financial, environmental, and other organizations as the Secretary deems appropriate based on his assessment of the technical and other qualifications of such representatives. Appointments to the technical panel shall be made within 90 days after November 15, 1990. The technical panel shall have a chairman, who shall be elected by the members from among their number.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation The heads of the departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Executive branch of the Federal Government shall cooperate with the technical panel in carrying out the requirements of this section and shall furnish to the technical panel such information as the technical panel deems necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12407_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review The technical panel shall review and make any necessary recommendations to the Secretary on the following items—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12407_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Support The Secretary shall provide such staff, funds and other support as may be necessary to enable the technical panel to carry out the functions described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>