<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12511" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12511/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12511/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12511"><akn:num>12511</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12511. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) Adult volunteerThe term “adult volunteer” means an individual, such as an older adult, an individual with a disability, a parent, or an employee of a business or public or private nonprofit organization, who—(A) works without financial remuneration in an educational institution to assist students or out-of-school youth; and

(B) is beyond the age of compulsory school attendance in the State in which the educational institution is located.


(2) Alaska Native-serving institutionThe term “Alaska Native-serving institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1059d(b) of title 20.


(3) Approved national service positionThe term “approved national service position” means a national service position for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a national service educational award described in section 12603 of this title as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.


(4) Approved silver scholar positionThe term “approved silver scholar position” means a position, in a program described in section 12653c(a) of this title, for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a silver scholarship educational award as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.


(5) Approved summer of service positionThe term “approved summer of service position” means a position, in a program described in section 12563(c)(8) of this title, for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a summer of service educational award as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.


(6) Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutionThe term “Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1059g(b) of title 20.


(7) Authorizing committeesThe term “authorizing committees” means the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Repr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adult volunteer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Adult volunteer The term “adult volunteer” means an individual, such as an older adult, an individual with a disability, a parent, or an employee of a business or public or private nonprofit organization, who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alaska Native-serving institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Alaska Native-serving institution The term “Alaska Native-serving institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1059d(b) of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved national service position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Approved national service position The term “approved national service position” means a national service position for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a national service educational award described in section 12603 of this title as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved silver scholar position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Approved silver scholar position The term “approved silver scholar position” means a position, in a program described in section 12653c(a) of this title, for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a silver scholarship educational award as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approved summer of service position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Approved summer of service position The term “approved summer of service position” means a position, in a program described in section 12563(c)(8) of this title, for which the Corporation has approved the provision of a summer of service educational award as one of the benefits to be provided for successful service in the position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution The term “Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution” has the meaning given the term in section 1059g(b) of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizing committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Authorizing committees The term “authorizing committees” means the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carry out</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Carry out The term “carry out”, when used in connection with a national service program, means the planning, establishment, operation, expansion, or replication of the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chief Executive Officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Chief Executive Officer The term “Chief Executive Officer”, except when used to refer to the chief executive officer of a State, means the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation appointed under section 12651c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12511_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Community-based agency The term “community-based agency” means a private nonprofit organization (including a church or other religious entity) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>