<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12561" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12561/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12561/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12561"><akn:num>12561</akn:num><akn:heading>Higher education innovative programs for community service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12561. Higher education innovative programs for community service(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this part to expand participation in community service by supporting innovative community service programs through service-learning carried out through institutions of higher education, acting as civic institutions to meet the human, educational, environmental, or public safety needs of neighboring communities.


(b) General authorityThe Corporation, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, is authorized to make grants to, and enter into contracts with, institutions of higher education (including a consortium of such institutions), and partnerships comprised of such institutions and of other public or private nonprofit organizations, to pay for the Federal share of the cost of—(1) enabling such an institution or partnership to create or expand an organized community service program that—(A) engenders a sense of social responsibility and commitment to the community in which the institution is located;

(B) provides projects for participants, who shall be students, faculty, administration, or staff of the institution, or residents of the community; and

(C) the institution or partnership may coordinate with service-learning curricula being offered in the academic curricula at the institution of higher education or at 1 or more members of the partnership;


(2) supporting student-initiated and student-designed community service projects through the program;

(3) strengthening the leadership and instructional capacity of institutions of higher education and their faculty, with respect to service-learning, by—(A) including service-learning as a key component of the preservice teacher curricula of the institution to strengthen the instructional capacity of teachers to provide service-learning at the elementary and secondary levels;

(B) including service-learning as a component of other curricula or academic programs (other than education curricula or programs), such</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this part to expand participation in community service by supporting innovative community service programs through service-learning carried out through institutions of higher education, acting as civic institutions to meet the human, educational, environmental, or public safety needs of neighboring communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority The Corporation, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, is authorized to make grants to, and enter into contracts with, institutions of higher education (including a consortium of such institutions), and partnerships comprised of such institutions and of other public or private nonprofit organizations, to pay for the Federal share of the cost of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal, State, and local contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal, State, and local contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application for grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special consideration To the extent practicable, in making grants and entering into contracts under subsection (b), the Corporation shall give special consideration to applications submitted by, or applications from partnerships including, institutions serving primarily low-income populations, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Considerations In making grants and entering into contracts under subsection (b), the Corporation shall take into consideration whether the applicants submit applications containing proposals that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal work-study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Federal work-study To be eligible for assistance under this part, an institution of higher education shall demonstrate that it meets the minimum requirements under section 443(b)(2)(A) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 2753(b)(2)(A)) 1 relating to the participation of students employed under part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (42 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.) 1 (relating to Federal Work-Study 22 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. programs) in community service activities, or has received a waiver of those requirements from the Secretary of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definition Notwithstanding section 12511 of this title, as used in this part, the term “student” means an individual who is enrolled in an institution of higher education on a full- or part-time basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12561_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>National service educational award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) National service educational award A participant in a program funded under this part shall be eligible for the national service educational award described in division D, if the participant served in an approved national service position.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>