<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12563" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12563/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12563/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12563"><akn:num>12563</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative and community-based service-learning programs and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12563. Innovative and community-based service-learning programs and research(a) DefinitionsIn this part:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a State educational agency, a State Commission, a territory, an Indian tribe, an institution of higher education, or a public or private nonprofit organization (including community-based entities), a public or private elementary school or secondary school, a local educational agency, a consortium of such entities, or a consortium of 2 or more such entities and a for-profit organization.


(2) Eligible partnershipThe term “eligible partnership” means a partnership that—(A) shall include—(i) 1 or more community-based entities that have demonstrated records of success in carrying out service-learning programs with economically disadvantaged students, and that meet such criteria as the Chief Executive Officer may establish; and

(ii) a local educational agency for which—(I) a high number or percentage, as determined by the Corporation, of the students served by the agency are economically disadvantaged students; and

(II) the four-year adjusted cohort graduation rate (as defined in section 7801 of title 20) for the secondary school students served by the agency is less than 70 percent; and



(B) may also include—(i) a local government agency that is not described in subparagraph (A);

(ii) the office of the chief executive officer of a unit of general local government;

(iii) an institution of higher education;

(iv) a State Commission or State educational agency; or

(v) more than 1 local educational agency described in subclause (I).11 So in original. Clause (v) does not contain subclauses.



(3) Youth engagement zoneThe term “youth engagement zone” means the area in which a youth engagement zone program is carried out.


(4) Youth engagement zone programThe term “youth engagement zone program” means a service-learning program in which members of an eligible partnership collaborate to provide coordinated school</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority From the amounts appropriated to carry out this part for a fiscal year, the Corporation may make grants (which may include approved summer of service positions in the case of a grant for a program described in subsection (c)(8)) and fixed-amount grants (in accordance with section 12581(l) of this title) to eligible entities or eligible partnerships, as appropriate, for programs and activities described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities Funds under this part may be used to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications To be eligible to receive a grant to carry out a program or activity under this part, an entity or partnership, as appropriate, shall prepare and submit to the Corporation an application at such time and in such manner as the Chief Executive Officer may reasonably require, and obtain approval of the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In making grants under this part, the Corporation shall give priority to applicants proposing to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12563_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>