<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12595" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12595/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12595/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12595"><akn:num>12595</akn:num><akn:heading>National service educational awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12595. National service educational awards(a) Eligibility generallyA participant in a national service program carried out using assistance provided to an applicant under section 12571 of this title shall be eligible for the national service educational award described in division D if the participant—(1) serves in an approved national service position; and

(2) satisfies the eligibility requirements specified in section 12602 of this title with respect to service in that approved national service position.


(b) Special rule for VISTA volunteersA VISTA volunteer who serves in an approved national service position shall be ineligible for a national service educational award if the VISTA volunteer accepts the stipend authorized under section 4955(a)(1) of this title.


(Pub. L. 101–610, title I, § 141, as added Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 101(b), Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 814.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 141 of Pub. L. 101–610 was classified to section 12571 of this title prior to the general amendment of subtitle D of title I of Pub. L. 101–610 [former part D of this subchapter] by Pub. L. 103–82, § 102(a).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1993, see section 123 of Pub. L. 103–82, set out as an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under section 1701 of Title 16, Conservation.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12595_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility generally</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility generally A participant in a national service program carried out using assistance provided to an applicant under section 12571 of this title shall be eligible for the national service educational award described in division D if the participant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12595_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for VISTA volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rule for VISTA volunteers A VISTA volunteer who serves in an approved national service position shall be ineligible for a national service educational award if the VISTA volunteer accepts the stipend authorized under section 4955(a)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>