<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12619" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12619/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12619/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12619"><akn:num>12619</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12619. Administrative provisions(a) SupervisionThe Chief Executive Officer shall monitor and supervise the administration of the National Civilian Community Corps Program authorized to be established under section 12612 of this title. In carrying out this section, the Chief Executive Officer shall—(1) approve such guidelines, including those recommended by the Board, for the design, selection of members, and operation of the National Civilian Community Corps as the Chief Executive Officer considers appropriate;

(2) evaluate the progress of the Corps in providing a basis for determining the matters set forth in section 12611 of this title; and

(3) carry out any other activities determined appropriate by the Board.


(b) Monitoring and coordinationThe Chief Executive Officer shall—(1) monitor the overall operation of the National Civilian Community Corps;

(2) coordinate the activities of the Corps with other youth service programs administered by the Corporation; and

(3) carry out any other activities determined appropriate by the Board.


(c) Staff(1) Director(A) AppointmentUpon the establishment of the Program, the Chief Executive Officer shall appoint a Director. The Director may be selected from among retired commissioned officers of the Armed Forces of the United States.


(B) DutiesThe Director shall—(i) design, develop, and administer the National Civilian Community Corps programs;

(ii) be responsible for managing the daily operations of the Corps; and

(iii) report to the Chief Executive Officer.


(C) Authority to employ staffThe Director may employ such staff as is necessary to carry out this division. The Director shall, to the maximum extent practicable, utilize in staff positions personnel who are detailed from departments and agencies of the Federal Government and, to the extent the Director considers appropriate, shall request and accept detail of personnel from such departments and agencies in order to do so.



(2) Permanent cadre(A) Establishm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12619_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supervision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Supervision The Chief Executive Officer shall monitor and supervise the administration of the National Civilian Community Corps Program authorized to be established under section 12612 of this title. In carrying out this section, the Chief Executive Officer shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12619_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Monitoring and coordination The Chief Executive Officer shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12619_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>