<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12615" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12615/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12615/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12615"><akn:num>12615</akn:num><akn:heading>National Civilian Community Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12615. National Civilian Community Corps(a) DirectorUpon the establishment of the National Civilian Community Corps Program, the National Civilian Community Corps shall be under the direction of the Director appointed pursuant to section 12619(c)(1) of this title.


(b) Membership in National Civilian Community Corps(1) Participants to be membersPersons selected to participate in the national service program or the summer national service program components of the Program shall become members of the National Civilian Community Corps.


(2) Selection of membersThe Director or the Director’s designee shall select individuals for membership in the Corps.


(3) Application for membershipTo be selected to become a Corps member an individual shall submit an application to the Director or to any other office as the Director may designate, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director shall require. At a minimum, the application shall contain information about the work experience of the applicant and sufficient information to enable the Director, or the campus director of the appropriate campus, to determine whether selection of the applicant for membership in the Corps is appropriate.


(4) Team leaders(A) In generalThe Director may select individuals with prior supervisory or service experience to be team leaders within units in the National Civilian Community Corps, to perform service that includes leading and supervising teams of Corps members. Each team leader shall be selected without regard to the age limitation under section 12613(b) of this title.


(B) Rights and benefitsA team leader shall be provided the same rights and benefits applicable to other Corps members, except that the Director may increase the limitation on the amount of the living allowance under section 12618(b) of this title by not more than 10 percent for a team leader.




(c) Organization of Corps into units(1) UnitsThe Corps shall be divided into permanent unit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Director Upon the establishment of the National Civilian Community Corps Program, the National Civilian Community Corps shall be under the direction of the Director appointed pursuant to section 12619(c)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership in National Civilian Community Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership in National Civilian Community Corps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization of Corps into units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Organization of Corps into units</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Campuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Campuses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of units and campuses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Distribution of units and campuses The Director shall ensure that the Corps units and campuses are cost effective and are distributed in urban areas and rural areas such that each Corps unit in a region can be easily deployed for disaster and emergency response to such region.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12615_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards of conduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Standards of conduct</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>