<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12622"><akn:num>12622</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12622. Responsibilities of Department of Defense(a) Liaison office(1) EstablishmentUpon the establishment of the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall establish an office to provide for liaison between the Secretary and the National Civilian Community Corps.


(2) DutiesThe office shall provide assistance in the coordination of Department of Defense activities with the Corps.



(b) Corps cadre(1) List of recommended personnelUpon the establishment of the Program, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the liaison office established under subsection (a) shall develop a list of individuals from which individuals may be selected for appointment by the Director in the permanent cadre of Corps personnel. Such personnel shall be selected from among members and former members of the Armed Forces referred to in section 12611(3) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title who are commissioned officers, noncommissioned officers, former commissioned officers, or former noncommissioned officers.


(2) Recommendations regarding grade and payThe Secretary of Defense shall recommend to the Director an appropriate rate of pay for each person recommended for the cadre pursuant to this subsection.


(3) Contribution for retired member’s payIf a listed individual receiving retired or retainer pay is appointed to a position in the cadre and the rate of pay for that individual is established at the amount equal to the difference between the active duty pay and allowances which that individual would receive if ordered to active duty and the amount of the individual’s retired or retainer pay, the Secretary of Defense shall pay, by transfer to the Corporation from amounts available for pay of active duty members of the Armed Forces, the amount equal to 50 percent of that individual’s rate of pay for service in the cadre.



(c) FacilitiesUpon the establishment of the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall identify military installations and other facilities of the Dep</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liaison office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liaison office</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corps cadre</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Corps cadre</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilities Upon the establishment of the Program, the Secretary of Defense shall identify military installations and other facilities of the Department of Defense and, in consultation with the adjutant generals of the State National Guards, National Guard facilities that may be used, in whole or in part, by the National Civilian Community Corps for training or housing Corps members. The Secretary of Defense shall carry out this subsection in consultation with the liaison office established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12622_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information regarding Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information regarding Corps The Secretary of Defense may permit Armed Forces recruiters to inform potential applicants for the Corps regarding service in the Corps as an alternative to service in the Armed Forces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>