<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12626"><akn:num>12626</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12626. Definitions
In this division:(1) BoardThe term “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Corporation.


(2) Campus directorThe term “campus director”, with respect to a Corps campus, means the head of the campus under section 12615(d) of this title.


(3) CorpsThe term “Corps” means the National Civilian Community Corps required under section 12615 of this title as part of the National Civilian Community Corps Program.


(4) Corps campusThe term “Corps campus” means the facility or central location established as the operational headquarters and boarding place for particular Corps units.


(5) Corps membersThe term “Corps members” means persons receiving training and participating in projects under the National Civilian Community Corps Program.


(6) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of the National Civilian Community Corps.


(7) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 1001 of title 20.


(8) ProgramThe term “Program” means the National Civilian Community Corps Program established pursuant to section 12612 of this title.


(9) Service-learningThe term “service-learning”, with respect to Corps members, means a method—(A) under which Corps members learn and develop through active participation in thoughtfully organized service experiences that meet actual community needs;

(B) that provides structured time for a Corps member to think, talk, or write about what the Corps member did and saw during an actual service activity;

(C) that provides Corps members with opportunities to use newly acquired skills and knowledge in real life situations in their own communities; and

(D) that helps to foster the development of a sense of caring for others, good citizenship, and civic responsibility.


(10) UnitThe term “unit” means a unit of the Corps referred to in section 12615(c) of this title.


(Pub. L. 101–610, title I, § 165, formerly § 195O, as added Pub. L. 102–484, div. A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Board The term “Board” means the Board of Directors of the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Campus director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Campus director The term “campus director”, with respect to a Corps campus, means the head of the campus under section 12615(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Corps The term “Corps” means the National Civilian Community Corps required under section 12615 of this title as part of the National Civilian Community Corps Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corps campus</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Corps campus The term “Corps campus” means the facility or central location established as the operational headquarters and boarding place for particular Corps units.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Corps members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Corps members The term “Corps members” means persons receiving training and participating in projects under the National Civilian Community Corps Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Director The term “Director” means the Director of the National Civilian Community Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given that term in section 1001 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Program The term “Program” means the National Civilian Community Corps Program established pursuant to section 12612 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service-learning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Service-learning The term “service-learning”, with respect to Corps members, means a method—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12626_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Unit The term “unit” means a unit of the Corps referred to in section 12615(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>