<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12631" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12631/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12631/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12631"><akn:num>12631</akn:num><akn:heading>Family and medical leave</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12631. Family and medical leave(a) Participants in private, State, and local projectsFor purposes of title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 [29 U.S.C. 2611 et seq.], if—(1) a participant has provided service for the period required by section 101(2)(A)(i) (29 U.S.C. 2611(2)(A)(i)), and has met the hours of service requirement of section 101(2)(A)(ii), of such Act with respect to a project authorized under the national service laws; and

(2) the service sponsor of the project is an employer described in section 101(4) of such Act (other than an employing agency within the meaning of subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5),


the participant shall be considered to be an eligible employee of the service sponsor.

(b) Participants in Federal projectsFor purposes of subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5, if—(1) a participant has provided service for the period required by section 6381(1)(B) of such title with respect to a project; and

(2) the service sponsor of the project is an employing agency within the meaning of such subchapter,


the participant shall be considered to be an employee of the service sponsor.

(c) Treatment of absenceThe period of any absence of a participant from a service position pursuant to title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 [29 U.S.C. 2611 et seq.] or subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5 shall not be counted toward the completion of the term of service of the participant under section 12593 of this title.


(Pub. L. 101–610, title I, § 171, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 3159; Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 113(a), Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 861; Pub. L. 111–13, title I, § 1601, Apr. 21, 2009, 123 Stat. 1529.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (c), is Pub. L. 103–3, Feb. 5, 1993, 107 Stat. 6. Title I of the Act is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 2611 et seq.) of chapter 28 of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Cod</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12631_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants in private, State, and local projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Participants in private, State, and local projects For purposes of title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 [29 U.S.C. 2611 et seq.], if— the participant shall be considered to be an eligible employee of the service sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12631_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants in Federal projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participants in Federal projects For purposes of subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5, if— the participant shall be considered to be an employee of the service sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12631_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of absence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment of absence The period of any absence of a participant from a service position pursuant to title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 [29 U.S.C. 2611 et seq.] or subchapter V of chapter 63 of title 5 shall not be counted toward the completion of the term of service of the participant under section 12593 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>