<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12638" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12638/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12638/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12638"><akn:num>12638</akn:num><akn:heading>State Commissions on National and Community Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12638. State Commissions on National and Community Service(a) Existence required(1) State CommissionExcept as provided in paragraph (2), to be eligible to receive a grant or allotment under division B or C or to receive a distribution of approved national service positions under division C, a State shall maintain a State Commission on National and Community Service that satisfies the requirements of this section.


(2) Alternative administrative entityThe chief executive officer of a State may apply to the Corporation for approval to use an alternative administrative entity to carry out the duties otherwise entrusted to a State Commission under this chapter. The chief executive officer shall ensure that any alternative administrative entity used in lieu of a State Commission provides for the individuals described in paragraph (1), and some of the individuals described in paragraph (2), of subsection (c) to play a significant policymaking role in carrying out the duties otherwise entrusted to a State Commission, including the submission of applications on behalf of the State under section 12582 of this title.



(b) Appointment and sizeExcept as provided in subsection (c)(3), the members of a State Commission for a State shall be appointed by the chief executive officer of the State. A State Commission shall consist of not fewer than 15, and not more than 25, voting members, and any ex officio nonvoting members, as described in paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (c).


(c) Composition and membership(1) Required membersThe State Commission for a State shall include as voting members at least one of each of the following individuals:(A) An individual with expertise in the educational, training, and development needs of youth, particularly disadvantaged youth.

(B) An individual with experience in promoting the involvement of older adults in service and voluntarism.

(C) A representative of community-based agencies or community-based organizations within the State.

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existence required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existence required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and size</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment and size Except as provided in subsection (c)(3), the members of a State Commission for a State shall be appointed by the chief executive officer of the State. A State Commission shall consist of not fewer than 15, and not more than 25, voting members, and any ex officio nonvoting members, as described in paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition and membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition and membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Miscellaneous matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of a State Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duties of a State Commission The State Commission or alternative administrative entity for a State shall be responsible for the following duties:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief from administrative requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Relief from administrative requirements Upon approval of a State plan submitted under subsection (e)(1), the Chief Executive Officer may waive for the State, or specify alternatives for the State to, administrative requirements (other than statutory provisions) otherwise applicable to grants made to States under the national service laws, including those requirements identified by the State as impeding the coordination and effectiveness of Federal, State, and local resources for service and volunteerism within the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State service plan for adults age 55 or older</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State service plan for adults age 55 or older</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activity ineligible for assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Activity ineligible for assistance A State Commission or alternative administrative entity may not directly carry out any national service program that receives assistance under section 12571 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Delegation Subject to such requirements as the Corporation may prescribe, a State Commission may delegate nonpolicymaking duties to a State agency or public or private nonprofit organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12638_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of State Commission or alternative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Approval of State Commission or alternative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>