<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12655f"><akn:num>12655f</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and education services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12655f. Training and education services(a) Assessment of skillsEach program agency shall assess the educational level of participants at the time of their entrance into the program, using any available records or simplified assessment means or methodology and shall, where appropriate, refer such participants for testing for specific learning disabilities.


(b) Enhancement of skillsEach program agency shall, through the programs and activities administered under this division, enhance the educational skills of participants.


(c) Provision of pre-service and in-service training and education(1) RequirementEach program agency shall use not less than 10 percent of the assistance made available to such agency under this division in each fiscal year to provide pre-service and in-service training and educational materials and services for participants in such a program. Program participants shall be provided with information concerning the benefits to the community that result from the activities undertaken by such participants.


(2) Agreements for academic studyA program agency may enter into arrangements with academic institutions or education providers, including—(A) local education agencies;

(B) community colleges;

(C) 4-year colleges;

(D) area vocational-technical schools; and

(E) community based organizations;


to evaluate the basic skills of participants and to make academic study available to participants to enable such participants to upgrade literacy skills, to obtain high school diplomas or the equivalent of such diplomas, to obtain college degrees, or to enhance employable skills.

(3) CounselingCareer and educational guidance and counseling shall be provided to a participant during a period of in-service training as described in this subsection. Each graduating participant shall be provided with counseling with respect to additional study, job skills training or employment and shall be provided job placement assistance where appropriate.


(4) Priori</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12655f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of skills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment of skills Each program agency shall assess the educational level of participants at the time of their entrance into the program, using any available records or simplified assessment means or methodology and shall, where appropriate, refer such participants for testing for specific learning disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12655f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancement of skills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enhancement of skills Each program agency shall, through the programs and activities administered under this division, enhance the educational skills of participants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12655f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of pre-service and in-service training and education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of pre-service and in-service training and education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12655f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standards and procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>