<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12655/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12655"><akn:num>12655</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12655. General authority
The Corporation may make grants to States or local applicants and may transfer funds to the Secretary of Agriculture or to the Secretary of the Interior for the creation or expansion of full-time, part-time, year-round, or summer, youth corps programs 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period. To the extent practicable, the Corporation shall apply the provisions of division C in making grants under this section.
(Pub. L. 101–610, title I, § 199A, formerly § 121, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 3140; Pub. L. 102–384, § 5, Oct. 5, 1992, 106 Stat. 1455; renumbered § 199A and amended Pub. L. 103–82, title I, § 101(a), (e)(1), (2), Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 788, 815.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was formerly classified to section 12541 of this title prior to renumbering by Pub. L. 103–82, § 101(a).

Amendments1993—Pub. L. 103–82, § 101(e)(1), (2), substituted “Corporation” for “Commission”, substituted “or to the Secretary of the Interior” for “, to the Secretary of the Interior, or to the Director of ACTION”, struck out “under section 12512 of this title” after “may make grants”, and inserted at end “To the extent practicable, the Corporation shall apply the provisions of division C in making grants under this section.”
1992—Pub. L. 102–384 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section read as follows: “The Commission may make grants under section 12512 of this title to States or local applicants, to the Secretary of Agriculture, to the Secretary of the Interior, or to the Director of ACTION for the creation or expansion of full-time or summer youth corps programs.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1993 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 103–82 effective Oct. 1, 1993, see section 123 of Pub. L. 103–82, set out as a note under section 1701 of Title 16, Conservation.

Short TitleFor short title of subtitle I of title I of Pub. L. 101–610 which enacted this division, as the American Conservation </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>