<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12653c"><akn:num>12653c</akn:num><akn:heading>Silver Scholarships and Encore Fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12653c. Silver Scholarships and Encore Fellowships(a) Silver Scholarship Grant Program(1) EstablishmentThe Corporation may award fixed-amount grants (in accordance with section 12581(l) of this title) to community-based entities to carry out a Silver Scholarship Grant Program for individuals age 55 or older, in which such individuals complete not less than 350 hours of service in a year carrying out projects of national need and receive a Silver Scholarship in the form of a $1,000 national service educational award. Under such a program, the Corporation shall establish criteria for the types of the 11 So in original. service required to be performed to receive such award.


(2) TermEach program funded under this subsection shall be carried out over a period of 3 years (which may include 1 planning year), with a 1-year extension possible, if the program meets performance levels developed in accordance with section 12639(k) of this title and any other criteria determined by the Corporation.


(3) ApplicationsTo be eligible for a grant under this subsection, a community-based entity shall—(A) submit to the Corporation an application at such time and in such manner as the Chief Executive Officer may reasonably require; and

(B) be a listed organization as described in subsection (b)(4).


(4) Collaboration encouragedA community-based entity awarded a grant under this subsection is encouraged to collaborate with programs funded under title II of the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 [42 U.S.C. 5001 et seq.] in carrying out this program.


(5) Eligibility for fellowshipAn individual is eligible to receive a Silver Scholarship if the community-based entity certifies to the Corporation that the individual has completed not less than 350 hours of service under this section in a 1-year period.


(6) Transfer to trustThe Corporation shall transfer an appropriate amount of funds to the National Service Trust to provide for the national service educational award for each </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Silver Scholarship Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Silver Scholarship Grant Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encore Fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Encore Fellowships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Evaluations The Corporation shall conduct an independent evaluation of the programs authorized under subsections (a) and (b) and widely disseminate the results, including recommendations for improvement, to the service community through multiple channels, including the Corporation’s Resource Center or a clearinghouse of effective strategies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>