<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12653p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12653p"><akn:num>12653p</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer generation fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12653p. Volunteer generation fund(a) Grants authorizedSubject to the availability of appropriations for this section, the Corporation may make grants to State Commissions and nonprofit organizations for the purpose of assisting the State Commissions and nonprofit organizations to—(1) develop and carry out volunteer programs described in subsection (c); and

(2) make subgrants to support and create new local community-based entities that recruit, manage, or support volunteers as described in such subsection.


(b) Application(1) In generalEach State Commission or nonprofit organization desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Corporation at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Corporation may reasonably require.


(2) ContentsEach application submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall contain—(A)(i) 11 So in original. No cl. (ii) has been enacted. a description of the program that the applicant will provide;


(B) an assurance that the applicant will annually collect information on—(i) the number of volunteers recruited for activities carried out under this section, using funds received under this section, and the type and amount of activities carried out by such volunteers; and

(ii) the number of volunteers managed or supported using funds received under this section, and the type and amount of activities carried out by such volunteers;


(C) a description of the outcomes the applicant will use to annually measure and track performance with regard to—(i) activities carried out by volunteers; and

(ii) volunteers recruited, managed, or supported; and


(D) such additional assurances as the Corporation determines to be essential to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section.



(c) Eligible volunteer programsA State Commission or nonprofit organization receiving a grant under this section shall use the assistance—(1) directly to carry out volunteer programs or to develop and support communit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized Subject to the availability of appropriations for this section, the Corporation may make grants to State Commissions and nonprofit organizations for the purpose of assisting the State Commissions and nonprofit organizations to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible volunteer programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible volunteer programs A State Commission or nonprofit organization receiving a grant under this section shall use the assistance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on administrative costs Not more than 5 percent of the amount of any grant provided under this section for a fiscal year may be used to pay for administrative costs incurred by either the recipient of the grant or any community-based entity receiving assistance or a subgrant under such grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12653p_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching fund requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching fund requirements The Corporation share of the cost of carrying out a program that receives assistance under this section, whether the assistance is provided directly or as a subgrant from the original recipient of the assistance, may not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>