<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12671" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12671/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12671/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12671"><akn:num>12671</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12671. Projects(a) DefinitionIn this section, the term “administrative organization” means a nonprofit private organization that enters into an agreement with the Corporation to carry out this section.


(b) Identification of projects(1) Estimated numberNot later than March 1, 2002, the administrative organization, after obtaining the guidance of the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, such as the Director of the Office of Homeland Security and the Attorney General, shall—(A) make an estimate of the number of victims killed as a result of the terrorist attacks on September 11, 2001 (referred to in this section as the “estimated number”); and

(B) compile a list that specifies, for each individual that the administrative organization determines to be such a victim, the name of the victim and the State in which the victim resided.


(2) Identified projectsThe administrative organization may identify approximately the estimated number of community-based national and community service projects that meet the requirements of subsection (d). The administrative organization may name projects in honor of victims described in subsection (b)(1)(A), after obtaining the permission of an appropriate member of the victim’s family and the entity carrying out the project.



(c) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to have a project named under this section, the entity carrying out the project shall be a political subdivision of a State, a business, a nonprofit organization (which may be a religious organization), an Indian tribe, or an institution of higher education.


(d) ProjectsThe administrative organization shall name, under this section, projects—(1) that advance the goals of unity, and improving the quality of life in communities; and

(2) that will be planned, or for which implementation will begin, within a reasonable period after January 10, 2002, as determined by the administrative organization.


(e) Website and databaseThe administrative organization shall create and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12671_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this section, the term “administrative organization” means a nonprofit private organization that enters into an agreement with the Corporation to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12671_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12671_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities To be eligible to have a project named under this section, the entity carrying out the project shall be a political subdivision of a State, a business, a nonprofit organization (which may be a religious organization), an Indian tribe, or an institution of higher education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12671_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects The administrative organization shall name, under this section, projects—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12671_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Website and database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Website and database The administrative organization shall create and maintain websites and databases, to describe projects named under this section and serve as appropriate vehicles for recognizing the projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>