<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12681" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12681/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12681/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12681"><akn:num>12681</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12681. Authorization of appropriations(a) Subchapter I(1) Division B(A) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated to provide financial assistance under division B of subchapter I—(i) $97,000,000 for fiscal year 2010; and

(ii) such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2014.


(B) Part IV reservationOf the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) for a fiscal year, the Corporation may reserve such sums as may be necessary to carry out part IV of division B of subchapter I.


(C) Section 12561aOf the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) and not reserved under subparagraph (B) for a fiscal year, not more than $7,000,000 shall be made available for awards to Campuses of Service under section 12561a of this title.


(D) Section 12563(c)(8)Of the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) and not reserved under subparagraph (B) for a fiscal year, not more than $10,000,000 shall be made available for summer of service program grants under section 12563(c)(8) of this title, and not more than $10,000,000 shall be deposited in the National Service Trust to support summer of service educational awards, consistent with section 12563(c)(8) of this title.


(E) Section 12563(c)(9)Of the amount appropriated under subparagraph (A) and not reserved under subparagraph (B) for a fiscal year, not more than $20,000,000 shall be made available for youth engagement zone programs under section 12563(c)(9) of this title.


(F) General programsOf the amount remaining after the application of subparagraphs (A) through (E) for a fiscal year—(i) not more than 60 percent shall be available to provide financial assistance under part I of division B of subchapter I;

(ii) not more than 25 percent shall be available to provide financial assistance under part II of such division; and

(iii) not less than 15 percent shall be available to provide financial assistance under part III of such division.



(2) Divisions C and DThere are authorized to be appropri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12681_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subchapter I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subchapter I</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12681_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of appropriations Funds appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>