<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12705c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12705c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12705c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12705c"><akn:num>12705c</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for regulatory barrier removal strategies and implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12705c. Grants for regulatory barrier removal strategies and implementation(a) FundingThere is authorized to be appropriated for grants under subsections (b) and (c) 11 See References in Text note below. such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2005.


(b) Grant authorityThe Secretary may make grants to States and units of general local government (including consortia of such governments) for the costs of developing and implementing strategies to remove regulatory barriers to affordable housing, including the costs of—(1) identifying, assessing, and monitoring State and local regulatory barriers;

(2) identifying State and local policies (including laws and regulations) that permit or encourage regulatory barriers;

(3) developing legislation to provide State, local, or regional programs to reduce regulatory barriers and developing a strategy for adoption of such legislation;

(4) developing model State or local standards and ordinances to reduce regulatory barriers and assisting in the adoption and use of the standards and ordinances;

(5) carrying out the simplification and consolidation of administrative procedures and processes constituting regulatory barriers to affordable housing, including the issuance of permits; and

(6) providing technical assistance and information to units of general local government for implementation of legislative and administrative reform programs to remove regulatory barriers to affordable housing.


(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–569, title I, § 102(c), Dec. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 2947

(d) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section, the terms “regulatory barriers to affordable housing” and “regulatory barriers” have the meaning given such terms in section 12705b of this title.


(e) Application and selectionThe Secretary shall provide for the form and manner of applications for grants under this section, which shall describe how grant amounts will assist the State or unit of general local governmen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Funding There is authorized to be appropriated for grants under subsections (b) and (c) 11 See References in Text note below. such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2001, 2002, 2003, 2004, and 2005.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant authority The Secretary may make grants to States and units of general local government (including consortia of such governments) for the costs of developing and implementing strategies to remove regulatory barriers to affordable housing, including the costs of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 106–569, title I, § 102(c), Dec. 27, 2000, 114 Stat. 2947</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section, the terms “regulatory barriers to affordable housing” and “regulatory barriers” have the meaning given such terms in section 12705b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application and selection The Secretary shall provide for the form and manner of applications for grants under this section, which shall describe how grant amounts will assist the State or unit of general local government in developing and implementing strategies to remove regulatory barriers to affordable housing. The Secretary shall establish criteria for approval of applications under this subsection and such criteria shall require that grant amounts be used in a manner consistent with the strategy contained in the comprehensive housing affordability strategy for the jurisdiction pursuant to section 12705(b)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of grantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Selection of grantees To the extent amounts are made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall provide grants on a competitive basis to eligible grantees based on the proposed uses of such amounts, as provided in applications under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with clearinghouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination with clearinghouse Each State and unit of general local government receiving a grant under this section, shall consult, coordinate, and exchange information with the clearinghouse established under section 12705d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12705c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports to Secretary Each State and unit of general local government receiving a grant under this section shall submit a report to the Secretary, not less than 12 months after receiving the grant, describing any activities carried out with the grant amounts. The report shall contain an assessment of the impact of any regulatory barriers identified by the grantee on the housing patterns of minorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>