<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12746" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12746/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12746/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12746"><akn:num>12746</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation by States and local governments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12746. Participation by States and local governments
The Secretary shall designate a State or unit of general local government to be a participating jurisdiction when it complies with procedures that the Secretary shall establish by regulation, which procedures shall only provide for the following:(1) AllocationNot later than 20 days after funds to carry out this part become available (or, during the first year after November 28, 1990, not later than 20 days after (A) funds to carry out this part are provided in an appropriations Act, or (B) regulations to implement this part are promulgated, whichever is later), the Secretary shall allocate funds in accordance with section 12747 of this title and promptly notify each jurisdiction receiving a formula allocation of its allocation amount. If a jurisdiction is not already a participating jurisdiction, the Secretary shall inform the jurisdiction in writing how the jurisdiction may become a participating jurisdiction.


(2) ConsortiaA consortium of geographically contiguous units of general local government shall be deemed to be a unit of general local government for purposes of this subchapter if the Secretary determines that the consortium—(A) has sufficient authority and administrative capability to carry out the purposes of this subchapter on behalf of its member jurisdictions, and

(B) will, according to a written certification by the State (or States, if the consortium includes jurisdictions in more than one State), direct its activities to alleviation of housing problems within the State or States.


(3) Eligibility(A) Except as provided in paragraph (10), a jurisdiction receiving a formula allocation under section 12747 of this title shall be eligible to become a participating jurisdiction if its formula allocation is $750,000 or greater, or if the Secretary finds that—(i) the jurisdiction has a local housing authority and has demonstrated a capacity to carry out provisions of this part, and

(ii) the State has</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Allocation Not later than 20 days after funds to carry out this part become available (or, during the first year after November 28, 1990, not later than 20 days after (A) funds to carry out this part are provided in an appropriations Act, or (B) regulations to implement this part are promulgated, whichever is later), the Secretary shall allocate funds in accordance with section 12747 of this title and promptly notify each jurisdiction receiving a formula allocation of its allocation amount. If a jurisdiction is not already a participating jurisdiction, the Secretary shall inform the jurisdiction in writing how the jurisdiction may become a participating jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Consortia A consortium of geographically contiguous units of general local government shall be deemed to be a unit of general local government for purposes of this subchapter if the Secretary determines that the consortium—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Notification If an eligible jurisdiction notifies the Secretary in writing, not later than 30 days after receiving notification under paragraph (1), of its intention to become a participating jurisdiction, the Secretary shall reserve an amount equal to the jurisdiction’s allocation (plus any reallocations for which the jurisdiction is eligible under section 12747(d)(1) of this title) pending the jurisdiction’s designation as a participating jurisdiction. The Secretary shall reallocate, in accordance with paragraph (6) of this section, any funds reserved under the previous sentence if the Secretary determines that the jurisdiction will not meet the requirements for designation as a participating jurisdiction within a reasonable period of time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Submission of strategy Not later than 90 days after providing notification under paragraph (4), an eligible jurisdiction shall submit to the Secretary a comprehensive housing affordability strategy in accordance with section 12705 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Reallocation If the Secretary determines that a jurisdiction has failed to meet the requirements of the previous 3 paragraphs or if the Secretary, after providing for amendments and resubmissions in accordance with section 12705(c)(3) of this title, disapproves the jurisdiction’s comprehensive housing affordability strategy, the Secretary shall reallocate any funds reserved for the jurisdiction as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Designation The Secretary shall designate an eligible jurisdiction to be a participating jurisdiction as soon as its comprehensive housing affordability strategy is approved in accordance with section 12705 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuous designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Continuous designation Once a State or unit of general local government is designated a participating jurisdiction, it shall remain a participating jurisdiction for subsequent fiscal years, except as provided in paragraph (9). The provisions of paragraphs (3) through (6) shall not apply to participating jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Revocation The Secretary may revoke a jurisdiction’s designation as a participating jurisdiction if— If a jurisdiction’s designation as a participating jurisdiction is revoked, any remaining line of credit in the jurisdiction’s HOME Investment Trust Fund established under section 12748 of this title shall be reallocated in accordance with paragraph (6) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12746_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Threshold reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Threshold reduction If the amount appropriated pursuant to section 12724 of this title for any fiscal year is less than $1,500,000,000, then this section shall be applied during that year—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>