<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12742" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12742/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12742/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12742"><akn:num>12742</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible uses of investment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12742. Eligible uses of investment(a) Housing uses(1) In generalFunds made available under this part may be used by participating jurisdictions to provide incentives to develop and support affordable rental housing and homeownership affordability through the acquisition, new construction, reconstruction, or moderate or substantial rehabilitation of affordable housing, including real property acquisition, site improvement, conversion, demolition, and other expenses, including financing costs, relocation expenses of any displaced persons, families, businesses, or organizations, to provide for the payment of reasonable administrative and planning costs, to provide for the payment of operating expenses of community housing development organizations, and to provide tenant-based rental assistance. For the purpose of this part, the term “affordable housing” includes permanent housing for disabled homeless persons, transitional housing, and single room occupancy housing.


(2) Preference to rehabilitationA participating jurisdiction shall give preference to rehabilitation of substandard housing unless the jurisdiction determines that—(A) such rehabilitation is not the most cost effective way to meet the jurisdiction’s need to expand the supply of affordable housing; and

(B) the jurisdiction’s housing needs cannot be met through rehabilitation of the available stock.


The Secretary shall not restrict a participating jurisdiction’s choice of rehabilitation, substantial rehabilitation, new construction, reconstruction, acquisition, or other eligible housing use unless such restriction is explicitly authorized under section 12753(2) of this title.

(3) Tenant-based rental assistance(A) In generalA participating jurisdiction may use funds provided under this part for tenant-based rental assistance only if—(i) the jurisdiction certifies that the use of funds under this part for tenant-based rental assistance is an essential element of the jurisdiction’s annual housing strateg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Housing uses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investments Participating jurisdictions shall have discretion to invest funds made available under this part as equity investments, interest-bearing loans or advances, noninterest-bearing loans or advances, interest subsidies or other forms of assistance that the Secretary has determined to be consistent with the purposes of this subchapter. Each participating jurisdiction shall have the right to establish the terms of assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative costs In each fiscal year, each participating jurisdiction may use not more than 10 percent of the funds made available under this part to the jurisdiction for such year for any administrative and planning costs of the jurisdiction in carrying out this part, including the costs of the salaries of persons engaged in administering and managing activities assisted with funds made available under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibited uses Funds made available under this part may not be used to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certification of compliance The requirements of section 3545(d) of this title shall be satisfied by a certification by a participating jurisdiction to the Secretary that the combination of Federal assistance provided to any housing project shall not be any more than is necessary to provide affordable housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12742_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on operating assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on operating assistance A participating jurisdiction may not use more than 5 percent of its allocation under this part for the payment of operating expenses for community housing development organizations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>