<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12750" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12750/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12750/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12750"><akn:num>12750</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12750. Matching requirements(a) ContributionEach participating jurisdiction shall make contributions to housing that qualifies as affordable housing under this subchapter that total, throughout a fiscal year, not less than 25 percent of the funds drawn from the jurisdiction’s HOME Investment Trust Fund in such fiscal year. Such contributions shall be in addition to any amounts made available under section 12746(3)(A)(ii) of this title.


(b) Recognition(1) In generalA contribution shall be recognized for purposes of subsection (a) only if it—(A) is made with respect to housing that qualifies as affordable housing under section 12745 of this title; or

(B) is made with respect to any portion of a project not less than 50 percent of the units of which qualify as affordable housing under section 12745 of this title.


(2) Administrative expensesContributions for administrative expenses may not be recognized for purposes of subsection (a).



(c) FormSuch contributions may be in the form of—(1) cash contributions from non-Federal resources, which may not include funds from a grant made under section 5306(b) or section 5306(d) of this title;

(2) the value of taxes, fees, or other charges that are normally and customarily imposed but are waived, foregone, or deferred in a manner that achieves affordability of housing assisted under this subchapter;

(3) the value of land or other real property as appraised according to procedures acceptable to the Secretary;

(4) the value of investment in on-site and off-site infrastructure directly required for affordable housing assisted under this subchapter;

(5) Redesignated (4)

(6) up to—(A) 50 percent of proceeds from bond financing validly issued by a State or local government, agency or instrumentality thereof, or political subdivision thereof, and repayable with revenues derived from a multifamily affordable housing project financed, and

(B) 25 percent of proceeds from bond financing validly issued by a State or local gove</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12750_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contribution Each participating jurisdiction shall make contributions to housing that qualifies as affordable housing under this subchapter that total, throughout a fiscal year, not less than 25 percent of the funds drawn from the jurisdiction’s HOME Investment Trust Fund in such fiscal year. Such contributions shall be in addition to any amounts made available under section 12746(3)(A)(ii) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12750_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recognition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12750_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Form Such contributions may be in the form of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12750_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reduction of requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>