<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12752" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12752/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12752/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12752"><akn:num>12752</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12752. Distribution of assistance(a) LocalEach participating jurisdiction shall, insofar as is feasible, distribute assistance under this part geographically within its boundaries and among different categories of housing need, according to the priorities of housing need identified in the jurisdiction’s approved housing strategy.


(b) StateParticipating States shall be responsible for distributing assistance throughout the State according to the State’s assessment of the geographical distribution of the housing need within the State, as identified in the State’s approved housing strategy. Participating States shall distribute assistance to rural areas in amounts that take into account the nonmetropolitan share of the State’s total population and objective measures of rural housing need, such as poverty and substandard housing, as set forth in the State’s housing strategy approved under section 12705 of this title. To the extent the need is within the boundaries of a participating unit of general local government, the State and the unit of general local government shall coordinate activities to address that need.


(Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 222, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4112.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12752_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Local Each participating jurisdiction shall, insofar as is feasible, distribute assistance under this part geographically within its boundaries and among different categories of housing need, according to the priorities of housing need identified in the jurisdiction’s approved housing strategy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12752_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State Participating States shall be responsible for distributing assistance throughout the State according to the State’s assessment of the geographical distribution of the housing need within the State, as identified in the State’s approved housing strategy. Participating States shall distribute assistance to rural areas in amounts that take into account the nonmetropolitan share of the State’s total population and objective measures of rural housing need, such as poverty and substandard housing, as set forth in the State’s housing strategy approved under section 12705 of this title. To the extent the need is within the boundaries of a participating unit of general local government, the State and the unit of general local government shall coordinate activities to address that need.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>