<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12774" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12774/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12774/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12774"><akn:num>12774</akn:num><akn:heading>Other requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12774. Other requirements(a) Tenant participation planA community housing development organization that receives assistance under this part shall provide a plan for and follow a program of tenant participation in management decisions and shall adhere to a fair lease and grievance procedure approved by the participating jurisdiction.


(b) Limitation on assistanceA community housing development organization may not receive assistance under this subchapter for any fiscal year in an amount that provides more than 50 percent of the organization’s total operating budget in the fiscal year or $50,000 annually, whichever is greater.


(c) Adjustments of other assistanceThe Secretary shall take account of assistance provided to a project under this part when adjusting other assistance to be provided to the project as required by section 3545(d) of this title.


(Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 234, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4117; Pub. L. 102–550, title II, § 212(c), Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3757.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 102–550 struck out “, together with other Federal assistance,” after “in an amount that” and inserted before period “or $50,000 annually, whichever is greater”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1992 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 102–550 applicable to unexpended funds allocated under subchapter II of this chapter in fiscal year 1992, except as otherwise specifically provided, see section 223 of Pub. L. 102–550, set out as a note under section 12704 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12774_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant participation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Tenant participation plan A community housing development organization that receives assistance under this part shall provide a plan for and follow a program of tenant participation in management decisions and shall adhere to a fair lease and grievance procedure approved by the participating jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12774_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on assistance A community housing development organization may not receive assistance under this subchapter for any fiscal year in an amount that provides more than 50 percent of the organization’s total operating budget in the fiscal year or $50,000 annually, whichever is greater.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12774_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments of other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments of other assistance The Secretary shall take account of assistance provided to a project under this part when adjusting other assistance to be provided to the project as required by section 3545(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>