<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12802" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12802/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12802/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12802"><akn:num>12802</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental housing production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12802. Rental housing production(a) Repayable advances(1) In generalThe Secretary shall make available a model program under which repayable advances may be made to public and private project sponsors in constructing, acquiring, or substantially rehabilitating projects to be used as affordable rental housing, including limited equity cooperatives and mutual housing.


(2) Maximum amount of advanceAn advance under this model program shall not exceed 50 percent of the total costs associated with the construction, acquisition, or substantial rehabilitation of the project, as determined by the participating jurisdiction.


(3) Terms of repayment(A) Interest payments(i) In generalUnder the model program, advances shall be repaid with interest calculated at a rate of not more than 3 percent per year, as determined by the participating jurisdiction to be appropriate. Interest shall begin to accrue 1 year after the completion of the construction, acquisition, or substantial rehabilitation of the project and shall be payable in annual installments.


(ii) ExceptionInterest and any accrued interest shall be payable only from the surplus cash flow of the project, after a minimum return on equity determined by the participating jurisdiction to be appropriate. As used in the previous sentence, the term “surplus cash flow” means the cash flow of the project after the payment of all amounts due under the first mortgage, operating expenses, and required replacement reserves, as determined by the participating jurisdiction.



(B) Additional interest paymentsUnder the model program, for any year in which the sum of the surplus cash flow of a project and the return on equity exceeds all interest payments due under subparagraph (A), 50 percent of the excess surplus cash flow shall be paid to the participating jurisdiction’s HOME Investment Trust Fund as additional interest.


(C) Principal and unpaid interestThe principal amount of an advance under the model program, and any interes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12802_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayable advances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repayable advances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12802_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12802_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Guidelines The Secretary shall publish guidelines for the model program under this section not later than 180 days after November 28, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>