<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12810" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12810/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12810/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12810"><akn:num>12810</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-saving building technologies and construction techniques</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12810. Cost-saving building technologies and construction techniques(a) In generalThe Secretary shall make available a model program to utilize cost-saving building technologies and construction techniques for purposes of providing homeownership and rental opportunities under this subchapter.


(b) Selection criteriaThe Secretary shall establish criteria for participating jurisdictions to select projects for assistance under the model program which may include—(1) the extent to which innovative, cost-saving building and construction technologies are utilized;

(2) the extent to which innovative, cost-saving construction techniques are utilized;

(3) the extent to which units will be made available to low-income families and individuals;

(4) the extent to which non-Federal public or private assistance is utilized; and

(5) any other factor, determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.


(c) GuidelinesThe Secretary shall publish guidelines for the model program under this section not later than 180 days after October 28, 1992.


(d) ReportThe Secretary shall submit a biennial report to the Congress on the utilization of the model program under this section.


(Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 260, as added Pub. L. 102–550, title II, § 216, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3760.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable to unexpended funds allocated under subchapter II of this chapter in fiscal year 1992, except as otherwise specifically provided, see section 223 of Pub. L. 102–550, set out as an Effective Date of 1992 Amendment note under section 12704 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12810_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall make available a model program to utilize cost-saving building technologies and construction techniques for purposes of providing homeownership and rental opportunities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12810_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection criteria The Secretary shall establish criteria for participating jurisdictions to select projects for assistance under the model program which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12810_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Guidelines The Secretary shall publish guidelines for the model program under this section not later than 180 days after October 28, 1992.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12810_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report The Secretary shall submit a biennial report to the Congress on the utilization of the model program under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>