<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12831" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12831/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12831/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12831"><akn:num>12831</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal opportunity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12831. Equal opportunity(a) Solicitation of contractsEach participating jurisdiction shall prescribe procedures acceptable to the Secretary to establish and oversee a minority outreach program within each such jurisdiction to ensure the inclusion, to the maximum extent possible, of minorities and women, and entities owned by minorities and women, including, without limitation, real estate firms, construction firms, appraisal firms, management firms, financial institutions, investment banking firms, underwriters, accountants, and providers of legal services, in all contracts, entered into by the participating jurisdiction with such persons or entities, public and private, in order to facilitate the activities of the participating jurisdiction to provide affordable housing authorized under this Act or any other Federal housing law applicable to such jurisdiction.


(b) Report to CongressBefore the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the first allocation of funds is made under section 12747 of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report containing a description of the actions taken by each participating jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (a) and such recommendations for administrative and legislative action as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate to carry out the purposes of such subsection.


(Pub. L. 101–625, title II, § 281, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4125.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 101–625, Nov. 28, 1990, 104 Stat. 4079, known as the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 12701 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12831_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Solicitation of contracts Each participating jurisdiction shall prescribe procedures acceptable to the Secretary to establish and oversee a minority outreach program within each such jurisdiction to ensure the inclusion, to the maximum extent possible, of minorities and women, and entities owned by minorities and women, including, without limitation, real estate firms, construction firms, appraisal firms, management firms, financial institutions, investment banking firms, underwriters, accountants, and providers of legal services, in all contracts, entered into by the participating jurisdiction with such persons or entities, public and private, in order to facilitate the activities of the participating jurisdiction to provide affordable housing authorized under this Act or any other Federal housing law applicable to such jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12831_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report to Congress Before the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date the first allocation of funds is made under section 12747 of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report containing a description of the actions taken by each participating jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (a) and such recommendations for administrative and legislative action as the Secretary may determine to be appropriate to carry out the purposes of such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>