<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12852" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12852/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12852/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12852"><akn:num>12852</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for first-time homebuyers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12852. Assistance for first-time homebuyers(a) In generalThe Trust shall provide assistance payments for first-time homebuyers (including homebuyers buying shares in limited equity cooperatives) in the following manners:(1) Interest rate buydownsAssistance payments so that the rate of interest payable on the mortgages by the homebuyers does not exceed 6 percent.


(2) Downpayment assistanceAssistance payments to provide amounts for downpayments (including closing costs and other costs payable at the time of closing) on mortgages for such homebuyers.


(3) Assistance in connection with mortgage revenue bonds financingInterest rate buydowns and downpayment assistance in the manner provided in subsection (e).


(4) Second mortgage assistanceAssistance payments to provide loans (secured by second mortgages) with deferred payment of interest and principal; and 11 So in original. The “; and” probably should be a period.


(5) Capitalization of revolving loan fundsGrants to public organizations or agencies to establish revolving loan funds to provide homeownership assistance to eligible first-time homebuyers consistent with the requirements of this subchapter. Such grants shall be matched by an equal amount of local investment in such revolving loan funds. Any proceeds or repayments from loans made under this paragraph shall be returned to the revolving loan fund established under this paragraph to be used for purposes related to this section.



(b) Eligibility requirementsAssistance payments under this subchapter may be made only to homebuyers and for mortgages meeting the following requirements:(1) First-time homebuyerThe homebuyer is an individual who—(A) (and whose spouse) has had no ownership in a principal residence during the 3-year period ending on the date of purchase of the property with respect to which assistance payments are made under this subchapter;

(B) is a displaced homemaker who, except for owning a home with his or her spouse or residing in a home o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12852_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Trust shall provide assistance payments for first-time homebuyers (including homebuyers buying shares in limited equity cooperatives) in the following manners:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12852_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility requirements Assistance payments under this subchapter may be made only to homebuyers and for mortgages meeting the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12852_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12852_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation formula</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation formula Amounts available in any fiscal year for assistance under this subchapter shall be allocated for homebuyers in each State on the basis of the need of eligible first-time homebuyers in each State for such assistance in comparison with the need of eligible first-time homebuyers for such assistance among all States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12852_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance in connection with housing financed with mortgage revenue bonds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance in connection with housing financed with mortgage revenue bonds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>