<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12898a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12898a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12898a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12898a"><akn:num>12898a</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise zone homeownership opportunity grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12898a. Enterprise zone homeownership opportunity grants(a) Statement of purposeIt is the purpose of this section—(1) to encourage homeownership by families in the United States who are not otherwise able to afford homeownership;

(2) to encourage the redevelopment of economically depressed areas; and

(3) to provide better housing opportunities in federally approved and equivalent State-approved enterprise zones.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section the following definitions shall apply:(1) HomeThe term “home” means any 1- to 4-family dwelling. Such term includes any dwelling unit in a condominium project or cooperative project consisting of not more than 4 dwelling units, any town house, and any manufactured home.


(2) Metropolitan statistical areaThe term “metropolitan statistical area” means a metropolitan statistical area as established by the Office of Management and Budget.


(3) Nonprofit organizationThe term “nonprofit organization” means a private nonprofit corporation, or other private nonprofit legal entity, that is approved by the Secretary as to financial responsibility.


(4) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.


(5) StateThe term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.


(6) Unit of general local governmentThe term “unit of general local government” means any borough, city, county, parish, town, township, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State.



(c) Assistance to nonprofit organizations(1) In generalThe Secretary may provide assistance to nonprofit organizations to carry out enterprise zone homeownership opportunity programs to promote homeownership in federally approved and equivalent State-approved enterprise zones in accordanc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Statement of purpose It is the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to nonprofit organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to nonprofit organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible uses of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible uses of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Terms and conditions of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program selection criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Regulations Not later than 180 days after October 28, 1992, the Secretary shall issue final regulations to carry out the provisions of this title.22 So in original. Probably should be “this section.” Any such regulations shall be issued in accordance with section 553 of title 5, notwithstanding the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12898a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $30,000,000 in each of fiscal years 1993 and 1994.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>