<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12892" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12892/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12892/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12892"><akn:num>12892</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12892. Planning grants(a) GrantsThe Secretary is authorized to make planning grants to applicants for the purpose of developing homeownership programs under this part. The amount of a planning grant under this section may not exceed $200,000, except that the Secretary may for good cause approve a grant in a higher amount.


(b) Eligible activitiesPlanning grants may be used for activities to develop homeownership programs (which may include programs for cooperative ownership), including—(1) identifying eligible properties;

(2) training and technical assistance of applicants related to the development of a specific homeownership program;

(3) studies of the feasibility of specific homeownership programs;

(4) inspection for lead-based paint hazards, as required by section 4822(a) of this title;

(5) preliminary architectural and engineering work;

(6) homebuyer counseling and training;

(7) planning for economic development, job training, and self-sufficiency activities that promote economic self-sufficiency for homebuyers and homeowners under the homeownership program;

(8) development of security plans; and

(9) preparation of an application for an implementation grant under this part.


(c) Application(1) Form and proceduresAn application for a planning grant shall be submitted by an applicant in such form and in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall establish.


(2) Minimum requirementsThe Secretary shall require that an application contain at a minimum—(A) a request for a planning grant, specifying the activities proposed to be carried out, the schedule for completing the activities, the personnel necessary to complete the activities, and the amount of the grant requested;

(B) a description of the applicant and a statement of its qualifications;

(C) identification and description of the eligible properties likely to be involved, and a description of the composition of the potential homebuyers and residents of the areas in which such eligibl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12892_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants The Secretary is authorized to make planning grants to applicants for the purpose of developing homeownership programs under this part. The amount of a planning grant under this section may not exceed $200,000, except that the Secretary may for good cause approve a grant in a higher amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12892_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible activities Planning grants may be used for activities to develop homeownership programs (which may include programs for cooperative ownership), including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12892_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12892_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection criteria The Secretary shall, by regulation, establish selection criteria for a national competition for assistance under this section, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>