<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12894" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12894/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12894/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12894"><akn:num>12894</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeownership program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12894. Homeownership program requirements(a) In generalA homeownership program under this part shall provide for acquisition by eligible families of ownership interests in, or shares representing, units in an eligible property under any arrangement determined by the Secretary to be appropriate, such as cooperative ownership (including limited equity cooperative ownership) and fee simple ownership (including condominium ownership), for occupancy by the eligible families.


(b) AffordabilityA homeownership program under this part shall provide for the establishment of sales prices (including principal, insurance, taxes, and interest and closing costs) for initial acquisition of the property, and for sales to eligible families, such that the eligible family shall not be required to expend more than 30 percent of the adjusted income of the family per month to complete a sale under the homeownership program.


(c) Eligible propertyA property may not participate in a homeownership program under this part unless all tenants or occupants of the property (at the time of 11 So in original. The word “of” probably should not appear. the application for the implementation grant covering the property is filed with the Secretary) participate in the homeownership program.


(d) PlanA homeownership program under this part shall provide, and include a plan, for—(1) identifying and selecting eligible families to participate in the homeownership program;

(2) providing relocation assistance to families who elect to move; and

(3) ensuring continued affordability of the property to homebuyers and homeowners.


(e) Housing quality standardsThe application shall include a plan ensuring that the unit—(1) will be free from any defects that pose a danger to health or safety before transfer of an ownership interest in, or shares representing, a unit to an eligible family; and

(2) will, not later than 2 years after the transfer to an eligible family, meet minimum housing standards establish</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A homeownership program under this part shall provide for acquisition by eligible families of ownership interests in, or shares representing, units in an eligible property under any arrangement determined by the Secretary to be appropriate, such as cooperative ownership (including limited equity cooperative ownership) and fee simple ownership (including condominium ownership), for occupancy by the eligible families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affordability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Affordability A homeownership program under this part shall provide for the establishment of sales prices (including principal, insurance, taxes, and interest and closing costs) for initial acquisition of the property, and for sales to eligible families, such that the eligible family shall not be required to expend more than 30 percent of the adjusted income of the family per month to complete a sale under the homeownership program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible property A property may not participate in a homeownership program under this part unless all tenants or occupants of the property (at the time of 11 So in original. The word “of” probably should not appear. the application for the implementation grant covering the property is filed with the Secretary) participate in the homeownership program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plan A homeownership program under this part shall provide, and include a plan, for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing quality standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Housing quality standards The application shall include a plan ensuring that the unit—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12894_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for acquisition of vacant units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preference for acquisition of vacant units Each homeownership program under this part shall provide that, in making vacant units in eligible properties available for acquisition by eligible families, preference shall be given to eligible families who reside in public or Indian housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>