<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12905"><akn:num>12905</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of grantees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12905. Responsibilities of grantees(a) Prohibition of substitution of fundsAmounts received from grants under this chapter may not be used to replace other amounts made available or designated by State or local governments for use for the purposes under this chapter.


(b) CapabilityThe recipient shall have, in the determination of the grantee or the Secretary, the capacity and capability to effectively administer a grant under this chapter.


(c) CooperationThe recipient shall agree to cooperate and coordinate in providing assistance under this chapter with the agencies of the relevant State and local governments responsible for services in the area served by the applicant for eligible persons and other public and private organizations and agencies providing services for such eligible persons.


(d) Prohibition of feesThe recipient shall agree that no fee will be charged to any eligible person for any housing or services provided with amounts from a grant under this chapter.


(e) ConfidentialityThe recipient shall agree to ensure the confidentiality of the name of any individual assisted with amounts from a grant under this chapter and any other information regarding individuals receiving such assistance.


(f) Financial recordsThe recipient shall agree to maintain and provide the grantee or the Secretary with financial records sufficient, in the determination of the Secretary, to ensure proper accounting and disbursing of amounts received from a grant under this chapter.


(g) Administrative expenses(1) GranteesNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, each grantee may use not more than 3 percent of the grant amount for administrative costs relating to administering grant amounts and allocating such amounts to project sponsors.


(2) Project sponsorsNotwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, each project sponsor receiving amounts from grants made under this chapter 11 See References in Text note below. may use not more than 7 percent of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of substitution of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition of substitution of funds Amounts received from grants under this chapter may not be used to replace other amounts made available or designated by State or local governments for use for the purposes under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Capability The recipient shall have, in the determination of the grantee or the Secretary, the capacity and capability to effectively administer a grant under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation The recipient shall agree to cooperate and coordinate in providing assistance under this chapter with the agencies of the relevant State and local governments responsible for services in the area served by the applicant for eligible persons and other public and private organizations and agencies providing services for such eligible persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibition of fees The recipient shall agree that no fee will be charged to any eligible person for any housing or services provided with amounts from a grant under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Confidentiality The recipient shall agree to ensure the confidentiality of the name of any individual assisted with amounts from a grant under this chapter and any other information regarding individuals receiving such assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Financial records The recipient shall agree to maintain and provide the grantee or the Secretary with financial records sufficient, in the determination of the Secretary, to ensure proper accounting and disbursing of amounts received from a grant under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Administrative expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Environmental review For purposes of environmental review, a grant under this chapter shall be treated as assistance for a special project that is subject to section 3547 of this title, and shall be subject to the regulations issued by the Secretary to implement such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbon monoxide alarms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Carbon monoxide alarms Each dwelling unit assisted under this chapter shall contain installed carbon monoxide alarms or detectors that meet or exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12905_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifying smoke alarms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Qualifying smoke alarms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>