<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12910" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12910/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/12910/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_12910"><akn:num>12910</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for community residences and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 12910. Grants for community residences and services(a) Grant authorityThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may make grants to States and metropolitan areas to develop and operate community residences and provide services for eligible persons.


(b) Community residences and services(1) Community residences(A) In generalA community residence under this section shall be a multiunit residence designed for eligible persons for the following purposes:(i) To provide a lower cost residential alternative to institutional care and to prevent or delay the need for institutional care.

(ii) To provide a permanent or transitional residential setting with appropriate services that enhances the quality of life for individuals who are unable to live independently.

(iii) To prevent homelessness among eligible persons by increasing available suitable housing resources.

(iv) To integrate eligible persons into local communities and provide services to maintain the abilities of such eligible persons to participate as fully as possible in community life.


(B) RentExcept to the extent that the costs of providing residence are reimbursed or provided by any other assistance from Federal or non-Federal public sources, each resident in a community residence shall pay as rent for a dwelling unit an amount equal to the following:(i) For low-income individuals, the amount of rent paid under section 3(a) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (42 U.S.C. 1437a(a)) by a low-income family (as the term is defined in section 3(b)(2) of such Act (42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(2))) for a dwelling unit assisted under such Act [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.].

(ii) For any resident that is not a low-income resident, an amount based on a formula, which shall be determined by the Secretary, under which rent is determined by the income and resources of the resident.


(C) FeesFees may be charged for any services provided under subsection (c)(2) to residents of a community residence, except that any fees charg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12910_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant authority The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may make grants to States and metropolitan areas to develop and operate community residences and provide services for eligible persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12910_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community residences and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Community residences and services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12910_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of grants Any amounts received from a grant under this section may be used only as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_12910_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations on use of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>