<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1301" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1301/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1301/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1301"><akn:num>1301</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1301. Definitions(a) When used in this chapter—(1) The term “State”, except where otherwise provided, includes the District of Columbia and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and when used in subchapters IV, V, VII, XI, XIX, and XXI includes the Virgin Islands and Guam. Such term when used in subchapters III, IX, and XII also includes the Virgin Islands. Such term when used in subchapter V and in part B of this subchapter also includes American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands. Such term when used in subchapters XIX and XXI also includes the Northern Mariana Islands and American Samoa. In the case of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam, subchapters I, X, and XIV, and subchapter XVI (as in effect without regard to the amendment made by section 301 of the Social Security Amendments of 1972) shall continue to apply, and the term “State” when used in such subchapters (but not in subchapter XVI as in effect pursuant to such amendment after December 31, 1973) includes Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam. Such term when used in subchapter XX also includes the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands. Such term when used in subchapter IV also includes American Samoa.

(2) The term “United States” when used in a geographical sense means, except where otherwise provided, the States.

(3) The term “person” means an individual, a trust or estate, a partnership, or a corporation.

(4) The term “corporation” includes associations, joint-stock companies, and insurance companies.

(5) The term “shareholder” includes a member in an association, joint-stock company, or insurance company.

(6) The term “Secretary”, except when the context otherwise requires, means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.

(7) The terms “physician” and “medical care” and “hospitalization” include osteopathic practitioners or the services of osteopathic practitioners and hospitals within the scope of their pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1301_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) When used in this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1301_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The terms “includes” and “including” when used in a definition contained in this chapter shall not be deemed to exclude other things otherwise within the meaning of the term defined.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1301_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Whenever under this chapter or any Act of Congress, or under the law of any State, an employer is required or permitted to deduct any amount from the remuneration of an employee and to pay the amount deducted to the United States, a State, or any political subdivision thereof, then for the purposes of this chapter the amount so deducted shall be considered to have been paid to the employee at the time of such deduction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1301_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as authorizing any Federal official, agent, or representative, in carrying out any of the provisions of this chapter, to take charge of any child over the objection of either of the parents of such child, or of the person standing in loco parentis to such child.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>