<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1306c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1306c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1306c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1306c"><akn:num>1306c</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on access to the Death Master File</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1306c. Restriction on access to the Death Master File(a) In generalThe Secretary of Commerce shall not disclose to any person information contained on the Death Master File with respect to any deceased individual at any time during the 3-calendar-year period beginning on the date of the individual’s death, unless such person is certified under the program established under subsection (b).


(b) Certification program(1) In generalThe Secretary of Commerce shall establish a program—(A) to certify persons who are eligible to access the information described in subsection (a) contained on the Death Master File, and

(B) to perform periodic and unscheduled audits of certified persons to determine the compliance by such certified persons with the requirements of the program.


(2) CertificationA person shall not be certified under the program established under paragraph (1) unless such person certifies that access to the information described in subsection (a) is appropriate because such person—(A) has—(i) a legitimate fraud prevention interest, or

(ii) a legitimate business purpose pursuant to a law, governmental rule, regulation, or fiduciary duty, and


(B) has systems, facilities, and procedures in place to safeguard such information, and experience in maintaining the confidentiality, security, and appropriate use of such information, pursuant to requirements similar to the requirements of section 6103(p)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, and

(C) agrees to satisfy the requirements of such section 6103(p)(4) as if such section applied to such person.


(3) Fees(A) In generalThe Secretary of Commerce shall establish under section 9701 of title 31 a program for the charge of fees sufficient to cover (but not to exceed) all costs associated with evaluating applications for certification and auditing, inspecting, and monitoring certified persons under the program. Any fees so collected shall be deposited and credited as offsetting collections to the accounts fro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Commerce shall not disclose to any person information contained on the Death Master File with respect to any deceased individual at any time during the 3-calendar-year period beginning on the date of the individual’s death, unless such person is certified under the program established under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certification program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imposition of penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Imposition of penalty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death Master File</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Death Master File For purposes of this section, the term “Death Master File” means information on the name, social security account number, date of birth, and date of death of deceased individuals maintained by the Commissioner of Social Security, other than information that was provided to such Commissioner under section 405(r) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from Freedom of Information Act requirement with respect to certain records of deceased individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exemption from Freedom of Information Act requirement with respect to certain records of deceased individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1306c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>