<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320a_9"><akn:num>1320a–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320a–9. Demonstration projects(a) Authority to approve demonstration projects(1) In generalThe Secretary may authorize States to conduct demonstration projects pursuant to this section which the Secretary finds are likely to promote the objectives of part B or E of subchapter IV.


(2) LimitationDuring fiscal years 2012 through 2014, the Secretary may authorize demonstration projects described in paragraph (1), with not more than 10 demonstration projects to be authorized in each fiscal year.


(3) Conditions for State eligibilityFor purposes of a new demonstration project under this section that is initially approved in any of fiscal years 2012 through 2014, a State shall be authorized to conduct such demonstration project only if the State satisfies the following conditions:(A) Identify 1 or more goals(i) In generalThe State shall demonstrate that the demonstration project is designed to accomplish 1 or more of the following goals:(I) Increase permanency for all infants, children, and youth by reducing the time in foster placements when possible and promoting a successful transition to adulthood for older youth.

(II) Increase positive outcomes for infants, children, youth, and families in their homes and communities, including tribal communities, and improve the safety and well-being of infants, children, and youth.

(III) Prevent child abuse and neglect and the re-entry of infants, children, and youth into foster care.


(ii) Long-term therapeutic family treatment centers; addressing domestic violenceWith respect to a demonstration project that is designed to accomplish 1 or more of the goals described in clause (i), the State may elect to establish a program—(I) to permit foster care maintenance payments to be made under part E of subchapter IV to a long-term therapeutic family treatment center (as described in paragraph (8)(B)) on behalf of a child residing in the center; or

(II) to identify and address domestic violence that endangers children and results</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to approve demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to approve demonstration projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver authority The Secretary may waive compliance with any requirement of part B or E of subchapter IV which (if applied) would prevent a State from carrying out a demonstration project under this section or prevent the State from effectively achieving the purpose of such a project, except that the Secretary may not waive—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as program expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment as program expenditures For purposes of parts B and E of subchapter IV, the Secretary shall consider the expenditures of any State to conduct a demonstration project under this section to be expenditures under subpart 1 or 2 of such part B, or under such part E, as the State may elect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of demonstration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duration of demonstration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application Any State seeking to conduct a demonstration project under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application, in such form as the Secretary may require, which includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluations Each State authorized to conduct a demonstration project under this section shall obtain an evaluation by an independent contractor of the effectiveness of the project, using an evaluation design approved by the Secretary which provides for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost neutrality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Cost neutrality The Secretary may not authorize a State to conduct a demonstration project under this section unless the Secretary determines that the total amount of Federal funds that will be expended under (or by reason of) the project over its approved term (or such portion thereof or other period as the Secretary may find appropriate) will not exceed the amount of such funds that would be expended by the State under the State plans approved under parts B and E of subchapter IV if the project were not conducted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_9_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribes operating IV–E programs considered States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Indian tribes operating IV–E programs considered States An Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium that has elected to operate a program under part E of subchapter IV in accordance with section 679c of this title shall be considered a State for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>