<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320a_7l"><akn:num>1320a–7l</akn:num><akn:heading>Nationwide program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of lo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320a–7l. Nationwide program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities and providers(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), shall establish a program to identify efficient, effective, and economical procedures for long term care facilities or providers to conduct background checks on prospective direct patient access employees on a nationwide basis (in this subsection, such program shall be referred to as the “nationwide program”). Except for the following modifications, the Secretary shall carry out the nationwide program under similar terms and conditions as the pilot program under section 307 of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (Public Law 108–173; 117 Stat. 2257), including the prohibition on hiring abusive workers and the authorization of the imposition of penalties by a participating State under subsection (b)(3)(A) and (b)(6), respectively, of such section 307:(1) Agreements(A) Newly participating StatesThe Secretary shall enter into agreements with each State—(i) that the Secretary has not entered into an agreement with under subsection (c)(1) of such section 307;

(ii) that agrees to conduct background checks under the nationwide program on a Statewide basis; and

(iii) that submits an application to the Secretary containing such information and at such time as the Secretary may specify.


(B) Certain previously participating StatesThe Secretary shall enter into agreements with each State—(i) that the Secretary has entered into an agreement with under such subsection (c)(1), but only in the case where such agreement did not require the State to conduct background checks under the program established under subsection (a) of such section 307 on a Statewide basis;

(ii) that agrees to conduct background checks under the nationwide program on a Statewide basis; and

(iii) that submits an ap</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), shall establish a program to identify efficient, effective, and economical procedures for long term care facilities or providers to conduct background checks on prospective direct patient access employees on a nationwide basis (in this subsection, such program shall be referred to as the “nationwide program”). Except for the following modifications, the Secretary shall carry out the nationwide program under similar terms and conditions as the pilot program under section 307 of the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 (Public Law 108–173; 117 Stat. 2257), including the prohibition on hiring abusive workers and the authorization of the imposition of penalties by a participating State under subsection (b)(3)(A) and (b)(6), respectively, of such section 307:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>