<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320f–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320f–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320f–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320f_3"><akn:num>1320f–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiation and renegotiation process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320f–3. Negotiation and renegotiation process(a) In generalFor purposes of this part, under an agreement under section 1320f–2 of this title between the Secretary and a manufacturer of a selected drug (or selected drugs), with respect to the period for which such agreement is in effect and in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Secretary and the manufacturer—(1) shall during the negotiation period with respect to such drug, in accordance with this section, negotiate a maximum fair price for such drug for the purpose described in section 1320f–2(a)(1) of this title; and

(2) renegotiate, in accordance with the process specified pursuant to subsection (f), such maximum fair price for such drug for the purpose described in section 1320f–2(a)(2) of this title if such drug is a renegotiation-eligible drug under such subsection.


(b) Negotiation process requirements(1) Methodology and processThe Secretary shall develop and use a consistent methodology and process, in accordance with paragraph (2), for negotiations under subsection (a) that aims to achieve the lowest maximum fair price for each selected drug.


(2) Specific elements of negotiation processAs part of the negotiation process under this section, with respect to a selected drug and the negotiation period with respect to the initial price applicability year with respect to such drug, the following shall apply:(A) Submission of informationNot later than March 1 of the year of the selected drug publication date, with respect to the selected drug, the manufacturer of the drug shall submit to the Secretary, in accordance with section 1320f–2(a)(4) of this title, the information described in such section.


(B) Initial offer by SecretaryNot later than the June 1 following the selected drug publication date, the Secretary shall provide the manufacturer of the selected drug with a written initial offer that contains the Secretary’s proposal for the maximum fair price of the drug and a concise justifi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For purposes of this part, under an agreement under section 1320f–2 of this title between the Secretary and a manufacturer of a selected drug (or selected drugs), with respect to the period for which such agreement is in effect and in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Secretary and the manufacturer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiation process requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Negotiation process requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceiling for maximum fair price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ceiling for maximum fair price</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary floor for small biotech drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Temporary floor for small biotech drugs In the case of a selected drug that is a qualifying single source drug described in section 1320f–1(d)(2) of this title and with respect to which the first initial price applicability year of the price applicability period with respect to such drug is 2029 or 2030, the maximum fair price negotiated under this section for such drug for such initial price applicability year may not be less than 66 percent of the average non-Federal average manufacturer price for such drug (as defined in subsection (c)(6)) for 2021 (or, in the case that there is not an average non-Federal average manufacturer price available for such drug for 2021, for the first full year following the market entry for such drug), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) from September 2021 (or December of such first full year following the market entry), as applicable, to September of the ye</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Factors For purposes of negotiating the maximum fair price of a selected drug under this part with the manufacturer of the drug, the Secretary shall consider the following factors, as applicable to the drug, as the basis for determining the offers and counteroffers under subsection (b) for the drug:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renegotiation process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Renegotiation process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320f_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Clarification The maximum fair price for a selected drug described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) 11 So in original. Probably means subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) of section 1320f–1(e) of this title. shall take effect no later than the first day of the first calendar quarter that begins after the date described in subparagraph 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “such”. (A) or (B), as applicable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>