<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_3"><akn:num>1320b–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicants or recipients under public assistance programs not to be required to make election respec</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–3. Applicants or recipients under public assistance programs not to be required to make election respecting certain veterans’ benefits(a) Supplemental Security Income programNotwithstanding any other provision of law (but subject to subsection (b)), no individual who is an applicant for or recipient of aid or assistance under a State plan approved under subchapter I, X, XIV, or XVI, or of benefits under the Supplemental Security Income program established by subchapter XVI shall—(1) be required, as a condition of eligibility for (or of continuing to receive) such aid, assistance, or benefits, to make an election under section 306 of the Veterans’ and Survivors’ Pension Improvement Act of 1978 with respect to pension paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or

(2) by reason of failure or refusal to make such an election, be denied (or suffer a reduction in the amount of) such aid, assistance, or benefits.


(b) Period of effectivenessThe provisions of subsection (a) shall be applicable only with respect to an individual, who is an applicant for or recipient of aid, assistance, or benefits described in subsection (a), during a period with respect to which there is in effect—(1) in case such individual is an applicant for or recipient of aid or assistance under a State plan referred to in subsection (a), in the State having such plan, or

(2) in case such individual is an applicant for or recipient of benefits under the Supplemental Security Income program established by subchapter XVI, in the State in which the individual applies for or receives such benefits,


a State plan for medical assistance, approved under subchapter XIX, under which medical assistance is available to such individual only for periods for which such individual is a recipient of aid, assistance, or benefits described in subsection (a).

(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XI, § 1133, as added Pub. L. 96–272, title III, § 310(a)(1), June 17, 1980, 94 Stat. 532; amended Pub. L. 102–54, § 13(q</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental Security Income program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Supplemental Security Income program Notwithstanding any other provision of law (but subject to subsection (b)), no individual who is an applicant for or recipient of aid or assistance under a State plan approved under subchapter I, X, XIV, or XVI, or of benefits under the Supplemental Security Income program established by subchapter XVI shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Period of effectiveness The provisions of subsection (a) shall be applicable only with respect to an individual, who is an applicant for or recipient of aid, assistance, or benefits described in subsection (a), during a period with respect to which there is in effect— a State plan for medical assistance, approved under subchapter XIX, under which medical assistance is available to such individual only for periods for which such individual is a recipient of aid, assistance, or benefits described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>