<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_13"><akn:num>1320b–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Social security account statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–13. Social security account statements(a) Provision upon request(1) Beginning not later than October 1, 1990, the Commissioner of Social Security shall provide upon the request of an eligible individual a social security account statement (hereinafter referred to as the “statement”).

(2) Each statement shall contain—(A) the amount of wages paid to and self-employment income derived by the eligible individual as shown by the records of the Commissioner at the date of the request;

(B) an estimate of the aggregate of the employer, employee, and self-employment contributions of the eligible individual for old-age, survivors, and disability insurance as shown by the records of the Commissioner on the date of the request;

(C) a separate estimate of the aggregate of the employer, employee, and self-employment contributions of the eligible individual for hospital insurance as shown by the records of the Commissioner on the date of the request;

(D) an estimate of the potential monthly retirement, disability, survivor, and auxiliary benefits payable on the eligible individual’s account together with a description of the benefits payable under the medicare program of subchapter XVIII; and

(E) in the case of an eligible individual described in paragraph (3)(C)(ii), an explanation, in language calculated to be understood by the average eligible individual, of the operation of the provisions under sections 402(k)(5) 11 See References in Text note below. and 415(a)(7) 1 of this title and an explanation of the maximum potential effects of such provisions on the eligible individual’s monthly retirement, survivor, and auxiliary benefits.


(3) For purposes of this section, the term “eligible individual” means an individual—(A) who has a social security account number,

(B) who has attained age 25 or over, and

(C)(i) who has wages or net earnings from self-employment, or (ii) with respect to whom the Commissioner has information that the pattern of wages or self-employme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision upon request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provision upon request</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice to eligible individuals The Commissioner shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take such steps as are necessary to assure that eligible individuals are informed of the availability of the statement described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory provision of statements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mandatory provision of statements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to governmental employees of effect of noncovered employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure to governmental employees of effect of noncovered employment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>