<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_6"><akn:num>1320b–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of representatives and health care providers convicted of violations from participation in</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–6. Exclusion of representatives and health care providers convicted of violations from participation in social security programs(a) In generalThe Commissioner of Social Security shall exclude from participation in the social security programs any representative or health care provider—(1) who is convicted of a violation of section 408 or 1383a of this title;

(2) who is convicted of any violation under title 18 relating to an initial application for or continuing entitlement to, or amount of, benefits under subchapter II of this chapter, or an initial application for or continuing eligibility for, or amount of, benefits under subchapter XVI of this chapter; or

(3) who the Commissioner determines has committed an offense described in section 1320a–8(a)(1) of this title.


(b) Notice, effective date, and period of exclusion(1) An exclusion under this section shall be effective at such time, for such period, and upon such reasonable notice to the public and to the individual excluded as may be specified in regulations consistent with paragraph (2).

(2) Such an exclusion shall be effective with respect to services furnished to any individual on or after the effective date of the exclusion. Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude, in determining disability under subchapter II or subchapter XVI, consideration of any medical evidence derived from services provided by a health care provider before the effective date of the exclusion of the health care provider under this section.

(3)(A) The Commissioner shall specify, in the notice of exclusion under paragraph (1), the period of the exclusion.

(B) Subject to subparagraph (C), in the case of an exclusion under subsection (a), the minimum period of exclusion shall be 5 years, except that the Commissioner may waive the exclusion in the case of an individual who is the sole source of essential services in a community. The Commissioner’s decision whether to waive the exclusion shall not be reviewable.

(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Commissioner of Social Security shall exclude from participation in the social security programs any representative or health care provider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, effective date, and period of exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice, effective date, and period of exclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice to State agencies The Commissioner shall promptly notify each appropriate State agency employed for the purpose of making disability determinations under section 421 or 1383b(a) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to State licensing agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice to State licensing agencies The Commissioner shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice, hearing, and judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice, hearing, and judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for termination of exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application for termination of exclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of records of excluded representatives and health care providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability of records of excluded representatives and health care providers Nothing in this section shall be construed to have the effect of limiting access by any applicant or beneficiary under subchapter II or XVI, any State agency acting under section 421 or 1383b(a) of this title, or the Commissioner to records maintained by any representative or health care provider in connection with services provided to the applicant or beneficiary prior to the exclusion of such representative or health care provider under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reporting requirement Any representative or health care provider participating in, or seeking to participate in, a social security program shall inform the Commissioner, in such form and manner as the Commissioner shall prescribe by regulation, whether such representative or health care provider has been convicted of a violation described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Delegation of authority The Commissioner may delegate authority granted by this section to the Inspector General.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_6_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>