<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13201" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13201/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13201/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13201"><akn:num>13201</akn:num><akn:heading>“Secretary” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13201. “Secretary” defined
For purposes of this Act, the term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.
(Pub. L. 102–486, § 2, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2782.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 102–486, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2776, known as the Energy Policy Act of 1992. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note below and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 102–486, § 1(a), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2776, provided that: “This Act [see Tables for classification] may be cited as the ‘Energy Policy Act of 1992’.”


Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 13211. Actions Concerning Regulations That Significantly Affect Energy Supply, Distribution, or Use
Ex. Ord. No. 13211, May 18, 2001, 66 F.R. 28355, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United States of America, and in order to appropriately weigh and consider the effects of the Federal Government’s regulations on the supply, distribution, and use of energy, it is hereby ordered as follows:
Section 1. Policy. The Federal Government can significantly affect the supply, distribution, and use of energy. Yet there is often too little information regarding the effects that governmental regulatory action can have on energy. In order to provide more useful energy-related information and hence improve the quality of agency decisionmaking, I am requiring that agencies shall prepare a Statement of Energy Effects when undertaking certain agency actions. As described more fully below, such Statements of Energy Effects shall describe the effects of certain regulatory actions on energy supply, distribution, or use.
Sec. 2. Preparation of a Statement of Energy Effects. (a) To the extent permitted by law, agencies shall prepare and submit a Statement of Energy Effects to the Administrator of the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, Office of Management and Budget, fo</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>