<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_12"><akn:num>1320b–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Research on outcomes of health care services and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–12. Research on outcomes of health care services and procedures(a) Establishment of program(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, shall—(A) conduct and support research with respect to the outcomes, effectiveness, and appropriateness of health care services and procedures in order to identify the manner in which diseases, disorders, and other health conditions can most effectively and appropriately be prevented, diagnosed, treated, and managed clinically; and

(B) assure that the needs and priorities of the program under subchapter XVIII are appropriately reflected in the development and periodic review and updating (through the process set forth in section 299b–2 11 See References in Text note below. of this title) of treatment-specific or condition-specific practice guidelines for clinical treatments and conditions in forms appropriate for use in clinical practice, for use in educational programs, and for use in reviewing quality and appropriateness of medical care.


(2) Evaluations of alternative services and proceduresIn carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall conduct or support evaluations of the comparative effects, on health and functional capacity, of alternative services and procedures utilized in preventing, diagnosing, treating, and clinically managing diseases, disorders, and other health conditions.


(3) Initial guidelines(A) In carrying out paragraph (1)(B) of this subsection, and section 299b–1(d) 1 of this title, the Secretary shall, by not later than January 1, 1991, assure the development of an initial set of the guidelines specified in paragraph (1)(B) that shall include not less than 3 clinical treatments or conditions that—(i)(I) account for a significant portion of expenditures under subchapter XVIII; and

(II) have a significant variation in the frequency or the type of treatment provided; or


(ii) otherwise meet the needs and priorities of the program unde</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methodologies and criteria for evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Methodologies and criteria for evaluations For the purpose of facilitating research under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for data bases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standards for data bases In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall develop—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of research findings and guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dissemination of research findings and guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Evaluations The Secretary shall conduct and support evaluations of the activities carried out under this section to determine the extent to which such activities have had an effect on the practices of physicians in providing medical treatment, the delivery of health care, and the outcomes of health care services and procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research with respect to dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Research with respect to dissemination The Secretary may conduct or support research with respect to improving methods of disseminating information on the effectiveness and appropriateness of health care services and procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_12_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>