<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320d"><akn:num>1320d</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320d. Definitions
For purposes of this part:(1) Code setThe term “code set” means any set of codes used for encoding data elements, such as tables of terms, medical concepts, medical diagnostic codes, or medical procedure codes.


(2) Health care clearinghouseThe term “health care clearinghouse” means a public or private entity that processes or facilitates the processing of nonstandard data elements of health information into standard data elements.


(3) Health care providerThe term “health care provider” includes a provider of services (as defined in section 1395x(u) of this title), a provider of medical or other health services (as defined in section 1395x(s) of this title), and any other person furnishing health care services or supplies.


(4) Health informationThe term “health information” means any information, whether oral or recorded in any form or medium, that—(A) is created or received by a health care provider, health plan, public health authority, employer, life insurer, school or university, or health care clearinghouse; and

(B) relates to the past, present, or future physical or mental health or condition of an individual, the provision of health care to an individual, or the past, present, or future payment for the provision of health care to an individual.


(5) Health planThe term “health plan” means an individual or group plan that provides, or pays the cost of, medical care (as such term is defined in section 300gg–91 of this title). Such term includes the following, and any combination thereof:(A) A group health plan (as defined in section 300gg–91(a) of this title), but only if the plan—(i) has 50 or more participants (as defined in section 1002(7) of title 29); or

(ii) is administered by an entity other than the employer who established and maintains the plan.


(B) A health insurance issuer (as defined in section 300gg–91(b) of this title).

(C) A health maintenance organization (as defined in section 300gg–91(b) of this title).

(D) Pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Code set</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Code set The term “code set” means any set of codes used for encoding data elements, such as tables of terms, medical concepts, medical diagnostic codes, or medical procedure codes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care clearinghouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Health care clearinghouse The term “health care clearinghouse” means a public or private entity that processes or facilitates the processing of nonstandard data elements of health information into standard data elements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Health care provider The term “health care provider” includes a provider of services (as defined in section 1395x(u) of this title), a provider of medical or other health services (as defined in section 1395x(s) of this title), and any other person furnishing health care services or supplies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Health information The term “health information” means any information, whether oral or recorded in any form or medium, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Health plan The term “health plan” means an individual or group plan that provides, or pays the cost of, medical care (as such term is defined in section 300gg–91 of this title). Such term includes the following, and any combination thereof:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individually identifiable health information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Individually identifiable health information The term “individually identifiable health information” means any information, including demographic information collected from an individual, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Standard The term “standard”, when used with reference to a data element of health information or a transaction referred to in section 1320d–2(a)(1) of this title, means any such data element or transaction that meets each of the standards and implementation specifications adopted or established by the Secretary with respect to the data element or transaction under sections 1320d–1 through 1320d–3 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard setting organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Standard setting organization The term “standard setting organization” means a standard setting organization accredited by the American National Standards Institute, including the National Council for Prescription Drug Programs, that develops standards for information transactions, data elements, or any other standard that is necessary to, or will facilitate, the implementation of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320d_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Operating rules The term “operating rules” means the necessary business rules and guidelines for the electronic exchange of information that are not defined by a standard or its implementation specifications as adopted for purposes of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>