<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320c–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320c–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320c–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320c_2"><akn:num>1320c–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts with quality improvement organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320c–2. Contracts with quality improvement organizations(a) Establishment of geographic areasThe Secretary shall establish throughout the United States such local, State, regional, national, or other geographic areas as the Secretary determines appropriate with respect to which contracts under this part will be made.


(b) Organizations entitled to contract with Secretary(1) The Secretary shall enter into contracts with one or more quality improvement organizations for each area established under subsection (a) if a qualified organization is available in such area and such organization and the Secretary have negotiated a proposed contract which the Secretary determines will be carried out by such organization in a manner consistent with the efficient and effective administration of this part. In entering into contracts with such qualified organizations, the Secretary shall, to the extent appropriate, seek to ensure that each of the functions described in section 1320c–3(a) of this title are carried out within an area established under subsection (a). If more than one such qualified organization will be operating in an area, the Secretary shall ensure that there is no duplication of the functions carried out by such organizations within the area.

(2)(A) Prior to November 15, 1984, the Secretary shall not enter into a contract under this part with any entity which is, or is affiliated with (through management, ownership, or common control), an entity (other than a self-insured employer) which directly or indirectly makes payments to any practitioner or provider whose health care services are reviewed by such entity or would be reviewed by such entity if it entered into a contract with the Secretary under this part. For purposes of this paragraph, an entity shall not be considered to be affiliated with another entity which makes payments (directly or indirectly) to any practitioner or provider, by reason of management, ownership, or common control, if the managemen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of geographic areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of geographic areas The Secretary shall establish throughout the United States such local, State, regional, national, or other geographic areas as the Secretary determines appropriate with respect to which contracts under this part will be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organizations entitled to contract with Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Organizations entitled to contract with Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of contract Each contract with an organization under this section shall provide that— In evaluating the performance of quality improvement organizations under contracts under this part, the Secretary shall place emphasis on the performance of such organizations in educating providers and practitioners (particularly those in rural areas) concerning the review process and criteria being applied by the organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 112–40, title II, § 261(b)(3)(C), Oct. 21, 2011, 125 Stat. 424</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination not subject to judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Termination not subject to judicial review Any determination by the Secretary to terminate or not to renew a contract under this section shall not be subject to judicial review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely provision of hospital data to quality improvement organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Timely provision of hospital data to quality improvement organizations The Secretary shall provide that fiscal intermediaries furnish to quality improvement organizations, each month on a timely basis, data necessary to initiate the review process under section 1320c–3(a) of this title on a timely basis. If the Secretary determines that a fiscal intermediary is unable to furnish such data on a timely basis, the Secretary shall require the hospital to do so.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320c_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of new policy or procedure and general criteria and standards for evaluation; performance comparison report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of new policy or procedure and general criteria and standards for evaluation; performance comparison report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>