<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–9a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–9a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–9a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_9a"><akn:num>1320b–9a</akn:num><akn:heading>Child health quality measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–9a. Child health quality measures(a) Development of an initial core set of health care quality measures for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP(1) In generalNot later than January 1, 2010, the Secretary shall identify and publish for general comment an initial, recommended core set of child health quality measures for use by State programs administered under subchapters XIX and XXI, health insurance issuers and managed care entities that enter into contracts with such programs, and providers of items and services under such programs.


(2) Identification of initial core measuresIn consultation with the individuals and entities described in subsection (b)(3), the Secretary shall identify existing quality of care measures for children that are in use under public and privately sponsored health care coverage arrangements, or that are part of reporting systems that measure both the presence and duration of health insurance coverage over time.


(3) Recommendations and disseminationBased on such existing and identified measures, the Secretary shall publish an initial core set of child health quality measures that includes (but is not limited to) the following:(A) The duration of children’s health insurance coverage over a 12-month time period.

(B) The availability and effectiveness of a full range of—(i) preventive services, treatments, and services for acute conditions, including services to promote healthy birth, prevent and treat premature birth, and detect the presence or risk of physical or mental conditions that could adversely affect growth and development; and

(ii) treatments to correct or ameliorate the effects of physical and mental conditions, including chronic conditions and, with respect to dental care, conditions requiring the restoration of teeth, relief of pain and infection, and maintenance of dental health, in infants, young children, school-age children, and adolescents.


(C) The availability of care in a range of ambulatory and inpatient </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of an initial core set of health care quality measures for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development of an initial core set of health care quality measures for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advancing and improving pediatric quality measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advancing and improving pediatric quality measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual State reports regarding State-specific quality of care measures applied under Medicaid or CHIP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual State reports regarding State-specific quality of care measures applied under Medicaid or CHIP</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects for improving the quality of children’s health care and the use of health information technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Demonstration projects for improving the quality of children’s health care and the use of health information technology</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Childhood obesity demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Childhood obesity demonstration project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of model electronic health record format for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Development of model electronic health record format for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study of pediatric health and health care quality measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Study of pediatric health and health care quality measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, no evidence based quality measure developed, published, or used as a basis of measurement or reporting under this section may be used to establish an irrebuttable presumption regarding either the medical necessity of care or the maximum permissible coverage for any individual child who is eligible for and receiving medical assistance under subchapter XIX or child health assistance under subchapter XXI.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_9a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Appropriation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>