<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320a_7h"><akn:num>1320a–7h</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency reports and reporting of physician ownership or investment interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320a–7h. Transparency reports and reporting of physician ownership or investment interests(a) Transparency reports(1) Payments or other transfers of value(A) In generalOn March 31, 2013, and on the 90th day of each calendar year beginning thereafter, any applicable manufacturer that provides a payment or other transfer of value to a covered recipient (or to an entity or individual at the request of or designated on behalf of a covered recipient), shall submit to the Secretary, in such electronic form as the Secretary shall require, the following information with respect to the preceding calendar year:(i) The name of the covered recipient.

(ii) The business address of the covered recipient and, in the case of a covered recipient who is a physician, the specialty and National Provider Identifier of the covered recipient.

(iii) The amount of the payment or other transfer of value.

(iv) The dates on which the payment or other transfer of value was provided to the covered recipient.

(v) A description of the form of the payment or other transfer of value, indicated (as appropriate for all that apply) as—(I) cash or a cash equivalent;

(II) in-kind items or services;

(III) stock, a stock option, or any other ownership interest, dividend, profit, or other return on investment; or

(IV) any other form of payment or other transfer of value (as defined by the Secretary).


(vi) A description of the nature of the payment or other transfer of value, indicated (as appropriate for all that apply) as—(I) consulting fees;

(II) compensation for services other than consulting;

(III) honoraria;

(IV) gift;

(V) entertainment;

(VI) food;

(VII) travel (including the specified destinations);

(VIII) education;

(IX) research;

(X) charitable contribution;

(XI) royalty or license;

(XII) current or prospective ownership or investment interest;

(XIII) direct compensation for serving as faculty or as a speaker for a medical education program;

(XIV) grant; or

(XV) any other na</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transparency reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transparency reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties for noncompliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for submission of information and public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Procedures for submission of information and public availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports and relation to State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual reports and relation to State laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>