<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–19" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–19/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–19/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_19"><akn:num>1320b–19</akn:num><akn:heading>The Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–19. The Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program(a) In generalThe Commissioner shall establish a Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program, under which a disabled beneficiary may use a ticket to work and self-sufficiency issued by the Commissioner in accordance with this section to obtain employment services, vocational rehabilitation services, or other support services from an employment network which is of the beneficiary’s choice and which is willing to provide such services to such beneficiary.


(b) Ticket system(1) Distribution of ticketsThe Commissioner may issue a ticket to work and self-sufficiency to disabled beneficiaries for participation in the Program.


(2) Assignment of ticketsA disabled beneficiary holding a ticket to work and self-sufficiency may assign the ticket to any employment network of the beneficiary’s choice which is serving under the Program and is willing to accept the assignment.


(3) Ticket termsA ticket issued under paragraph (1) shall consist of a document which evidences the Commissioner’s agreement to pay (as provided in paragraph (4)) an employment network, which is serving under the Program and to which such ticket is assigned by the beneficiary, for such employment services, vocational rehabilitation services, and other support services as the employment network may provide to the beneficiary.


(4) Payments to employment networksThe Commissioner shall pay an employment network under the Program in accordance with the outcome payment system under subsection (h)(2) or under the outcome-milestone payment system under subsection (h)(3) (whichever is elected pursuant to subsection (h)(1)). An employment network may not request or receive compensation for such services from the beneficiary.



(c) State participation(1) In generalEach State agency administering or supervising the administration of the State plan approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.) may elect to participate in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Commissioner shall establish a Ticket to Work and Self-Sufficiency Program, under which a disabled beneficiary may use a ticket to work and self-sufficiency issued by the Commissioner in accordance with this section to obtain employment services, vocational rehabilitation services, or other support services from an employment network which is of the beneficiary’s choice and which is willing to provide such services to such beneficiary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ticket system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ticket system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of the Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Responsibilities of the Commissioner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program managers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program managers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment networks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employment networks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual work plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Individual work plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment network payment systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Employment network payment systems</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of disability reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Suspension of disability reviews During any period for which an individual is using, as defined by the Commissioner, a ticket to work and self-sufficiency issued under this section, the Commissioner (and any applicable State agency) may not initiate a continuing disability review or other review under section 421 of this title of whether the individual is or is not under a disability or a review under subchapter XVI similar to any such review under section 421 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_19_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>