<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–10" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–10/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–10/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_10"><akn:num>1320b–10</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions relating to references to Social Security or Medicare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–10. Prohibitions relating to references to Social Security or Medicare(a) Prohibited acts(1) No person may use, in connection with any item constituting an advertisement, solicitation, circular, book, pamphlet, or other communication (including any Internet or other electronic communication), or a play, motion picture, broadcast, telecast, or other production, alone or with other words, letters, symbols, or emblems—(A) the words “Social Security”, “Social Security Account”, “Social Security System”, “Social Security Administration”, “Medicare”, “Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services”, “Department of Health and Human Services”, “Health and Human Services”, “Supplemental Security Income Program”, “Medicaid”, “Death Benefits Update”, “Federal Benefit Information”, “Funeral Expenses”, or “Final Supplemental Plan”, the letters “SSA”, “CMS”, “DHHS”, “HHS”, or “SSI”, or any other combination or variation of such words or letters, or

(B) a symbol or emblem of the Social Security Administration, Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, or Department of Health and Human Services (including the design of, or a reasonable facsimile of the design of, the social security card issued pursuant to section 405(c)(2)(F) of this title or the Medicare card,,11 So in original. the check used for payment of benefits under subchapter II, or envelopes or other stationery used by the Social Security Administration, Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, or Department of Health and Human Services), or any other combination or variation of such symbols or emblems,


in a manner which such person knows or should know would convey, or in a manner which reasonably could be interpreted or construed as conveying, the false impression that such item is approved, endorsed, or authorized by the Social Security Administration, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, or the Department of Health and Human Services or that such person has some connection with, or authorization from, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_10_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibited acts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_10_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil penalties The Commissioner or the Secretary (as applicable) may, pursuant to regulations, impose a civil money penalty not to exceed— against any person for each violation by such person of subsection (a). In the case of any items referred to in subsection (a)(1) consisting of pieces of mail, each such piece of mail which contains one or more words, letters, symbols, or emblems in violation of subsection (a) shall represent a separate violation. In the case of any items referred to in subsection (a)(1) consisting of Internet or other electronic communications, each dissemination, viewing, or accessing of such a communication which contains one or more words, letters, symbols, or emblems in violation of subsection (a) shall represent a separate violation 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period. In the case of any item referred to in subsection (a)(2), the reproduction, reprinting, or distribution of such item shall be treated as a separate violation with res</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_10_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of other law; compromise, recovery, and deposit into Treasury of civil money penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application of other law; compromise, recovery, and deposit into Treasury of civil money penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_10_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enforcement The preceding provisions of this section may be enforced through the Office of the Inspector General of the Social Security Administration or the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services (as appropriate).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>