<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320a–7a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320a_7a"><akn:num>1320a–7a</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil monetary penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320a–7a. Civil monetary penalties(a) Improperly filed claimsAny person (including an organization, agency, or other entity, but excluding a beneficiary, as defined in subsection (i)(5)) that—(1) knowingly presents or causes to be presented to an officer, employee, or agent of the United States, or of any department or agency thereof, or of any State agency (as defined in subsection (i)(1)), a claim (as defined in subsection (i)(2)) that the Secretary determines—(A) is for a medical or other item or service that the person knows or should know was not provided as claimed, including any person who engages in a pattern or practice of presenting or causing to be presented a claim for an item or service that is based on a code that the person knows or should know will result in a greater payment to the person than the code the person knows or should know is applicable to the item or service actually provided,

(B) is for a medical or other item or service and the person knows or should know the claim is false or fraudulent,

(C) is presented for a physician’s service (or an item or service incident to a physician’s service) by a person who knows or should know that the individual who furnished (or supervised the furnishing of) the service—(i) was not licensed as a physician,

(ii) was licensed as a physician, but such license had been obtained through a misrepresentation of material fact (including cheating on an examination required for licensing), or

(iii) represented to the patient at the time the service was furnished that the physician was certified in a medical specialty by a medical specialty board when the individual was not so certified,


(D) is for a medical or other item or service furnished during a period in which the person was excluded from the Federal health care program (as defined in section 1320a–7b(f) of this title) under which the claim was made pursuant to Federal law.11 So in original. Probably should be “law, or”.

(E) is for a pattern of med</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improperly filed claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Improperly filed claims Any person (including an organization, agency, or other entity, but excluding a beneficiary, as defined in subsection (i)(5)) that— shall be subject, in addition to any other penalties that may be prescribed by law, to a civil money penalty of not more than $20,000 for each item or service (or, in cases under paragraph (3), $30,000 for each individual with respect to whom false or misleading information was given; in cases under paragraph (4), $20,000 for each day the prohibited relationship occurs; in cases under paragraph (7), $100,000 for each such act,66 So in original. The comma probably should be a semicolon. in cases under paragraph (8),77 So in original. Probably is a reference to the first paragraph (8). $100,000 for each false record or statement,6 or 3 in cases under paragraph (9),88 So in original. Probably is a reference to the first paragraph (9). $15,000 for each day of the failure described in such paragraph); 99 So in original. Probably shou</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to induce reduction or limitation of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments to induce reduction or limitation of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of proceeding; authorization by Attorney General, notice, etc., estoppel, failure to comply with order or procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initiation of proceeding; authorization by Attorney General, notice, etc., estoppel, failure to comply with order or procedure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount or scope of penalty, assessment, or exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount or scope of penalty, assessment, or exclusion In determining the amount or scope of any penalty, assessment, or exclusion imposed pursuant to subsection (a) or (b), the Secretary shall take into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by courts of appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review by courts of appeals Any person adversely affected by a determination of the Secretary under this section may obtain a review of such determination in the United States Court of Appeals for the circuit in which the person resides, or in which the claim or specified claim was presented, by filing in such court (within sixty days following the date the person is notified of the Secretary’s determination) a written petition requesting that the determination be modified or set aside. A copy of the petition shall be forthwith transmitted by the clerk of the court to the Secretary, and thereupon the Secretary shall file in the Court 1111 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. the record in the proceeding as provided in section 2112 of title 28. Upon such filing, the court shall have jurisdiction of the proceeding and of the question determined therein, and shall have the power to make and enter upon the pleadings, testimony, and proceedings set forth in such record a </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compromise of penalties and assessments; recovery; use of funds recovered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compromise of penalties and assessments; recovery; use of funds recovered Civil money penalties and assessments imposed under this section may be compromised by the Secretary and may be recovered in a civil action in the name of the United States brought in United States district court for the district where the claim or specified claim (as defined in subsection (r)) was presented, or where the claimant (or, with respect to a person described in subsection (o), the person) resides, as determined by the Secretary. Amounts recovered under this section shall be paid to the Secretary and disposed of as follows: The amount of such penalty or assessment, when finally determined, or the amount agreed upon in compromise, may be deducted from any sum then or later owing by the United States or a State agency (or, in the case of a penalty or assessment under subsection (o), by a specified State agency (as defined in subsection (q)(6)), to the person against whom the penalty or assessment has</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finality of determination respecting penalty, assessment, or exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Finality of determination respecting penalty, assessment, or exclusion A determination by the Secretary to impose a penalty, assessment, or exclusion under subsection (a) or (b) shall be final upon the expiration of the sixty-day period referred to in subsection (e). Matters that were raised or that could have been raised in a hearing before the Secretary or in an appeal pursuant to subsection (e) may not be raised as a defense to a civil action by the United States to collect a penalty, assessment, or exclusion assessed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of appropriate entities of finality of determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notification of appropriate entities of finality of determination Whenever the Secretary’s determination to impose a penalty, assessment, or exclusion under subsection (a) or (b) becomes final, he shall notify the appropriate State or local medical or professional organization, the appropriate State agency or agencies administering or supervising the administration of State health care programs (as defined in section 1320a–7(h) of this title), and the appropriate utilization and quality control peer review organization, and the appropriate State or local licensing agency or organization (including the agency specified in section 1395aa(a) and 1396a(a)(33) of this title) that such a penalty, assessment, or exclusion has become final and the reasons therefor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For the purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320a_7a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpoenas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Subpoenas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>