<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1320b–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1320b_21"><akn:num>1320b–21</akn:num><akn:heading>State grants for work incentives assistance to disabled beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1320b–21. State grants for work incentives assistance to disabled beneficiaries(a) In generalSubject to subsection (c), the Commissioner may make payments in each State to the protection and advocacy system established pursuant to part C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (42 U.S.C. 6041 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. for the purpose of providing services to disabled beneficiaries.


(b) Services providedServices provided to disabled beneficiaries pursuant to a payment made under this section may include—(1) information and advice about obtaining vocational rehabilitation and employment services; and

(2) advocacy or other services that a disabled beneficiary may need to secure, maintain, or regain gainful employment.


(c) ApplicationIn order to receive payments under this section, a protection and advocacy system shall submit an application to the Commissioner, at such time, in such form and manner, and accompanied by such information and assurances as the Commissioner may require.


(d) Amount of payments(1) In generalSubject to the amount appropriated for a fiscal year for making payments under this section, a protection and advocacy system shall not be paid an amount that is less than—(A) in the case of a protection and advocacy system located in a State (including the District of Columbia and Puerto Rico) other than Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the greater of—(i) $100,000; or

(ii) ⅓ of 1 percent of the amount available for payments under this section; and


(B) in the case of a protection and advocacy system located in Guam, American Samoa, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, $50,000.


(2) Inflation adjustmentFor each fiscal year in which the total amount appropriated to carry out this section exceeds the total amount appropriated to carry out this section in the pre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsection (c), the Commissioner may make payments in each State to the protection and advocacy system established pursuant to part C of title I of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act (42 U.S.C. 6041 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. for the purpose of providing services to disabled beneficiaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Services provided Services provided to disabled beneficiaries pursuant to a payment made under this section may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application In order to receive payments under this section, a protection and advocacy system shall submit an application to the Commissioner, at such time, in such form and manner, and accompanied by such information and assurances as the Commissioner may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report Each protection and advocacy system that receives a payment under this section shall submit an annual report to the Commissioner and the Ticket to Work and Work Incentives Advisory Panel established under section 101(f) of the Ticket to Work and Work Incentives Improvement Act of 1999 on the services provided to individuals by the system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1320b_21_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $7,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2000 through 2011.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>