<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1321"><akn:num>1321</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements for transfer of funds; reimbursement by State; application; certification; </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1321. Eligibility requirements for transfer of funds; reimbursement by State; application; certification; limitation(a)(1) Advances shall be made to the States from the Federal unemployment account in the Unemployment Trust Fund as provided in this section, and shall be repayable, with interest to the extent provided in section 1322(b) of this title, in the manner provided in sections 1101(d)(1), 1103(b)(2), and 1322 of this title. An advance to a State for the payment of compensation in any 3-month period may be made if—(A) the Governor of the State applies therefor no earlier than the first day of the month preceding the first month of such 3-month period, and

(B) he furnishes to the Secretary of Labor his estimate of the amount of an advance which will be required by the State for the payment of compensation in each month of such 3-month period.


(2) In the case of any application for an advance under this section to any State for any 3-month period, the Secretary of Labor shall—(A) determine the amount (if any) which he finds will be required by such State for the payment of compensation in each month of such 3-month period, and

(B) certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the amount (not greater than the amount estimated by the Governor of the State) determined under subparagraph (A).


The aggregate of the amounts certified by the Secretary of Labor with respect to any 3-month period shall not exceed the amount which the Secretary of the Treasury reports to the Secretary of Labor is available in the Federal unemployment account for advances with respect to each month of such 3-month period.

(3) For purposes of this subsection—(A) an application for an advance shall be made on such forms, and shall contain such information and data (fiscal and otherwise) concerning the operation and administration of the State unemployment compensation law, as the Secretary of Labor deems necessary or relevant to the performance of his duties under this subchapter,

(B) t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary of the Treasury shall, prior to audit or settlement by the Government Accountability Office, transfer in monthly installments from the Federal unemployment account to the account of the State in the Unemployment Trust Fund the amount certified under subsection (a) by the Secretary of Labor (but not exceeding that portion of the balance in the Federal unemployment account at the time of the transfer which is not restricted as to use pursuant to section 1103(b)(1) of this title). The amount of any monthly installment so transferred shall not exceed the amount estimated by the State to be required for the payment of compensation for the month with respect to which such installment is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>