<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13213" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13213/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13213/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13213"><akn:num>13213</akn:num><akn:heading>Refueling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13213. Refueling(a) In generalFederal agencies shall, to the maximum extent practicable, arrange for the fueling of alternative fueled vehicles acquired under section 13212 of this title at commercial fueling facilities that offer alternative fuels for sale to the public. If publicly available fueling facilities are not convenient or accessible to the location of Federal alternative fueled vehicles purchased under section 13212 of this title, Federal agencies are authorized to enter into commercial arrangements for the purposes of fueling Federal alternative fueled vehicles, including, as appropriate, purchase, lease, contract, construction, or other arrangements in which the Federal Government is a participant.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1993 through 1998, to remain available until expended.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title III, § 304, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2872.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13213_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Federal agencies shall, to the maximum extent practicable, arrange for the fueling of alternative fueled vehicles acquired under section 13212 of this title at commercial fueling facilities that offer alternative fuels for sale to the public. If publicly available fueling facilities are not convenient or accessible to the location of Federal alternative fueled vehicles purchased under section 13212 of this title, Federal agencies are authorized to enter into commercial arrangements for the purposes of fueling Federal alternative fueled vehicles, including, as appropriate, purchase, lease, contract, construction, or other arrangements in which the Federal Government is a participant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13213_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1993 through 1998, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>