<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13257" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13257/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13257/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13257"><akn:num>13257</akn:num><akn:heading>Fleet requirement program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13257. Fleet requirement program(a) Fleet program purchase goals(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), the following percentages of new light duty motor vehicles acquired in each model year for a fleet, other than a Federal fleet, State fleet, or fleet owned, operated, leased, or otherwise controlled by a covered person subject to section 13251 of this title, shall be alternative fueled vehicles:(A) 20 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model years 1999, 2000, and 2001;

(B) 30 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model year 2002;

(C) 40 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model year 2003;

(D) 50 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model year 2004;

(E) 60 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model year 2005; and

(F) 70 percent of the motor vehicles acquired in model year 2006 and thereafter.


(2) The Secretary may not establish percentage requirements higher than those described in paragraph (1). The Secretary may, if appropriate, and pursuant to a rule under subsection (b), establish a lesser percentage requirement for any model year. The Secretary may, by rule, establish a date later than 1998 (or model year 1999) for initiating the fleet requirements under paragraph (1).

(3) The Secretary shall publish an advance notice of proposed rulemaking for the purpose of—(A) evaluating the progress toward achieving the goals of replacement fuel use described in section 13252(b)(2) of this title, as modified under section 13254 of this title;

(B) identifying the problems associated with achieving those goals;

(C) assessing the adequacy and practicability of those goals; and

(D) considering all actions needed to achieve those goals.


The Secretary shall provide for at least 3 regional hearings on the advance notice of proposed rulemaking, with respect to which official transcripts shall be maintained. The comment period in connection with such advance notice of proposed rulemaking shall be completed within 7 months after publication</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fleet program purchase goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fleet program purchase goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Early rulemaking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance notice of proposed rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advance notice of proposed rulemaking Not later than April 1, 1998, the Secretary shall publish an advance notice of proposed rulemaking for the purpose of— The Secretary shall provide for at least 3 regional hearings on the advance notice of proposed rulemaking, with respect to which official transcripts shall be maintained. The comment period in connection with such advance notice of proposed rulemaking shall be completed within 7 months after publication of the advance notice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Proposed rule Before May 1, 1999, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a proposed rule for the rule required under subsection (g), and shall provide for a public comment period, with hearings, of not less than 90 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Explanation of determination that fleet requirement program is not necessary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Explanation of determination that fleet requirement program is not necessary If the Secretary determines, based on findings under subsection (b) or (e), that a fleet requirement program under this section is not necessary, the Secretary shall— publish such determination in the Federal Register as a final agency action, including an explanation of the findings on which such determination is made and the basis for the determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fleet requirement program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fleet requirement program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of deadlines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Extension of deadlines The Secretary may, by notice published in the Federal Register, extend the deadlines established under subsections (e), (f)(2), and (g) for an additional 90 days if the Secretary is unable to meet such deadlines. Such extension shall not be reviewable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exemptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13257_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Conversions Nothing in this subchapter or the amendments made by this subchapter shall require a fleet owner to acquire conversion vehicles.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>