<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13251"><akn:num>13251</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandate for alternative fuel providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13251. Mandate for alternative fuel providers(a) In general(1) The Secretary shall, before January 1, 1994, issue regulations requiring that of the new light duty motor vehicles acquired by a covered person described in paragraph (2), the following percentages shall be alternative fueled vehicles for the following model years:(A) 30 percent for model year 1996.

(B) 50 percent for model year 1997.

(C) 70 percent for model year 1998.

(D) 90 percent for model year 1999 and thereafter.


(2) For purposes of this section, a person referred to in paragraph (1) is—(A) a covered person whose principal business is producing, storing, refining, processing, transporting, distributing, importing, or selling at wholesale or retail any alternative fuel other than electricity;

(B) a non-Federal covered person whose principal business is generating, transmitting, importing, or selling at wholesale or retail electricity; or

(C) a covered person—(i) who produces, imports, or produces and imports in combination, an average of 50,000 barrels per day or more of petroleum; and

(ii) a substantial portion of whose business is producing alternative fuels.



(3)(A) In the case of a covered person described in paragraph (2) with more than one affiliate, division, or other business unit, only an affiliate, division, or business unit which is substantially engaged in the alternative fuels business (as determined by the Secretary by rule) shall be subject to this subsection.

(B) No covered person or affiliate, division, or other business unit of such person whose principal business is—(i) transforming alternative fuels into a product that is not an alternative fuel; or

(ii) consuming alternative fuels as a feedstock or fuel in the manufacture of a product that is not an alternative fuel,


shall be subject to this subsection.


(4) The vehicles purchased pursuant to this section shall be operated solely on alternative fuels except when operating in an area where the appropriate altern</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revisions and extensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Revisions and extensions With respect to model years 1997 and thereafter, the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Option for electric utilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Option for electric utilities The Secretary shall, within 1 year after October 24, 1992, issue regulations requiring that, in the case of a covered person whose principal business is generating, transmitting, importing, or selling at wholesale or retail electricity, the requirements of subsection (a)(1) shall not apply until after December 31, 1997, with respect to electric motor vehicles. Any covered person described in this subsection which plans to acquire electric motor vehicles to comply with the requirements of this section shall so notify the Secretary before January 1, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13251_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to Congress The Secretary shall, before January 1, 1998, submit a report to the Congress providing detailed information on actions taken to carry out this section, and the progress made and problems encountered thereunder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>