<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13254" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13254/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13254/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13254"><akn:num>13254</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of goals; additional rulemaking authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13254. Modification of goals; additional rulemaking authority(a) Examination of goalsWithin 3 years after October 24, 1992, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary shall examine the goals established under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, in the context of the program goals stated under section 13252(a) of this title, to determine if the goals under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, including the applicable percentage requirements and dates, should be modified under this section. The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the results of each examination under this subsection and provide an opportunity for public comment.


(b) Modification of goalsIf, after analysis of information obtained in connection with carrying out subsection (a) or section 13252 of this title, or other information, and taking into account the determination of technical and economic feasibility made under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary determines that goals described in section 13252(b)(2) of this title, including the percentage requirements or dates, are not achievable, the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, shall, by rule, establish goals that are achievable, for purposes of this subchapter. The modification of goals under this section may include changing the target dates specified in section 13252(b)(2) of this title.


(c) Additional rulemaking authorityIf the Secretary determines that the achievement of goals described in section 13252(b)(2) of this title would result in a significant and correctable failure to meet the program goals described in section 13252(a) of this title, the Secretary shall issue such additional regulations as are necessary to remedy such failure. The Secretary shall have no authority under this Act to mandate the production of alternative fueled vehicles or to specify, as applicable, the models, lines, or types of, or marketing or pricing practices, policies, or strategies for, vehicles subject to this</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13254_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination of goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Examination of goals Within 3 years after October 24, 1992, and periodically thereafter, the Secretary shall examine the goals established under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, in the context of the program goals stated under section 13252(a) of this title, to determine if the goals under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, including the applicable percentage requirements and dates, should be modified under this section. The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the results of each examination under this subsection and provide an opportunity for public comment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13254_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modification of goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Modification of goals If, after analysis of information obtained in connection with carrying out subsection (a) or section 13252 of this title, or other information, and taking into account the determination of technical and economic feasibility made under section 13252(b)(2) of this title, the Secretary determines that goals described in section 13252(b)(2) of this title, including the percentage requirements or dates, are not achievable, the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, shall, by rule, establish goals that are achievable, for purposes of this subchapter. The modification of goals under this section may include changing the target dates specified in section 13252(b)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13254_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional rulemaking authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional rulemaking authority If the Secretary determines that the achievement of goals described in section 13252(b)(2) of this title would result in a significant and correctable failure to meet the program goals described in section 13252(a) of this title, the Secretary shall issue such additional regulations as are necessary to remedy such failure. The Secretary shall have no authority under this Act to mandate the production of alternative fueled vehicles or to specify, as applicable, the models, lines, or types of, or marketing or pricing practices, policies, or strategies for, vehicles subject to this Act. Nothing in this Act shall be construed to give the Secretary authority to mandate marketing or pricing practices, policies, or strategies for alternative fuels or to mandate the production or delivery of such fuels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>