<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13317" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13317/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13317/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13317"><akn:num>13317</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable energy production incentive</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13317. Renewable energy production incentive(a) Incentive payments(1) For electric energy generated and sold by a qualified renewable energy facility during the incentive period, the Secretary shall make, subject to the availability of appropriations, incentive payments to the owner or operator of such facility.

(2) The amount of such payment made to any such owner or operator shall be as determined under subsection (e).

(3) Payments under this section may only be made upon receipt by the Secretary of an incentive payment application which establishes that the applicant is eligible to receive such payment.

(4)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), if there are insufficient appropriations to make full payments for electric production from all qualified renewable energy facilities for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall assign—(i) 60 percent of appropriated funds for the fiscal year to facilities that use solar, wind, marine energy (as defined in section 17211 of this title), geothermal, or closed-loop (dedicated energy crops) biomass technologies to generate electricity; and

(ii) 40 percent of appropriated funds for the fiscal year to other projects.


(B) After submitting to Congress an explanation of the reasons for the alteration, the Secretary may alter the percentage requirements of subparagraph (A).



(b) Qualified renewable energy facilityFor purposes of this section, a qualified renewable energy facility is a facility which is owned by a not-for-profit electric cooperative, a public utility described in section 115 of title 26, a State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, or a political subdivision thereof, an Indian tribal government or subdivision thereof, or a Native Corporation (as defined in section 1602 of title 43), and which generates electric energy for sale in, or affecting, interstate commerce using solar, wind, biomass, landfill gas, livestock methane, marine energy (as defined in section 17211</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentive payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Incentive payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified renewable energy facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualified renewable energy facility For purposes of this section, a qualified renewable energy facility is a facility which is owned by a not-for-profit electric cooperative, a public utility described in section 115 of title 26, a State, Commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, or the District of Columbia, or a political subdivision thereof, an Indian tribal government or subdivision thereof, or a Native Corporation (as defined in section 1602 of title 43), and which generates electric energy for sale in, or affecting, interstate commerce using solar, wind, biomass, landfill gas, livestock methane, marine energy (as defined in section 17211 of this title), or geothermal energy, except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility window</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility window Payments may be made under this section only for electricity generated from a qualified renewable energy facility first used before October 1, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment period A qualified renewable energy facility may receive payments under this section for a 10-fiscal year period. Such period shall begin with the fiscal year in which electricity generated from the facility is first eligible for such payments, or in which the Secretary determines that all necessary Federal and State authorizations have been obtained to begin construction of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount of payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sunset No payment may be made under this section to any facility after September 30, 2026, and no payment may be made under this section to any facility after a payment has been made with respect to such facility for a 10-fiscal year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13317_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2026, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>