<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13361" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13361/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13361/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13361"><akn:num>13361</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean coal technology export promotion and interagency coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13361. Clean coal technology export promotion and interagency coordination(a) EstablishmentThere shall be established within the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (established by the President on May 23, 1990) a Clean Coal Technology Subgroup (in this part referred to as the “CCT Subgroup”) to focus interagency efforts on clean coal technologies. The CCT Subgroup shall seek to expand the export and use of clean coal technologies, particularly in those countries which can benefit from gains in the efficiency of, and the control of environmental emissions from, coal utilization.


(b) MembershipThe CCT Subgroup shall include 1 member from each agency represented on the Energy, Environment, and Infrastructure Working Group of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee as of October 24, 1992. The Secretary shall serve as chair of the CCT Subgroup and shall be responsible for ensuring that the functions of the CCT Subgroup are carried out through its member agencies.


(c) Consultation(1) In carrying out this section, the CCT Subgroup shall consult with representatives from the United States coal industry, representatives of railroads and other transportation industries, organizations representing workers, the electric utility industry, manufacturers of equipment utilizing clean coal technology, members of organizations formed to further the goals of environmental protection or to promote the development and use of clean coal technologies that are developed, manufactured, or controlled by United States firms, and other appropriate interested members of the public.

(2) The CCT Subgroup shall maintain ongoing liaison with other elements of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee relating to clean coal technologies or regions where these technologies could be important, including Eastern Europe, Asia, and the Pacific.


(d) DutiesThe Secretary, acting through the CCT Subgroup, shall—(1) facilitate the establishment of technical training for the consideration, pla</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be established within the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee (established by the President on May 23, 1990) a Clean Coal Technology Subgroup (in this part referred to as the “CCT Subgroup”) to focus interagency efforts on clean coal technologies. The CCT Subgroup shall seek to expand the export and use of clean coal technologies, particularly in those countries which can benefit from gains in the efficiency of, and the control of environmental emissions from, coal utilization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The CCT Subgroup shall include 1 member from each agency represented on the Energy, Environment, and Infrastructure Working Group of the Trade Promotion Coordinating Committee as of October 24, 1992. The Secretary shall serve as chair of the CCT Subgroup and shall be responsible for ensuring that the functions of the CCT Subgroup are carried out through its member agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties The Secretary, acting through the CCT Subgroup, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data and information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data and information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13361_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Within 180 days after the Secretary submits the report to the Congress as required by section 409 of Public Law 101–549, the Secretary, acting through the CCT Subgroup, shall provide to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, a plan which details actions to be taken in order to address those recommendations and findings made in the report submitted pursuant to section 409 of Public Law 101–549. As a part of the plan required by this subsection, the Secretary, acting through the CCT Subgroup, shall specifically address the adequacy of financial assistance available from Federal departments and agencies and international financing organizations to aid in the financing of prefeasibility and feasibility studies and projects that would use a clean coal technology in developing countries and countries making the transition from nonmarket to market economies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>