<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13368" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13368/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13368/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13368"><akn:num>13368</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership of coalbed methane</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13368. Ownership of coalbed methane(a) Federal lands and mineral rightsIn the case of any deposit of coalbed methane where the United States is the owner of the surface estate or where the United States has transferred the surface estate but reserved the subsurface mineral estate, the Secretary of the Interior shall administer this section. This section and the definitions contained herein shall be applicable only on lands within Affected States.


(b) Affected StatesNot later than 180 days after October 24, 1992, the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall publish in the Federal Register a list of Affected States which shall be comprised of States—(1) in which the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, determines that disputes, uncertainty, or litigation exist, regarding the ownership of coalbed methane gas;

(2) in which the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, determines that development of significant deposits of coalbed methane gas is being impeded by such existing disputes, uncertainty, or litigation regarding ownership of such coalbed methane;

(3) which do not have in effect a statutory or regulatory procedure or existing case law permitting and encouraging the development of coalbed methane gas within that State; and

(4) which do not have extensive development of coalbed methane gas.


The Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall revise such list of Affected States from time to time. Any Affected State shall be deleted from the list of Affected States upon the receipt by the Secretary of the Interior of a Governor’s petition requesting such deletion, a State law requesting such deletion, or a resolution requesting such deletion enacted by the legislative body of the State. A Governor intending to petition the Secretary of the Interior to delete a State from the list of Affected States shall</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal lands and mineral rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal lands and mineral rights In the case of any deposit of coalbed methane where the United States is the owner of the surface estate or where the United States has transferred the surface estate but reserved the subsurface mineral estate, the Secretary of the Interior shall administer this section. This section and the definitions contained herein shall be applicable only on lands within Affected States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Affected States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Affected States Not later than 180 days after October 24, 1992, the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall publish in the Federal Register a list of Affected States which shall be comprised of States— The Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall revise such list of Affected States from time to time. Any Affected State shall be deleted from the list of Affected States upon the receipt by the Secretary of the Interior of a Governor’s petition requesting such deletion, a State law requesting such deletion, or a resolution requesting such deletion enacted by the legislative body of the State. A Governor intending to petition the Secretary of the Interior to delete a State from the list of Affected States shall provide the State’s legislative body with 6 months notice of such petition during a legislative session. At the end of such 6-month period, the Governor may petition the Secretary of the Inter</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to adopt statutory or regulatory procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to adopt statutory or regulatory procedure If an Affected State has not placed in effect, by statute or by regulation, a substantial program promoting the permitting, drilling and production of coalbed methane wells (including pooling arrangements) within that State within 3 years after becoming an Affected State, the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall administer this section and shall promulgate such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section in that State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation by Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation by Secretary of the Interior In implementing this section, the Secretary of the Interior, with the participation of the Secretary of Energy, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Spacing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Spacing Except where State law in an Affected State contains existing spacing requirements regarding the minimum distance between coalbed methane wells and the minimum distance of a coalbed methane well from a property line, the Secretary of the Interior shall establish such requirements within 90 days after the assertion of jurisdiction pursuant to subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Spacing units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Spacing units Applications to establish spacing units for the drilling and operation of coalbed methane gas wells may be filed by any entity claiming a coalbed methane ownership interest within a proposed spacing unit. Upon receipt and approval of an application, the Secretary of the Interior shall issue an order establishing the boundaries of the coalbed methane spacing unit. Spacing units shall generally be uniform in size.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development under pooling arrangement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Development under pooling arrangement Following issuance of an order establishing a spacing unit under subsection (f), and pursuant to an application for pooling filed by the entity claiming a coalbed methane ownership interest and proposing to drill a coalbed methane gas well, the Secretary of the Interior shall hold a hearing to consider the application for pooling and shall, if the criteria of this section are met, issue an order allowing the proposed pooling of acreage within the designated spacing unit for purposes of drilling and production of coalbed methane from the spacing unit. The pooling order shall not be issued before notice or a reasonable and diligent effort to provide notice has been made to each entity which may claim an ownership interest in the coalbed methane gas within such spacing unit and each such entity has been offered an opportunity to appear before the Secretary of the Interior at the hearing. Upon issuance of a pooling order, each owner or claimant of </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Escrow account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Escrow account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Approval of Secretary of the Interior No entity may drill any well for the production of coalbed methane gas from a coal seam, subject to the provisions of subsection (g), in an Affected State unless the drilling of such well has been approved by the Secretary of the Interior.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13368_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization to stimulate coal seam</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization to stimulate coal seam</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>