<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13389" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13389/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13389/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13389"><akn:num>13389</akn:num><akn:heading>Greenhouse gas intensity reducing strategies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13389. Greenhouse gas intensity reducing strategies(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Advisory CommitteeThe term “Advisory Committee” means the Climate Change Technology Advisory Committee established under subsection (f)(1).


(2) Carbon sequestrationThe term “carbon sequestration” means the capture of carbon dioxide through terrestrial, geological, biological, or other means, which prevents the release of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.


(3) CommitteeThe term “Committee” means the Committee on Climate Change Technology established under subsection (b)(1).


(4) Developing countryThe term “developing country” has the meaning given the term in section 13387(m) of this title.


(5) Greenhouse gasThe term “greenhouse gas” means—(A) carbon dioxide;

(B) methane;

(C) nitrous oxide;

(D) hydrofluorocarbons;

(E) perfluorocarbons; and

(F) sulfur hexafluoride.


(6) Greenhouse gas intensityThe term “greenhouse gas intensity” means the ratio of greenhouse gas emissions to economic output.


(7) National LaboratoryThe term “National Laboratory” has the meaning given the term in section 15801(3) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.



(b) Committee on Climate Change Technology(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after August 8, 2005, the President shall establish a Committee on Climate Change Technology to—(A) integrate current Federal climate reports; and

(B) coordinate Federal climate change technology activities and programs carried out in furtherance of the strategy developed under subsection (c)(1).


(2) MembershipThe Committee shall be composed of at least 7 members, including—(A) the Secretary, who shall chair the Committee;

(B) the Secretary of Commerce;

(C) the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality;

(D) the Secretary of Agriculture;

(E) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;

(F) the Secretary of Transportation;

(G) the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy; and

(H) other representative</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee on Climate Change Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Committee on Climate Change Technology</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National climate change technology policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National climate change technology policy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Climate Change Technology Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Climate Change Technology Program Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Committee is established under subsection (b)(1), the Secretary, in consultation with the Committee, shall establish within the Department of Energy the Climate Change Technology Program to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology inventory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technology inventory</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Climate Change Technology Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Climate Change Technology Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Greenhouse gas intensity reducing technology deployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Greenhouse gas intensity reducing technology deployment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for calculating, monitoring, and analyzing greenhouse gas intensity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Procedures for calculating, monitoring, and analyzing greenhouse gas intensity The Secretary, in collaboration with the Committee and the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and after public notice and opportunity for comment, shall develop standards and best practices for calculating, monitoring, and analyzing greenhouse gas intensity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Demonstration projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13389_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative research and development agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Cooperative research and development agreements In carrying out greenhouse gas intensity reduction research and technology deployment activities under this subtitle,22 So in original. See References in Text note below. the Secretary may enter into cooperative research and development agreements under section 3710a of title 15.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>