<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13387" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13387/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13387/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13387"><akn:num>13387</akn:num><akn:heading>Innovative environmental technology transfer program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13387. Innovative environmental technology transfer program(a) Establishment of programThe Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the interagency working group established under section 6276(d) of this title (in this section referred to as the “interagency working group”,11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by a closing parenthesis. shall establish a technology transfer program to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b). Within 150 days after October 24, 1992, the Secretary and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall enter into a written agreement to carry out this section. The agreement shall establish a procedure for resolving any disputes between the Secretary and the Administrator regarding the implementation of specific projects. With respect to countries not assisted by the Agency for International Development, the Secretary may enter into agreements with other appropriate Federal agencies. If the Secretary and the Administrator, or the Secretary and an agency described in the previous sentence, are unable to reach an agreement, each shall send a memorandum to the President outlining an appropriate agreement. Within 90 days after receipt of either memorandum, the President shall determine which version of the agreement shall be in effect. Any agreement entered into under this subsection shall be provided to the appropriate committees of the Congress and made available to the public.


(b) Purposes of programThe purposes of the technology transfer program under this section are to—(1) reduce the United States balance of trade deficit through the export of United States energy technologies and technological expertise;

(2) retain and create manufacturing and related service jobs in the United States;

(3) encourage the export of United States technologies, including services related thereto, to those countries that have a need for developmentally sound facilities to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program The Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the interagency working group established under section 6276(d) of this title (in this section referred to as the “interagency working group”,11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by a closing parenthesis. shall establish a technology transfer program to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b). Within 150 days after October 24, 1992, the Secretary and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development shall enter into a written agreement to carry out this section. The agreement shall establish a procedure for resolving any disputes between the Secretary and the Administrator regarding the implementation of specific projects. With respect to countries not assisted by the Agency for International Development, the Secretary may enter into agreements with other appropriate Federal agencies. If the Secretary and the Administrator, or the Secre</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes of program The purposes of the technology transfer program under this section are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification Pursuant to the agreements required by subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and after consultation with the interagency working group, United States firms, and representatives from foreign countries, shall develop mechanisms to identify potential energy projects in host countries that substantially reduce environmental pollutants, including greenhouse gases, and shall identify a list of such projects within 240 days after October 24, 1992, and periodically thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial mechanisms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Financial mechanisms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitations for project proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Solicitations for project proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to United States firms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assistance to United States firms Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the interagency working group, shall establish a procedure to provide financial assistance to United States firms under this section for a project identified under subsection (c) where solicitations for the project are being conducted by the host country or by a multilateral lending institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other program requirements Pursuant to the agreements under subsection (a), the Secretary, through the Agency for International Development, and in consultation with the interagency working group, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Eligible technologies Not later than 6 months after October 24, 1992, the Secretary shall prepare a list of eligible technologies and services under this section. In preparing such a list, the Secretary shall consider fuel cell powerplants, aeroderivitive gas turbines and catalytic combustion technologies for aeroderivitive gas turbines, ocean thermal energy conversion technology, anaerobic digester and storage tanks, and other renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Selection of projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13387_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States-Asia Environmental Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) United States-Asia Environmental Partnership Activities carried out under this section shall be coordinated with the United States-Asia Environmental Partnership.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>