<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13382" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13382/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13382/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13382"><akn:num>13382</akn:num><akn:heading>Least-cost energy strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13382. Least-cost energy strategy(a) StrategyThe first National Energy Policy Plan (in this subchapter referred to as the “Plan”) under section 7321 of this title prepared and required to be submitted by the President to Congress after February 1, 1993, and each subsequent such Plan, shall include a least-cost energy strategy prepared by the Secretary. In developing the least-cost energy strategy, the Secretary shall take into consideration the economic, energy, social, environmental, and competitive costs and benefits, including costs and benefits for jobs, of his choices. Such strategy shall also take into account the report required under section 13381 of this title and relevant Federal, State, and local requirements. Such strategy shall be designed to achieve to the maximum extent practicable and at least-cost to the Nation—(1) the energy production, utilization, and energy conservation priorities of subsection (d);

(2) the stabilization and eventual reduction in the generation of greenhouse gases;

(3) an increase in the efficiency of the Nation’s total energy use by 30 percent over 1988 levels by the year 2010;

(4) an increase in the percentage of energy derived from renewable resources by 75 percent over 1988 levels by the year 2005; and

(5) a reduction in the Nation’s oil consumption from the 1990 level of approximately 40 percent of total energy use to 35 percent by the year 2005.


(b) Additional contentsThe least-cost energy strategy shall also include—(1) a comprehensive inventory of available energy and energy efficiency resources and their projected costs, taking into account all costs of production, transportation, distribution, and utilization of such resources, including—(A) coal, clean coal technologies, coal seam methane, and underground coal gasification;

(B) energy efficiency, including existing technologies for increased efficiency in production, transportation, distribution, and utilization of energy, and other technologies that are anti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Strategy The first National Energy Policy Plan (in this subchapter referred to as the “Plan”) under section 7321 of this title prepared and required to be submitted by the President to Congress after February 1, 1993, and each subsequent such Plan, shall include a least-cost energy strategy prepared by the Secretary. In developing the least-cost energy strategy, the Secretary shall take into consideration the economic, energy, social, environmental, and competitive costs and benefits, including costs and benefits for jobs, of his choices. Such strategy shall also take into account the report required under section 13381 of this title and relevant Federal, State, and local requirements. Such strategy shall be designed to achieve to the maximum extent practicable and at least-cost to the Nation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Additional contents The least-cost energy strategy shall also include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretarial consideration In developing the least-cost energy strategy, the Secretary shall give full consideration to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priorities The least-cost energy strategy shall identify Federal priorities, including policies that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assumptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assumptions The Secretary shall include in the least-cost energy strategy an identification of all of the assumptions used in developing the strategy and priorities thereunder, and the reasons for such assumptions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preference When comparing an energy efficiency resource to an energy resource, a higher priority shall be assigned to the energy efficiency resource whenever all direct and quantifiable net costs for the resource over its available life are equal to the estimated cost of the energy resource.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13382_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public review and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public review and comment The Secretary shall provide for a period of public review and comment of the least-cost energy strategy, for a period of at least 30 days, to be completed at least 60 days before the issuance of such strategy. The Secretary shall also provide for public review and comment before the issuance of any update to the least-cost energy strategy required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>