<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13388" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13388/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13388/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13388"><akn:num>13388</akn:num><akn:heading>Global Climate Change Response Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13388. Global Climate Change Response Fund(a) Establishment of FundThe Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish a Global Climate Change Response Fund to act as a mechanism for United States contributions to assist global efforts in mitigating and adapting to global climate change.


(b) Restrictions on depositsNo deposits shall be made to the Global Climate Change Response Fund until the United States has ratified the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change.


(c) Use of FundMoneys deposited into the Fund shall be used by the President, to the extent authorized and appropriated under section 2222 of title 22, solely for contributions to a financial mechanism negotiated pursuant to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, including all protocols or agreements related thereto.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated for deposit in the Fund to carry out the purposes of this section, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1995 and 1996.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title XVI, § 1609, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3007.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13388_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Fund The Secretary of the Treasury, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall establish a Global Climate Change Response Fund to act as a mechanism for United States contributions to assist global efforts in mitigating and adapting to global climate change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13388_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restrictions on deposits No deposits shall be made to the Global Climate Change Response Fund until the United States has ratified the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13388_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of Fund Moneys deposited into the Fund shall be used by the President, to the extent authorized and appropriated under section 2222 of title 22, solely for contributions to a financial mechanism negotiated pursuant to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, including all protocols or agreements related thereto.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13388_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated for deposit in the Fund to carry out the purposes of this section, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 1995 and 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>