<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13413"><akn:num>13413</akn:num><akn:heading>Natural gas supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13413. Natural gas supply(a) Program directionThe Secretary shall conduct a 5-year program, in accordance with sections 13541 and 13542 of this title, to increase the recoverable natural gas resource base including, but not limited to—(1) more intensive recovery of natural gas from discovered conventional resources;

(2) the extraction of natural gas from tight gas sands and devonian shales or other unconventional sources;

(3) surface gasification of coal; and

(4) recovery of methane from biofuels including municipal solid waste.


(b) ProposalsWithin 1 year after October 24, 1992, the Secretary shall solicit proposals for conducting activities under this section.


(c) Cofiring of natural gas and coal(1) ProgramThe Secretary shall establish and carry out a 5-year program, in accordance with sections 13541 and 13542 of this title, on cofiring natural gas with coal in utility and large industrial boilers in order to determine optimal natural gas injection levels for both environmental and operational benefits.


(2) Financial assistanceThe Secretary shall enter into agreements with, and provide financial assistance to, appropriate parties for application of cofiring technologies to boilers to demonstrate this technology.


(3) Report to CongressThe Secretary shall, before December 31, 1995, submit to the Congress a report on the progress made in carrying out this subsection.



(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section and sections 13414 and 13415 of this title, $29,745,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $45,000,000 for fiscal year 1994.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title XX, § 2013, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3059.)

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 13605. Supporting Safe and Responsible Development of Unconventional Domestic Natural Gas Resources
Ex. Ord. No. 13605, Apr. 13, 2012, 77 F.R. 23107, provided:
By the authority vested in me as President by the Constitution and the laws of the United Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program direction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program direction The Secretary shall conduct a 5-year program, in accordance with sections 13541 and 13542 of this title, to increase the recoverable natural gas resource base including, but not limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Proposals Within 1 year after October 24, 1992, the Secretary shall solicit proposals for conducting activities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cofiring of natural gas and coal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cofiring of natural gas and coal</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section and sections 13414 and 13415 of this title, $29,745,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $45,000,000 for fiscal year 1994.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>