<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13504" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13504/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13504/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13504"><akn:num>13504</akn:num><akn:heading>Math and science education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13504. Math and science education program(a) ProgramThe Secretary shall enter into contracts with existing qualified entities to conduct science and mathematics education programs that supplement the Special Programs for Students from Disadvantaged Backgrounds carried out by the Secretary of Education under sections 1070d through 1070d–1d of title 20.11 See References in Text note below.


(b) Purpose(1) The purpose of the programs shall be to provide support to Federal, State, and private programs designed to promote the participation of low-income and first generation college students as defined in section 1070d of title 20 1 in post-secondary science and mathematics education.

(2) Support activities may include—(A) the development of educational materials;

(B) the training of teachers and counselors;

(C) the establishment of student internships;

(D) the development of seminars on mathematics and science;

(E) tutoring in mathematics and science;

(F) academic counseling;

(G) the development of opportunities for research; and

(H) such other activities that may promote the participation of low-income and first generation college students in post-secondary science and mathematics education.



(c) Support(1) In carrying out the purpose of this section, the entities may provide support under subsection (b)(2) to—(A) low-income and first generation college students; and

(B) institutions of higher education, public and private agencies and organizations, and secondary and middle schools that principally benefit low-income students.


(2) The qualified entities shall, to the extent practicable, coordinate support activities under this section with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary.


(d) Cooperation with qualified entitiesThe Secretary shall cooperate with qualified entities and, to the extent practicable, make available to the entities such personnel, facilities, and other resources of the Department of Energy as may be necessary to carry out the du</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program The Secretary shall enter into contracts with existing qualified entities to conduct science and mathematics education programs that supplement the Special Programs for Students from Disadvantaged Backgrounds carried out by the Secretary of Education under sections 1070d through 1070d–1d of title 20.11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with qualified entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperation with qualified entities The Secretary shall cooperate with qualified entities and, to the extent practicable, make available to the entities such personnel, facilities, and other resources of the Department of Energy as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Not later than October 1 of each year, the entities shall report to the Secretary, the Secretary of Education, and the Congress on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect on existing programs The programs in this section shall supplement and be developed in cooperation with the current mathematics and science education programs of the Department of Energy and the Department of Education but shall not supplant them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Qualified entity” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Qualified entity” defined For purposes of this section, the term “qualified entity” means a nonprofit corporation, association, or institution that has demonstrated special knowledge of, and experience with, the education of low-income and first generation college students and whose primary mission is the operation of national programs that focus on low-income students and provide training and other services to educators.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13504_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary, to be derived from section 13503(e) of this title and the Environmental Restoration and Waste Management program, to carry out the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>