<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13542" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13542/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13542/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13542"><akn:num>13542</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13542. Cost sharing(a) Research and developmentExcept as otherwise provided in this Act, for research and development programs carried out under this Act, the Secretary shall require a commitment from non-Federal sources of at least 20 percent of the cost of the project. The Secretary may reduce or eliminate the non-Federal requirement under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the research and development is of a basic or fundamental nature.


(b) Demonstration and commercial applicationExcept as otherwise provided in this Act, the Secretary shall require at least 50 percent of the costs directly and specifically related to any demonstration or commercial application project under this Act to be provided from non-Federal sources. The Secretary may reduce the non-Federal requirement under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the reduction is necessary and appropriate considering the technological risks involved in the project and is necessary to meet the objectives of this Act.


(c) Calculation of amountIn calculating the amount of the non-Federal commitment under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary shall include cash, personnel, services, equipment, and other resources.


(d) Tennessee Valley AuthorityFunds derived by the Tennessee Valley Authority from its power program may be used for all or part of any cost sharing requirements under this section, except to the extent that such funds are provided by annual appropriation Acts.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title XXX, § 3002, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3127.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is Pub. L. 102–486, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2776, known as the Energy Policy Act of 1992. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 13201 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13542_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research and development Except as otherwise provided in this Act, for research and development programs carried out under this Act, the Secretary shall require a commitment from non-Federal sources of at least 20 percent of the cost of the project. The Secretary may reduce or eliminate the non-Federal requirement under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the research and development is of a basic or fundamental nature.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13542_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration and commercial application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Demonstration and commercial application Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the Secretary shall require at least 50 percent of the costs directly and specifically related to any demonstration or commercial application project under this Act to be provided from non-Federal sources. The Secretary may reduce the non-Federal requirement under this subsection if the Secretary determines that the reduction is necessary and appropriate considering the technological risks involved in the project and is necessary to meet the objectives of this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13542_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Calculation of amount In calculating the amount of the non-Federal commitment under paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary shall include cash, personnel, services, equipment, and other resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13542_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tennessee Valley Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tennessee Valley Authority Funds derived by the Tennessee Valley Authority from its power program may be used for all or part of any cost sharing requirements under this section, except to the extent that such funds are provided by annual appropriation Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>