<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13552" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13552/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13552/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13552"><akn:num>13552</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of energy futures for fuel purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13552. Use of energy futures for fuel purchases(a) Fuel studyThe Secretary shall conduct a study—(1) to ascertain if the use of energy futures and options contracts could provide cost-effective protection for Government entities (including Government purchases for military purposes and for the Strategic Petroleum Reserve) and consumer cooperatives (or any organization whose purpose is to purchase fuel in bulk) from unanticipated surges in the price of fuel; and

(2) to ascertain how such Government entities or consumer cooperatives may be educated in the prudent use of energy futures and options contracts to maximize their purchasing effectiveness, protect themselves against unanticipated surges in the price of fuel, and minimize fuel costs.


(b) Pilot programThe Secretary shall conduct a pilot program, commencing not later than 30 days after the transmission of the study required in subsection (b),11 See References in Text note below. to educate such governmental entities, consumer cooperatives, or other organizations on the prudent and cost-effective use of energy futures and options contracts to increase their protection against unanticipated surges in the price of fuel and thereby increase the efficiency of their fuel purchase or assistance programs.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 102–486, title XXX, § 3014, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3128; Pub. L. 105–362, title IV, § 401(f), Nov. 10, 1998, 112 Stat. 3282.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSubsection (b), referred to in subsec. (b), was repealed and subsec. (c) of this section was redesignated (b) by Pub. L. 105–362, title IV, § 401(f), Nov. 10, 1998, 112 Stat. 3282. See 1998 Amendment note below.

Amendments1998—Subsecs. (b) to (d). Pub. L. 105–362 redesignated subsecs. (c) and (d) as (b) and (c), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former subsec. (b). Text read as follows: “The Se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13552_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fuel study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fuel study The Secretary shall conduct a study—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13552_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pilot program The Secretary shall conduct a pilot program, commencing not later than 30 days after the transmission of the study required in subsection (b),11 See References in Text note below. to educate such governmental entities, consumer cooperatives, or other organizations on the prudent and cost-effective use of energy futures and options contracts to increase their protection against unanticipated surges in the price of fuel and thereby increase the efficiency of their fuel purchase or assistance programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13552_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>