<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13574" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13574/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/13574/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_13574"><akn:num>13574</akn:num><akn:heading>Air quality enhancement program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 13574. Air quality enhancement program(a) Eligible projectsProjects supported under section 13572(a)(2) of this title shall—(1) utilize technologies that meet relevant Federal and State clean air requirements applicable to the unit or facility, including being adequately demonstrated for purposes of section 7411 of this title, achievable for purposes of section 7479 of this title, or achievable in practice for purposes of section 7501 of this title; or

(2) utilize equipment or processes that exceed relevant Federal or State clean air requirements applicable to the unit or facilities included in the projects by achieving greater efficiency or environmental performance.


(b) Priority in project selectionIn making an award under section 13572(a)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall give priority to—(1) projects whose installation is likely to result in significant air quality improvements in nonattainment air quality areas or substantially reduce the emission level of criteria pollutants and mercury air emissions;

(2) projects for pollution control that result in the mitigation or collection of more than 1 pollutant; and

(3) projects designed to allow the use of the waste byproducts or other byproducts of the equipment.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out section 13572(a)(2) of this title—(1) $300,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;

(2) $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(3) $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;

(4) $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2010; and

(5) $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2011.


(d) ApplicabilityNo technology, or level of emission reduction under subsection (a)(2) shall be treated as adequately demonstrated for purpose of Section 11 So in original. Probably should be “purposes of section”. 7411 of this title, achievable for purposes of section 7479 of this title, or achievable in practice for purposes of section 7501 of this title solely by reason of the use of such technology, or the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13574_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligible projects Projects supported under section 13572(a)(2) of this title shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13574_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority in project selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority in project selection In making an award under section 13572(a)(2) of this title, the Secretary shall give priority to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13574_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out section 13572(a)(2) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_13574_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability No technology, or level of emission reduction under subsection (a)(2) shall be treated as adequately demonstrated for purpose of Section 11 So in original. Probably should be “purposes of section”. 7411 of this title, achievable for purposes of section 7479 of this title, or achievable in practice for purposes of section 7501 of this title solely by reason of the use of such technology, or the achievement of such emission reduction, by one or more facilities receiving assistance under section 13572(a)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>