<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1382d"><akn:num>1382d</akn:num><akn:heading>Rehabilitation services for blind and disabled individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1382d. Rehabilitation services for blind and disabled individuals(a) Referral by Commissioner of eligible individuals to appropriate State agencyIn the case of any blind or disabled individual who—(1) has not attained age 16; and

(2) with respect to whom benefits are paid under this subchapter,


the Commissioner of Social Security shall make provision for referral of such individual to the appropriate State agency administering the State program under subchapter V.

(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(c)(8)(B), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 828

(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–170, title I, § 101(b)(2)(B), Dec. 17, 1999, 113 Stat. 1874

(d) Reimbursement by Commissioner to State agency of costs of providing services to referred individualsThe Commissioner of Social Security is authorized to reimburse the State agency administering or supervising the administration of a State plan for vocational rehabilitation services approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.] for the costs incurred under such plan in the provision of rehabilitation services to individuals who are referred for such services pursuant to subsection (a), (1) in cases where the furnishing of such services results in the performance by such individuals of substantial gainful activity for a continuous period of nine months, (2) in cases where such individuals receive benefits as a result of section 1383(a)(6) of this title (except that no reimbursement under this subsection shall be made for services furnished to any individual receiving such benefits for any period after the close of such individual’s ninth consecutive month of substantial gainful activity or the close of the month with which his or her entitlement to such benefits ceases, whichever first occurs), and (3) in cases where such individuals, without good cause, refuse to continue to accept vocational rehabilitation services or fail to cooperate in such a manner as to preclude their successful rehabili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral by Commissioner of eligible individuals to appropriate State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Referral by Commissioner of eligible individuals to appropriate State agency In the case of any blind or disabled individual who— the Commissioner of Social Security shall make provision for referral of such individual to the appropriate State agency administering the State program under subchapter V.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2193(c)(8)(B), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 828</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 106–170, title I, § 101(b)(2)(B), Dec. 17, 1999, 113 Stat. 1874</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement by Commissioner to State agency of costs of providing services to referred individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reimbursement by Commissioner to State agency of costs of providing services to referred individuals The Commissioner of Social Security is authorized to reimburse the State agency administering or supervising the administration of a State plan for vocational rehabilitation services approved under title I of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 [29 U.S.C. 720 et seq.] for the costs incurred under such plan in the provision of rehabilitation services to individuals who are referred for such services pursuant to subsection (a), (1) in cases where the furnishing of such services results in the performance by such individuals of substantial gainful activity for a continuous period of nine months, (2) in cases where such individuals receive benefits as a result of section 1383(a)(6) of this title (except that no reimbursement under this subsection shall be made for services furnished to any individual receiving such benefits for any period after the close of such individual’s ninth consecutiv</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for vocational rehabilitation services furnished during certain months of nonpayment of insurance benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reimbursement for vocational rehabilitation services furnished during certain months of nonpayment of insurance benefits The Commissioner of Social Security may reimburse the State agency described in subsection (d) for the costs described therein incurred in the provision of rehabilitation services—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>