<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1382h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1382h"><akn:num>1382h</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits for individuals who perform substantial gainful activity despite severe medical impairment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1382h. Benefits for individuals who perform substantial gainful activity despite severe medical impairment(a) Eligible individuals(1) Except as provided in section 1383(j) of this title, any individual who was determined to be an eligible individual (or eligible spouse) by reason of being under a disability and was eligible to receive benefits under section 1382 of this title (or a federally administered State supplementary payment) for a month and whose earnings in a subsequent month exceed the amount designated by the Commissioner of Social Security ordinarily to represent substantial gainful activity shall qualify for a monthly benefit under this subsection for such subsequent month (which shall be in lieu of any benefit under section 1382 of this title) equal to an amount determined under section 1382(b)(1) of this title (or, in the case of an individual who has an eligible spouse, under section 1382(b)(2) of this title), and for purposes of subchapter XIX shall be considered to be receiving supplemental security income benefits under this subchapter, for so long as—(A) such individual continues to have the disabling physical or mental impairment on the basis of which such individual was found to be under a disability; and

(B) the income of such individual, other than income excluded pursuant to section 1382a(b) of this title, is not equal to or in excess of the amount which would cause him to be ineligible for payments under section 1382 of this title and such individual meets all other non-disability-related requirements for eligibility for benefits under this subchapter.


(2) The Commissioner of Social Security shall make a determination under paragraph (1)(A) with respect to an individual not later than 12 months after the first month for which the individual qualifies for a benefit under this subsection.


(b) Blind or disabled individuals receiving supplemental security income benefits(1) Except as provided in section 1383(j) of this title, for purpose</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligible individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Blind or disabled individuals receiving supplemental security income benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Blind or disabled individuals receiving supplemental security income benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing disability or blindness reviews; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Continuing disability or blindness reviews; limitation Subsection (a)(2) and section 1383(j)(2)(A) of this title shall not be construed, singly or jointly, to require more than 1 determination during any 12-month period with respect to the continuing disability or blindness of an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1382h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information and training programs The Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary of Education shall jointly develop and disseminate information, and establish training programs for staff personnel, with respect to the potential availability of benefits and services for disabled individuals under the provisions of this section. The Commissioner of Social Security shall provide such information to individuals who are applicants for and recipients of benefits based on disability under this subchapter and shall conduct such programs for the staffs of the district offices of the Social Security Administration. The Secretary of Education shall conduct such programs for the staffs of the State Vocational Rehabilitation agencies, and in cooperation with such agencies shall also provide such information to other appropriate individuals and to public and private organizations and agencies which are concerned with rehabilitation and social services or which represent the disabled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>