<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1383b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1383b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1383b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1383b"><akn:num>1383b</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1383b. Administration(a) Authority of CommissionerSubject to subsection (b), the Commissioner of Social Security may make such administrative and other arrangements (including arrangements for the determination of blindness and disability under section 1382c(a)(2) and (3) of this title in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided with respect to disability determinations under section 421 of this title) as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the Commissioner’s functions under this subchapter.


(b) Examination to determine blindnessIn determining, for purposes of this subchapter, whether an individual is blind, there shall be an examination of such individual by a physician skilled in the diseases of the eye or by an optometrist, whichever the individual may select.


(c) Notification of review(1) In any case in which the Commissioner of Social Security initiates a review under this subchapter, similar to the continuing disability reviews authorized for purposes of subchapter II under section 421(i) of this title, the Commissioner of Social Security shall notify the individual whose case is to be reviewed in the same manner as required under section 421(i)(4) of this title.

(2) For suspension of continuing disability reviews and other reviews under this subchapter similar to reviews under section 421 of this title in the case of an individual using a ticket to work and self-sufficiency, see section 1320b–19(i) of this title.


(d) Regulations regarding completion of plans for achieving self-supportThe Commissioner of Social Security shall establish by regulation criteria for time limits and other criteria related to individuals’ plans for achieving self-support, that take into account—(1) the length of time that the individual will need to achieve the individual’s employment goal (within such reasonable period as the Commissioner of Social Security may establish); and

(2) other factors determined by the Commissioner of Social Securi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Commissioner Subject to subsection (b), the Commissioner of Social Security may make such administrative and other arrangements (including arrangements for the determination of blindness and disability under section 1382c(a)(2) and (3) of this title in the same manner and subject to the same conditions as provided with respect to disability determinations under section 421 of this title) as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the Commissioner’s functions under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examination to determine blindness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Examination to determine blindness In determining, for purposes of this subchapter, whether an individual is blind, there shall be an examination of such individual by a physician skilled in the diseases of the eye or by an optometrist, whichever the individual may select.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations regarding completion of plans for achieving self-support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations regarding completion of plans for achieving self-support The Commissioner of Social Security shall establish by regulation criteria for time limits and other criteria related to individuals’ plans for achieving self-support, that take into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1383b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of State agency blindness and disability determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review of State agency blindness and disability determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>