<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_22"><akn:num>1395w–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefits and beneficiary protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–22. Benefits and beneficiary protections(a) Basic benefits(1) Requirement(A) In generalExcept as provided in section 1395w–28(b)(3) of this title for MSA plans and except as provided in paragraph (6) for MA regional plans, each Medicare+Choice plan shall provide to members enrolled under this part, through providers and other persons that meet the applicable requirements of this subchapter and part A of subchapter XI, benefits under the original medicare fee-for-service program option (and, for plan years before 2006, additional benefits required under section 1395w–24(f)(1)(A) of this title).


(B) Benefits under the original medicare fee-for-service program option defined(i) In generalFor purposes of this part, the term “benefits under the original medicare fee-for-service program option” means, subject to subsection (m), those items and services (other than hospice care or coverage for organ acquisitions for kidney transplants, including as covered under section 1395rr(d) of this title) for which benefits are available under parts A and B to individuals entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B, with cost-sharing for those services as required under parts A and B or, subject to clause (iii), an actuarially equivalent level of cost-sharing as determined in this part.


(ii) Special rule for regional plansIn the case of an MA regional plan in determining an actuarially equivalent level of cost-sharing with respect to benefits under the original medicare fee-for-service program option, there shall only be taken into account, with respect to the application of section 1395w–27a(b)(2) of this title, such expenses only with respect to subparagraph (A) of such section.


(iii) Limitation on variation of cost sharing for certain benefitsSubject to clause (v), cost-sharing for services described in clause (iv) shall not exceed the cost-sharing required for those services under parts A and B.


(iv) Services describedThe following services are des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Basic benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antidiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Antidiscrimination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disclosure requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality improvement program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Quality improvement program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grievance mechanism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grievance mechanism Each Medicare+Choice organization must provide meaningful procedures for hearing and resolving grievances between the organization (including any entity or individual through which the organization provides health care services) and enrollees with Medicare+Choice plans of the organization under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage determinations, reconsiderations, and appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coverage determinations, reconsiderations, and appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality and accuracy of enrollee records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Confidentiality and accuracy of enrollee records Insofar as a Medicare+Choice organization maintains medical records or other health information regarding enrollees under this part, the Medicare+Choice organization shall establish procedures—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on advance directives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Information on advance directives Each Medicare+Choice organization shall meet the requirement of section 1395cc(f) of this title (relating to maintaining written policies and procedures respecting advance directives).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_22_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules regarding provider participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rules regarding provider participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>