<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395rr–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395rr–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395rr–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395rr_1"><akn:num>1395rr–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare coverage for individuals exposed to environmental health hazards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395rr–1. Medicare coverage for individuals exposed to environmental health hazards(a) Deeming of individuals as eligible for medicare benefits(1) In generalFor purposes of eligibility for benefits under this subchapter, an individual determined under subsection (c) to be an environmental exposure affected individual described in subsection (e)(2) shall be deemed to meet the conditions specified in section 426(a) of this title.


(2) Discretionary deemingFor purposes of eligibility for benefits under this subchapter, the Secretary may deem an individual determined under subsection (c) to be an environmental exposure affected individual described in subsection (e)(3) to meet the conditions specified in section 426(a) of this title.


(3) Effective date of coverageAn Individual 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. who is deemed eligible for benefits under this subchapter under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be—(A) entitled to benefits under the program under Part 1 A as of the date of such deeming; and

(B) eligible to enroll in the program under Part 1 B beginning with the month in which such deeming occurs.



(b) Pilot program for care of certain individuals residing in emergency declaration areas(1) Program; purpose(A) Primary pilot programThe Secretary shall establish a pilot program in accordance with this subsection to provide innovative approaches to furnishing comprehensive, coordinated, and cost-effective care under this subchapter to individuals described in paragraph (2)(A).


(B) Optional pilot programsThe Secretary may establish a separate pilot program, in accordance with this subsection, with respect to each geographic area subject to an emergency declaration (other than the declaration of June 17, 2009), in order to furnish such comprehensive, coordinated and cost-effective care to individuals described in subparagraph (2)(B) who reside in each such area.



(2) Individual describedFor purposes of paragraph (1), an individual described</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395rr_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deeming of individuals as eligible for medicare benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deeming of individuals as eligible for medicare benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395rr_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot program for care of certain individuals residing in emergency declaration areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pilot program for care of certain individuals residing in emergency declaration areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395rr_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395rr_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency declaration defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Emergency declaration defined For purposes of this section, the term “emergency declaration” means a declaration of a public health emergency under section 9604(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395rr_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental exposure affected individual defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental exposure affected individual defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>