<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395pp" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395pp/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395pp/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395pp"><akn:num>1395pp</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on liability where claims are disallowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395pp. Limitation on liability where claims are disallowed(a) Conditions prerequisite to payment for items and services notwithstanding determination of disallowanceWhere—(1) a determination is made that, by reason of section 1395y(a)(1) or (9) of this title or by reason of a coverage denial described in subsection (g), payment may not be made under part A or part B of this subchapter for any expenses incurred for items or services furnished an individual by a provider of services or by another person pursuant to an assignment under section 1395u(b)(3)(B)(ii) of this title, and

(2) both such individual and such provider of services or such other person, as the case may be, did not know, and could not reasonably have been expected to know, that payment would not be made for such items or services under such part A or part B,


then to the extent permitted by this subchapter, payment shall, notwithstanding such determination, be made for such items or services (and for such period of time as the Secretary finds will carry out the objectives of this subchapter), as though section 1395y(a)(1) and section 1395y(a)(9) of this title did not apply and as though the coverage denial described in subsection (g) had not occurred. In each such case the Secretary shall notify both such individual and such provider of services or such other person, as the case may be, of the conditions under which payment for such items or services was made and in the case of comparable situations arising thereafter with respect to such individual or such provider or such other person, each shall, by reason of such notice (or similar notices provided before the enactment of this section), be deemed to have knowledge that payment cannot be made for such items or services or reasonably comparable items or services. Any provider or other person furnishing items or services for which payment may not be made by reason of section 1395y(a)(1) or (9) of this title or by reason of a coverage denial des</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions prerequisite to payment for items and services notwithstanding determination of disallowance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions prerequisite to payment for items and services notwithstanding determination of disallowance Where— then to the extent permitted by this subchapter, payment shall, notwithstanding such determination, be made for such items or services (and for such period of time as the Secretary finds will carry out the objectives of this subchapter), as though section 1395y(a)(1) and section 1395y(a)(9) of this title did not apply and as though the coverage denial described in subsection (g) had not occurred. In each such case the Secretary shall notify both such individual and such provider of services or such other person, as the case may be, of the conditions under which payment for such items or services was made and in the case of comparable situations arising thereafter with respect to such individual or such provider or such other person, each shall, by reason of such notice (or similar notices provided before the enactment of this section), be deemed to have knowledge that paym</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Knowledge of person or provider that payment could not be made; indemnification of individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Knowledge of person or provider that payment could not be made; indemnification of individual In any case in which the provisions of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) are met, except that such provider or such other person, as the case may be, knew, or could be expected to know, that payment for such services or items could not be made under such part A or part B, then the Secretary shall, upon proper application filed within such time as may be prescribed in regulations, indemnify the individual (referred to in such paragraphs) for any payments received from such individual by such provider or such other person, as the case may be, for such items or services. Any payments made by the Secretary as indemnification shall be deemed to have been made to such provider or such other person, as the case may be, and shall be treated as overpayments, recoverable from such provider or such other person, as the case may be, under applicable provisions of law. In each such case the Secr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Knowledge of both provider and individual to whom items or services were furnished that payment could not be made</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Knowledge of both provider and individual to whom items or services were furnished that payment could not be made No payments shall be made under this subchapter in any cases in which the provisions of paragraph (1) of subsection (a) are met, but both the individual to whom the items or services were furnished and the provider of service or other person, as the case may be, who furnished the items or services knew, or could reasonably have been expected to know, that payment could not be made for items or services under part A or part B by reason of section 1395y(a)(1) or (a)(9) of this title or by reason of a coverage denial described in subsection (g).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercise of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exercise of rights In any case arising under subsection (b) (but without regard to whether payments have been made by the individual to the provider or other person) or subsection (c), the provider or other person shall have the same rights that an individual has under sections 1395ff(b) and 1395u(b)(3)(C) of this title (as may be applicable) when the amount of benefit or payments is in controversy, except that such rights may, under prescribed regulations, be exercised by such provider or other person only after the Secretary determines that the individual will not exercise such rights under such sections.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment where beneficiary not at fault</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payment where beneficiary not at fault Where payment for inpatient hospital services or extended care services may not be made under part A of this subchapter on behalf of an individual entitled to benefits under such part solely because of an unintentional, inadvertent, or erroneous action with respect to the transfer of such individual from a hospital or skilled nursing facility that meets the requirements of section 1395x(e) or (j) of this title by such a provider of services acting in good faith in accordance with the advice of a utilization review committee, quality improvement organization, or fiscal intermediary, or on the basis of a clearly erroneous administrative decision by a provider of services, the Secretary shall take such action with respect to the payment of such benefits as he determines may be necessary to correct the effects of such unintentional, inadvertent, or erroneous action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumption with respect to coverage denial; rebuttal; requirements; “fiscal intermediary” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Presumption with respect to coverage denial; rebuttal; requirements; “fiscal intermediary” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage denial defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coverage denial defined The coverage denial described in this subsection is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplier responsibility for items furnished on assignment basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Supplier responsibility for items furnished on assignment basis If a supplier of medical equipment and supplies (as defined in section 1395m(j)(5) of this title)— any expenses incurred for items and services furnished to an individual by such a supplier on an assignment-related basis shall be the responsibility of such supplier. The individual shall have no financial responsibility for such expenses and the supplier shall refund on a timely basis to the individual (and shall be liable to the individual for) any amounts collected from the individual for such items or services. The provisions of section 1395m(a)(18) of this title shall apply to refunds required under the previous sentence in the same manner as such provisions apply to refunds under such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395pp_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hospice program eligibility recertification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Hospice program eligibility recertification The provisions of this section shall apply with respect to a denial of a payment under this subchapter by reason of section 1395f(a)(7)(E) of this title in the same manner as such provisions apply with respect to a denial of a payment under this subchapter by reason of section 1395y(a)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>