<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395x" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395x/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395x/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395x"><akn:num>1395x</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395x. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter—(a) Spell of illnessThe term “spell of illness” with respect to any individual means a period of consecutive days—(1) beginning with the first day (not included in a previous spell of illness) (A) on which such individual is furnished inpatient hospital services, inpatient critical access hospital services or extended care services, and (B) which occurs in a month for which he is entitled to benefits under part A, and

(2) ending with the close of the first period of 60 consecutive days thereafter on each of which he is neither an inpatient of a hospital or critical access hospital nor an inpatient of a facility described in section 1395i–3(a)(1) of this title or subsection (y)(1).


(b) Inpatient hospital servicesThe term “inpatient hospital services” means the following items and services furnished to an inpatient of a hospital and (except as provided in paragraph (3)) by the hospital—(1) bed and board;

(2) such nursing services and other related services, such use of hospital facilities, and such medical social services as are ordinarily furnished by the hospital for the care and treatment of inpatients, and such drugs, biologicals, supplies, appliances, and equipment, for use in the hospital, as are ordinarily furnished by such hospital for the care and treatment of inpatients; and

(3) such other diagnostic or therapeutic items or services, furnished by the hospital or by others under arrangements with them made by the hospital, as are ordinarily furnished to inpatients either by such hospital or by others under such arrangements;


excluding, however—
(4) medical or surgical services provided by a physician, resident, or intern, services described by subsection (s)(2)(K), certified nurse-midwife services, qualified psychologist services, and services of a certified registered nurse anesthetist; and

(5) the services of a private-duty nurse or other private-duty attendant.


Paragraph (4) shall not apply to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Spell of illness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Spell of illness The term “spell of illness” with respect to any individual means a period of consecutive days—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inpatient hospital services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inpatient hospital services The term “inpatient hospital services” means the following items and services furnished to an inpatient of a hospital and (except as provided in paragraph (3)) by the hospital— excluding, however— Paragraph (4) shall not apply to services provided in a hospital by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inpatient psychiatric hospital services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inpatient psychiatric hospital services The term “inpatient psychiatric hospital services” means inpatient hospital services furnished to an inpatient of a psychiatric hospital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supplier The term “supplier” means, unless the context otherwise requires, a physician or other practitioner, a facility, or other entity (other than a provider of services) that furnishes items or services under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hospital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hospital The term “hospital” (except for purposes of sections 1395f(d), 1395f(f), and 1395n(b) of this title, subsection (a)(2) of this section, paragraph (7) of this subsection, and subsection (i) of this section) means an institution which— For purposes of subsection (a)(2), such term includes any institution which meets the requirements of paragraph (1) of this subsection. For purposes of sections 1395f(d) and 1395n(b) of this title (including determination of whether an individual received inpatient hospital services or diagnostic services for purposes of such sections), section 1395f(f)(2) of this title, and subsection (i) of this section, such term includes any institution which (i) meets the requirements of paragraphs (5) and (7) of this subsection, (ii) is not primarily engaged in providing the services described in subsection (j)(1)(A) and (iii) is primarily engaged in providing, by or under the supervision of individuals referred to in paragraph (1) of subsection (r), to </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Psychiatric hospital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Psychiatric hospital The term “psychiatric hospital” means an institution which— In the case of an institution which satisfies paragraphs (1) and (2) of the preceding sentence and which contains a distinct part which also satisfies paragraphs (3) and (4) of such sentence, such distinct part shall be considered to be a “psychiatric hospital”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outpatient occupational therapy services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Outpatient occupational therapy services The term “outpatient occupational therapy services” has the meaning given the term “outpatient physical therapy services” in subsection (p), except that “occupational” shall be substituted for “physical” each place it appears therein.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extended care services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Extended care services The term “extended care services” means the following items and services furnished to an inpatient of a skilled nursing facility and (except as provided in paragraphs (3), (6), and (7)) by such skilled nursing facility— excluding, however, any item or service if it would not be included under subsection (b) if furnished to an inpatient of a hospital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Post-hospital extended care services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Post-hospital extended care services The term “post-hospital extended care services” means extended care services furnished an individual after transfer from a hospital in which he was an inpatient for not less than 3 consecutive days before his discharge from the hospital in connection with such transfer. For purposes of the preceding sentence, items and services shall be deemed to have been furnished to an individual after transfer from a hospital, and he shall be deemed to have been an inpatient in the hospital immediately before transfer therefrom, if he is admitted to the skilled nursing facility (A) within 30 days after discharge from such hospital, or (B) within such time as it would be medically appropriate to begin an active course of treatment, in the case of an individual whose condition is such that skilled nursing facility care would not be medically appropriate within 30 days after discharge from a hospital; and an individual shall be deemed not to have been discharge</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395x_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Skilled nursing facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Skilled nursing facility The term “skilled nursing facility” has the meaning given such term in section 1395i–3(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>