<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395gg" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395gg/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395gg/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395gg"><akn:num>1395gg</akn:num><akn:heading>Overpayment on behalf of individuals and settlement of claims for benefits on behalf of deceased ind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395gg. Overpayment on behalf of individuals and settlement of claims for benefits on behalf of deceased individuals(a) Payments to providers of services or other person regarded as payment to individualsAny payment under this subchapter to any provider of services or other person with respect to any items or services furnished any individual shall be regarded as a payment to such individual.


(b) Incorrect payments on behalf of individuals; payment adjustmentWhere—(1) more than the correct amount is paid under this subchapter to a provider of services or other person for items or services furnished an individual and the Secretary determines (A) that, within such period as he may specify, the excess over the correct amount cannot be recouped from such provider of services or other person, or (B) that such provider of services or other person was without fault with respect to the payment of such excess over the correct amount, or

(2) any payment has been made under section 1395f(e) of this title to a provider of services or other person for items or services furnished an individual,


proper adjustments shall be made, under regulations prescribed (after consultation with the Railroad Retirement Board) by the Secretary, by decreasing subsequent payments—
(3) to which such individual is entitled under subchapter II of this chapter or under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.], as the case may be, or

(4) if such individual dies before such adjustment has been completed, to which any other individual is entitled under subchapter II of this chapter or under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.], as the case may be, with respect to the wages and self-employment income or the compensation constituting the basis of the benefits of such deceased individual under subchapter II of this chapter.


As soon as practicable after any adjustment under paragraph (3) or (4) is determined to be necessary, the Secretary, for purposes of t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to providers of services or other person regarded as payment to individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments to providers of services or other person regarded as payment to individuals Any payment under this subchapter to any provider of services or other person with respect to any items or services furnished any individual shall be regarded as a payment to such individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incorrect payments on behalf of individuals; payment adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Incorrect payments on behalf of individuals; payment adjustment Where— proper adjustments shall be made, under regulations prescribed (after consultation with the Railroad Retirement Board) by the Secretary, by decreasing subsequent payments— As soon as practicable after any adjustment under paragraph (3) or (4) is determined to be necessary, the Secretary, for purposes of this section, section 1395i(g) of this title, and section 1395t(f) of this title, shall certify (to the Railroad Retirement Board if the adjustment is to be made by decreasing subsequent payments under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.]) the amount of the overpayment as to which the adjustment is to be made. For purposes of clause (B) of paragraph (1), such provider of services or such other person shall, in the absence of evidence to the contrary, be deemed to be without fault if the Secretary’s determination that more than such correct amount was paid was made subsequent to the fifth ye</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception to subsection (b) payment adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception to subsection (b) payment adjustment There shall be no adjustment as provided in subsection (b) (nor shall there be recovery) in any case where the incorrect payment has been made (including payments under section 1395f(e) of this title) with respect to an individual who is without fault or where the adjustment (or recovery) would be made by decreasing payments to which another person who is without fault is entitled as provided in subsection (b)(4), if such adjustment (or recovery) would defeat the purposes of subchapter II or subchapter XVIII or would be against equity and good conscience. Adjustment or recovery of an incorrect payment (or only such part of an incorrect payment as the Secretary determines to be inconsistent with the purposes of this subchapter) against an individual who is without fault shall be deemed to be against equity and good conscience if (A) the incorrect payment was made for expenses incurred for items or services for which payment may not be m</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of certifying or disbursing officer for failure to recoup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Liability of certifying or disbursing officer for failure to recoup No certifying or disbursing officer shall be held liable for any amount certified or paid by him to any provider of services or other person where the adjustment or recovery of such amount is waived under subsection (c) or where adjustment under subsection (b) is not completed prior to the death of all persons against whose benefits such adjustment is authorized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement of claims for benefits under this subchapter on behalf of deceased individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Settlement of claims for benefits under this subchapter on behalf of deceased individuals If an individual, who received services for which payment may be made to such individual under this subchapter, dies, and payment for such services was made (other than under this subchapter), and the individual died before any payment due him under this subchapter with respect to such services was completed, payment of the amount due (including the amount of any unnegotiated checks) shall be made—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement of claims for section 1395k benefits on behalf of deceased individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Settlement of claims for section 1395k benefits on behalf of deceased individuals If an individual who received medical and other health services for which payment may be made under section 1395k(a)(1) of this title dies, and no assignment of the right to payment for such services was made by such individual before his death, and payment for such services has not been made— but only in such amount and subject to such conditions as would be applicable if the individual who received the services had not died.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refund of premiums for deceased individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Refund of premiums for deceased individuals If an individual, who is enrolled under section 1395i–2(c) of this title or under section 1395p of this title, dies, and premiums with respect to such enrollment have been received with respect to such individual for any month after the month of his death, such premiums shall be refunded to the person or persons determined by the Secretary under regulations to have paid such premiums or if payment for such premiums was made by the deceased individual before his death, to the legal representative of the estate of such deceased individual, if any. If there is no person who meets the requirements of the preceding sentence such premiums shall be refunded to the person or persons in the priorities specified in paragraphs (2) through (7) of subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395gg_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals by providers of services or suppliers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appeals by providers of services or suppliers Notwithstanding subsection (f) or any other provision of law, the Secretary shall permit a provider of services or supplier to appeal any determination of the Secretary under this subchapter relating to services rendered under this subchapter to an individual who subsequently dies if there is no other party available to appeal such determination.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>