<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w"><akn:num>1395w</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations to cover Government contributions and contingency reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w. Appropriations to cover Government contributions and contingency reserve(a) In generalThere are authorized to be appropriated from time to time, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund—(1)(A) a Government contribution equal to the aggregate premiums payable for a month for enrollees age 65 and over under this part and deposited in the Trust Fund, multiplied by the ratio of—(i) twice the dollar amount of the actuarially adequate rate per enrollee age 65 and over as determined under section 1395r(a)(1) of this title for such month minus the dollar amount of the premium per enrollee for such month, as determined under section 1395r(a)(3) of this title, to

(ii) the dollar amount of the premium per enrollee for such month, plus


(B) a Government contribution equal to the aggregate premiums payable for a month for enrollees under age 65 under this part and deposited in the Trust Fund, multiplied by the ratio of—(i) twice the dollar amount of the actuarially adequate rate per enrollee under age 65 as determined under section 1395r(a)(4) of this title for such month minus the dollar amount of the premium per enrollee for such month, as determined under section 1395r(a)(3) of this title, to

(ii) the dollar amount of the premium per enrollee for such month; minus


(C) the aggregate amount of additional premium payments attributable to the application of section 1395r(i) of this title; plus


(2) such sums as the Secretary deems necessary to place the Trust Fund, at the end of any fiscal year occurring after June 30, 1967, in the same position in which it would have been at the end of such fiscal year if (A) a Government contribution representing the excess of the premiums deposited in the Trust Fund during the fiscal year ending June 30, 1967, over the Government contribution actually appropriated to the Trust Fund during such fiscal year had been appropriated to it on June 30, 1967, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There are authorized to be appropriated from time to time, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund— In applying paragraph (1), the amounts transferred under subsection (d)(1) with respect to enrollees described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such subsection shall be treated as premiums payable and deposited in the Trust Fund under subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, of paragraph (1). In applying paragraph (1), the amounts transferred under subsection (e)(1) with respect to enrollees described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such subsection shall be treated as premiums payable and deposited in the Trust Fund under subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, of paragraph (1). The Government contribution under paragraph (4) shall be treated as premiums payable and deposited for purposes of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingency reserve</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contingency reserve In order to assure prompt payment of benefits provided under this part and the administrative expenses thereunder during the early months of the program established by this part, and to provide a contingency reserve, there is also authorized to be appropriated, out of any moneys in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to remain available through the calendar year 1969 for repayable advances (without interest) to the Trust Fund, an amount equal to $18 multiplied by the number of individuals (as estimated by the Secretary) who could be covered in July 1966 by the insurance program established by this part if they had theretofore enrolled under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election under section 1395w–24</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Election under section 1395w–24 The Secretary shall determine the Government contribution under subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(1) without regard to any premium reduction resulting from an election under section 1395w–24(f)(1)(E) of this title or any credits provided under section 1395w–24(b)(1)(C)(iv) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and without regard to any premium adjustment effected under sections 1395r(h) and 1395w–29(f) 1 of this title and without regard to any premium adjustment under section 1395r(i) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for 2016</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for 2016</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for 2021</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for 2021</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for COVID–19 public health emergency period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer of certain General Fund amounts for COVID–19 public health emergency period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>