<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395kk_1"><akn:num>1395kk–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts with medicare administrative contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395kk–1. Contracts with medicare administrative contractors(a) Authority(1) Authority to enter into contractsThe Secretary may enter into contracts with any eligible entity to serve as a medicare administrative contractor with respect to the performance of any or all of the functions described in paragraph (4) or parts of those functions (or, to the extent provided in a contract, to secure performance thereof by other entities).


(2) Eligibility of entitiesAn entity is eligible to enter into a contract with respect to the performance of a particular function described in paragraph (4) only if—(A) the entity has demonstrated capability to carry out such function;

(B) the entity complies with such conflict of interest standards as are generally applicable to Federal acquisition and procurement;

(C) the entity has sufficient assets to financially support the performance of such function; and

(D) the entity meets such other requirements as the Secretary may impose.


(3) Medicare administrative contractor definedFor purposes of this subchapter and subchapter XI—(A) In generalThe term “medicare administrative contractor” means an agency, organization, or other person with a contract under this section.


(B) Appropriate medicare administrative contractorWith respect to the performance of a particular function in relation to an individual entitled to benefits under part A or enrolled under part B, or both, a specific provider of services or supplier (or class of such providers of services or suppliers), the “appropriate” medicare administrative contractor is the medicare administrative contractor that has a contract under this section with respect to the performance of that function in relation to that individual, provider of services or supplier or class of provider of services or supplier.



(4) Functions describedThe functions referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) are payment functions (including the function of developing local coverage determinations, as defi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contracting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on liability of medicare administrative contractors and certain officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on liability of medicare administrative contractors and certain officers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for information security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements for information security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives to improve contractor performance in provider education and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Incentives to improve contractor performance in provider education and outreach The Secretary shall use specific claims payment error rates or similar methodology of medicare administrative contractors in the processing or reviewing of medicare claims in order to give such contractors an incentive to implement effective education and outreach programs for providers of services and suppliers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Communications with beneficiaries, providers of services and suppliers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Communications with beneficiaries, providers of services and suppliers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improper payment outreach and education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Improper payment outreach and education program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>