<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395b_4"><akn:num>1395b–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Health insurance information, counseling, and assistance grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395b–4. Health insurance information, counseling, and assistance grants(a) GrantsThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall make grants to States, with approved State regulatory programs under section 1395ss of this title, that submit applications to the Secretary that meet the requirements of this section for the purpose of providing information, counseling, and assistance relating to the procurement of adequate and appropriate health insurance coverage to individuals who are eligible to receive benefits under this subchapter (in this section referred to as “eligible individuals”). The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to establish a minimum level of funding for a grant issued under this section.


(b) Grant applications(1) In submitting an application under this section, a State may consolidate and coordinate an application that consists of parts prepared by more than one agency or department of such State.

(2) As part of an application for a grant under this section, a State shall submit a plan for a State-wide health insurance information, counseling, and assistance program. Such program shall—(A) establish or improve upon a health insurance information, counseling, and assistance program that provides counseling and assistance to eligible individuals in need of health insurance information, including—(i) information that may assist individuals in obtaining benefits and filing claims under this subchapter and subchapter XIX of this chapter;

(ii) policy comparison information for medicare supplemental policies (as described in section 1395ss(g)(1) of this title) and information that may assist individuals in filing claims under such medicare supplemental policies;

(iii) information regarding long-term care insurance; and

(iv) information regarding other types of health insurance benefits that the Secretary determines to be appropriate;


(B) in conjunction with the health insurance information, cou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall make grants to States, with approved State regulatory programs under section 1395ss of this title, that submit applications to the Secretary that meet the requirements of this section for the purpose of providing information, counseling, and assistance relating to the procurement of adequate and appropriate health insurance coverage to individuals who are eligible to receive benefits under this subchapter (in this section referred to as “eligible individuals”). The Secretary shall prescribe regulations to establish a minimum level of funding for a grant issued under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for issuing grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criteria for issuing grants In issuing a grant under this section, the Secretary shall consider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual State report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual State report A State that receives a grant under this section shall, not later than 180 days after receiving such grant, and annually thereafter during the period of the grant, issue a report to the Secretary that includes information concerning—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report to Congress Beginning with 1992, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall issue a report to the Committee on Finance of the Senate, the Special Committee on Aging of the Senate, the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations for grants There are authorized to be appropriated, in equal parts from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 1991, 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, and 1996, to fund the grant programs described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>