<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_5"><akn:num>1395w–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Public reporting of performance information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–5. Public reporting of performance information(a) In general(1) DevelopmentNot later than January 1, 2011, the Secretary shall develop a Physician Compare Internet website with information on physicians enrolled in the Medicare program under section 1866(j) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395cc(j)) and other eligible professionals who participate in the Physician Quality Reporting Initiative under section 1848 of such Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–4).


(2) PlanNot later than January 1, 2013, and with respect to reporting periods that begin no earlier than January 1, 2012, the Secretary shall also implement a plan for making publicly available through Physician Compare, consistent with subsection (c), information on physician performance that provides comparable information for the public on quality and patient experience measures with respect to physicians enrolled in the Medicare program under such section 1866(j). To the extent scientifically sound measures that are developed consistent with the requirements of this section are available, such information, to the extent practicable, shall include—(A) measures collected under the Physician Quality Reporting Initiative;

(B) an assessment of patient health outcomes and the functional status of patients;

(C) an assessment of the continuity and coordination of care and care transitions, including episodes of care and risk-adjusted resource use;

(D) an assessment of efficiency;

(E) an assessment of patient experience and patient, caregiver, and family engagement;

(F) an assessment of the safety, effectiveness, and timeliness of care; and

(G) other information as determined appropriate by the Secretary.



(b) Other required considerationsIn developing and implementing the plan described in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, include—(1) processes to assure that data made public, either by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services or by other entities, is statistically valid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other required considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other required considerations In developing and implementing the plan described in subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring patient privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ensuring patient privacy The Secretary shall ensure that information on physician performance and patient experience is not disclosed under this section in a manner that violates sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 552 or 552a of title 5 with regard to the privacy of individually identifiable health information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Feedback from multi-stakeholder groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Feedback from multi-stakeholder groups The Secretary shall take into consideration input provided by multi-stakeholder groups, consistent with sections 1890(b)(7) and 1890A of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395aaa(b)(7), 1395aaa–1], as added by section 3014 of this Act, in selecting quality measures for use under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of transition to value-based purchasing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consideration of transition to value-based purchasing In developing the plan under this 22 So in original. The word “this” probably should not appear. subsection (a)(2), the Secretary shall, as the Secretary determines appropriate, consider the plan to transition to a value-based purchasing program for physicians and other practitioners developed under section 131 of the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 (Public Law 110–275).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report to Congress Not later than January 1, 2015, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the Physician Compare Internet website developed under subsection (a)(1). Such report shall include information on the efforts of and plans made by the Secretary to collect and publish data on physician quality and efficiency and on patient experience of care in support of value-based purchasing and consumer choice, together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Expansion At any time before the date on which the report is submitted under subsection (f), the Secretary may expand (including expansion to other providers of services and suppliers under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.]) the information made available on such website.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial incentives to encourage consumers to choose high quality providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Financial incentives to encourage consumers to choose high quality providers The Secretary may establish a demonstration program, not later than January 1, 2019, to provide financial incentives to Medicare beneficiaries who are furnished services by high quality physicians, as determined by the Secretary based on factors in subparagraphs (A) through (G) of subsection (a)(2). In no case may Medicare beneficiaries be required to pay increased premiums or cost sharing or be subject to a reduction in benefits under title XVIII of the Social Security Act as a result of such demonstration program. The Secretary shall ensure that any such demonstration program does not disadvantage those beneficiaries without reasonable access to high performing physicians or create financial inequities under such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_5_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>