<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_114a"><akn:num>1395w–114a</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare coverage gap discount program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–114a. Medicare coverage gap discount program(a) EstablishmentSubject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall establish a Medicare coverage gap discount program (in this section referred to as the “program”) by not later than January 1, 2011. Under the program, the Secretary shall enter into agreements described in subsection (b) with manufacturers and provide for the performance of the duties described in subsection (c)(1). The Secretary shall establish a model agreement for use under the program by not later than 180 days after March 23, 2010, in consultation with manufacturers, and allow for comment on such model agreement.


(b) Terms of agreement(1) In general(A) AgreementAn agreement under this section shall require the manufacturer to provide applicable beneficiaries access to discounted prices for applicable drugs of the manufacturer.


(B) Provision of discounted prices at the point-of-saleExcept as provided in subsection (c)(1)(A)(iii), such discounted prices shall be provided to the applicable beneficiary at the pharmacy or by the mail order service at the point-of-sale of an applicable drug.


(C) Timing of agreement(i) Special rule for 2011In order for an agreement with a manufacturer to be in effect under this section with respect to the period beginning on January 1, 2011, and ending on December 31, 2011, the manufacturer shall enter into such agreement not later than not later than 11 So in original. Second “not later than” probably should not appear. 30 days after the date of the establishment of a model agreement under subsection (a).


(ii) 2012 and subsequent yearsIn order for an agreement with a manufacturer to be in effect under this section with respect to plan year 2012 or a subsequent plan year, the manufacturer shall enter into such agreement (or such agreement shall be renewed under paragraph (4)(A)) not later than January 30 of the preceding year.




(2) Provision of appropriate dataEach manufacturer with an agreement in effect und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall establish a Medicare coverage gap discount program (in this section referred to as the “program”) by not later than January 1, 2011. Under the program, the Secretary shall enter into agreements described in subsection (b) with manufacturers and provide for the performance of the duties described in subsection (c)(1). The Secretary shall establish a model agreement for use under the program by not later than 180 days after March 23, 2010, in consultation with manufacturers, and allow for comment on such model agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms of agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties described and special rule for supplemental benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties described and special rule for supplemental benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification regarding availability of other covered part D drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Clarification regarding availability of other covered part D drugs Nothing in this section shall prevent an applicable beneficiary from purchasing a covered part D drug that is not an applicable drug (including a generic drug or a drug that is not on the formulary of the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan that the applicable beneficiary is enrolled in).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sunset of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>