<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395cc_4"><akn:num>1395cc–4</akn:num><akn:heading>National pilot program on payment bundling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395cc–4. National pilot program on payment bundling(a) Implementation(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a pilot program for integrated care during an episode of care provided to an applicable beneficiary around a hospitalization in order to improve the coordination, quality, and efficiency of health care services under this subchapter.


(2) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) Applicable beneficiaryThe term “applicable beneficiary” means an individual who—(i) is entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part A and enrolled for benefits under part B of such subchapter, but not enrolled under part C or a PACE program under section 1395eee of this title; and

(ii) is admitted to a hospital for an applicable condition.


(B) Applicable conditionThe term “applicable condition” means 1 or more of 10 conditions selected by the Secretary. In selecting conditions under the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall take into consideration the following factors:(i) Whether the conditions selected include a mix of chronic and acute conditions.

(ii) Whether the conditions selected include a mix of surgical and medical conditions.

(iii) Whether a condition is one for which there is evidence of an opportunity for providers of services and suppliers to improve the quality of care furnished while reducing total expenditures under this subchapter.

(iv) Whether a condition has significant variation in—(I) the number of readmissions; and

(II) the amount of expenditures for post-acute care spending under this subchapter.


(v) Whether a condition is high-volume and has high post-acute care expenditures under this subchapter.

(vi) Which conditions the Secretary determines are most amenable to bundling across the spectrum of care given practice patterns under this subchapter.


(C) Applicable servicesThe term “applicable services” means the following:(i) Acute care inpatient services.

(ii) Physicians’ services delivered in and outside of an acute care hospital setting.

(iii</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developmental phase</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Developmental phase</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Details</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Details</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver The Secretary may waive such provisions of this subchapter and subchapter XI as may be necessary to carry out the pilot program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent evaluation and reports on pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Independent evaluation and reports on pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consultation The Secretary shall consult with representatives of small rural hospitals, including critical access hospitals (as defined in section 1395x(mm)(1) of this title), regarding their participation in the pilot program. Such consultation shall include consideration of innovative methods of implementing bundled payments in hospitals described in the preceding sentence, taking into consideration any difficulties in doing so as a result of the low volume of services provided by such hospitals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of pilot program to continuing care hospitals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Application of pilot program to continuing care hospitals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administration Chapter 35 of title 44 shall not apply to the selection, testing, and evaluation of models or the expansion of such models under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>