<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_153"><akn:num>1395w–153</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition for coverage of drugs under this part</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–153. Condition for coverage of drugs under this part(a) In generalIn order for coverage to be available under this part for covered part D drugs (as defined in section 1395w–102(e) of this title) of a manufacturer, the manufacturer must—(1) participate in—(A) for 2011 through 2024, the Medicare coverage gap discount program under section 1395w–114a of this title; and

(B) for 2025 and each subsequent year, the manufacturer discount program under section 1395w–114c of this title;


(2) have entered into and have in effect—(A) for 2011 through 2024, an agreement described in subsection (b) of section 1395w–114a of this title with the Secretary; and

(B) for 2025 and each subsequent year, an agreement described in subsection (b) of section 1395w–114c of this title with the Secretary; and


(3) have entered into and have in effect, under terms and conditions specified by the Secretary, a contract with a third party that the Secretary has entered into a contract with under subsection (d)(3) of section 1395w–114a of this title.


(b) Effective dateParagraphs (1)(A), (2)(A), and (3) of subsection (a) shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2011, and before January 1, 2025, and paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B) of such subsection shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2025.


(c) Authorizing coverage for drugs not covered under agreements(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), subsection (a) shall not apply to the dispensing of a covered part D drug if—(A) the Secretary has made a determination that the availability of the drug is essential to the health of beneficiaries under this part; or

(B) the Secretary determines that in the period beginning on January 1, 2011, and 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “ending on”. December 31, 2011, there were extenuating circumstances.


(2) ExceptionParagraph (1)(A) shall not apply to a covered part D drug of a manufacturer fo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order for coverage to be available under this part for covered part D drugs (as defined in section 1395w–102(e) of this title) of a manufacturer, the manufacturer must—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective date Paragraphs (1)(A), (2)(A), and (3) of subsection (a) shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2011, and before January 1, 2025, and paragraphs (1)(B) and (2)(B) of such subsection shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizing coverage for drugs not covered under agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorizing coverage for drugs not covered under agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of manufacturer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition of manufacturer In this section, the term “manufacturer” has the meaning given such term in section 1395w–114a(g)(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>