<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_3"><akn:num>1395w–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive acquisition of certain items and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–3. Competitive acquisition of certain items and services(a) Establishment of competitive acquisition programs(1) Implementation of programs(A) In generalThe Secretary shall establish and implement programs under which competitive acquisition areas are established throughout the United States for contract award purposes for the furnishing under this part of competitively priced items and services (described in paragraph (2)) for which payment is made under this part. Such areas may differ for different items and services.


(B) Phased-in implementationThe programs—(i) shall be phased in among competitive acquisition areas in a manner consistent with subparagraph (D) so that the competition under the programs occurs in—(I) 10 of the largest metropolitan statistical areas in 2007;

(II) an additional 91 of the largest metropolitan statistical areas in 2011; and

(III) additional areas after 2011 (or, in the case of national mail order for items and services, after 2010); and


(ii) may be phased in first among the highest cost and highest volume items and services or those items and services that the Secretary determines have the largest savings potential.


(C) Waiver of certain provisionsIn carrying out the programs, the Secretary may waive such provisions of the Federal Acquisition Regulation as are necessary for the efficient implementation of this section, other than provisions relating to confidentiality of information and such other provisions as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(D) Changes in competitive acquisition programs(i) Round 1 of competitive acquisition programNotwithstanding subparagraph (B)(i)(I) and in implementing the first round of the competitive acquisition programs under this section—(I) the contracts awarded under this section before July 15, 2008, are terminated, no payment shall be made under this subchapter on or after July 15, 2008, based on such a contract, and, to the extent that any damages may be applicable as a result o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of competitive acquisition programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of competitive acquisition programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program Advisory and Oversight Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program Advisory and Oversight Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than July 1, 2011, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the programs under this section. The report shall include information on savings, reductions in cost-sharing, access to and quality of items and services, and satisfaction of individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 110–275, title I, § 145(a)(1), July 15, 2008, 122 Stat. 2547</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive acquisition ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Competitive acquisition ombudsman The Secretary shall provide for a competitive acquisition ombudsman within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in order to respond to complaints and inquiries made by suppliers and individuals relating to the application of the competitive acquisition program under this section. The ombudsman may be within the office of the Medicare Beneficiary Ombudsman appointed under section 1395b–9(c) of this title. The ombudsman shall submit to Congress an annual report on the activities under this subsection, which report shall be coordinated with the report provided under section 1395b–9(c)(2)(C) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>