<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395aaa" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395aaa/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395aaa/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395aaa"><akn:num>1395aaa</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract with a consensus-based entity regarding performance measurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395aaa. Contract with a consensus-based entity regarding performance measurement(a) Contract(1) In generalFor purposes of activities conducted under this chapter, the Secretary shall identify and have in effect a contract with a consensus-based entity, such as the National Quality Forum, that meets the requirements described in subsection (c). Such contract shall provide that the entity will perform the duties described in subsection (b).


(2) Timing for first contractAs soon as practicable after July 15, 2008, the Secretary shall enter into the first contract under paragraph (1).


(3) Period of contractA contract under paragraph (1) shall be for a period of 4 years (except as may be renewed after a subsequent bidding process).


(4) Competitive proceduresCompetitive procedures (as defined in section 132 of title 41) shall be used to enter into a contract under paragraph (1).



(b) DutiesThe duties described in this subsection are the following:(1) Priority setting processThe entity shall synthesize evidence and convene key stakeholders to make recommendations, with respect to activities conducted under this chapter, on an integrated national strategy and priorities for health care performance measurement in all applicable settings. In making such recommendations, the entity shall—(A) ensure that priority is given to measures—(i) that address the health care provided to patients with prevalent, high-cost chronic diseases;

(ii) with the greatest potential for improving the quality, efficiency, and patient-centeredness of health care; and

(iii) that may be implemented rapidly due to existing evidence, standards of care, or other reasons; and


(B) take into account measures that—(i) may assist consumers and patients in making informed health care decisions;

(ii) address health disparities across groups and areas; and

(iii) address the continuum of care a patient receives, including services furnished by multiple health care providers or practitioners and acr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The duties described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements described The requirements described in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report by Secretary to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Annual report by Secretary to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395aaa_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional reporting by the Secretary to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional reporting by the Secretary to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>