<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395kk–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395kk_2"><akn:num>1395kk–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding availability of Medicare data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395kk–2. Expanding availability of Medicare data(a) Expanding uses of Medicare data by qualified entities(1) Additional analyses(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), to the extent consistent with applicable information, privacy, security, and disclosure laws (including paragraph (3)), notwithstanding paragraph (4)(B) of section 1874(e) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395kk(e)) and the second sentence of paragraph (4)(D) of such section, beginning July 1, 2016, a qualified entity may use the combined data described in paragraph (4)(B)(iii) of such section received by such entity under such section, and information derived from the evaluation described in such paragraph (4)(D), to conduct additional non-public analyses (as determined appropriate by the Secretary) and provide or sell such analyses to authorized users for non-public use (including for the purposes of assisting providers of services and suppliers to develop and participate in quality and patient care improvement activities, including developing new models of care).


(B) Limitations with respect to analyses(i) EmployersAny analyses provided or sold under subparagraph (A) to an employer described in paragraph (9)(A)(iii) may only be used by such employer for purposes of providing health insurance to employees and retirees of the employer.


(ii) Health insurance issuersA qualified entity may not provide or sell an analysis to a health insurance issuer described in paragraph (9)(A)(iv) unless the issuer is providing the qualified entity with data under section 1874(e)(4)(B)(iii) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395kk(e)(4)(B)(iii)).




(2) Access to certain data(A) AccessTo the extent consistent with applicable information, privacy, security, and disclosure laws (including paragraph (3)), notwithstanding paragraph (4)(B) of section 1874(e) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395kk(e)) and the second sentence of paragraph (4)(D) of such section, beginning July 1, 2016, a qualified e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding uses of Medicare data by qualified entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expanding uses of Medicare data by qualified entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395kk_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to Medicare data by qualified clinical data registries to facilitate quality improvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access to Medicare data by qualified clinical data registries to facilitate quality improvement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>