<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395hhh" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395hhh/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395hhh/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395hhh"><akn:num>1395hhh</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care infrastructure improvement program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395hhh. Health care infrastructure improvement program(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a loan program that provides loans to qualifying hospitals for payment of the capital costs of projects described in subsection (d).


(b) ApplicationNo loan may be provided under this section to a qualifying hospital except pursuant to an application that is submitted and approved in a time, manner, and form specified by the Secretary. A loan under this section shall be on such terms and conditions and meet such requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(c) Selection criteria(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish criteria for selecting among qualifying hospitals that apply for a loan under this section. Such criteria shall consider the extent to which the project for which loan is sought is nationally or regionally significant, in terms of expanding or improving the health care infrastructure of the United States or the region or in terms of the medical benefit that the project will have.


(2) Qualifying hospital definedFor purposes of this section, the term “qualifying hospital” means a hospital or an entity described in paragraph (3) that—(A) is engaged in research in the causes, prevention, and treatment of cancer; and

(B) is designated as a cancer center for the National Cancer Institute or is designated by the State legislature as the official cancer institute of the State and such designation by the State legislature occurred prior to December 8, 2003.


(3) Entity describedAn entity described in this paragraph is an entity that—(A) is described in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code;

(B) has at least 1 existing memorandum of understanding or affiliation agreement with a hospital located in the State in which the entity is located; and

(C) retains clinical outpatient treatment for cancer on site as well as lab research and education and outreach for cancer in the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a loan program that provides loans to qualifying hospitals for payment of the capital costs of projects described in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application No loan may be provided under this section to a qualifying hospital except pursuant to an application that is submitted and approved in a time, manner, and form specified by the Secretary. A loan under this section shall be on such terms and conditions and meet such requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects A project described in this subsection is a project of a qualifying hospital that is designed to improve the health care infrastructure of the hospital, including construction, renovation, or other capital improvements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State and local permits The provision of a loan under this section with respect to a project shall not—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Forgiveness of indebtedness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Forgiveness of indebtedness The Secretary may forgive a loan provided to a qualifying hospital under this section under terms and conditions that are analogous to the loan forgiveness provision for student loans under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.), except that the Secretary shall condition such forgiveness on the establishment by the hospital of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not later than 4 years after December 8, 2003, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the projects for which loans are provided under this section and a recommendation as to whether the Congress should authorize the Secretary to continue loans under this section beyond fiscal year 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395hhh_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitation on review There shall be no administrative or judicial review of any determination made by the Secretary under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>