<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395t"><akn:num>1395t</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395t. Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund(a) Creation; deposits; fund transfersThere is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”). The Trust Fund shall consist of such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in section 401(i)(1) of this title, such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, such fund as provided in this part or section 9008(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act of 2009, and such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, the Medicare Prescription Drug Account established by section 1395w–116 of this title or the Transitional Assistance Account established by section 1395w–141(k)(1) of this title.


(b) Board of Trustees; composition; meetings; dutiesWith respect to the Trust Fund, there is hereby created a body to be known as the Board of Trustees of the Trust Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board of Trustees”) composed of the Commissioner of Social Security, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, all ex officio, and of two members of the public (both of whom may not be from the same political party), who shall be nominated by the President for a term of four years and subject to confirmation by the Senate. A member of the Board of Trustees serving as a member of the public and nominated and confirmed to fill a vacancy occurring during a term shall be nominated and confirmed only for the remainder of such term. An individual nominated and confirmed as a member of the public may serve in such position after the expiration of such member’s term until the earlier of the time at which the member’s successor takes office or the time at which a report of the Board is first issued under paragraph (2) after the e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Creation; deposits; fund transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Creation; deposits; fund transfers There is hereby created on the books of the Treasury of the United States a trust fund to be known as the “Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund” (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Trust Fund”). The Trust Fund shall consist of such gifts and bequests as may be made as provided in section 401(i)(1) of this title, such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, such fund as provided in this part or section 9008(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act of 2009, and such amounts as may be deposited in, or appropriated to, the Medicare Prescription Drug Account established by section 1395w–116 of this title or the Transitional Assistance Account established by section 1395w–141(k)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of Trustees; composition; meetings; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Board of Trustees; composition; meetings; duties With respect to the Trust Fund, there is hereby created a body to be known as the Board of Trustees of the Trust Fund (hereinafter in this section referred to as the “Board of Trustees”) composed of the Commissioner of Social Security, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, all ex officio, and of two members of the public (both of whom may not be from the same political party), who shall be nominated by the President for a term of four years and subject to confirmation by the Senate. A member of the Board of Trustees serving as a member of the public and nominated and confirmed to fill a vacancy occurring during a term shall be nominated and confirmed only for the remainder of such term. An individual nominated and confirmed as a member of the public may serve in such position after the expiration of such member’s term until the earlier of the time at which the member’s </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of Trust Fund by Managing Trustee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Investment of Trust Fund by Managing Trustee It shall be the duty of the Managing Trustee to invest such portion of the Trust Fund as is not, in his judgment, required to meet current withdrawals. Such investments may be made only in interest-bearing obligations of the United States or in obligations guaranteed as to both principal and interest by the United States. For such purpose such obligations may be acquired (1) on original issue at the issue price, or (2) by purchase of outstanding obligations at the market price. The purposes for which obligations of the United States may be issued under chapter 31 of title 31 are hereby extended to authorize the issuance at par of public-debt obligations for purchase by the Trust Fund. Such obligations issued for purchase by the Trust Fund shall have maturities fixed with due regard for the needs of the Trust Fund and shall bear interest at a rate equal to the average market yield (computed by the Managing Trustee on the basis of market q</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Managing Trustee to sell obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority of Managing Trustee to sell obligations Any obligations acquired by the Trust Fund (except public-debt obligations issued exclusively to the Trust Fund) may be sold by the Managing Trustee at the market price, and such public-debt obligations may be redeemed at par plus accrued interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest on or proceeds from sale or redemption of obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interest on or proceeds from sale or redemption of obligations The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Trust Fund shall be credited to and form a part of the Trust Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers to other Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfers to other Funds There shall be transferred periodically (but not less often than once each fiscal year) to the Trust Fund from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and from the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund amounts equivalent to the amounts not previously so transferred which the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall have certified as overpayments (other than amounts so certified to the Railroad Retirement Board) pursuant to section 1395gg(b) of this title. There shall be transferred periodically (but not less often than once each fiscal year) to the Trust Fund from the Railroad Retirement Account amounts equivalent to the amounts not previously so transferred which the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall have certified as overpayments to the Railroad Retirement Board pursuant to section 1395gg(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments from Trust Fund of amounts provided for by this part or with respect to administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payments from Trust Fund of amounts provided for by this part or with respect to administrative expenses The Managing Trustee shall pay from time to time from the Trust Fund such amounts as the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies are necessary to make the payments provided for by this part, and the payments with respect to administrative expenses in accordance with section 401(g)(1) of this title. The payments provided for under part D, other than under section 1395w–141(k)(2) of this title, shall be made from the Medicare Prescription Drug Account in the Trust Fund. The payments provided for under section 1395w–141(k)(2) of this title shall be made from the Transitional Assistance Account in the Trust Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments from Trust Fund of costs incurred by Director of Office of Personnel Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Payments from Trust Fund of costs incurred by Director of Office of Personnel Management The Managing Trustee shall pay from time to time from the Trust Fund such amounts as the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies are necessary to pay the costs incurred by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management in making deductions pursuant to section 1395s(d) of this title or pursuant to section 1395w–113(c)(1) or 1395w–24(d)(2)(A) of this title (in which case payments shall be made in appropriate part from the Medicare Prescription Drug Account in the Trust Fund). During each fiscal year, or after the close of such fiscal year, the Director of the Office of Personnel Management shall certify to the Secretary the amount of the costs the Director incurred in making such deductions, and such certified amount shall be the basis for the amount of such costs certified by the Secretary to the Managing Trustee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395t_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments from Trust Fund of costs incurred by Railroad Retirement Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Payments from Trust Fund of costs incurred by Railroad Retirement Board The Managing Trustee shall pay from time to time from the Trust Fund such amounts as the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies are necessary to pay the costs incurred by the Railroad Retirement Board for services performed pursuant to section 1395s(b)(1) and section 1395u(g) of this title and pursuant to sections 1395w–113(c)(1) and 1395w–24(d)(2)(A) of this title (in which case payments shall be made in appropriate part from the Medicare Prescription Drug Account in the Trust Fund). During each fiscal year or after the close of such fiscal year, the Railroad Retirement Board shall certify to the Secretary the amount of the costs it incurred in performing such services and such certified amount shall be the basis for the amount of such costs certified by the Secretary to the Managing Trustee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>