<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_112"><akn:num>1395w–112</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for and contracts with prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–112. Requirements for and contracts with prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors(a) General requirementsEach PDP sponsor of a prescription drug plan shall meet the following requirements:(1) LicensureSubject to subsection (c), the sponsor is organized and licensed under State law as a risk-bearing entity eligible to offer health insurance or health benefits coverage in each State in which it offers a prescription drug plan.


(2) Assumption of financial risk for unsubsidized coverage(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), to the extent that the entity is at risk the entity assumes financial risk on a prospective basis for benefits that it offers under a prescription drug plan and that is not covered under section 1395w–115(b) of this title.


(B) Reinsurance permittedThe plan sponsor may obtain insurance or make other arrangements for the cost of coverage provided to any enrollee to the extent that the sponsor is at risk for providing such coverage.



(3) Solvency for unlicensed sponsorsIn the case of a PDP sponsor that is not described in paragraph (1) and for which a waiver has been approved under subsection (c), such sponsor shall meet solvency standards established by the Secretary under subsection (d).



(b) Contract requirements(1) In generalThe Secretary shall not permit the enrollment under section 1395w–101 of this title in a prescription drug plan offered by a PDP sponsor under this part, and the sponsor shall not be eligible for payments under section 1395w–114 or 1395w–115 of this title, unless the Secretary has entered into a contract under this subsection with the sponsor with respect to the offering of such plan. Such a contract with a sponsor may cover more than one prescription drug plan. Such contract shall provide that the sponsor agrees to comply with the applicable requirements and standards of this part and the terms and conditions of payment as provided for in this part.


(2) Limitation on entities offering fallback prescription dr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General requirements Each PDP sponsor of a prescription drug plan shall meet the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of certain requirements to expand choice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of certain requirements to expand choice</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solvency standards for non-licensed entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Solvency standards for non-licensed entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensure does not substitute for or constitute certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Licensure does not substitute for or constitute certification The fact that a PDP sponsor is licensed in accordance with subsection (a)(1) or has a waiver application approved under subsection (c) does not deem the sponsor to meet other requirements imposed under this part for a sponsor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review and revision of standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Periodic review and revision of standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_112_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of State imposition of premium taxes; relation to State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition of State imposition of premium taxes; relation to State laws The provisions of sections 1395w–24(g) and 1395w–26(b)(3) of this title shall apply with respect to PDP sponsors and prescription drug plans under this part in the same manner as such sections apply to MA organizations and MA plans under part C.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>