<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395cc–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395cc_6"><akn:num>1395cc–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Opioid use disorder treatment demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395cc–6. Opioid use disorder treatment demonstration program(a) Implementation of 4-year demonstration program(1) In generalNot later than January 1, 2021, the Secretary shall implement a 4-year demonstration program under this subchapter (in this section referred to as the “Program”) to increase access of applicable beneficiaries to opioid use disorder treatment services, improve physical and mental health outcomes for such beneficiaries, and to the extent possible, reduce expenditures under this subchapter. Under the Program, the Secretary shall make payments under subsection (e) to participants (as defined in subsection (c)(1)(A)) for furnishing opioid use disorder treatment services delivered through opioid use disorder care teams, or arranging for such services to be furnished, to applicable beneficiaries participating in the Program.


(2) Opioid use disorder treatment servicesFor purposes of this section, the term “opioid use disorder treatment services”—(A) means, with respect to an applicable beneficiary, services that are furnished for the treatment of opioid use disorders and that utilize drugs approved under section 355 of title 21 for the treatment of opioid use disorders in an outpatient setting; and

(B) includes—(i) medication-assisted treatment;

(ii) treatment planning;

(iii) psychiatric, psychological, or counseling services (or any combination of such services), as appropriate;

(iv) social support services, as appropriate; and

(v) care management and care coordination services, including coordination with other providers of services and suppliers not on an opioid use disorder care team.




(b) Program design(1) In generalThe Secretary shall design the Program in such a manner to allow for the evaluation of the extent to which the Program accomplishes the following purposes:(A) Reduces hospitalizations and emergency department visits.

(B) Increases use of medication-assisted treatment for opioid use disorders.

(C) Improves health outcomes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of 4-year demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Implementation of 4-year demonstration program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program design</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program design</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participants; opioid use disorder care teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participants; opioid use disorder care teams</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation of applicable beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Participation of applicable beneficiaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multipayer strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Multipayer strategy In carrying out the Program, the Secretary shall encourage other payers to provide similar payments and to use similar criteria as applied under the Program under subsection (e)(2)(C). The Secretary may enter into a memorandum of understanding with other payers to align the methodology for payment provided by such a payer related to opioid use disorder treatment services with such methodology for payment under the Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395cc_6_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Waivers The Secretary may waive any provision of this subchapter as may be necessary to carry out the Program under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>