<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395nn" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395nn/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395nn/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395nn"><akn:num>1395nn</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on certain physician referrals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395nn. Limitation on certain physician referrals(a) Prohibition of certain referrals(1) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b), if a physician (or an immediate family member of such physician) has a financial relationship with an entity specified in paragraph (2), then—(A) the physician may not make a referral to the entity for the furnishing of designated health services for which payment otherwise may be made under this subchapter, and

(B) the entity may not present or cause to be presented a claim under this subchapter or bill to any individual, third party payor, or other entity for designated health services furnished pursuant to a referral prohibited under subparagraph (A).


(2) Financial relationship specifiedFor purposes of this section, a financial relationship of a physician (or an immediate family member of such physician) with an entity specified in this paragraph is—(A) except as provided in subsections (c) and (d), an ownership or investment interest in the entity, or

(B) except as provided in subsection (e), a compensation arrangement (as defined in subsection (h)(1)) between the physician (or an immediate family member of such physician) and the entity.


An ownership or investment interest described in subparagraph (A) may be through equity, debt, or other means and includes an interest in an entity that holds an ownership or investment interest in any entity providing the designated health service.


(b) General exceptions to both ownership and compensation arrangement prohibitionsSubsection (a)(1) shall not apply in the following cases:(1) Physicians’ servicesIn the case of physicians’ services (as defined in section 1395x(q) of this title) provided personally by (or under the personal supervision of) another physician in the same group practice (as defined in subsection (h)(4)) as the referring physician.


(2) In-office ancillary servicesIn the case of services (other than durable medical equipment (excluding infusion pumps) and pa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of certain referrals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition of certain referrals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General exceptions to both ownership and compensation arrangement prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General exceptions to both ownership and compensation arrangement prohibitions Subsection (a)(1) shall not apply in the following cases:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>General exception related only to ownership or investment prohibition for ownership in publicly traded securities and mutual funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) General exception related only to ownership or investment prohibition for ownership in publicly traded securities and mutual funds Ownership of the following shall not be considered to be an ownership or investment interest described in subsection (a)(2)(A):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional exceptions related only to ownership or investment prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional exceptions related only to ownership or investment prohibition The following, if not otherwise excepted under subsection (b), shall not be considered to be an ownership or investment interest described in subsection (a)(2)(A):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exceptions relating to other compensation arrangements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exceptions relating to other compensation arrangements The following shall not be considered to be a compensation arrangement described in subsection (a)(2)(B):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting requirements Each entity providing covered items or services for which payment may be made under this subchapter shall provide the Secretary with the information concerning the entity’s ownership, investment, and compensation arrangements, including— Such information shall be provided in such form, manner, and at such times as the Secretary shall specify. The requirement of this subsection shall not apply to designated health services provided outside the United States or to entities which the Secretary determines provides 33 So in original. Probably should be “provide”. services for which payment may be made under this subchapter very infrequently.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions and special rules For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395nn_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for hospitals to qualify for rural provider and hospital exception to ownership or investment prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Requirements for hospitals to qualify for rural provider and hospital exception to ownership or investment prohibition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>