<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395b_2"><akn:num>1395b–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of medicare benefits; medicare and medigap information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395b–2. Notice of medicare benefits; medicare and medigap information(a) Notice of medicare benefitsThe Secretary shall prepare (in consultation with groups representing the elderly and with health insurers) and provide for distribution of a notice containing—(1) a clear, simple explanation of the benefits available under this subchapter and the major categories of health care for which benefits are not available under this subchapter,

(2) the limitations on payment (including deductibles and coinsurance amounts) that are imposed under this subchapter, and

(3) a description of the limited benefits for long-term care services available under this subchapter and generally available under State plans approved under subchapter XIX.


Such notice shall be mailed annually to individuals entitled to benefits under part A or part B of this subchapter and when an individual applies for benefits under part A or enrolls under part B.

(b) Medicare and medigap informationThe Secretary shall provide information via a toll-free telephone number on the programs under this subchapter. The Secretary shall provide, through the toll-free telephone number 1–800–MEDICARE, for a means by which individuals seeking information about, or assistance with, such programs who phone such toll-free number are transferred (without charge) to appropriate entities for the provision of such information or assistance. Such toll-free number shall be the toll-free number listed for general information and assistance in the annual notice under subsection (a) instead of the listing of numbers of individual contractors.


(c) Contents of noticeThe notice provided under subsection (a) shall include—(1) a statement which indicates that because errors do occur and because medicare fraud, waste, and abuse is a significant problem, beneficiaries should carefully check any explanation of benefits or itemized statement furnished pursuant to section 1395b–7 of this title for accuracy and report any errors or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of medicare benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice of medicare benefits The Secretary shall prepare (in consultation with groups representing the elderly and with health insurers) and provide for distribution of a notice containing— Such notice shall be mailed annually to individuals entitled to benefits under part A or part B of this subchapter and when an individual applies for benefits under part A or enrolls under part B.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare and medigap information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Medicare and medigap information The Secretary shall provide information via a toll-free telephone number on the programs under this subchapter. The Secretary shall provide, through the toll-free telephone number 1–800–MEDICARE, for a means by which individuals seeking information about, or assistance with, such programs who phone such toll-free number are transferred (without charge) to appropriate entities for the provision of such information or assistance. Such toll-free number shall be the toll-free number listed for general information and assistance in the annual notice under subsection (a) instead of the listing of numbers of individual contractors.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of notice The notice provided under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare opioid safety education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Medicare opioid safety education The notice provided under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>