<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–114b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_114b"><akn:num>1395w–114b</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufacturer rebate for certain drugs with prices increasing faster than inflation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–114b. Manufacturer rebate for certain drugs with prices increasing faster than inflation(a) Requirements(1) Secretarial provision of informationNot later than 9 months after the end of each applicable period (as defined in subsection (g)(7)), subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary shall, for each part D rebatable drug, report to each manufacturer of such part D rebatable drug the following for such period:(A) The amount (if any) of the excess annual manufacturer price increase described in subsection (b)(1)(A)(ii) for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug and period.

(B) The rebate amount specified under subsection (b) for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug and period.


(2) Manufacturer requirementsFor each applicable period, the manufacturer of a part D rebatable drug, for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug, not later than 30 days after the date of receipt from the Secretary of the information described in paragraph (1) for such period, shall provide to the Secretary a rebate that is equal to the amount specified in subsection (b) for such dosage form and strength with respect to such drug for such period.


(3) Transition rule for reportingThe Secretary may, for each rebatable covered part D drug, delay the timeframe for reporting the information and rebate amount described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such paragraph for the applicable periods beginning October 1, 2022, and October 1, 2023, until not later than December 31, 2025.



(b) Rebate amount(1) In general(A) CalculationFor purposes of this section, the amount specified in this subsection for a dosage form and strength with respect to a part D rebatable drug and applicable period is, subject to subparagraph (C), paragraph (5)(B), and paragraph (6), the estimated amount equal to the product of—(i) subject to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the total number of units of such dosage form and strength for each rebatable covered part D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rebate amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rebate amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rebate deposits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rebate deposits Amounts paid as rebates under subsection (b) shall be deposited into the Medicare Prescription Drug Account in the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1395t of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information For purposes of carrying out this section, the Secretary shall use information submitted by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Civil money penalty If a manufacturer of a part D rebatable drug has failed to comply with the requirement under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such drug for an applicable period, the manufacturer shall be subject to a civil money penalty in an amount equal to 125 percent of the amount specified in subsection (b) for such drug for such period. The provisions of section 1320a–7a of this title (other than subsections (a) (with respect to amounts of penalties or additional assessments) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1320a–7a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative or judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on administrative or judicial review There shall be no administrative or judicial review of any of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_114b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation for 2022, 2023, and 2024</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Implementation for 2022, 2023, and 2024 The Secretary shall implement this section for 2022, 2023, and 2024 by program instruction or other forms of program guidance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>