<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–28" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–28/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–28/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_28"><akn:num>1395w–28</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–28. Definitions; miscellaneous provisions(a) Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice organizationsIn this part—(1) Medicare+Choice organizationThe term “Medicare+Choice organization” means a public or private entity that is certified under section 1395w–26 of this title as meeting the requirements and standards of this part for such an organization.


(2) Provider-sponsored organizationThe term “provider-sponsored organization” is defined in section 1395w–25(d)(1) of this title.



(b) Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice plans(1) Medicare+Choice planThe term “Medicare+Choice plan” means health benefits coverage offered under a policy, contract, or plan by a Medicare+Choice organization pursuant to and in accordance with a contract under section 1395w–27 of this title.


(2) Medicare+Choice private fee-for-service planThe term “Medicare+Choice private fee-for-service plan” means a Medicare+Choice plan that—(A) reimburses hospitals, physicians, and other providers at a rate determined by the plan on a fee-for-service basis without placing the provider at financial risk;

(B) does not vary such rates for such a provider based on utilization relating to such provider; and

(C) does not restrict the selection of providers among those who are lawfully authorized to provide the covered services and agree to accept the terms and conditions of payment established by the plan.


Nothing in subparagraph (B) shall be construed to preclude a plan from varying rates for such a provider based on the specialty of the provider, the location of the provider, or other factors related to such provider that are not related to utilization, or to preclude a plan from increasing rates for such a provider based on increased utilization of specified preventive or screening services.

(3) MSA plan(A) In generalThe term “MSA plan” means a Medicare+ÐChoice plan that—(i) provides reimbursement for at least the items and services described in section 1395w–22(a)(1) of this title in a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice organizations In this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions relating to Medicare+Choice plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other references to other terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other references to other terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinated acute and long-term care benefits under Medicare+Choice plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordinated acute and long-term care benefits under Medicare+Choice plan Nothing in this part shall be construed as preventing a State from coordinating benefits under a medicaid plan under subchapter XIX with those provided under a Medicare+Choice plan in a manner that assures continuity of a full-range of acute care and long-term care services to poor elderly or disabled individuals eligible for benefits under this subchapter and under such plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on enrollment for certain Medicare+Choice plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restriction on enrollment for certain Medicare+Choice plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements regarding enrollment in specialized MA plans for special needs individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirements regarding enrollment in specialized MA plans for special needs individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for senior housing facility plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Special rules for senior housing facility plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>National testing of Medicare Advantage Value-Based Insurance Design model</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) National testing of Medicare Advantage Value-Based Insurance Design model</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_28_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program integrity transparency measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Program integrity transparency measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>