<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395iii" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395iii/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395iii/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395iii"><akn:num>1395iii</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare Improvement Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395iii. Medicare Improvement Fund(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish under this subchapter a Medicare Improvement Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”) which shall be available to the Secretary to make improvements under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B for individuals entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part 11 So in original. or enrolled under part B including adjustments to payments for items and services furnished by providers of services and suppliers under such original Medicare fee-for-service program.


(b) Funding(1) In generalThere shall be available to the Fund, for expenditures from the Fund for services furnished during and after fiscal year 2027, $1,403,000,000.


(2) Payment from Trust FundsThe amount specified under paragraph (1) shall be available to the Fund, as expenditures are made from the Fund, from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund in such proportion as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(3) Funding limitationAmounts in the Fund shall be available in advance of appropriations but only if the total amount obligated from the Fund does not exceed the amount available to the Fund under paragraph (1). The Secretary may obligate funds from the Fund only if the Secretary determines (and the Chief Actuary of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the appropriate budget officer certify) that there are available in the Fund sufficient amounts to cover all such obligations incurred consistent with the previous sentence.


(4) No effect on payments in subsequent yearsIn the case that expenditures from the Fund are applied to, or otherwise affect, a payment rate for an item or service under this subchapter for a year, the payment rate for such item or service shall be computed for a subsequent year as if such application or effect had never occurred.



(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title XVIII, § 1898, as added Pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395iii_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish under this subchapter a Medicare Improvement Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”) which shall be available to the Secretary to make improvements under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under parts A and B for individuals entitled to, or enrolled for, benefits under part 11 So in original. or enrolled under part B including adjustments to payments for items and services furnished by providers of services and suppliers under such original Medicare fee-for-service program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395iii_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>