<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_104"><akn:num>1395w–104</akn:num><akn:heading>Beneficiary protections for qualified prescription drug coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–104. Beneficiary protections for qualified prescription drug coverage(a) Dissemination of information(1) General information(A) Application of MA informationA PDP sponsor shall disclose, in a clear, accurate, and standardized form to each enrollee with a prescription drug plan offered by the sponsor under this part at the time of enrollment and at least annually thereafter, the information described in section 1395w–22(c)(1) of this title relating to such plan, insofar as the Secretary determines appropriate with respect to benefits provided under this part, and, subject to subparagraph (C), including the information described in subparagraph (B).


(B) Drug specific informationThe information described in this subparagraph is information concerning the following:(i) Access to specific covered part D drugs, including access through pharmacy networks.

(ii) How any formulary (including any tiered formulary structure) used by the sponsor functions, including a description of how a part D eligible individual may obtain information on the formulary consistent with paragraph (3).

(iii) Beneficiary cost-sharing requirements and how a part D eligible individual may obtain information on such requirements, including tiered or other copayment level applicable to each drug (or class of drugs), consistent with paragraph (3).

(iv) The medication therapy management program required under subsection (c).

(v) The drug management program for at-risk beneficiaries under subsection (c)(5).

(vi) For plan year 2021 and each subsequent plan year, subject to subparagraph (C), with respect to the treatment of pain—(I) the risks associated with prolonged opioid use; and

(II) coverage of nonpharmacological therapies, devices, and nonopioid medications—(aa) in the case of an MA–PD plan under part C, under such plan; and

(bb) in the case of a prescription drug plan, under such plan and under parts A and B.




(C) Targeted provision of informationA PDP sponsor of a prescription </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Dissemination of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to covered part D drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access to covered part D drugs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost and utilization management; quality assurance; medication therapy management program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cost and utilization management; quality assurance; medication therapy management program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer satisfaction surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consumer satisfaction surveys In order to provide for comparative information under section 1395w–101(c)(3)(A)(v) of this title, the Secretary shall conduct consumer satisfaction surveys with respect to PDP sponsors and prescription drug plans in a manner similar to the manner such surveys are conducted for MA organizations and MA plans under part C.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic prescription program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Electronic prescription program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grievance mechanism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grievance mechanism Each PDP sponsor shall provide meaningful procedures for hearing and resolving grievances between the sponsor (including any entity or individual through which the sponsor provides covered benefits) and enrollees with prescription drug plans of the sponsor under this part in accordance with section 1395w–22(f) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage determinations and reconsiderations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coverage determinations and reconsiderations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appeals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy, confidentiality, and accuracy of enrollee records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Privacy, confidentiality, and accuracy of enrollee records The provisions of section 1395w–22(h) of this title shall apply to a PDP sponsor and prescription drug plan in the same manner as it applies to an MA organization and an MA plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_104_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Treatment of accreditation Subparagraph (A) of section 1395w–22(e)(4) of this title (relating to treatment of accreditation) shall apply to a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to the following requirements, in the same manner as it applies to an MA organization with respect to the requirements in subparagraph (B) (other than clause (vii) thereof) of such section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>