<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ss" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ss/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ss/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395ss"><akn:num>1395ss</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of medicare supplemental health insurance policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395ss. Certification of medicare supplemental health insurance policies(a) Submission of policy by insurer(1) The Secretary shall establish a procedure whereby medicare supplemental policies (as defined in subsection (g)(1)) may be certified by the Secretary as meeting minimum standards and requirements set forth in subsection (c). Such procedure shall provide an opportunity for any insurer to submit any such policy, and such additional data as the Secretary finds necessary, to the Secretary for his examination and for his certification thereof as meeting the standards and requirements set forth in subsection (c). Subject to subsections (k)(3), (m), and (n), such certification shall remain in effect if the insurer files a notarized statement with the Secretary no later than June 30 of each year stating that the policy continues to meet such standards and requirements and if the insurer submits such additional data as the Secretary finds necessary to independently verify the accuracy of such notarized statement. Where the Secretary determines such a policy meets (or continues to meet) such standards and requirements, he shall authorize the insurer to have printed on such policy (but only in accordance with such requirements and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe) an emblem which the Secretary shall cause to be designed for use as an indication that a policy has received the Secretary’s certification. The Secretary shall provide each State commissioner or superintendent of insurance with a list of all the policies which have received his certification.

(2) No medicare supplemental policy may be issued in a State on or after the date specified in subsection (p)(1)(C) unless—(A) the State’s regulatory program under subsection (b)(1) provides for the application and enforcement of the standards and requirements set forth in such subsection (including the 1991 NAIC Model Regulation or 1991 Federal Regulation (as the case may be)) by the date specified in subsec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of policy by insurer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of policy by insurer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and requirements; periodic review by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards and requirements; periodic review by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisite findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requisite findings The Secretary shall certify under this section any medicare supplemental policy, or continue certification of such a policy, only if he finds that such policy (or, with respect to paragraph (3) or the requirement described in subsection (s), the issuer of the policy)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties; civil penalties for certain violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criminal penalties; civil penalties for certain violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dissemination of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and evaluation of comparative effectiveness of various State approaches to regulating medicare supplemental policies; report to Congress no later than January 1, 1982; periodic evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Study and evaluation of comparative effectiveness of various State approaches to regulating medicare supplemental policies; report to Congress no later than</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules and regulations The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary for the effective, efficient, and equitable administration of the certification procedure established under this section. The Secretary shall first issue final regulations to implement the certification procedure established under subsection (a) not later than March 1, 1981.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of certification program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Commencement of certification program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ss_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State regulation of policies issued in other States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State regulation of policies issued in other States Nothing in this section shall be construed so as to affect the right of any State to regulate medicare supplemental policies which, under the provisions of this section, are considered to be issued in another State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>