<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395i_6"><akn:num>1395i–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Hospice program survey and enforcement procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395i–6. Hospice program survey and enforcement procedures(a) Surveys(1) FrequencyAny entity that is certified as a hospice program (as defined in section 1395x(dd)(2) of this title) shall be subject to a standard survey by an appropriate State or local survey agency, or an approved accreditation agency, as determined by the Secretary, not less frequently than once every 36 months.


(2) Public transparency of survey and certification information(A) Submission of information to the Secretary(i) In generalEach State or local survey agency, and each national accreditation body with respect to which the Secretary has made a finding under section 1395bb(a) of this title respecting the accreditation of a hospice program by such body, shall submit, in a form and manner, and at a time, specified by the Secretary for purposes of this paragraph, information respecting any survey or certification made with respect to a hospice program by such survey agency or body, as applicable. Such information shall include any inspection report made by such survey agency or body with respect to such survey or certification, any enforcement actions taken as a result of such survey or certification, and any other information determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(ii) Required inclusion of specified formWith respect to a survey under this subsection carried out by a national accreditation body described in clause (i) on or after October 1, 2021, information described in such clause shall include Form CMS-2567 (or a successor form), along with such additional information determined appropriate by such body.



(B) Public disclosure of informationBeginning not later than October 1, 2022, the Secretary shall publish the information submitted under subparagraph (A) on the public website of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services in a manner that is prominent, easily accessible, readily understandable, and searchable. The Secretary shall provide for the timely update of such informati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Surveys</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special focus program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special focus program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>