<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ddd" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ddd/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395ddd/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395ddd"><akn:num>1395ddd</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare Integrity Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395ddd. Medicare Integrity Program(a) Establishment of ProgramThere is hereby established the Medicare Integrity Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”) under which the Secretary shall promote the integrity of the medicare program by entering into contracts in accordance with this section with eligible entities, or otherwise, to carry out the activities described in subsection (b).


(b) Activities describedThe activities described in this subsection are as follows:(1) Review of activities of providers of services or other individuals and entities furnishing items and services for which payment may be made under this subchapter (including skilled nursing facilities and home health agencies), including medical and utilization review and fraud review (employing similar standards, processes, and technologies used by private health plans, including equipment and software technologies which surpass the capability of the equipment and technologies used in the review of claims under this subchapter as of August 21, 1996).

(2) Audit of cost reports.

(3) Determinations as to whether payment should not be, or should not have been, made under this subchapter by reason of section 1395y(b) of this title, and recovery of payments that should not have been made.

(4) Education of providers of services, beneficiaries, and other persons with respect to payment integrity and benefit quality assurance issues.

(5) Developing (and periodically updating) a list of items of durable medical equipment in accordance with section 1395m(a)(15) of this title which are subject to prior authorization under such section.

(6) The Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program in accordance with subsection (g).


(c) Eligibility of entitiesAn entity is eligible to enter into a contract under the Program to carry out any of the activities described in subsection (b) if—(1) the entity has demonstrated capability to carry out such activities;

(2) in carrying out such activities, the entity</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Program There is hereby established the Medicare Integrity Program (in this section referred to as the “Program”) under which the Secretary shall promote the integrity of the medicare program by entering into contracts in accordance with this section with eligible entities, or otherwise, to carry out the activities described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities described The activities described in this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility of entities An entity is eligible to enter into a contract under the Program to carry out any of the activities described in subsection (b) if— In the case of the activity described in subsection (b)(5), an entity shall be deemed to be eligible to enter into a contract under the Program to carry out the activity if the entity is a carrier with a contract in effect under section 1395u of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process for entering into contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Process for entering into contracts The Secretary shall enter into contracts under the Program in accordance with such procedures as the Secretary shall by regulation establish, except that such procedures shall include the following: The Secretary may enter into such contracts without regard to final rules having been promulgated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on contractor liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on contractor liability The Secretary shall by regulation provide for the limitation of a contractor’s liability for actions taken to carry out a contract under the Program, and such regulation shall, to the extent the Secretary finds appropriate, employ the same or comparable standards and other substantive and procedural provisions as are contained in section 1320c–6 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of overpayments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recovery of overpayments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Medicare-Medicaid Data Match Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of recovery audit contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Use of recovery audit contractors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations and annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Evaluations and annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395ddd_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding activities of Medicare drug integrity contractors (MEDICs)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Expanding activities of Medicare drug integrity contractors (MEDICs)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>