<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395u"><akn:num>1395u</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to the administration of part B</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395u. Provisions relating to the administration of part B(a) In generalThe administration of this part shall be conducted through contracts with medicare administrative contractors under section 1395kk–1 of this title.


(b) Determination of reasonable charges(1) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 911(c)(3)(A), Dec. 8, 2003, 117 Stat. 2384.

(2)(A), (B) Repealed. Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 911(c)(3)(B)(i), Dec. 8, 2003, 117 Stat. 2384.

(C) In the case of residents of nursing facilities who receive services described in clause (i) or (ii) of section 1395x(s)(2)(K) of this title performed by a member of a team, the Secretary shall instruct medicare administrative contractors to develop mechanisms which permit routine payment under this part for up to 1.5 visits per month per resident. In the previous sentence, the term “team” refers to a physician and includes a physician assistant acting under the supervision of the physician or a nurse practitioner working in collaboration with that physician, or both.


(3) The Secretary—(A) shall take such action as may be necessary to assure that, where payment under this part for a service is on a cost basis, the cost is reasonable cost (as determined under section 1395x(v) of this title);

(B) shall take such action as may be necessary to assure that, where payment under this part for a service is on a charge basis, such charge will be reasonable and not higher than the charge applicable, for a comparable service and under comparable circumstances, to the policyholders and subscribers of the medicare administrative contractor, and such payment will (except as otherwise provided in section 1395gg(f) of this title) be made—(i) on the basis of an itemized bill; or

(ii) on the basis of an assignment under the terms of which (I) the reasonable charge is the full charge for the service, (II) the physician or other person furnishing such service agrees not to charge (and to refund amounts already collected) for services for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The administration of this part shall be conducted through contracts with medicare administrative contractors under section 1395kk–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of reasonable charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of reasonable charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt payment of claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prompt payment of claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (f). Repealed. Pub. L. 108–173, title IX, § 911(c)(5), Dec. 8, 2003, 117 Stat. 2384</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) to (f). Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Railroad Retirement Board to enter into contracts with medicare administrative contractors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authority of Railroad Retirement Board to enter into contracts with medicare administrative contractors The Railroad Retirement Board shall, in accordance with such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, contract with a medicare administrative contractor or contractors to perform the functions set out in this section with respect to individuals entitled to benefits as qualified railroad retirement beneficiaries pursuant to section 426(a) of this title and section 231f(d) of title 45.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating physician or supplier; agreement with Secretary; publication of directories; availability; inclusion of program in explanation of benefits; payment of claims on assignment-related basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Participating physician or supplier; agreement with Secretary; publication of directories; availability; inclusion of program in explanation of benefits; payment of claims on assignment-related basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions For purposes of this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of charges of nonparticipating physicians; sanctions; restitution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Monitoring of charges of nonparticipating physicians; sanctions; restitution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sanctions for billing for services of assistant at cataract operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Sanctions for billing for services of assistant at cataract operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395u_l"><akn:num>(l)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of unassigned billing of services determined to be medically unnecessary by carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(l) Prohibition of unassigned billing of services determined to be medically unnecessary by carrier</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>