<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–24" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–24/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–24/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_24"><akn:num>1395w–24</akn:num><akn:heading>Premiums and bid amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–24. Premiums and bid amounts(a) Submission of proposed premiums, bid amounts, and related information(1) In general(A) Initial submissionNot later than the second Monday in September of 2002, 2003, and 2004 (or the first Monday in June of each subsequent year), each MA organization shall submit to the Secretary, in a form and manner specified by the Secretary and for each MA plan for the service area (or segment of such an area if permitted under subsection (h)) in which it intends to be offered in the following year the following:(i) The information described in paragraph (2), (3), (4), or (6)(A) for the type of plan and year involved.

(ii) The plan type for each plan.

(iii) The enrollment capacity (if any) in relation to the plan and area.


(B) Beneficiary rebate informationIn the case of a plan required to provide a monthly rebate under subsection (b)(1)(C) for a year, the MA organization offering the plan shall submit to the Secretary, in such form and manner and at such time as the Secretary specifies, information on—(i) the manner in which such rebate will be provided under clause (ii) of such subsection; and

(ii) the MA monthly prescription drug beneficiary premium (if any) and the MA monthly supplemental beneficiary premium (if any).


(C) Paperwork reduction for offering of MA regional plans nationally or in multi-region areasThe Secretary shall establish requirements for information submission under this subsection in a manner that promotes the offering of MA regional plans in more than one region (including all regions) through the filing of consolidated information.



(2) Information required for coordinated care plans before 2006For a Medicare+Choice plan described in section 1395w–21(a)(2)(A) of this title for a year before 2006, the information described in this paragraph is as follows:(A) Basic (and additional) benefitsFor benefits described in section 1395w–22(a)(1)(A) of this title—(i) the adjusted community rate (as defined in subsect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of proposed premiums, bid amounts, and related information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of proposed premiums, bid amounts, and related information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly premium charged</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Monthly premium charged</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform premium and bid amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uniform premium and bid amounts Except as permitted under section 1395w–27(i) of this title, the MA monthly bid amount submitted under subsection (a)(6), the amounts of the MA monthly basic, prescription drug, and supplemental beneficiary premiums, and the MA monthly MSA premium charged under subsection (b) of an MA organization under this part may not vary among individuals enrolled in the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions of imposing premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions of imposing premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on enrollee liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on enrollee liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for additional benefits before 2006</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirement for additional benefits before 2006</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of State imposition of premium taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Prohibition of State imposition of premium taxes No State may impose a premium tax or similar tax with respect to payments to Medicare+Choice organizations under section 1395w–23 of this title or premiums paid to such organizations under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_24_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permitting use of segments of service areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Permitting use of segments of service areas The Secretary shall permit a Medicare+Choice organization to elect to apply the provisions of this section uniformly to separate segments of a service area (rather than uniformly to an entire service area) as long as such segments are composed of one or more Medicare+Choice payment areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>