<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_6"><akn:num>1395w–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Empowering beneficiary choices through continued access to information on physicians’ services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–6. Empowering beneficiary choices through continued access to information on physicians’ services(a) In generalOn an annual basis (beginning with 2015), the Secretary shall make publicly available, in an easily understandable format, information with respect to physicians and, as appropriate, other eligible professionals on items and services furnished to Medicare beneficiaries under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.).


(b) Type and manner of informationThe information made available under this section shall be similar to the type of information in the Medicare Provider Utilization and Payment Data: Physician and Other Supplier Public Use File released by the Secretary with respect to 2012 and shall be made available in a manner similar to the manner in which the information in such file is made available.


(c) RequirementsThe information made available under this section shall include, at a minimum, the following:(1) Information on the number of services furnished by the physician or other eligible professional under part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395j et seq.), which may include information on the most frequent services furnished or groupings of services.

(2) Information on submitted charges and payments for services under such part.

(3) A unique identifier for the physician or other eligible professional that is available to the public, such as a national provider identifier.


(d) SearchabilityThe information made available under this section shall be searchable by at least the following:(1) The specialty or type of the physician or other eligible professional.

(2) Characteristics of the services furnished, such as volume or groupings of services.

(3) The location of the physician or other eligible professional.


(e) Integration on physician compareBeginning with 2016, the Secretary shall integrate the information made available under this section on Physician Compare.


(f) DefinitionsIn </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general On an annual basis (beginning with 2015), the Secretary shall make publicly available, in an easily understandable format, information with respect to physicians and, as appropriate, other eligible professionals on items and services furnished to Medicare beneficiaries under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Type and manner of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Type and manner of information The information made available under this section shall be similar to the type of information in the Medicare Provider Utilization and Payment Data: Physician and Other Supplier Public Use File released by the Secretary with respect to 2012 and shall be made available in a manner similar to the manner in which the information in such file is made available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The information made available under this section shall include, at a minimum, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Searchability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Searchability The information made available under this section shall be searchable by at least the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integration on physician compare</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Integration on physician compare Beginning with 2016, the Secretary shall integrate the information made available under this section on Physician Compare.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>