<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395v"><akn:num>1395v</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395v. Agreements with States(a) Duty of Secretary; enrollment of eligible individualsThe Secretary shall, at the request of a State made before January 1, 1970, or during 1981 or after 1988, enter into an agreement with such State pursuant to which all eligible individuals in either of the coverage groups described in subsection (b) (as specified in the agreement) will be enrolled under the program established by this part.


(b) Coverage of groups to which applicableAn agreement entered into with any State pursuant to subsection (a) may be applicable to either of the following coverage groups:(1) individuals receiving money payments under the plan of such State approved under subchapter I or subchapter XVI; or

(2) individuals receiving money payments under all of the plans of such State approved under subchapters I, X, XIV, and XVI, and part A of subchapter IV.


Except as provided in subsection (g), there shall be excluded from any coverage group any individual who is entitled to monthly insurance benefits under subchapter II or who is entitled to receive an annuity under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.]. Effective January 1, 1974, and subject to section 1396a(f) of this title, the Secretary shall, at the request of any State not eligible to participate in the State plan program established under subchapter XVI, continue in effect the agreement entered into under this section with such State subject to such modifications as the Secretary may by regulations provide to take account of the termination of any plans of such State approved under subchapters I, X, XIV, and XVI and the establishment of the supplemental security income program under subchapter XVI.

(c) Eligible individualsFor purposes of this section, an individual shall be treated as an eligible individual only if he is an eligible individual (within the meaning of section 1395o of this title) on the date an agreement covering him is entered into under subsection (a) or he </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Secretary; enrollment of eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duty of Secretary; enrollment of eligible individuals The Secretary shall, at the request of a State made before January 1, 1970, or during 1981 or after 1988, enter into an agreement with such State pursuant to which all eligible individuals in either of the coverage groups described in subsection (b) (as specified in the agreement) will be enrolled under the program established by this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage of groups to which applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coverage of groups to which applicable An agreement entered into with any State pursuant to subsection (a) may be applicable to either of the following coverage groups: Except as provided in subsection (g), there shall be excluded from any coverage group any individual who is entitled to monthly insurance benefits under subchapter II or who is entitled to receive an annuity under the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 [45 U.S.C. 231 et seq.]. Effective January 1, 1974, and subject to section 1396a(f) of this title, the Secretary shall, at the request of any State not eligible to participate in the State plan program established under subchapter XVI, continue in effect the agreement entered into under this section with such State subject to such modifications as the Secretary may by regulations provide to take account of the termination of any plans of such State approved under subchapters I, X, XIV, and XVI and the establishment of the supplemental security income program under subcha</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible individuals For purposes of this section, an individual shall be treated as an eligible individual only if he is an eligible individual (within the meaning of section 1395o of this title) on the date an agreement covering him is entered into under subsection (a) or he becomes an eligible individual (within the meaning of such section) at any time after such date; and he shall be treated as receiving money payments described in subsection (b) if he receives such payments for the month in which the agreement is entered into or any month thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly premiums; coverage periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monthly premiums; coverage periods In the case of any individual enrolled pursuant to this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsection (d)(3) terminations deemed resulting in section 1395p enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subsection (d)(3) terminations deemed resulting in section 1395p enrollment Any individual whose coverage period attributable to the State agreement is terminated pursuant to subsection (d)(3) shall be deemed for purposes of this part (including the continuation of his coverage period under this part) to have enrolled under section 1395p of this title in the initial general enrollment period provided by section 1395p(c) of this title. The coverage period under this part of any such individual who (in the last month of his coverage period attributable to the State agreement or in any of the following six months) files notice that he no longer wishes to participate in the insurance program established by this part, shall terminate at the close of the month in which the notice is filed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Carrier” as including State agency; provisions facilitating deductions, coinsurance, etc., and leading to economy and efficiency of operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Carrier” as including State agency; provisions facilitating deductions, coinsurance, etc., and leading to economy and efficiency of operation With respect to eligible individuals receiving money payments under the plan of a State approved under subchapter I, X, XIV, or XVI, or part A of subchapter IV, or eligible to receive medical assistance under the plan of such State approved under subchapter XIX, if the agreement entered into under this section so provides, the term “carrier” as defined in section 1395u(f) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title also includes the State agency, specified in such agreement, which administers or supervises the administration of the plan of such State approved under subchapter I, XVI, or XIX. The agreement shall also contain such provisions as will facilitate the financial transactions of the State and the carrier with respect to deductions, coinsurance, and otherwise, and as will lead to economy and efficiency of operation, with resp</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subsection (b) exclusions from coverage groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Subsection (b) exclusions from coverage groups</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modifications respecting subsection (b) coverage groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Modifications respecting subsection (b) coverage groups</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395v_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment of qualified medicare beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Enrollment of qualified medicare beneficiaries For provisions relating to enrollment of qualified medicare beneficiaries under part A, see section 1395i–2(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>