<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395i–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395i_2"><akn:num>1395i–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Hospital insurance benefits for uninsured elderly individuals not otherwise eligible</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395i–2. Hospital insurance benefits for uninsured elderly individuals not otherwise eligible(a) Individuals eligible to enrollEvery individual who—(1) has attained the age of 65,

(2) is enrolled under part B of this subchapter,

(3) is a resident of the United States, and is either (A) a citizen or (B) an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence who has resided in the United States continuously during the 5 years immediately preceding the month in which he applies for enrollment under this section, and

(4) is not otherwise entitled to benefits under this part,


shall be eligible to enroll in the insurance program established by this part. Except as otherwise provided, any reference to an individual entitled to benefits under this part includes an individual entitled to benefits under this part pursuant to an enrollment under this section or section 1395i–2a of this title.

(b) Time, manner, and form of enrollmentAn individual may enroll under this section only in such manner and form as may be prescribed in regulations, and only during an enrollment period prescribed in or under this section.


(c) Period of enrollment; scope of coverageThe provisions of section 1395p of this title (except subsections (f) and (o) thereof), section 1395q of this title, subsection (b) of section 1395r of this title, and subsections (f) and (h) of section 1395s of this title shall apply to persons authorized to enroll under this section except that—(1) individuals who meet the conditions of subsection (a)(1), (3), and (4) on or before the last day of the seventh month after October 1972 may enroll under this part and (if not already so enrolled) may also enroll under part B during an initial general enrollment period which shall begin on the first day of the second month which begins after October 30, 1972, and shall end on the last day of the tenth month after October 1972;

(2) in the case of an individual who first meets the conditions of eligibility under this section </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals eligible to enroll</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Individuals eligible to enroll Every individual who— shall be eligible to enroll in the insurance program established by this part. Except as otherwise provided, any reference to an individual entitled to benefits under this part includes an individual entitled to benefits under this part pursuant to an enrollment under this section or section 1395i–2a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time, manner, and form of enrollment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Time, manner, and form of enrollment An individual may enroll under this section only in such manner and form as may be prescribed in regulations, and only during an enrollment period prescribed in or under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of enrollment; scope of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period of enrollment; scope of coverage The provisions of section 1395p of this title (except subsections (f) and (o) thereof), section 1395q of this title, subsection (b) of section 1395r of this title, and subsections (f) and (h) of section 1395s of this title shall apply to persons authorized to enroll under this section except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monthly premiums</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract or other arrangement for payment of monthly premiums</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contract or other arrangement for payment of monthly premiums Payment of the monthly premiums on behalf of any individual who meets the conditions of subsection (a) may be made by any public or private agency or organization under a contract or other arrangement entered into between it and the Secretary if the Secretary determines that payment of such premiums under such contract or arrangement is administratively feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of amounts into Treasury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Deposit of amounts into Treasury Amounts paid to the Secretary for coverage under this section shall be deposited in the Treasury to the credit of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395i_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Buy-in under this part for qualified medicare beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Buy-in under this part for qualified medicare beneficiaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>