<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395b–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395b_9"><akn:num>1395b–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395b–9. Provisions relating to administration(a) Coordinated administration of medicare prescription drug and Medicare Advantage programs(1) In generalThere is within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services a center to carry out the duties described in paragraph (3).


(2) DirectorSuch center shall be headed by a director who shall report directly to the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.


(3) DutiesThe duties described in this paragraph are the following:(A) The administration of parts C and D.

(B) The provision of notice and information under section 1395b–2 of this title.

(C) Such other duties as the Secretary may specify.


(4) DeadlineThe Secretary shall ensure that the center is carrying out the duties described in paragraph (3) by not later than January 1, 2008.



(b) Employment of management staff(1) In generalThe Secretary may employ, within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, such individuals as management staff as the Secretary determines to be appropriate. With respect to the administration of parts C and D, such individuals shall include individuals with private sector expertise in negotiations with health benefits plans.


(2) EligibilityTo be eligible for employment under paragraph (1) an individual shall be required to have demonstrated, by their education and experience (either in the public or private sector), superior expertise in at least one of the following areas:(A) The review, negotiation, and administration of health care contracts.

(B) The design of health care benefit plans.

(C) Actuarial sciences.

(D) Compliance with health plan contracts.

(E) Consumer education and decision making.

(F) Any other area specified by the Secretary that requires specialized management or other expertise.


(3) Rates of payment(A) Performance-related paySubject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall establish the rate of pay for an individual employed under paragraph (1). Such rate shall take into accoun</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinated administration of medicare prescription drug and Medicare Advantage programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordinated administration of medicare prescription drug and Medicare Advantage programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of management staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Employment of management staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medicare Beneficiary Ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Medicare Beneficiary Ombudsman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pharmaceutical and technology ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Pharmaceutical and technology ombudsman</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395b_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for implementation of beneficiary enrollment simplification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding for implementation of beneficiary enrollment simplification For purposes of carrying out the provisions of and the amendments made by section 120 of division CC of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021, the Secretary shall provide for the transfer, from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 1395i of this title and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund under section 1395t of this title (in such proportion as the Secretary determines appropriate), to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, of $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2030, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>