<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–25" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–25/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395w–25/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395w_25"><akn:num>1395w–25</akn:num><akn:heading>Organizational and financial requirements for Medicare+Choice organizations; provider-sponsored orga</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395w–25. Organizational and financial requirements for Medicare+Choice organizations; provider-sponsored organizations(a) Organized and licensed under State law(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3), a Medicare+Choice organization shall be organized and licensed under State law as a risk-bearing entity eligible to offer health insurance or health benefits coverage in each State in which it offers a Medicare+Choice plan.


(2) Special exception for provider-sponsored organizations(A) In generalIn the case of a provider-sponsored organization that seeks to offer a Medicare+Choice plan in a State, the Secretary shall waive the requirement of paragraph (1) that the organization be licensed in that State if—(i) the organization files an application for such waiver with the Secretary by not later than November 1, 2002, and

(ii) the Secretary determines, based on the application and other evidence presented to the Secretary, that any of the grounds for approval of the application described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) has been met.


(B) Failure to act on licensure application on a timely basisThe ground for approval of such a waiver application described in this subparagraph is that the State has failed to complete action on a licensing application of the organization within 90 days of the date of the State’s receipt of a substantially complete application. No period before August 5, 1997, shall be included in determining such 90-day period.


(C) Denial of application based on discriminatory treatmentThe ground for approval of such a waiver application described in this subparagraph is that the State has denied such a licensing application and—(i) the standards or review process imposed by the State as a condition of approval of the license imposes any material requirements, procedures, or standards (other than solvency requirements) to such organizations that are not generally applicable to other entities engaged in a substantially similar business, or
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_25_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organized and licensed under State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Organized and licensed under State law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_25_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assumption of full financial risk</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assumption of full financial risk The Medicare+Choice organization shall assume full financial risk on a prospective basis for the provision of the health care services for which benefits are required to be provided under section 1395w–22(a)(1) of this title, except that the organization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_25_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of provision against risk of insolvency for unlicensed PSOs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certification of provision against risk of insolvency for unlicensed PSOs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395w_25_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Provider-sponsored organization” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Provider-sponsored organization” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>