<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395bbb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395bbb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395bbb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395bbb"><akn:num>1395bbb</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of participation for home health agencies; home health quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395bbb. Conditions of participation for home health agencies; home health quality(a) Conditions of participation; protection of individual rights; notification of State entities; use of home health aides; medical equipment; individual’s plan of care; compliance with Federal, State, and local laws and regulationsThe conditions of participation that a home health agency is required to meet under this subsection are as follows:(1) The agency protects and promotes the rights of each individual under its care, including each of the following rights:(A) The right to be fully informed in advance about the care and treatment to be provided by the agency, to be fully informed in advance of any changes in the care or treatment to be provided by the agency that may affect the individual’s well-being, and (except with respect to an individual adjudged incompetent) to participate in planning care and treatment or changes in care or treatment.

(B) The right to voice grievances with respect to treatment or care that is (or fails to be) furnished without discrimination or reprisal for voicing grievances.

(C) The right to confidentiality of the clinical records described in section 1395x(o)(3) of this title.

(D) The right to have one’s property treated with respect.

(E) The right to be fully informed orally and in writing (in advance of coming under the care of the agency) of—(i) all items and services furnished by (or under arrangements with) the agency for which payment may be made under this subchapter,

(ii) the coverage available for such items and services under this subchapter, subchapter XIX, and any other Federal program of which the agency is reasonably aware,

(iii) any charges for items and services not covered under this subchapter and any charges the individual may have to pay with respect to items and services furnished by (or under arrangements with) the agency, and

(iv) any changes in the charges or items and services described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of participation; protection of individual rights; notification of State entities; use of home health aides; medical equipment; individual’s plan of care; compliance with Federal, State, and local laws and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions of participation; protection of individual rights; notification of State entities; use of home health aides; medical equipment; individual’s plan of care; compliance with Federal, State, and local laws and regulations The conditions of participation that a home health agency is required to meet under this subsection are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duty of Secretary It is the duty and responsibility of the Secretary to assure that the conditions of participation and requirements specified in or pursuant to section 1395x(o) of this title and subsection (a) of this section and the enforcement of such conditions and requirements are adequate to protect the health and safety of individuals under the care of a home health agency and to promote the effective and efficient use of public moneys.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveys of home health agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Surveys of home health agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment process; reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assessment process; reports to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermediate sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Intermediate sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395bbb_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment on basis of location of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Payment on basis of location of service A home health agency shall submit claims for payment for home health services under this subchapter only on the basis of the geographic location at which the service is furnished, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>