<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395mm" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395mm/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395mm/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395mm"><akn:num>1395mm</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to health maintenance organizations and competitive medical plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395mm. Payments to health maintenance organizations and competitive medical plans(a) Rates and adjustments(1)(A) The Secretary shall annually determine, and shall announce (in a manner intended to provide notice to interested parties) not later than September 7 before the calendar year concerned—(i) a per capita rate of payment for each class of individuals who are enrolled under this section with an eligible organization which has entered into a risk-sharing contract and who are entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B, and

(ii) a per capita rate of payment for each class of individuals who are so enrolled with such an organization and who are enrolled under part B only.


For purposes of this section, the term “risk-sharing contract” means a contract entered into under subsection (g) and the term “reasonable cost reimbursement contract” means a contract entered into under subsection (h).

(B) The Secretary shall define appropriate classes of members, based on age, disability status, and such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, so as to ensure actuarial equivalence. The Secretary may add to, modify, or substitute for such classes, if such changes will improve the determination of actuarial equivalence.

(C) The annual per capita rate of payment for each such class shall be equal to 95 percent of the adjusted average per capita cost (as defined in paragraph (4)) for that class.

(D) In the case of an eligible organization with a risk-sharing contract, the Secretary shall make monthly payments in advance and in accordance with the rate determined under subparagraph (C) and except as provided in subsection (g)(2), to the organization for each individual enrolled with the organization under this section.

(E)(i) The amount of payment under this paragraph may be retroactively adjusted to take into account any difference between the actual number of individuals enrolled in the plan under this section and the number of such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rates and adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rates and adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions; requirements For purposes of this section, the term “eligible organization” means a public or private entity (which may be a health maintenance organization or a competitive medical plan), organized under the laws of any State, which— Paragraph (2)(A)(ii) shall not apply to an entity which had contracted with a single State agency administering a State plan approved under subchapter XIX for the provision of services (other than inpatient hospital services) to individuals eligible for such services under such State plan on a prepaid risk basis prior to 1970.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment in plan; duties of organization to enrollees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enrollment in plan; duties of organization to enrollees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right to enroll with contracting organization in geographic area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Right to enroll with contracting organization in geographic area Subject to the provisions of subsection (c)(3), every individual entitled to benefits under part A and enrolled under part B or enrolled under part B only (other than an individual medically determined to have end-stage renal disease) shall be eligible to enroll under this section with any eligible organization with which the Secretary has entered into a contract under this section and which serves the geographic area in which the individual resides.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on charges; election of coverage; “adjusted community rate” defined; workmen’s compensation and insurance benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on charges; election of coverage; “adjusted community rate” defined; workmen’s compensation and insurance benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Membership requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk-sharing contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Risk-sharing contract</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cost reimbursement contract; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reasonable cost reimbursement contract; requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration, termination, effective date, and terms of contract; powers and duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Duration, termination, effective date, and terms of contract; powers and duties of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395mm_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment in full and limitation on actual charges; physicians, providers of services, or renal dialysis facilities not under contract with organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Payment in full and limitation on actual charges; physicians, providers of services, or renal dialysis facilities not under contract with organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>