<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395p"><akn:num>1395p</akn:num><akn:heading>Enrollment periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395p. Enrollment periods(a) Generally; regulationsAn individual may enroll in the insurance program established by this part only in such manner and form as may be prescribed by regulations, and only during an enrollment period prescribed in or under this section.


(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 96–499, title IX, § 945(a), Dec. 5, 1980, 94 Stat. 2642

(c) Initial general enrollment period; eligible individuals before March 1, 1966In the case of individuals who first satisfy paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1395o(a) of this title before March 1, 1966, the initial general enrollment period shall begin on the first day of the second month which begins after July 30, 1965, and shall end on May 31, 1966. For purposes of this subsection and subsection (d), an individual who has attained age 65 and who satisfies paragraph (1) of section 1395o(a) of this title but not paragraph (2) of such section shall be treated as satisfying such paragraph (1) on the first day on which he is (or on filing application would have been) entitled to hospital insurance benefits under part A.


(d) Eligible individuals on or after March 1, 1966In the case of an individual who first satisfies paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1395o(a) of this title on or after March 1, 1966, his initial enrollment period shall begin on the first day of the third month before the month in which he first satisfies such paragraphs and shall end seven months later. Where the Secretary finds that an individual who has attained age 65 failed to enroll under this part during his initial enrollment period (based on a determination by the Secretary of the month in which such individual attained age 65), because such individual (relying on documentary evidence) was mistaken as to his correct date of birth, the Secretary shall establish for such individual an initial enrollment period based on his attaining age 65 at the time shown in such documentary evidence (with a coverage period determined under section 1395q of this title a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Generally; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Generally; regulations An individual may enroll in the insurance program established by this part only in such manner and form as may be prescribed by regulations, and only during an enrollment period prescribed in or under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 96–499, title IX, § 945(a), Dec. 5, 1980, 94 Stat. 2642</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial general enrollment period; eligible individuals before March 1, 1966</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initial general enrollment period; eligible individuals before In the case of individuals who first satisfy paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1395o(a) of this title before March 1, 1966, the initial general enrollment period shall begin on the first day of the second month which begins after July 30, 1965, and shall end on May 31, 1966. For purposes of this subsection and subsection (d), an individual who has attained age 65 and who satisfies paragraph (1) of section 1395o(a) of this title but not paragraph (2) of such section shall be treated as satisfying such paragraph (1) on the first day on which he is (or on filing application would have been) entitled to hospital insurance benefits under part A.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible individuals on or after March 1, 1966</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible individuals on or after In the case of an individual who first satisfies paragraph (1) or (2) of section 1395o(a) of this title on or after March 1, 1966, his initial enrollment period shall begin on the first day of the third month before the month in which he first satisfies such paragraphs and shall end seven months later. Where the Secretary finds that an individual who has attained age 65 failed to enroll under this part during his initial enrollment period (based on a determination by the Secretary of the month in which such individual attained age 65), because such individual (relying on documentary evidence) was mistaken as to his correct date of birth, the Secretary shall establish for such individual an initial enrollment period based on his attaining age 65 at the time shown in such documentary evidence (with a coverage period determined under section 1395q of this title as though he had attained such age at that time).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General enrollment period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General enrollment period There shall be a general enrollment period during the period beginning on January 1 and ending on March 31 of each year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individuals deemed enrolled in medical insurance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Individuals deemed enrolled in medical insurance program Any individual— shall be deemed to have enrolled in the medical insurance program established by this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of enrollment period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Commencement of enrollment period All of the provisions of this section shall apply to individuals satisfying subsection (f), except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of enrollment period requirements where individual’s rights were prejudiced by administrative error or inaction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Waiver of enrollment period requirements where individual’s rights were prejudiced by administrative error or inaction In any case where the Secretary finds that an individual’s enrollment or nonenrollment in the insurance program established by this part or part A pursuant to section 1395i–2 of this title is unintentional, inadvertent, or erroneous and is the result of the error, misrepresentation, or inaction of an officer, employee, or agent of the Federal Government, or its instrumentalities, the Secretary may take such action (including the designation for such individual of a special initial or subsequent enrollment period, with a coverage period determined on the basis thereof and with appropriate adjustments of premiums) as may be necessary to correct or eliminate the effects of such error, misrepresentation, or inaction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special enrollment periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special enrollment periods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395p_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for individuals with ALS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Special rules for individuals with ALS In applying this section in the case of an individual who is entitled to benefits under part A pursuant to the operation of section 426(h) of this title, the following special rules apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>