<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395yy" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395yy/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1395yy/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1395yy"><akn:num>1395yy</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment to skilled nursing facilities for routine service costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1395yy. Payment to skilled nursing facilities for routine service costs(a) Per diem limitationsThe Secretary, in determining the amount of the payments which may be made under this subchapter with respect to routine service costs of extended care services shall not recognize as reasonable (in the efficient delivery of health services) per diem costs of such services to the extent that such per diem costs exceed the following per diem limits, except as otherwise provided in this section:(1) With respect to freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas, the limit shall be equal to 112 percent of the mean per diem routine service costs for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas.

(2) With respect to freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas, the limit shall be equal to 112 percent of the mean per diem routine service costs for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas.

(3) With respect to hospital-based skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas, the limit shall be equal to the sum of the limit for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas, plus 50 percent of the amount by which 112 percent of the mean per diem routine service costs for hospital-based skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas exceeds the limit for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in urban areas.

(4) With respect to hospital-based skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas, the limit shall be equal to the sum of the limit for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas, plus 50 percent of the amount by which 112 percent of the mean per diem routine service costs for hospital-based skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas exceeds the limit for freestanding skilled nursing facilities located in rural areas.


In applying this subsection the Secretary shall make appropriate adjustments to the labor related portion of the costs based upo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per diem limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Per diem limitations The Secretary, in determining the amount of the payments which may be made under this subchapter with respect to routine service costs of extended care services shall not recognize as reasonable (in the efficient delivery of health services) per diem costs of such services to the extent that such per diem costs exceed the following per diem limits, except as otherwise provided in this section: In applying this subsection the Secretary shall make appropriate adjustments to the labor related portion of the costs based upon an appropriate wage index, and shall, for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1992, on or after October 1, 1995, and every 2 years thereafter, provide for an update to the per diem cost limits described in this subsection, except that the limits effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1997, shall be based on the limits effective for cost reporting periods beginning on or after October 1, 1996.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excess overhead allocations for hospital-based facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Excess overhead allocations for hospital-based facilities With respect to a hospital-based skilled nursing facility, the Secretary may not recognize as reasonable the portion of the cost differences between hospital-based and freestanding skilled nursing facilities attributable to excess overhead allocations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments in limitations; publication of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adjustments in limitations; publication of data The Secretary may make adjustments in the limits set forth in subsection (a) with respect to any skilled nursing facility to the extent the Secretary deems appropriate, based upon case mix or circumstances beyond the control of the facility. The Secretary shall publish the data and criteria to be used for purposes of this subsection on an annual basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to skilled nursing facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to skilled nursing facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prospective payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prospective payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting of direct care expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reporting of direct care expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Skilled nursing facility readmission measure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Skilled nursing facility readmission measure</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1395yy_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Skilled nursing facility value-based purchasing program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Skilled nursing facility value-based purchasing program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>