<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396u_8"><akn:num>1396u–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Health opportunity accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396u–8. Health opportunity accounts(a) Authority(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, the Secretary shall establish a demonstration program under which States may provide under their State plans under this subchapter (including such a plan operating under a statewide waiver under section 1315 of this title) in accordance with this section for the provision of alternative benefits consistent with subsection (c) for eligible population groups in one or more geographic areas of the State specified by the State. An amendment under the previous sentence is referred to in this section as a “State demonstration program”.


(2) Initial demonstration(A) In generalThe demonstration program under this section shall begin on January 1, 2007. During the first 5 years of such program, the Secretary shall not approve more than 10 States to conduct demonstration programs under this section, with each State demonstration program covering 1 or more geographic areas specified by the State. After such 5-year period—(i) unless the Secretary finds, taking into account cost-effectiveness, quality of care, and other criteria that the Secretary specifies, that a State demonstration program previously implemented has been unsuccessful, such a demonstration program may be extended or made permanent in the State; and

(ii) unless the Secretary finds, taking into account cost-effectiveness, quality of care, and other criteria that the Secretary specifies, that all State demonstration programs previously implemented were unsuccessful, other States may implement State demonstration programs.


(B) GAO report(i) In generalNot later than 3 months after the end of the 5-year period described in subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit a report to Congress evaluating the demonstration programs conducted under this section during such period.


(ii) AppropriationOut of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, there is a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible population groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible population groups</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative benefits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_8_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health opportunity account</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Health opportunity account</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>