<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396j"><akn:num>1396j</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Health Service facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396j. Indian Health Service facilities(a) Eligibility for reimbursement for medical assistanceA facility of the Indian Health Service (including a hospital, nursing facility, or any other type of facility which provides services of a type otherwise covered under the State plan), whether operated by such Service or by an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 1603 of title 25), shall be eligible for reimbursement for medical assistance provided under a State plan if and for so long as it meets all of the conditions and requirements which are applicable generally to such facilities under this subchapter.


(b) Facilities deemed to meet requirements upon submission of acceptable plan for achieving complianceNotwithstanding subsection (a), a facility of the Indian Health Service (including a hospital, nursing facility, or any other type of facility which provides services of a type otherwise covered under the State plan) which does not meet all of the conditions and requirements of this subchapter which are applicable generally to such facility, but which submits to the Secretary within six months after September 30, 1976, an acceptable plan for achieving compliance with such conditions and requirements, shall be deemed to meet such conditions and requirements (and to be eligible for reimbursement under this subchapter), without regard to the extent of its actual compliance with such conditions and requirements, during the first twelve months after the month in which such plan is submitted.


(c) Agreement to reimburse State agency for providing care and servicesThe Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements with the State agency for the purpose of reimbursing such agency for health care and services provided in Indian Health Service facilities to Indians who are eligible for medical assistance under the State plan.


(d) Cross referenceFor provisions relating to the authority of certain Indian tribes, tribal organizations, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for reimbursement for medical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Eligibility for reimbursement for medical assistance A facility of the Indian Health Service (including a hospital, nursing facility, or any other type of facility which provides services of a type otherwise covered under the State plan), whether operated by such Service or by an Indian tribe or tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 1603 of title 25), shall be eligible for reimbursement for medical assistance provided under a State plan if and for so long as it meets all of the conditions and requirements which are applicable generally to such facilities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities deemed to meet requirements upon submission of acceptable plan for achieving compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facilities deemed to meet requirements upon submission of acceptable plan for achieving compliance Notwithstanding subsection (a), a facility of the Indian Health Service (including a hospital, nursing facility, or any other type of facility which provides services of a type otherwise covered under the State plan) which does not meet all of the conditions and requirements of this subchapter which are applicable generally to such facility, but which submits to the Secretary within six months after September 30, 1976, an acceptable plan for achieving compliance with such conditions and requirements, shall be deemed to meet such conditions and requirements (and to be eligible for reimbursement under this subchapter), without regard to the extent of its actual compliance with such conditions and requirements, during the first twelve months after the month in which such plan is submitted.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement to reimburse State agency for providing care and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement to reimburse State agency for providing care and services The Secretary is authorized to enter into agreements with the State agency for the purpose of reimbursing such agency for health care and services provided in Indian Health Service facilities to Indians who are eligible for medical assistance under the State plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cross reference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cross reference For provisions relating to the authority of certain Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and Alaska Native health organizations to elect to directly bill for, and receive payment for, health care services provided by a hospital or clinic of such tribes or organizations and for which payment may be made under this subchapter, see section 1645 of title 25.11 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>