<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396u_4"><akn:num>1396u–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Program of all-inclusive care for elderly (PACE)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396u–4. Program of all-inclusive care for elderly (PACE)(a) State option(1) In generalA State may elect to provide medical assistance under this section with respect to PACE program services to PACE program eligible individuals who are eligible for medical assistance under the State plan and who are enrolled in a PACE program under a PACE program agreement. Such individuals need not be eligible for benefits under part A, or enrolled under part B, of subchapter XVIII to be eligible to enroll under this section. In the case of an individual enrolled with a PACE program pursuant to such an election—(A) the individual shall receive benefits under the plan solely through such program, and

(B) the PACE provider shall receive payment in accordance with the PACE program agreement for provision of such benefits.


A State may establish a numerical limit on the number of individuals who may be enrolled in a PACE program under a PACE program agreement.

(2) “PACE program” definedFor purposes of this section, the term “PACE program” means a program of all-inclusive care for the elderly that meets the following requirements:(A) OperationThe entity operating the program is a PACE provider (as defined in paragraph (3)).


(B) Comprehensive benefitsThe program provides comprehensive health care services to PACE program eligible individuals in accordance with the PACE program agreement and regulations under this section.


(C) TransitionIn the case of an individual who is enrolled under the program under this section and whose enrollment ceases for any reason (including that the individual no longer qualifies as a PACE program eligible individual, the termination of a PACE program agreement, or otherwise), the program provides assistance to the individual in obtaining necessary transitional care through appropriate referrals and making the individual’s medical records available to new providers.



(3) “PACE provider” defined(A) In generalFor purposes of this section, the term “</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State option</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State option</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of benefits; beneficiary safeguards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of benefits; beneficiary safeguards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to PACE providers on a capitated basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payments to PACE providers on a capitated basis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>PACE program agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) PACE program agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Waivers of requirements With respect to carrying out a PACE program under this section, the following requirements of this subchapter (and regulations relating to such requirements) shall not apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration project for for-profit entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Demonstration project for for-profit entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Post-eligibility treatment of income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Post-eligibility treatment of income A State may provide for post-eligibility treatment of income for individuals enrolled in PACE programs under this section in the same manner as a State treats post-eligibility income for individuals receiving services under a waiver under section 1396n(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_4_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Miscellaneous provisions Nothing in this section or section 1395eee of this title shall be construed as preventing a PACE provider from entering into contracts with other governmental or nongovernmental payers for the care of PACE program eligible individuals who are not eligible for benefits under part A, or enrolled under part B, of subchapter XVIII or eligible for medical assistance under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>