<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396r"><akn:num>1396r</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for nursing facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396r. Requirements for nursing facilities(a) “Nursing facility” definedIn this subchapter, the term “nursing facility” means an institution (or a distinct part of an institution) which—(1) is primarily engaged in providing to residents—(A) skilled nursing care and related services for residents who require medical or nursing care,

(B) rehabilitation services for the rehabilitation of injured, disabled, or sick persons, or

(C) on a regular basis, health-related care and services to individuals who because of their mental or physical condition require care and services (above the level of room and board) which can be made available to them only through institutional facilities,


and is not primarily for the care and treatment of mental diseases;

(2) has in effect a transfer agreement (meeting the requirements of section 1395x(l) of this title) with one or more hospitals having agreements in effect under section 1395cc of this title; and

(3) meets the requirements for a nursing facility described in subsections (b), (c), and (d) of this section.


Such term also includes any facility which is located in a State on an Indian reservation and is certified by the Secretary as meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) and subsections (b), (c), and (d).

(b) Requirements relating to provision of services(1) Quality of life(A) In generalA nursing facility must care for its residents in such a manner and in such an environment as will promote maintenance or enhancement of the quality of life of each resident.


(B) Quality assessment and assuranceA nursing facility must maintain a quality assessment and assurance committee, consisting of the director of nursing services, a physician designated by the facility, and at least 3 other members of the facility’s staff, which (i) meets at least quarterly to identify issues with respect to which quality assessment and assurance activities are necessary and (ii) develops and implements appropriate plans of action to correct ide</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Nursing facility” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Nursing facility” defined In this subchapter, the term “nursing facility” means an institution (or a distinct part of an institution) which— Such term also includes any facility which is located in a State on an Indian reservation and is certified by the Secretary as meeting the requirements of paragraph (1) and subsections (b), (c), and (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements relating to provision of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements relating to provision of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements relating to residents’ rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements relating to residents’ rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements relating to administration and other matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements relating to administration and other matters</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State requirements relating to nursing facility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State requirements relating to nursing facility requirements As a condition of approval of its plan under this subchapter, a State must provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Secretary relating to nursing facility requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Responsibilities of Secretary relating to nursing facility requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Survey and certification process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Survey and certification process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Enforcement process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nursing Home Compare website</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Nursing Home Compare website</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Construction Where requirements or obligations under this section are identical to those provided under section 1395i–3 of this title, the fulfillment of those requirements or obligations under section 1395i–3 of this title shall be considered to be the fulfillment of the corresponding requirements or obligations under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>