<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396r_1a"><akn:num>1396r–1a</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumptive eligibility for children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396r–1a. Presumptive eligibility for children(a) In generalA State plan approved under section 1396a of this title may provide for making medical assistance with respect to health care items and services covered under the State plan available to a child during a presumptive eligibility period.


(b) Definitions; regulationsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “child” means an individual under 19 years of age.

(2) The term “presumptive eligibility period” means, with respect to a child, the period that—(A) begins with the date on which a qualified entity determines, on the basis of preliminary information, that the family income of the child does not exceed the applicable income level of eligibility under the State plan, and

(B) ends with (and includes) the earlier of—(i) the day on which a determination is made with respect to the eligibility of the child for medical assistance under the State plan, or

(ii) in the case of a child on whose behalf an application is not filed by the last day of the month following the month during which the entity makes the determination referred to in subparagraph (A), such last day.



(3)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the term “qualified entity” means any entity that—(i)(I) is eligible for payments under a State plan approved under this subchapter and provides items and services described in subsection (a), (II) is authorized to determine eligibility of a child to participate in a Head Start program under the Head Start Act (42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.), eligibility of a child to receive child care services for which financial assistance is provided under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990 [42 U.S.C. 9857 et seq.], eligibility of an infant or child to receive assistance under the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC) under section 1786 of this title 11 So in original. A comma probably should appear after “title”. eligibility of a child for medical assistance under t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State plan approved under section 1396a of this title may provide for making medical assistance with respect to health care items and services covered under the State plan available to a child during a presumptive eligibility period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions; regulations For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for medical assistance; procedure upon determination of presumptive eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application for medical assistance; procedure upon determination of presumptive eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of medical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of medical assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, medical assistance for items and services described in subsection (a) that— shall be treated as medical assistance provided by such plan for purposes of section 1396b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>