<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396r_2"><akn:num>1396r–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Information concerning sanctions taken by State licensing authorities against health care practition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396r–2. Information concerning sanctions taken by State licensing authorities against health care practitioners and providers(a) Information reporting requirementThe requirement referred to in section 1396a(a)(49) of this title is that the State must provide for the following:(1) Information reporting system(A) Licensing or certification actionsThe State must have in effect a system of reporting the following information with respect to formal proceedings (as defined by the Secretary in regulations) concluded against a health care practitioner or entity by a State licensing or certification agency:(i) Any adverse action taken by such licensing authority as a result of the proceeding, including any revocation or suspension of a license (and the length of any such suspension), reprimand, censure, or probation.

(ii) Any dismissal or closure of the proceedings by reason of the practitioner or entity surrendering the license or leaving the State or jurisdiction.

(iii) Any other loss of license or the right to apply for, or renew, a license by the practitioner or entity, whether by operation of law, voluntary surrender, nonrenewability, or otherwise.

(iv) Any negative action or finding by such authority, organization, or entity regarding the practitioner or entity.


(B) Other final adverse actionsThe State must have in effect a system of reporting information with respect to any final adverse action (not including settlements in which no findings of liability have been made) taken against a health care provider, supplier, or practitioner by a State law or fraud enforcement agency.



(2) Access to documentsThe State must provide the Secretary (or an entity designated by the Secretary) with access to such documents of a State licensing or certification agency or State law or fraud enforcement agency as may be necessary for the Secretary to determine the facts and circumstances concerning the actions and determinations described in such paragraph for the purpose of c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information reporting requirement The requirement referred to in section 1396a(a)(49) of this title is that the State must provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form of information The information described in subsection (a)(1) shall be provided to the Secretary (or to an appropriate private or public agency, under suitable arrangements made by the Secretary with respect to receipt, storage, protection of confidentiality, and dissemination of information) in such a form and manner as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in order to provide for activities of the Secretary under this chapter and in order to provide, directly or through suitable arrangements made by the Secretary, information— in order for such authorities to determine the fitness of individuals to provide health care services, to protect the health and safety of individuals receiving health care through such programs, and to protect the fiscal integrity of such programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information provided</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Confidentiality of information provided The Secretary shall provide for suitable safeguards for the confidentiality of the information furnished under subsection (a). Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the disclosure of such information by a party which is otherwise authorized, under applicable State law, to make such disclosure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure and correction of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure and correction of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Fees for disclosure The Secretary may establish or approve reasonable fees for the disclosure of information under this section. The amount of such a fee may not exceed the costs of processing the requests for disclosure and of providing such information. Such fees shall be available to the Secretary to cover such costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection from liability for reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protection from liability for reporting No person or entity, including any agency designated by the Secretary in subsection (b), shall be held liable in any civil action with respect to any reporting of information as required under this section, without knowledge of the falsity of the information contained in the report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>References</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) References For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appropriate coordination In implementing this section, the Secretary shall provide for the maximum appropriate coordination with part B of the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 (42 U.S.C. 11131 et seq.) and section 1320a–7e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>