<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396r–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396r_1"><akn:num>1396r–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Presumptive eligibility for pregnant women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396r–1. Presumptive eligibility for pregnant women(a) Ambulatory prenatal careA State plan approved under section 1396a of this title may provide for making ambulatory prenatal care available to a pregnant woman during a presumptive eligibility period.


(b) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “presumptive eligibility period” means, with respect to a pregnant woman, the period that—(A) begins with the date on which a qualified provider determines, on the basis of preliminary information, that the family income of the woman does not exceed the applicable income level of eligibility under the State plan, and

(B) ends with (and includes) the earlier of—(i) the day on which a determination is made with respect to the eligibility of the woman for medical assistance under the State plan, or

(ii) in the case of a woman who does not file an application by the last day of the month following the month during which the provider makes the determination referred to in subparagraph (A), such last day; and



(2) the term “qualified provider” means any provider that—(A) is eligible for payments under a State plan approved under this subchapter,

(B) provides services of the type described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1396d(a)(2) of this title or in section 1396d(a)(9) of this title,

(C) is determined by the State agency to be capable of making determinations of the type described in paragraph (1)(A), and

(D)(i) receives funds under—(I) section 254b or 254c of this title,

(II) subchapter V of this chapter, or

(III) title V of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act [25 U.S.C. 1651 et seq.];


(ii) participates in a program established under—(I) section 1786 of this title, or

(II) section 4(a) of the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973;


(iii) participates in a State perinatal program; or

(iv) is the Indian Health Service or is a health program or facility operated by a tribe or tribal organization under the Indian Self-Determination</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ambulatory prenatal care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Ambulatory prenatal care A State plan approved under section 1396a of this title may provide for making ambulatory prenatal care available to a pregnant woman during a presumptive eligibility period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions For purposes of this section— The term “qualified provider” also includes a qualified entity, as defined in section 1396r–1a(b)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of State agency, qualified providers, and presumptively eligible pregnant women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties of State agency, qualified providers, and presumptively eligible pregnant women</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ambulatory prenatal care as medical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ambulatory prenatal care as medical assistance Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, ambulatory prenatal care that— shall be treated as medical assistance provided by such plan for purposes of section 1396b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396r_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Option to provide presumptive eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Option to provide presumptive eligibility If the State has elected the option to provide a presumptive eligibility period under this section or section 1396r–1a of this title, the State may elect to provide a presumptive eligibility period (as defined in subsection (b)(1)) for individuals who are eligible for medical assistance under clause (i)(VIII), clause (i)(IX), or clause (ii)(XX) of subsection (a)(10)(A) 11 So in original. Probably means subsection (a)(10)(A) of section 1396a of this title. or section 1396u–1 of this title in the same manner as the State provides for such a period under this section or section 1396r–1a of this title, subject to such guidance as the Secretary shall establish.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>