<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396h"><akn:num>1396h</akn:num><akn:heading>State false claims act requirements for increased State share of recoveries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396h. State false claims act requirements for increased State share of recoveries(a) In generalNotwithstanding section 1396d(b) of this title, if a State has in effect a law relating to false or fraudulent claims that meets the requirements of subsection (b), the Federal medical assistance percentage with respect to any amounts recovered under a State action brought under such law, shall be decreased by 10 percentage points.


(b) RequirementsFor purposes of subsection (a), the requirements of this subsection are that the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines that the State has in effect a law that meets the following requirements:(1) The law establishes liability to the State for false or fraudulent claims described in section 3729 of title 31 with respect to any expenditure described in section 1396b(a) of this title.

(2) The law contains provisions that are at least as effective in rewarding and facilitating qui tam actions for false or fraudulent claims as those described in sections 3730 through 3732 of title 31.

(3) The law contains a requirement for filing an action under seal for 60 days with review by the State Attorney General.

(4) The law contains a civil penalty that is not less than the amount of the civil penalty authorized under section 3729 of title 31.


(c) Deemed complianceA State that, as of January 1, 2007, has a law in effect that meets the requirements of subsection (b) shall be deemed to be in compliance with such requirements for so long as the law continues to meet such requirements.


(d) No preclusion of broader lawsNothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting a State that has in effect a law that establishes liability to the State for false or fraudulent claims described in section 3729 of title 31, with respect to programs in addition to the State program under this subchapter, or with respect to expenditures in addition to expenditures </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding section 1396d(b) of this title, if a State has in effect a law relating to false or fraudulent claims that meets the requirements of subsection (b), the Federal medical assistance percentage with respect to any amounts recovered under a State action brought under such law, shall be decreased by 10 percentage points.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements For purposes of subsection (a), the requirements of this subsection are that the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Attorney General, determines that the State has in effect a law that meets the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deemed compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Deemed compliance A State that, as of January 1, 2007, has a law in effect that meets the requirements of subsection (b) shall be deemed to be in compliance with such requirements for so long as the law continues to meet such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No preclusion of broader laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No preclusion of broader laws Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting a State that has in effect a law that establishes liability to the State for false or fraudulent claims described in section 3729 of title 31, with respect to programs in addition to the State program under this subchapter, or with respect to expenditures in addition to expenditures described in section 1396b(a) of this title, from being considered to be in compliance with the requirements of subsection (a) so long as the law meets such requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>