<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1396u–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1396u_1"><akn:num>1396u–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Assuring coverage for certain low-income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1396u–1. Assuring coverage for certain low-income families(a) References to subchapter IV–A are references to pre-welfare-reform provisionsSubject to the succeeding provisions of this section, with respect to a State any reference in this subchapter (or any other provision of law in relation to the operation of this subchapter) to a provision of part A of subchapter IV, or a State plan under such part (or a provision of such a plan), including income and resource standards and income and resource methodologies under such part or plan, shall be considered a reference to such a provision or plan as in effect as of July 16, 1996, with respect to the State.


(b) Application of pre-welfare-reform eligibility criteria(1) In generalFor purposes of this subchapter, subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), in determining eligibility for medical assistance—(A) an individual shall be treated as receiving aid or assistance under a State plan approved under part A of subchapter IV only if the individual meets—(i) the income and resource standards for determining eligibility under such plan, and

(ii) the eligibility requirements of such plan under subsections (a) through (c) of section 606 of this title and section 607(a) of this title,


as in effect as of July 16, 1996; and

(B) the income and resource methodologies under such plan as of such date shall be used in the determination of whether any individual meets income and resource standards under such plan.


(2) State optionFor purposes of applying this section, a State—(A) may lower its income standards applicable with respect to part A of subchapter IV, but not below the income standards applicable under its State plan under such part on May 1, 1988;

(B) may increase income or resource standards under the State plan referred to in paragraph (1) over a period (beginning after July 16, 1996) by a percentage that does not exceed the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumers (all items; United Stat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>References to subchapter IV–A are references to pre-welfare-reform provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) References to subchapter IV–A are references to pre-welfare-reform provisions Subject to the succeeding provisions of this section, with respect to a State any reference in this subchapter (or any other provision of law in relation to the operation of this subchapter) to a provision of part A of subchapter IV, or a State plan under such part (or a provision of such a plan), including income and resource standards and income and resource methodologies under such part or plan, shall be considered a reference to such a provision or plan as in effect as of July 16, 1996, with respect to the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of pre-welfare-reform eligibility criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of pre-welfare-reform eligibility criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment for purposes of transitional coverage provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment for purposes of transitional coverage provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waivers In the case of a waiver of a provision of part A of subchapter IV in effect with respect to a State as of July 16, 1996, or which is submitted to the Secretary before August 22, 1996, and approved by the Secretary on or before July 1, 1997, if the waiver affects eligibility of individuals for medical assistance under this subchapter, such waiver may (but need not) continue to be applied, at the option of the State, in relation to this subchapter after the date the waiver would otherwise expire.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State option to use 1 application form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State option to use 1 application form Nothing in this section, or part A of subchapter IV, shall be construed as preventing a State from providing for the same application form for assistance under a State program funded under part A of subchapter IV (on or after the welfare reform effective date) and for medical assistance under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional rules of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional rules of construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relation to other provisions The provisions of this section shall apply notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional increased Federal matching rate for increased administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transitional increased Federal matching rate for increased administrative costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1396u_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Welfare reform effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Welfare reform effective date In this section, the term “welfare reform effective date” means the effective date, with respect to a State, of title I of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (as specified in section 116 of such Act).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>