<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397k–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397k–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397k–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397k_1"><akn:num>1397k–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397k–1. Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation(a) EstablishmentThere is established a board to be known as the “Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation” (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Board”) to create short- and long-term multidisciplinary strategic plans for the development of the field of elder justice and to make recommendations to the Elder Justice Coordinating Council established under section 1397k of this title.


(b) CompositionThe Advisory Board shall be composed of 27 members appointed by the Secretary from among members of the general public who are individuals with experience and expertise in elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation prevention, detection, treatment, intervention, or prosecution.


(c) Solicitation of nominationsThe Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for the appointment of members of the Advisory Board under subsection (b).


(d) Terms(1) In generalEach member of the Advisory Board shall be appointed for a term of 3 years, except that, of the members first appointed—(A) 9 shall be appointed for a term of 3 years;

(B) 9 shall be appointed for a term of 2 years; and

(C) 9 shall be appointed for a term of 1 year.


(2) Vacancies(A) In generalAny vacancy on the Advisory Board shall not affect its powers, but shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.


(B) Filling unexpired termAn individual chosen to fill a vacancy shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the member replaced.



(3) Expiration of termsThe term of any member shall not expire before the date on which the member’s successor takes office.



(e) Election of officersThe Advisory Board shall elect a Chair and Vice Chair from among its members. The Advisory Board shall elect its initial Chair and Vice Chair at its initial meeting.


(f) Duties(1) Enhance communication on promoting quality of, and preventing abuse, neglect, and exploitation in, long-te</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a board to be known as the “Advisory Board on Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation” (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Board”) to create short- and long-term multidisciplinary strategic plans for the development of the field of elder justice and to make recommendations to the Elder Justice Coordinating Council established under section 1397k of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition The Advisory Board shall be composed of 27 members appointed by the Secretary from among members of the general public who are individuals with experience and expertise in elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation prevention, detection, treatment, intervention, or prosecution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of nominations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Solicitation of nominations The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for the appointment of members of the Advisory Board under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election of officers The Advisory Board shall elect a Chair and Vice Chair from among its members. The Advisory Board shall elect its initial Chair and Vice Chair at its initial meeting.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of the Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Powers of the Advisory Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Travel expenses The members of the Advisory Board shall not receive compensation for the performance of services for the Advisory Board. The members shall be allowed travel expenses for up to 4 meetings per year, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Advisory Board. Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, the Secretary may accept the voluntary and uncompensated services of the members of the Advisory Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of Government employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Detail of Government employees Any Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Advisory Board without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397k_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status as permanent advisory committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Status as permanent advisory committee Section 1013 of title 5 shall not apply to the advisory board.11 So in original. Probably should be “Advisory Board”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>