<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397a"><akn:num>1397a</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397a. Payments to States(a) Amount; covered services(1) Each State shall be entitled to payment under this division for each fiscal year in an amount equal to its allotment for such fiscal year, to be used by such State for services directed at the goals set forth in section 1397 of this title, subject to the requirements of this division.

(2) For purposes of paragraph (1)—(A) services which are directed at the goals set forth in section 1397 of this title include, but are not limited to, child care services, protective services for children and adults, services for children and adults in foster care, services related to the management and maintenance of the home, day care services for adults, transportation services, family planning services, training and related services, employment services, information, referral, and counseling services, the preparation and delivery of meals, health support services and appropriate combinations of services designed to meet the special needs of children, the aged, the mentally retarded, the blind, the emotionally disturbed, the physically handicapped, and alcoholics and drug addicts; and

(B) expenditures for such services may include expenditures for—(i) administration (including planning and evaluation);

(ii) personnel training and retraining directly related to the provision of those services (including both short- and long-term training at educational institutions through grants to such institutions or by direct financial assistance to students enrolled in such institutions); and

(iii) conferences or workshops, and training or retraining through grants to nonprofit organizations within the meaning of section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or to individuals with social services expertise, or through financial assistance to individuals participating in such conferences, workshops, and training or retraining (and this clause shall apply with respect to all persons involved in the delivery of such services).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount; covered services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount; covered services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Funding requirements The Secretary shall make payments in accordance with section 6503 of title 31 to each State from its allotment for use under this division.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expenditure of funds Payments to a State from its allotment for any fiscal year must be expended by the State in such fiscal year or in the succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfers of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfers of funds A State may transfer up to 10 percent of its allotment under section 1397b of this title for any fiscal year for its use for that year under other provisions of Federal law providing block grants for support of health services, health promotion and disease prevention activities, or low-income home energy assistance (or any combination of those activities). Amounts allotted to a State under any provisions of Federal law referred to in the preceding sentence and transferred by a State for use in carrying out the purposes of this division shall be treated as if they were paid to the State under this division but shall not affect the computation of the State’s allotment under this division. The State shall inform the Secretary of any such transfer of funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of portion of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of portion of funds A State may use a portion of the amounts described in subsection (a) for the purpose of purchasing technical assistance from public or private entities if the State determines that such assistance is required in developing, implementing, or administering programs funded under this division.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to use vouchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority to use vouchers A State may use funds provided under this division to provide vouchers, for services directed at the goals set forth in section 1397 of this title, to families, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>