<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397m"><akn:num>1397m</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancement of long-term care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397m. Enhancement of long-term care(a) Grants and incentives for long-term care staffing(1) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out activities, including activities described in paragraphs (2) and (3), to provide incentives for individuals to train for, seek, and maintain employment providing direct care in long-term care.


(2) Specific programs to enhance training, recruitment, and retention of staff(A) Coordination with Secretary of Labor to recruit and train long-term care staffThe Secretary shall coordinate activities under this subsection with the Secretary of Labor in order to provide incentives for individuals to train for and seek employment providing direct care in long-term care.


(B) Career ladders and wage or benefit increases to increase staffing in long-term care(i) In generalThe Secretary shall make grants to eligible entities to carry out programs through which the entities—(I) offer, to employees who provide direct care to residents of an eligible entity or individuals receiving community-based long-term care from an eligible entity, continuing training and varying levels of certification, based on observed clinical care practices and the amount of time the employees spend providing direct care; and

(II) provide, or make arrangements to provide, bonuses or other increased compensation or benefits to employees who achieve certification under such a program.


(ii) ApplicationTo be eligible to receive a grant under this subparagraph, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require (which may include evidence of consultation with the State in which the eligible entity is located with respect to carrying out activities funded under the grant).


(iii) Authority to limit number of applicantsNothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as prohibiting the Secretary from limiting the number of applicants for a grant under this subparagraph.


</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and incentives for long-term care staffing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants and incentives for long-term care staffing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified EHR technology grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certified EHR technology grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adoption of standards for transactions involving clinical data by long-term care facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Adoption of standards for transactions involving clinical data by long-term care facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>