<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397n–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397n–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397n–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397n_2"><akn:num>1397n–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Awarding social impact partnership agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397n–2. Awarding social impact partnership agreements(a) Timeline in awarding agreementNot later than 6 months after receiving an application in accordance with section 1397n–1 of this title, the Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships, shall determine whether to enter into an agreement for a social impact partnership project with a State or local government.


(b) Considerations in awarding agreementIn determining whether to enter into an agreement for a social impact partnership project (the application for which was submitted under section 1397n–1 of this title) the Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships and the head of any Federal agency administering a similar intervention or serving a population similar to that served by the project, shall consider each of the following:(1) The recommendations made by the Commission on Social Impact Partnerships.

(2) The value to the Federal Government of the outcomes expected to be achieved if the outcomes specified in the agreement are achieved as a result of the intervention.

(3) The likelihood, based on evidence provided in the application and other evidence, that the State or local government in collaboration with the intermediary and the service providers will achieve the outcomes.

(4) The savings to the Federal Government if the outcomes specified in the agreement are achieved as a result of the intervention.

(5) The savings to the State and local governments if the outcomes specified in the agreement are achieved as a result of the intervention.

(6) The expected quality of the evaluation that would be conducted with respect to the agreement.

(7) The capacity and commitment of the State or local government to sustain the intervention, if appropriate and timely and if the intervention is successful, beyond the period of the social impact partnership.


(c) Agreement authority(1) Agreement requirementsIn a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timeline in awarding agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Timeline in awarding agreement Not later than 6 months after receiving an application in accordance with section 1397n–1 of this title, the Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships, shall determine whether to enter into an agreement for a social impact partnership project with a State or local government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in awarding agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Considerations in awarding agreement In determining whether to enter into an agreement for a social impact partnership project (the application for which was submitted under section 1397n–1 of this title) the Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Interagency Council on Social Impact Partnerships and the head of any Federal agency administering a similar intervention or serving a population similar to that served by the project, shall consider each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of Agreement Award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Notice of Agreement Award Not later than 30 days after entering into an agreement under this section the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that includes, with regard to the agreement, the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to transfer administration of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority to transfer administration of agreement The Secretary may transfer to the head of another Federal agency the authority to administer (including making payments under) an agreement entered into under subsection (c), and any funds necessary to do so.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397n_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement on funding used to benefit children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirement on funding used to benefit children Not less than 50 percent of all Federal payments made to carry out agreements under this section shall be used for initiatives that directly benefit children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>