<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397ee"><akn:num>1397ee</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397ee. Payments to States(a) Payments(1) In generalSubject to the succeeding provisions of this section, the Secretary shall pay to each State with a plan approved under this subchapter, from its allotment under section 1397dd of this title, an amount for each quarter equal to the enhanced FMAP (or, in the case of expenditures described in subparagraph (D)(iv), the higher of 75 percent or the sum of the enhanced FMAP plus 5 percentage points) of expenditures in the quarter—(A) for child health assistance under the plan for targeted low-income children in the form of providing medical assistance for which payment is made on the basis of an enhanced FMAP under the fourth sentence of section 1396d(b) of this title;

(B)
 [reserved]

(C) for child health assistance under the plan for targeted low-income children in the form of providing health benefits coverage that meets the requirements of section 1397cc of this title; and

(D) only to the extent permitted consistent with subsection (c)—(i) for payment for other child health assistance for targeted low-income children;

(ii) for expenditures for health services initiatives under the plan for improving the health of children (including targeted low-income children and other low-income children);

(iii) for expenditures for outreach activities as provided in section 1397bb(c)(1) of this title under the plan;

(iv) for translation or interpretation services in connection with the enrollment of, retention of, and use of services under this subchapter by, individuals for whom English is not their primary language (as found necessary by the Secretary for the proper and efficient administration of the State plan); and

(v) for other reasonable costs incurred by the State to administer the plan.



(2) Order of paymentsPayments under paragraph (1) from a State’s allotment shall be made in the following order:(A) First, for expenditures for items described in paragraph (1)(A).

(B) Second, for expenditures for items describ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced FMAP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enhanced FMAP For purposes of subsection (a), the “enhanced FMAP”, for a State for a fiscal year, is equal to the Federal medical assistance percentage (as defined in the first sentence of section 1396d(b) of this title) for the State increased by a number of percentage points equal to 30 percent of the number of percentage points by which (1) such Federal medical assistance percentage for the State, is less than (2) 100 percent; but in no case shall the enhanced FMAP for a State exceed 85 percent. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, during the period that begins on October 1, 2015, and ends on September 30, 2019, the enhanced FMAP determined for a State for a fiscal year (or for any portion of a fiscal year occurring during such period) shall be increased by 23 percentage points, and during the period that begins on October 1, 2019, and ends on September 30, 2020, the enhanced FMAP determined for a State for a fiscal year (or for any portion of a fiscal year occurring during s</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on certain payments for certain expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on certain payments for certain expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maintenance of effort</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance payment; retrospective adjustment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advance payment; retrospective adjustment The Secretary may make payments under this section for each quarter on the basis of advance estimates of expenditures submitted by the State and such other investigation as the Secretary may find necessary, and may reduce or increase the payments as necessary to adjust for any overpayment or underpayment for prior quarters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibility in submittal of claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Flexibility in submittal of claims Nothing in this section or subsections (e) and (f) of section 1397dd of this title shall be construed as preventing a State from claiming as expenditures in the quarter expenditures that were incurred in a previous quarter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for qualifying States to use certain funds for medicaid expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authority for qualifying States to use certain funds for medicaid expenditures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ee_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural health transformation program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rural health transformation program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>