<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ii" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ii/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397ii/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397ii"><akn:num>1397ii</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397ii. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Relation to other laws(1) HIPAAHealth benefits coverage provided under section 1397aa(a)(1) of this title (and coverage provided under a waiver under section 1397ee(c)(2)(B) of this title) shall be treated as creditable coverage for purposes of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 [29 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.], title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.], and subtitle K of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.


(2) ERISANothing in this subchapter shall be construed as affecting or modifying section 514 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (29 U.S.C. 1144) with respect to a group health plan (as defined in section 2791(a)(1) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(a)(1))).



(b) Adjustment to Current Population Survey to include State-by-State data relating to children without health insurance coverage(1) In generalThe Secretary of Commerce shall make appropriate adjustments to the annual Current Population Survey conducted by the Bureau of the Census in order to produce statistically reliable annual State data on the number of low-income children who do not have health insurance coverage, so that real changes in the uninsurance rates of children can reasonably be detected. The Current Population Survey should produce data under this subsection that categorizes such children by family income, age, and race or ethnicity. The adjustments made to produce such data shall include, where appropriate, expanding the sample size used in the State sampling units, expanding the number of sampling units in a State, and an appropriate verification element.


(2) Additional requirementsIn addition to making the adjustments required to produce the data described in paragraph (1), with respect to data collection occurring for fiscal years beginning with fiscal year 2009, in appropriate consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ii_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Relation to other laws</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397ii_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment to Current Population Survey to include State-by-State data relating to children without health insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjustment to Current Population Survey to include State-by-State data relating to children without health insurance coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>