<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397hh" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397hh/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397hh/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397hh"><akn:num>1397hh</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports; evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397hh. Annual reports; evaluations(a) Annual reportSubject to subsection (e), the State shall—(1) assess the operation of the State plan under this subchapter in each fiscal year, including the progress made in reducing the number of uncovered low-income children; and

(2) report to the Secretary, by January 1 following the end of the fiscal year, on the result of the assessment.


(b) State evaluations(1) In generalBy March 31, 2000, each State that has a State child health plan shall submit to the Secretary an evaluation that includes each of the following:(A) An assessment of the effectiveness of the State plan in increasing the number of children with creditable health coverage.

(B) A description and analysis of the effectiveness of elements of the State plan, including—(i) the characteristics of the children and families assisted under the State plan including age of the children, family income, and the assisted child’s access to or coverage by other health insurance prior to the State plan and after eligibility for the State plan ends,

(ii) the quality of health coverage provided including the types of benefits provided,

(iii) the amount and level (including payment of part or all of any premium) of assistance provided by the State,

(iv) the service area of the State plan,

(v) the time limits for coverage of a child under the State plan,

(vi) the State’s choice of health benefits coverage and other methods used for providing child health assistance, and

(vii) the sources of non-Federal funding used in the State plan.


(C) An assessment of the effectiveness of other public and private programs in the State in increasing the availability of affordable quality individual and family health insurance for children.

(D) A review and assessment of State activities to coordinate the plan under this subchapter with other public and private programs providing health care and health care financing, including medicaid and maternal and child health services.

(E</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual report Subject to subsection (e), the State shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to records for IG and GAO audits and evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to records for IG and GAO audits and evaluations For the purpose of evaluating and auditing the program established under this subchapter, or subchapter XIX, the Secretary, the Office of Inspector General, and the Comptroller General shall have access to any books, accounts, records, correspondence, and other documents that are related to the expenditure of Federal funds under this subchapter and that are in the possession, custody, or control of States receiving Federal funds under this subchapter or political subdivisions thereof, or any grantee or contractor of such States or political subdivisions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two subsecs. (e) have been enacted. Information required for inclusion in State annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The State shall include the following information in the annual report required under subsection (a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397hh_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 Information on dental care for children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>