<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397jj" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397jj/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1397jj/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1397jj"><akn:num>1397jj</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1397jj. Definitions(a) Child health assistanceFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “child health assistance” means payment for part or all of the cost of health benefits coverage for targeted low-income children that includes any of the following (and includes, in the case described in section 1397ee(a)(1)(D)(i) of this title, payment for part or all of the cost of providing any of the following), as specified under the State plan:(1) Inpatient hospital services.

(2) Outpatient hospital services.

(3) Physician services.

(4) Surgical services.

(5) Clinic services (including health center services) and other ambulatory health care services.

(6) Prescription drugs and biologicals and the administration of such drugs and biologicals, only if such drugs and biologicals are not furnished for the purpose of causing, or assisting in causing, the death, suicide, euthanasia, or mercy killing of a person.

(7) Over-the-counter medications.

(8) Laboratory and radiological services.

(9) Prenatal care and prepregnancy family planning services and supplies.

(10) Inpatient mental health services, other than services described in paragraph (18) but including services furnished in a State-operated mental hospital and including residential or other 24-hour therapeutically planned structured services.

(11) Outpatient mental health services, other than services described in paragraph (19) but including services furnished in a State-operated mental hospital and including community-based services.

(12) Durable medical equipment and other medically-related or remedial devices (such as prosthetic devices, implants, eyeglasses, hearing aids, dental devices, and adaptive devices).

(13) Disposable medical supplies.

(14) Home and community-based health care services and related supportive services (such as home health nursing services, home health aide services, personal care, assistance with activities of daily living, chore services, day care services, respite care services</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397jj_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child health assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Child health assistance For purposes of this subchapter, the term “child health assistance” means payment for part or all of the cost of health benefits coverage for targeted low-income children that includes any of the following (and includes, in the case described in section 1397ee(a)(1)(D)(i) of this title, payment for part or all of the cost of providing any of the following), as specified under the State plan:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397jj_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Targeted low-income child” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Targeted low-income child” defined For purposes of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1397jj_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional definitions For purposes of this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>