<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14302"><akn:num>14302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14302. Definitions
For purposes of this chapter:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(2) Button cellThe term “button cell” means a button- or coin-shaped battery.


(3) Easily removableThe term “easily removable”, with respect to a battery, means detachable or removable at the end of the life of the battery—(A) from a consumer product by a consumer with the use of common household tools; or

(B) by a retailer of replacements for a battery used as the principal electrical power source for a vehicle.


(4) Mercuric-oxide batteryThe term “mercuric-oxide battery” means a battery that uses a mercuric-oxide electrode.


(5) Rechargeable batteryThe term “rechargeable battery”—(A) means 1 or more voltaic or galvanic cells, electrically connected to produce electric energy, that is designed to be recharged for repeated uses; and

(B) includes any type of enclosed device or sealed container consisting of 1 or more such cells, including what is commonly called a battery pack (and in the case of a battery pack, for the purposes of the requirements of easy removability and labeling under section 14322 of this title, means the battery pack as a whole rather than each component individually); but

(C) does not include—(i) a lead-acid battery used to start an internal combustion engine or as the principal electrical power source for a vehicle, such as an automobile, a truck, construction equipment, a motorcycle, a garden tractor, a golf cart, a wheelchair, or a boat;

(ii) a lead-acid battery used for load leveling or for storage of electricity generated by an alternative energy source, such as a solar cell or wind-driven generator;

(iii) a battery used as a backup power source for memory or program instruction storage, timekeeping, or any similar purpose that requires uninterrupted electrical power in order to function if the primary energy supply fails or fluctuates momentarily; or

(iv) a rechargeable alka</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Button cell</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Button cell The term “button cell” means a button- or coin-shaped battery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Easily removable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Easily removable The term “easily removable”, with respect to a battery, means detachable or removable at the end of the life of the battery—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mercuric-oxide battery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Mercuric-oxide battery The term “mercuric-oxide battery” means a battery that uses a mercuric-oxide electrode.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rechargeable battery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Rechargeable battery The term “rechargeable battery”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rechargeable consumer product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Rechargeable consumer product The term “rechargeable consumer product”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulated battery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Regulated battery The term “regulated battery” means a rechargeable battery that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remanufactured product</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Remanufactured product The term “remanufactured product” means a rechargeable consumer product that has been altered by the replacement of parts, repackaged, or repaired after initial sale by the original manufacturer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>