<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437s"><akn:num>1437s</akn:num><akn:heading>Public housing homeownership and management opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437s. Public housing homeownership and management opportunities(a) Homeownership opportunities in generalLow-income families residing in a public housing project shall be provided with the opportunity to purchase the dwelling units in the project through a qualifying resident management corporation as follows:(1) Formation of resident management corporationAs a condition for public housing homeownership—(A) the adult residents of a public housing project shall have formed a resident management corporation in accordance with regulations and requirements of the Secretary prescribed under this section and section 1437r of this title;

(B) the resident management corporation shall have entered into a contract with the public housing agency establishing the respective management rights and responsibilities of the resident management corporation and the public housing agency; and

(C) the resident management corporation shall have demonstrated its ability to manage public housing effectively and efficiently for a period of not less than 3 years.


(2) Homeownership assistance(A) The Secretary may provide assistance from the Capital Fund to a public housing project in which homeownership activities under this section are conducted.

(B) The Secretary may provide financial assistance to public housing agencies, resident management corporations, or resident councils that obtain, by contract or otherwise, training, technical assistance, and educational assistance as the Secretary determines to be necessary to promote homeownership opportunities under this section.

(C) This paragraph shall not have effect after February 4, 1991. The Secretary may not provide financial assistance under subparagraph (B), after such date, unless the Secretary determines that such assistance is necessary for the development of a homeownership program that was initiated, as determined by the Secretary, before November 28, 1990.


(3) Conditions of purchase by a resident management corporation(A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Homeownership opportunities in general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Homeownership opportunities in general Low-income families residing in a public housing project shall be provided with the opportunity to purchase the dwelling units in the project through a qualifying resident management corporation as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of nonpurchasing families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Protection of nonpurchasing families</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance for public housing agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial assistance for public housing agencies The Secretary shall provide to public housing agencies such financial assistance as is necessary to permit such agencies to carry out the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional homeownership and management opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional homeownership and management opportunities This section shall not apply to the turnkey III, the mutual help, or any other homeownership program established under section 1437d(c)(4)(D) of this title, as in effect before the effective date under section 503(a) of the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, and in existence before February 5, 1988.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Secretary shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this section. Such regulations may establish any additional terms and conditions for homeownership or resident management under this section that are determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–66, title I, § 1071(a), Dec. 21, 1995, 109 Stat. 720</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437s_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation Any authority of the Secretary under this section to provide financial assistance, or to enter into contracts to provide financial assistance, shall be effective only to such extent or in such amounts as are or have been provided in advance in an appropriation Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>