<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437k"><akn:num>1437k</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortia, joint ventures, affiliates, and subsidiaries of public housing agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437k. Consortia, joint ventures, affiliates, and subsidiaries of public housing agencies(a) Consortia(1) In generalAny 2 or more public housing agencies may participate in a consortium for the purpose of administering any or all of the housing programs of those public housing agencies in accordance with this section.


(2) EffectWith respect to any consortium described in paragraph (1)—(A) any assistance made available under this subchapter to each of the public housing agencies participating in the consortium shall be paid to the consortium; and

(B) all planning and reporting requirements imposed upon each public housing agency participating in the consortium with respect to the programs operated by the consortium shall be consolidated.


(3) Restrictions(A) AgreementEach consortium described in paragraph (1) shall be formed and operated in accordance with a consortium agreement, and shall be subject to the requirements of a joint public housing agency plan, which shall be submitted by the consortium in accordance with section 1437c–1 of this title.


(B) Minimum requirementsThe Secretary shall specify minimum requirements relating to the formation and operation of consortia and the minimum contents of consortium agreements under this paragraph.




(b) Joint ventures(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a public housing agency, in accordance with the public housing agency plan, may—(A) form and operate wholly owned or controlled subsidiaries (which may be nonprofit corporations) and other affiliates, any of which may be directed, managed, or controlled by the same persons who constitute the board of directors or similar governing body of the public housing agency, or who serve as employees or staff of the public housing agency; or

(B) enter into joint ventures, partnerships, or other business arrangements with, or contract with, any person, organization, entity, or governmental unit—(i) with respect to the administration of the programs of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consortia</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint ventures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Joint ventures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>