<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437t"><akn:num>1437t</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to convert public housing to vouchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437t. Authority to convert public housing to vouchers(a) AuthorityA public housing agency may convert any public housing project (or portion thereof) owned by the public housing agency to tenant-based assistance, but only in accordance with the requirements of this section.


(b) Conversion assessment(1) In generalTo convert public housing under this section, a public housing agency shall conduct an assessment of the public housing that includes—(A) a cost analysis that demonstrates whether or not the cost (both on a net present value basis and in terms of new budget authority requirements) of providing tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of this title for the same families in substantially similar dwellings over the same period of time is less expensive than continuing public housing assistance in the public housing project for the remaining useful life of the project;

(B) an analysis of the market value of the public housing project both before and after rehabilitation, and before and after conversion;

(C) an analysis of the rental market conditions with respect to the likely success of the use of tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of this title in that market for the specific residents of the public housing project, including an assessment of the availability of decent and safe dwellings renting at or below the payment standard established for tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of this title by the agency;

(D) the impact of the conversion to tenant-based assistance under this section on the neighborhood in which the public housing project is located; and

(E) a plan that identifies actions, if any, that the public housing agency would take with regard to converting any public housing project or projects (or portions thereof) of the public housing agency to tenant-based assistance.


(2) TimingNot later than 2 years after the effective date under section 503(a) of the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, each public </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority A public housing agency may convert any public housing project (or portion thereof) owned by the public housing agency to tenant-based assistance, but only in accordance with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conversion assessment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for implementation of conversion plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for implementation of conversion plan A public housing agency may convert a public housing project (or portion thereof) owned by the agency to tenant-based assistance only pursuant to a conversion assessment under subsection (b) that one year 11 So in original. and that demonstrates that the conversion—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion plan requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conversion plan requirement A public housing project may be converted under this section to tenant-based assistance only as provided in a conversion plan under this subsection, which has not been disapproved by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (e). Each conversion plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and approval of conversion plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review and approval of conversion plans The Secretary shall disapprove a conversion plan only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant-based assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Tenant-based assistance To the extent approved by the Secretary, the funds used by the public housing agency to provide tenant-based assistance under section 1437f of this title shall be added to the annual contribution contract administered by the public housing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>