<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437v"><akn:num>1437v</akn:num><akn:heading>Demolition, site revitalization, replacement housing, and tenant-based assistance grants for project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437v. Demolition, site revitalization, replacement housing, and tenant-based assistance grants for projects(a) PurposesThe purpose of this section is to provide assistance to public housing agencies for the purposes of—(1) improving the living environment for public housing residents of severely distressed public housing projects through the demolition, rehabilitation, reconfiguration, or replacement of obsolete public housing projects (or portions thereof);

(2) revitalizing sites (including remaining public housing dwelling units) on which such public housing projects are located and contributing to the improvement of the surrounding neighborhood;

(3) providing housing that will avoid or decrease the concentration of very low-income families; and

(4) building sustainable communities.


It is also the purpose of this section to provide assistance to smaller communities for the purpose of facilitating the development of affordable housing for low-income families that is undertaken in connection with a main street revitalization or redevelopment project in such communities.

(b) Grant authorityThe Secretary may make grants as provided in this section to applicants whose applications for such grants are approved by the Secretary under this section.


(c) Contribution requirement(1) In generalThe Secretary may not make any grant under this section to any applicant unless the applicant certifies to the Secretary that the applicant will—(A) supplement the aggregate amount of assistance provided under this section with an amount of funds from sources other than this section equal to not less than 5 percent of the amount provided under this section; and

(B) in addition to supplemental amounts provided in accordance with subparagraph (A), if the applicant uses more than 5 percent of the amount of assistance provided under this section for services under subsection (d)(1)(L), provide supplemental funds from sources other than this section in an amount equal to the amou</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purpose of this section is to provide assistance to public housing agencies for the purposes of— It is also the purpose of this section to provide assistance to smaller communities for the purpose of facilitating the development of affordable housing for low-income families that is undertaken in connection with a main street revitalization or redevelopment project in such communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant authority The Secretary may make grants as provided in this section to applicants whose applications for such grants are approved by the Secretary under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contribution requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contribution requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application and selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application and selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cost limits Subject to the provisions of this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition and replacement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Disposition and replacement Any severely distressed public housing disposed of pursuant to a revitalization plan and any public housing developed in lieu of such severely distressed housing, shall be subject to the provisions of section 1437p of this title. Severely distressed public housing demolished pursuant to a revitalization plan shall not be subject to the provisions of section 1437p of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration by other entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Administration by other entities The Secretary may require a grantee under this section to make arrangements satisfactory to the Secretary for use of an entity other than the public housing agency to carry out activities assisted under the revitalization plan, if the Secretary determines that such action will help to effectuate the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Withdrawal of funding If a grantee under this section does not proceed within a reasonable timeframe, in the determination of the Secretary, the Secretary shall withdraw any grant amounts under this section that have not been obligated by the public housing agency. The Secretary shall redistribute any withdrawn amounts to one or more other applicants eligible for assistance under this section or to one or more other entities capable of proceeding expeditiously in the same locality in carrying out the revitalization plan of the original grantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437v_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>