<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437bbb_1"><akn:num>1437bbb–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexible grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437bbb–1. Flexible grant program(a) Authority and useThe Secretary shall carry out a demonstration program in accordance with the purposes under section 1437bbb of this title and the provisions of this subchapter. A jurisdiction approved by the Secretary for participation in the program may receive and combine and enter into performance-based contracts for the use of amounts of covered housing assistance, in the manner determined appropriate by the participating jurisdiction, during the period of the jurisdiction’s participation—(1) to provide housing assistance and services for low-income families in a manner that facilitates the transition of such families to work;

(2) to reduce homelessness through providing permanent housing solutions;

(3) to increase homeownership among low-income families; or

(4) for other housing purposes for low-income families determined by the participating jurisdiction.


(b) Period of participationA jurisdiction may participate in the demonstration program under this subchapter for a period consisting of not less than 1 nor more than 5 fiscal years.


(c) Participating jurisdictions(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), during the 4-year period consisting of fiscal years 1999 through 2002, the Secretary may approve for participation in the program under this subchapter not more than an aggregate of 100 jurisdictions over the entire term of the demonstration program. A jurisdiction that was approved for participation in the demonstration program under this subchapter in a fiscal year and that is continuing such participation in any subsequent fiscal year shall count as a single jurisdiction for purposes of the numerical limitation under this paragraph.


(2) Exclusion of high performing agenciesNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter other than paragraph (4) of this subsection, the Secretary may approve for participation in the demonstration program under this subchapter only jurisdictions served by public housing ag</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority and use The Secretary shall carry out a demonstration program in accordance with the purposes under section 1437bbb of this title and the provisions of this subchapter. A jurisdiction approved by the Secretary for participation in the program may receive and combine and enter into performance-based contracts for the use of amounts of covered housing assistance, in the manner determined appropriate by the participating jurisdiction, during the period of the jurisdiction’s participation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Period of participation A jurisdiction may participate in the demonstration program under this subchapter for a period consisting of not less than 1 nor more than 5 fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating jurisdictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participating jurisdictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>