<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437d"><akn:num>1437d</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract provisions and requirements; loans and annual contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437d. Contract provisions and requirements; loans and annual contributions(a) Conditions; elevatorsThe Secretary may include in any contract for loans, contributions, sale, lease, mortgage, or any other agreement or instrument made pursuant to this chapter, such covenants, conditions, or provisions as he may deem necessary in order to insure the lower income character of the project involved, in a manner consistent with the public housing agency plan. Any such contract shall require that, except in the case of housing predominantly for elderly or disabled families, high-rise elevator projects shall not be provided for families with children unless the Secretary makes a determination that there is no practical alternative.


(b) Limitation on development costs(1) Each contract for loans (other than preliminary loans) or contributions for the development, acquisition, or operation of public housing shall provide that the total development cost of the project on which the computation of any annual contributions under this chapter may be based may not exceed the amount determined under paragraph (2) (for the appropriate structure type) unless the Secretary provides otherwise, and in any case may not exceed 110 per centum of such amount unless the Secretary for good cause determines otherwise.

(2) For purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall determine the total development cost by multiplying the construction cost guideline for the project (which shall be determined by averaging the current construction costs, as listed by not less than 2 nationally recognized residential construction cost indices, for publicly bid construction of a good and sound quality) by—(A) in the case of elevator type structures, 1.6; and

(B) in the case of nonelevator type structures, 1.75.


(3) In calculating the total development cost of a project under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall consider only capital assistance provided by the Secretary to a public housing agency that are 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions; elevators</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions; elevators The Secretary may include in any contract for loans, contributions, sale, lease, mortgage, or any other agreement or instrument made pursuant to this chapter, such covenants, conditions, or provisions as he may deem necessary in order to insure the lower income character of the project involved, in a manner consistent with the public housing agency plan. Any such contract shall require that, except in the case of housing predominantly for elderly or disabled families, high-rise elevator projects shall not be provided for families with children unless the Secretary makes a determination that there is no practical alternative.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on development costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on development costs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of maximum income limits; certification of compliance with requirements; notification of eligibility; informal hearing; compliance with procedures for sound management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revision of maximum income limits; certification of compliance with requirements; notification of eligibility; informal hearing; compliance with procedures for sound management Every contract for contributions shall provide that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption from personal and real property taxes; payments in lieu of taxes; cash contribution or tax remission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption from personal and real property taxes; payments in lieu of taxes; cash contribution or tax remission Every contract for contributions with respect to a low-income housing project shall provide that no contributions by the Secretary shall be made available for such project unless such project (exclusive of any portion thereof which is not assisted by contributions under this chapter) is exempt from all real and personal property taxes levied or imposed by the State, city, county, or other political subdivision; and such contract shall require the public housing agency to make payments in lieu of taxes equal to 10 per centum of the sum of the shelter rents charged in such project, or such lesser amount as (i) is prescribed by State law, or (ii) is agreed to by the local governing body in its agreement for local cooperation with the public housing agency required under section 1437c(e)(2) of this title, or (iii) is due to failure of a local public body or bodies other than t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 529(2), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2569</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing quality requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Housing quality requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial default; conveyance of title and delivery of possession; reconveyance and redelivery; payments for outstanding obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Substantial default; conveyance of title and delivery of possession; reconveyance and redelivery; payments for outstanding obligations Every contract for contributions (including contracts which amend or supersede contracts previously made) may provide that— Whenever such a contract for annual contributions includes provisions which the Secretary in such contract determines are in accordance with this subsection, and the portion of the annual contribution payable for debt service requirements pursuant to such contract has been pledged by the public housing agency as security for the payment of the principal and interest on any of its obligations, the Secretary (notwithstanding any other provisions of this chapter) shall continue to make such annual contributions available for the project so long as any of such obligations remain outstanding, and may covenant in such contract that in any event such annual contributions shall in each year be at least equal to an amount which, togethe</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>New construction contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) New construction contracts On or after October 1, 1983, the Secretary may enter into a contract involving new construction only if the public housing agency demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the cost of new construction in the neighborhood where the public housing agency determines the housing is needed is less than the cost of acquisition or acquisition and rehabilitation in such neighborhood, including any reserve fund under subsection (i), would be.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve fund; major repairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reserve fund; major repairs The Secretary may, upon application by a public housing agency in connection with the acquisition of housing for use as public housing, establish and set aside a reserve fund in an amount not to exceed 30 per centum of the acquisition cost which shall be available for use for major repairs to such housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance indicators for public housing agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Performance indicators for public housing agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>