<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437bbb–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437bbb_5"><akn:num>1437bbb–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437bbb–5. Application(a) In generalThe Secretary shall provide for jurisdictions to submit applications for approval to participate in the demonstration program under this subchapter. An application—(1) shall be submitted only after the jurisdiction provides for citizen participation through a public hearing and, if appropriate, other means;

(2) shall include a plan for the provision of housing assistance with amounts received pursuant to this subchapter that—(A) is developed by the jurisdiction;

(B) takes into consideration comments from the public hearing, any other public comments on the proposed program, and comments from current and prospective residents who would be affected; and

(C) identifies each term or condition for which the jurisdiction is requesting waiver under section 1437bbb–3(a)(1) of this title;


(3) shall describe how the plan for use of amounts will assist in meeting the purposes of, and be used in accordance with, sections 1437bbb and 1437bbb–1(a) of this title, respectively;

(4) shall propose standards for measuring performance in using assistance provided pursuant to this subchapter based on the performance standards under subsection (b)(4);

(5) shall propose the length of the period for participation of the jurisdiction is 11 So in original. in the demonstration program under this subchapter;

(6) shall—(A) in the case of the application of any jurisdiction within whose boundaries are areas subject to any other unit of general local government, include the signed consent of the appropriate executive official of such unit to the application; and

(B) in the case of the application of a consortia of units of general local government (as provided under section 1437bbb–8(1)(B) of this title), include the signed consent of the appropriate executive officials of each unit included in the consortia;


(7) shall include information sufficient, in the determination of the Secretary—(A) to demonstrate that the jurisdiction has or will have ma</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall provide for jurisdictions to submit applications for approval to participate in the demonstration program under this subchapter. An application— A plan required under paragraph (2) to be included in the application may be contained in a memorandum of agreement or other document executed by a jurisdiction and public housing agency, if such document is submitted together with the application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review, approval, and performance standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Review, approval, and performance standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status of PHAs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Status of PHAs This subchapter may not be construed to require any change in the legal status of any public housing agency or in any legal relationship between a jurisdiction and a public housing agency as a condition of participation in the program under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437bbb_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>PHA plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) PHA plans In carrying out this subchapter, the Secretary may provide for a streamlined public housing agency plan and planning process under section 1437c–1 of this title for participating jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>