<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437z_4"><akn:num>1437z–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Resident homeownership programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437z–4. Resident homeownership programs(a) In generalA public housing agency may carry out a homeownership program in accordance with this section and the public housing agency plan of the agency to make public housing dwelling units, public housing projects, and other housing projects available for purchase by low-income families for use only as principal residences for such families. An agency may transfer a unit pursuant to a homeownership program only if the program is authorized under this section and approved by the Secretary.


(b) Participating unitsA program under this section may cover any existing public housing dwelling units or projects, and may include other dwelling units and housing owned, assisted, or operated, or otherwise acquired for use under such program, by the public housing agency.


(c) Eligible purchasers(1) Low-income requirementOnly low-income families assisted by a public housing agency, other low-income families, and entities formed to facilitate such sales by purchasing units for resale to low-income families shall be eligible to purchase housing under a homeownership program under this section.


(2) Other requirementsA public housing agency may establish other requirements or limitations for families to purchase housing under a homeownership program under this section, including requirements or limitations regarding employment or participation in employment counseling or training activities, criminal activity, participation in homeownership counseling programs, evidence of regular income, and other requirements. In the case of purchase by an entity for resale to low-income families, the entity shall sell the units to low-income families within 5 years from the date of its acquisition of the units. The entity shall use any net proceeds from the resale and from managing the units, as determined in accordance with guidelines of the Secretary, for housing purposes, such as funding resident organizations and reserves for capital repla</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A public housing agency may carry out a homeownership program in accordance with this section and the public housing agency plan of the agency to make public housing dwelling units, public housing projects, and other housing projects available for purchase by low-income families for use only as principal residences for such families. An agency may transfer a unit pursuant to a homeownership program only if the program is authorized under this section and approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating units</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Participating units A program under this section may cover any existing public housing dwelling units or projects, and may include other dwelling units and housing owned, assisted, or operated, or otherwise acquired for use under such program, by the public housing agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible purchasers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible purchasers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of first refusal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Right of first refusal In making any sale under this section, the public housing agency shall initially offer the public housing unit at issue to the resident or residents occupying that unit, if any, or to an organization serving as a conduit for sales to any such resident.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of nonpurchasing residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Protection of nonpurchasing residents If a public housing resident does not exercise the right of first refusal under subsection (d) with respect to the public housing unit in which the resident resides, the public housing agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financing and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Financing and assistance A homeownership program under this section may provide financing for acquisition of housing by families purchasing under the program, or for acquisition of housing by the public housing agency for sale under the program, in any manner considered appropriate by the agency (including sale to a resident management corporation).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Downpayment requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Downpayment requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ownership interests</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Ownership interests A homeownership program under this section may provide for sale to the purchasing family of any ownership interest that the public housing agency considers appropriate under the program, including ownership in fee simple, a condominium interest, an interest in a limited dividend cooperative, a shared appreciation interest with a public housing agency providing financing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Resale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_4_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Net proceeds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Net proceeds The net proceeds of any sales under a homeownership program under this section remaining after payment of all costs of the sale shall be used for purposes relating to low-income housing and in accordance with the public housing agency plan of the agency carrying out the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>