<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437aaa–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437aaa–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437aaa–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437aaa_2"><akn:num>1437aaa–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437aaa–2. Implementation grants(a) GrantsThe Secretary is authorized to make implementation grants to applicants for the purpose of carrying out homeownership programs approved under this subchapter.


(b) Eligible activitiesImplementation grants may be used for activities to carry out homeownership programs (including programs for cooperative ownership) that meet the requirements under this subchapter, including the following activities:(1) Architectural and engineering work.

(2) Implementation of the homeownership program, including acquisition of the public housing project from a public housing agency for the purpose of transferring ownership to eligible families in accordance with a homeownership program that meets the requirements under this subchapter.

(3) Rehabilitation of any public housing project covered by the homeownership program, in accordance with standards established by the Secretary.

(4) Abatement of lead-based paint hazards, as required by section 4822(a) of this title.

(5) Administrative costs of the applicant, which may not exceed 15 percent of the amount of assistance provided under this section.

(6) Development of resident management corporations and resident management councils, but only if the applicant has not received assistance under section 1437aaa–1 of this title for such activities.

(7) Counseling and training of homebuyers and homeowners under the homeownership program.

(8) Relocation of tenants who elect to move.

(9) Any necessary temporary relocation of tenants during rehabilitation.

(10) Funding of operating expenses and replacement reserves of the project covered by the homeownership program, except that the amount of assistance for operating expenses shall not exceed the amount the project would have received if it had continued to receive such assistance from the Operating Fund, with adjustments comparable to those that would have been made under section 1437g of this title, and except that implementation grants may </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants The Secretary is authorized to make implementation grants to applicants for the purpose of carrying out homeownership programs approved under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible activities Implementation grants may be used for activities to carry out homeownership programs (including programs for cooperative ownership) that meet the requirements under this subchapter, including the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Matching funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Selection criteria The Secretary shall establish selection criteria for a national competition for assistance under this section, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location within participating jurisdictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Location within participating jurisdictions The Secretary may approve applications for grants under this subchapter only for public housing projects located within the boundaries of jurisdictions—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437aaa_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Approval The Secretary shall notify each applicant, not later than 6 months after the date of the submission of the application, whether the application is approved or not approved. The Secretary may approve the application for an implementation grant with a statement that the application for the section 8 [42 U.S.C. 1437f] assistance for replacement housing and for residents of the project not purchasing units is conditionally approved, subject to the availability of appropriations in subsequent fiscal years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>