<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437z_6"><akn:num>1437z–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Services for public and Indian housing residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437z–6. Services for public and Indian housing residents(a) In generalTo the extent that amounts are provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary may make grants to public housing agencies on behalf of public housing residents, recipients under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.] (notwithstanding section 502 of such Act [25 U.S.C. 4181]) on behalf of residents of housing assisted under such Act, or directly to resident management corporations, resident councils, or resident organizations (including nonprofit entities supported by residents), for the purposes of providing a program of supportive services and resident empowerment activities to provide supportive services to public housing residents and residents of housing assisted under such Act or assist such residents in becoming economically self-sufficient.


(b) Eligible activitiesGrantees under this section may use such amounts only for activities on or near the property of the public housing agency or public housing project or the property of a recipient under such Act or housing assisted under such Act that are designed to promote the self-sufficiency of public housing residents or residents of housing assisted under such Act or provide supportive services for such residents, including activities relating to—(1) physical improvements to a public housing project or residents of housing assisted under such Act in order to provide space for supportive services for residents;

(2) the provision of service coordinators or a congregate housing services program for elderly individuals, elderly disabled individuals, nonelderly disabled individuals, or temporarily disabled individuals;

(3) the provision of services related to work readiness, including education, job training and counseling, job search skills, business development training and planning, tutoring, mentoring, adult literacy, computer access, personal and family counseling, he</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To the extent that amounts are provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary may make grants to public housing agencies on behalf of public housing residents, recipients under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 [25 U.S.C. 4101 et seq.] (notwithstanding section 502 of such Act [25 U.S.C. 4181]) on behalf of residents of housing assisted under such Act, or directly to resident management corporations, resident councils, or resident organizations (including nonprofit entities supported by residents), for the purposes of providing a program of supportive services and resident empowerment activities to provide supportive services to public housing residents and residents of housing assisted under such Act or assist such residents in becoming economically self-sufficient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible activities Grantees under this section may use such amounts only for activities on or near the property of the public housing agency or public housing project or the property of a recipient under such Act or housing assisted under such Act that are designed to promote the self-sufficiency of public housing residents or residents of housing assisted under such Act or provide supportive services for such residents, including activities relating to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching requirement The Secretary may not make any grant under this section to any applicant unless the applicant supplements amounts made available under this section with funds from sources other than this section in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the grant amount. Such supplemental amounts may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for resident organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding for resident organizations To the extent that there are a sufficient number of qualified applications for assistance under this section, not less than 25 percent of any amounts appropriated to carry out this section shall be provided directly to resident councils, resident organizations, and resident management corporations. In any case in which a resident council, resident organization, or resident management corporation lacks adequate expertise, the Secretary may require the council, organization, or corporation to utilize other qualified organizations as contract administrators with respect to financial assistance provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>