<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437g"><akn:num>1437g</akn:num><akn:heading>Public housing Capital and Operating Funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437g. Public housing Capital and Operating Funds(a) Merger into Capital FundExcept as otherwise provided in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, any assistance made available for public housing under section 1437l of this title before October 1, 1999, shall be merged into the Capital Fund established under subsection (d).


(b) Merger into Operating FundExcept as otherwise provided in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, any assistance made available for public housing under this section before October 1, 1999, shall be merged into the Operating Fund established under subsection (e).


(c) Allocation amount(1) In generalFor fiscal year 2000 and each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary shall allocate amounts in the Capital Fund and Operating Funds 11 So in original. Probably should be “Fund”. for assistance for public housing agencies eligible for such assistance. The Secretary shall determine the amount of the allocation for each eligible agency, which shall be, for any fiscal year beginning after the effective date of the formulas described in subsections (d)(2) and (e)(2)—(A) for assistance from the Capital Fund, the amount determined for the agency under the formula under subsection (d)(2); and

(B) for assistance from the Operating Fund, the amount determined for the agency under the formula under subsection (e)(2).


(2) FundingThere are authorized to be appropriated for assistance for public housing agencies under this section the following amounts:(A) Capital FundFor allocations of assistance from the Capital Fund, $3,000,000,000 for fiscal year 1999, and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2000, 2001, 2002, and 2003.


(B) Operating FundFor allocations of assistance from the Operating Fund, $2,900,000,000 for fiscal year 1999, and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2000, 2001, 2002, and 2003.




(d) Capital Fund(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a Capital Fund for the purpo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merger into Capital Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Merger into Capital Fund Except as otherwise provided in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, any assistance made available for public housing under section 1437l of this title before October 1, 1999, shall be merged into the Capital Fund established under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Merger into Operating Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Merger into Operating Fund Except as otherwise provided in the Quality Housing and Work Responsibility Act of 1998, any assistance made available for public housing under this section before October 1, 1999, shall be merged into the Operating Fund established under subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capital Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Capital Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operating Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Operating Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Negotiated rulemaking procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Negotiated rulemaking procedure The formulas under subsections (d)(2) and (e)(2) shall be developed according to procedures for issuance of regulations under the negotiated rulemaking procedure under subchapter III of chapter 5 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitations on use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance To the extent amounts are provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary may make grants or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements in accordance with this subsection for purposes of providing, either directly or indirectly— As used in this subsection, the terms “training” and “technical assistance” shall include training or technical assistance and the cost of necessary travel for participants in such training or technical assistance, by or to officials and employees of the Department and of public housing agencies, and to residents and to other eligible grantees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of units acquired from proceeds of sales under demolition or disposition plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Eligibility of units acquired from proceeds of sales under demolition or disposition plan If a public housing agency uses proceeds from the sale of units under a homeownership program in accordance with section 1437z–4 of this title to acquire additional units to be sold to low-income families, the additional units shall be counted as public housing for purposes of determining the amount of the allocation to the agency under this section until sale by the agency, but in no case longer than 5 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437g_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for slow expenditure of capital funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Penalty for slow expenditure of capital funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>