<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437f"><akn:num>1437f</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437f. Low-income housing assistance(a) Authorization for assistance paymentsFor the purpose of aiding low-income families in obtaining a decent place to live and of promoting economically mixed housing, assistance payments may be made with respect to existing housing in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(b) Other existing housing programs(1) In general.—The Secretary is authorized to enter into annual contributions contracts with public housing agencies pursuant to which such agencies may enter into contracts to make assistance payments to owners of existing dwelling units in accordance with this section. In areas where no public housing agency has been organized or where the Secretary determines that a public housing agency is unable to implement the provisions of this section, the Secretary is authorized to enter into such contracts and to perform the other functions assigned to a public housing agency by this section.

(2) The Secretary is authorized to enter into annual contributions contracts with public housing agencies for the purpose of replacing public housing transferred in accordance with subchapter II–A of this chapter. Each contract entered into under this subsection shall be for a term of not more than 60 months.


(c) Contents and purposes of contracts for assistance payments; amount and scope of monthly assistance payments(1)(A) An assistance contract entered into pursuant to this section shall establish the maximum monthly rent (including utilities and all maintenance and management charges) which the owner is entitled to receive for each dwelling unit with respect to which such assistance payments are to be made. The maximum monthly rent shall not exceed by more than 10 per centum the fair market rental established by the Secretary periodically but not less than annually for existing or newly constructed rental dwelling units of various sizes and types in the market area suitable for occupancy by persons assisted under this secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization for assistance payments For the purpose of aiding low-income families in obtaining a decent place to live and of promoting economically mixed housing, assistance payments may be made with respect to existing housing in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other existing housing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other existing housing programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents and purposes of contracts for assistance payments; amount and scope of monthly assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents and purposes of contracts for assistance payments; amount and scope of monthly assistance payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required provisions and duration of contracts for assistance payments; waiver of limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Required provisions and duration of contracts for assistance payments; waiver of limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on contracts for assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restrictions on contracts for assistance payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations applicable for implementation of assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations applicable for implementation of assistance payments Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, assistance payments under this section may be provided, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the Secretary, with respect to some or all of the units in any project approved pursuant to section 1701q of title 12.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonapplicability of inconsistent provisions to contracts for assistance payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Nonapplicability of inconsistent provisions to contracts for assistance payments Sections 1437c(e) and 1437d of this title (except as provided in section 1437d(j)(3) of this title), and any other provisions of this chapter which are inconsistent with the provisions of this section shall not apply to contracts for assistance entered into under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Receipt of assistance by public housing agency under other law not to be considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Receipt of assistance by public housing agency under other law not to be considered The Secretary may not consider the receipt by a public housing agency of assistance under section 811(b)(1) of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act [42 U.S.C. 8013(b)(1)], or the amount received, in approving assistance for the agency under this section or determining the amount of such assistance to be provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437f_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbon monoxide alarms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Carbon monoxide alarms Each owner of a dwelling unit receiving project-based assistance under this section shall ensure that carbon monoxide alarms or detectors are installed in the dwelling unit in a manner that meets or exceeds—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>