<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437u"><akn:num>1437u</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Self-Sufficiency program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437u. Family Self-Sufficiency program(a) PurposeThe purpose of the Family Self-Sufficiency program established under this section is to promote the development of local strategies to coordinate use of assistance under sections 1437f and 1437g of this title with public and private resources, to enable eligible families to achieve economic independence and self-sufficiency.


(b) Continuation of prior required programs(1) In generalEach public housing agency that was required to administer a local Family Self-Sufficiency program on May 24, 2018, shall operate such local program for, at a minimum, the number of families the agency was required to serve on May 24, 2018, subject only to the availability under appropriations Acts of sufficient amounts for housing assistance and the requirements of paragraph (2).


(2) ReductionThe number of families for which a public housing agency is required to operate such local program under paragraph (1) shall be decreased by 1 for each family from any supported rental housing program administered by such agency that, after October 21, 1998, fulfills its obligations under the contract of participation.


(3) ExceptionThe Secretary shall not require a public housing agency to carry out a mandatory program for a period of time upon the request of the public housing agency and upon a determination by the Secretary that implementation is not feasible because of local circumstances, which may include—(A) lack of supportive services accessible to eligible families, which shall include insufficient availability of resources for programs under title I of the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (29 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.);

(B) lack of funding for reasonable administrative costs;

(C) lack of cooperation by other units of State or local government; or

(D) any other circumstances that the Secretary may consider appropriate.



(c) Eligibility(1) Eligible familiesA family is eligible to participate in a local Family Self-Sufficiency program unde</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of the Family Self-Sufficiency program established under this section is to promote the development of local strategies to coordinate use of assistance under sections 1437f and 1437g of this title with public and private resources, to enable eligible families to achieve economic independence and self-sufficiency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of prior required programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Continuation of prior required programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract of participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Contract of participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives for participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Incentives for participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of increases in family income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of increases in family income Any increase in the earned income of a family during the participation of the family in a local program established under this section may not be considered as income or a resource for purposes of eligibility of the family for other benefits, or amount of benefits payable to the family, under any program administered by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program coordinating committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program coordinating committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Action plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Family Self-Sufficiency awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Family Self-Sufficiency awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437u_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>On-site facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) On-site facilities Each eligible entity carrying out a local program may, subject to the approval of the Secretary, make available and utilize common areas or unoccupied units for the provision or coordination of supportive services under the local program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>