<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437z_7"><akn:num>1437z–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Mixed-finance public housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437z–7. Mixed-finance public housing(a) AuthorityA public housing agency may own, operate, assist, or otherwise participate in 1 or more mixed-finance projects in accordance with this section.


(b) Assistance(1) FormsA public housing agency may provide to a mixed-finance project assistance from the Operating Fund under section 1437g of this title, assistance from the Capital Fund under such section, or both forms of assistance. A public housing agency may, in accordance with regulations established by the Secretary, provide capital assistance to a mixed-finance project in the form of a grant, loan, guarantee, or other form of investment in the project, which may involve drawdown of funds on a schedule commensurate with construction draws for deposit into an interest-bearing escrow account to serve as collateral or credit enhancement for bonds issued by a public agency, or for other forms of public or private borrowings, for the construction or rehabilitation of the development.


(2) UseTo the extent deemed appropriate by the Secretary, assistance used in connection with the costs associated with the operation and management of mixed-finance projects may be used for funding of an operating reserve to ensure affordability for low-income and very low-income families in lieu of the availability of operating funds for public housing units in a mixed-finance project.



(c) Compliance with public housing requirementsThe units assisted with capital or operating assistance in a mixed-finance project shall be developed, operated, and maintained in accordance with the requirements of this chapter relating to public housing during the period required by under 11 So in original. this chapter, unless otherwise specified in this section. For purposes of this chapter, any reference to public housing owned or operated by a public housing agency shall include dwelling units in a mixed finance project that are assisted by the agency with capital or operating assistance.


(d) Mi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority A public housing agency may own, operate, assist, or otherwise participate in 1 or more mixed-finance projects in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with public housing requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance with public housing requirements The units assisted with capital or operating assistance in a mixed-finance project shall be developed, operated, and maintained in accordance with the requirements of this chapter relating to public housing during the period required by under 11 So in original. this chapter, unless otherwise specified in this section. For purposes of this chapter, any reference to public housing owned or operated by a public housing agency shall include dwelling units in a mixed finance project that are assisted by the agency with capital or operating assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mixed-finance projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mixed-finance projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Structure of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Structure of projects Each mixed-finance project shall be developed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Taxation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Taxation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of savings Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, to the extent deemed appropriate by the Secretary, to facilitate the establishment of socioeconomically mixed communities, a public housing agency that uses assistance from the Capital Fund for a mixed-finance project, to the extent that income from such a project reduces the amount of assistance used for operating or other costs relating to public housing, may use such resulting savings to rent privately developed dwelling units in the neighborhood of the mixed-finance project. Such units shall be made available for occupancy only by low-income families eligible for residency in public housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_7_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of certain contract terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effect of certain contract terms If an entity that owns or operates a mixed-finance project, that includes a significant number of units other than public housing units enters into a contract with a public housing agency, the terms of which obligate the entity to operate and maintain a specified number of units in the project as public housing units in accordance with the requirements of this chapter for the period required by law, such contractual terms may provide that, if, as a result of a reduction in appropriations under section 1437g of this title or any other change in applicable law, the public housing agency is unable to fulfill its contractual obligations with respect to those public housing units, that entity may deviate, under procedures and requirements developed through regulations by the Secretary, from otherwise applicable restrictions under this chapter regarding rents, income eligibility, and other areas of public housing management with respect to a portion or al</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>