<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437r"><akn:num>1437r</akn:num><akn:heading>Public housing resident management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437r. Public housing resident management(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to encourage increased resident management of public housing projects, as a means of improving existing living conditions in public housing projects, by providing increased flexibility for public housing projects that are managed by residents by—(1) permitting the retention, and use for certain purposes, of any revenues exceeding operating and project costs; and

(2) providing funding, from amounts otherwise available, for technical assistance to promote formation and development of resident management entities.


For purposes of this section, the term “public housing project” includes one or more contiguous buildings or an area of contiguous row houses the elected resident councils of which approve the establishment of a resident management corporation and otherwise meet the requirements of this section.

(b) Program requirements(1) Resident councilAs a condition of entering into a resident management program, the elected resident council of a public housing project shall approve the establishment of a resident management corporation. When such approval is made by the elected resident council of a building or row house area, the resident management program shall not interfere with the rights of other families residing in the project or harm the efficient operation of the project. The resident management corporation and the resident council may be the same organization, if the organization complies with the requirements applicable to both the corporation and council. The corporation shall be a nonprofit corporation organized under the laws of the State in which the project is located, and the tenants of the project shall be the sole voting members of the corporation. If there is no elected resident council, a majority of the households of the public housing project shall approve the establishment of a resident council to determine the feasibility of establishing a resident managemen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to encourage increased resident management of public housing projects, as a means of improving existing living conditions in public housing projects, by providing increased flexibility for public housing projects that are managed by residents by— For purposes of this section, the term “public housing project” includes one or more contiguous buildings or an area of contiguous row houses the elected resident councils of which approve the establishment of a resident management corporation and otherwise meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance amounts A contract under this section for management of a public housing project by a resident management corporation shall provide for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of Federal requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waiver of Federal requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct provision of operating and capital assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Direct provision of operating and capital assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (g) Repealed. Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 532(a)(5), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2575</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) , (g) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437r_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Applicability Any management contract between a public housing agency and a resident management corporation that is entered into after November 7, 1988, shall be subject to this section and the regulations issued to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>