<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437z–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437z_1"><akn:num>1437z–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalties against section 1437f owners</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437z–1. Civil money penalties against section 1437f owners(a) In general(1) Effect on other remediesThe penalties set forth in this section shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty, and may be imposed regardless of whether the Secretary imposes other administrative sanctions.


(2) Failure of SecretaryThe Secretary may not impose penalties under this section for a violation, if a material cause of the violation is the failure of the Secretary, an agent of the Secretary, or a public housing agency to comply with an existing agreement.



(b) Violations of housing assistance payment contracts for which penalty may be imposed(1) Liable partiesThe Secretary may impose a civil money penalty under this section on—(A) any owner of a property receiving project-based assistance under section 8 [42 U.S.C. 1437f];

(B) any general partner of a partnership owner of that property; and

(C) any agent employed to manage the property that has an identity of interest with the owner or the general partner of a partnership owner of the property.


(2) ViolationsA penalty may be imposed under this section for a knowing and material breach of a housing assistance payments contract, including the following—(A) failure to provide decent, safe, and sanitary housing pursuant to section 8 [42 U.S.C. 1437f]; or

(B) knowing or willful submission of false, fictitious, or fraudulent statements or requests for housing assistance payments to the Secretary or to any department or agency of the United States.


(3) Amount of penaltyThe amount of a penalty imposed for a violation under this subsection, as determined by the Secretary, may not exceed $25,000 per violation.



(c) Agency procedures(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall issue regulations establishing standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under subsection (b). These standards and procedures—(A) shall provide for the Secretary or other department offic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations of housing assistance payment contracts for which penalty may be imposed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Violations of housing assistance payment contracts for which penalty may be imposed</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agency procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of agency determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Judicial review of agency determination Judicial review of determinations made under this section shall be carried out in accordance with section 1735f–15(e) of title 12.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies for noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Remedies for noncompliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Settlement by Secretary The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deposit of penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Deposit of penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437z_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>