<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1437n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1437n"><akn:num>1437n</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for assisted housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1437n. Eligibility for assisted housing(a) Income eligibility for public housing(1) Income mix within projectsA public housing agency may establish and utilize income-mix criteria for the selection of residents for dwelling units in public housing projects, subject to the requirements of this section.


(2) PHA income mix(A) 11 So in original. No subpar. (B) has been enacted. Targeting.—Except as provided in paragraph (4), of the public housing dwelling units of a public housing agency made available for occupancy in any fiscal year by eligible families, not less than 40 percent shall be occupied by extremely low-income families.


(3) Prohibition of concentration of low-income families(A) ProhibitionA public housing agency may not, in complying with the requirements under paragraph (2), concentrate very low-income families (or other families with relatively low incomes) in public housing dwelling units in certain public housing projects or certain buildings within projects. The Secretary shall review the income and occupancy characteristics of the public housing projects and the buildings of such projects of such agencies to ensure compliance with the provisions of this paragraph and paragraph (2).


(B) Deconcentration(i) In generalA public housing agency shall submit with its annual public housing agency plan under section 1437c–1 of this title an admissions policy designed to provide for deconcentration of poverty and income-mixing by bringing higher income tenants into lower income projects and lower income tenants into higher income projects. This clause may not be construed to impose or require any specific income or racial quotas for any project or projects.


(ii) IncentivesIn implementing the policy under clause (i), a public housing agency may offer incentives for eligible families having higher incomes to occupy dwelling unit in projects predominantly occupied by eligible families having lower incomes, and provide for occupancy of eligible families hav</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income eligibility for public housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Income eligibility for public housing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income eligibility for tenant-based section 1437f assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Income eligibility for tenant-based section 1437f assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income eligibility for project-based section 1437f assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Income eligibility for project-based section 1437f assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of different standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishment of different standards Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) or (b)(1), if approved by the Secretary, a public housing agency may for good cause establish and implement, in accordance with the public housing agency plan, an admission standard other than the standard under such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for assistance based on assets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Eligibility for assistance based on assets</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1437n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility of individuals convicted of manufacturing or producing methamphetamine on the premises</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Ineligibility of individuals convicted of manufacturing or producing methamphetamine on the premises Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a public housing agency shall establish standards for occupancy in public housing dwelling units and assistance under section 1437f of this title that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>