<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1439" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1439/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1439/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1439"><akn:num>1439</akn:num><akn:heading>Local housing assistance plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1439. Local housing assistance plan(a) Applicability of approved plan to housing assistance application; procedure upon receipt of application by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; definitions(1) The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, upon receiving an application for housing assistance under the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.],11 So in original. The comma probably should be “or”. section 101 of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1965 [12 U.S.C. 1701s], or,22 So in original. The word “or” and the comma probably should not appear. if the unit of general local government in which the proposed assistance is to be provided has an approved housing assistance plan, shall—(A) not later than ten days after receipt of the application, notify the chief executive officer of such unit of general local government that such application is under consideration; and

(B) afford such unit of general local government the opportunity, during the thirty-day period beginning on the date of such notification, to object to the approval of the application on the grounds that the application is inconsistent with its housing assistance plan.


Upon receiving an application for such housing assistance, the Secretary shall assure that funds made available under this section shall be utilized to the maximum extent practicable to meet the needs and goals identified in the unit of local government’s housing assistance plan.

(2) If the unit of general local government objects to the application on the grounds that it is inconsistent with its housing assistance plan, the Secretary may not approve the application unless he determines that the application is consistent with such housing assistance plan. If the Secretary determines, that such application is consistent with the housing assistance plan, he shall notify the chief executive officer of the unit of general local government of his determination and the reasons therefor in writing. If the S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1439_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of approved plan to housing assistance application; procedure upon receipt of application by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of approved plan to housing assistance application; procedure upon receipt of application by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1439_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing assistance applications subject to procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Housing assistance applications subject to procedures The provisions of subsection (a) shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1439_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 105–276, title V, § 551(1), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2610</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1439_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation and reservation of housing assistance funds; purposes; prohibited reallocation of un­utilized funds; enumerated uses for retained funds; competition for reservation and obligation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation and reservation of housing assistance funds; purposes; prohibited reallocation of un­utilized funds; enumerated uses for retained funds; competition for reservation and obligation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1439_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance payments for properties in Jefferson County, Texas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Assistance payments for properties in Jefferson County, Texas From budget authority made available in appropriation Acts for fiscal year 1988, the Secretary shall enter into an annual contributions contract for a term of 180 months to obligate sufficient funds to provide assistance payments pursuant to section 8(b)(1) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 [42 U.S.C. 1437f(b)(1)] on behalf of 500 lower income families from budget authority made available for fiscal year 1988, so long as such families occupy properties in Jefferson County, Texas. If a lower income family receiving assistance payments pursuant to this subsection ceases to qualify for assistance payments pursuant to the provisions of section 8 of such Act [42 U.S.C. 1437f] or of this subsection during the 180-month term of the annual contributions contract, assistance payments shall be made on behalf of another lower income family who occupies a unit identified in the previous sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>