<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14404" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14404/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14404/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14404"><akn:num>14404</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of Federal funds by advocacy programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14404. Restriction on use of Federal funds by advocacy programs(a) In generalSubject to section 14402(b) of this title (relating to construction and treatment of certain services), no funds appropriated by Congress may be used to assist in, to support, or to fund any activity or service which has a purpose of assisting in, or to bring suit or provide any other form of legal assistance for the purpose of—(1) securing or funding any item, benefit, program, or service furnished for the purpose of causing, or the purpose of assisting in causing, the suicide, euthanasia, or mercy killing of any individual;

(2) compelling any person, institution, governmental entity 11 So in original. Probably should be “or governmental entity”. to provide or fund any item, benefit, program, or service for such purpose; or

(3) asserting or advocating a legal right to cause, or to assist in causing, the suicide, euthanasia, or mercy killing of any individual.


(b) List of programs to which restrictions apply(1) In generalSubsection (a) applies to funds appropriated under or to carry out the following:(A) Protection and advocacy systems under the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000Subtitle C of the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 [42 U.S.C. 15041 et seq.].


(B) Protection and advocacy systems under the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals ActThe Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 22 See References in Text note below. [42 U.S.C. 10801 et seq.].


(C) Protection and advocacy systems under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973Section 509 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 794e).


(D) Ombudsman programs under the Older Americans Act of 1965Ombudsman programs under the Older Americans Act of 1965 [42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.].


(E) Legal assistanceLegal assistance programs under the Legal Services Corporation Act [42 U.S.C. 2996 et seq.].



(2) Nonexclusive listNothing in th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14404_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to section 14402(b) of this title (relating to construction and treatment of certain services), no funds appropriated by Congress may be used to assist in, to support, or to fund any activity or service which has a purpose of assisting in, or to bring suit or provide any other form of legal assistance for the purpose of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14404_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of programs to which restrictions apply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) List of programs to which restrictions apply</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>