<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1485" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1485/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1485/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1485"><akn:num>1485</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing and related facilities for elderly persons and families or other persons and families of low</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1485. Housing and related facilities for elderly persons and families or other persons and families of low income(a) Direct loans; authorization; terms and conditions; revolving fund; appropriationThe Secretary is authorized to make loans to private nonprofit corporations and consumer cooperatives and Indian tribes to provide rental or cooperative housing and related facilities for elderly or handicapped persons or families of low or moderate income or other persons and families of low income in rural areas, in accordance with terms and conditions substantially identical with those specified in section 1472 of this title; except that—(1) no such loan shall exceed the development cost or the value of the security, whichever is less;

(2) such a loan may be made for a period of up to 30 years from the making of the loan; and

(3) such a loan, when made to a consumer cooperative for cooperative housing purposes, may, notwithstanding any other provision of law, be made upon the condition that any person who is admitted as an eligible member and tenant of the cooperative may not subsequently be deprived of his membership or tenancy by reason of his no longer meeting the income eligibility requirements established by the Secretary.


There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $50,000,000, which shall constitute a revolving fund to be used by the Secretary in carrying out this subsection.

(b) Insurance of loans; authorization; terms and conditions; utilization of Agricultural Credit Insurance FundThe Secretary is authorized to insure and make commitments to insure loans made to any individual, corporation, association, trust, Indian tribe, or partnership to provide rental or cooperative housing and related facilities for elderly or handicapped persons or families or other persons and families of moderate income in rural areas, in accordance with terms and conditions substantially identical with those specified in section 1472 of this title; except that—(1) no </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct loans; authorization; terms and conditions; revolving fund; appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Direct loans; authorization; terms and conditions; revolving fund; appropriation The Secretary is authorized to make loans to private nonprofit corporations and consumer cooperatives and Indian tribes to provide rental or cooperative housing and related facilities for elderly or handicapped persons or families of low or moderate income or other persons and families of low income in rural areas, in accordance with terms and conditions substantially identical with those specified in section 1472 of this title; except that— There is authorized to be appropriated not to exceed $50,000,000, which shall constitute a revolving fund to be used by the Secretary in carrying out this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance of loans; authorization; terms and conditions; utilization of Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Insurance of loans; authorization; terms and conditions; utilization of Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund The Secretary is authorized to insure and make commitments to insure loans made to any individual, corporation, association, trust, Indian tribe, or partnership to provide rental or cooperative housing and related facilities for elderly or handicapped persons or families or other persons and families of moderate income in rural areas, in accordance with terms and conditions substantially identical with those specified in section 1472 of this title; except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equity recapture loans and loans to nonprofit organizations and public agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equity recapture loans and loans to nonprofit organizations and public agencies With respect to a loan made or insured under subsection (a) or (b), the Secretary is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction requirements; detached units for cooperative housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Construction requirements; detached units for cooperative housing No loan shall be made or insured under subsection (a) or (b) unless the Secretary finds that the construction involved will be undertaken in an economical manner and will not be of elaborate or extravagant design or materials. However, specifically designed equipment required by elderly or handicapped persons or families shall not be considered elaborate or extravagant. A loan may be made or insured under subsection (a) or (b) with respect to detached units, including those on scattered sites, for cooperative housing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative expenses Amounts made available pursuant to section 1483 of this title shall be available for administrative expenses incurred under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans for financing transfers of memberships in cooperatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Loans for financing transfers of memberships in cooperatives Notwithstanding the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) of this section, the Secretary may make and insure loans to consumer cooperatives to enable such cooperatives to finance the transfers of memberships in the cooperatives upon such terms and conditions as low- and moderate-income persons can reasonably afford, except that such loans shall not be made upon terms more favorable than are authorized under section 1490a(a) of this title, and that the total loan to a cooperative under this section shall not exceed the value of the property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Project transfers After August 6, 1996, the ownership or control of a project for which a loan is made or insured under this section may be transferred only if the Secretary determines that such transfer would further the provision of housing and related facilities for low-income families or persons and would be in the best interests of residents and the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on cost increases after approval for project involving newly constructed or substantially rehabilitated units; applicable factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitations on cost increases after approval for project involving newly constructed or substantially rehabilitated units; applicable factors After approving a project involving newly constructed or substantially rehabilitated units under this section, the Secretary shall limit cost increases to those approved by the Secretary. The Secretary may approve those increases only for unforeseen factors beyond the owner’s control, design changes required by the Secretary or the local government, or changes in financing approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1485_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract preferences for providing units in newly constructed projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contract preferences for providing units in newly constructed projects For the purpose of achieving the lowest cost in providing units in newly constructed projects assisted under this section, the Secretary shall give a preference in entering into contracts under this section for projects which are to be located on specific tracts of land provided by States, units of local government, or others if the Secretary determines that the tract of land is suitable for such housing, and that affording such preference will be cost effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>