<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1487" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1487/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1487/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1487"><akn:num>1487</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Housing Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1487. Rural Housing Insurance Fund(a) Authority to make and insure loans for housing and buildings on adequate farms; amountsThe Secretary may insure loans meeting the requirements of section 1472 of this title, and may make loans in accordance with the requirements of such section to be sold and insured. The amount of such a loan to a low income person or family shall not exceed the amount necessary to provide adequate housing which is modest in size, design, and cost (as determined by the Secretary).


(b) Authority to make and insure loans for housing and related facilities for domestic farm labor and elderly persons; transfer of notes, contracts, and mortgages from Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund; compensationThe Secretary may insure loans in accordance with the requirements of section 1484 of this title (exclusive of subsections (a)(3), (a)(5), and (b) thereof), 1485 of this title (exclusive of subsections (a) and (b)(3) thereof), 1490d, and 1490f of this title, and may make loans meeting such requirements to be sold and insured. Upon the expiration of ninety days after the original capitalization of the Rural Housing Insurance Fund, created by subsection (e) of this section, no new loans shall be made or insured under section 1484 or 1485(b) of this title, except in conformity with this section. The notes held in the Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund (section 1929 of title 7) which evidence loans made or insured by the Secretary under section 1484 or 1485(b) of this title, the rights and liabilities of that Fund under insurance contracts relating to such loans held by insured investors, the mortgages securing the obligations of the borrowers under such loans held in the Fund or by insured investors, and all rights to subsequent collections on and proceeds of such notes, contracts, and mortgages, are hereby transferred to the Rural Housing Insurance Fund and for the purposes of this subchapter and any other Act shall be subject to the provisions of this s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make and insure loans for housing and buildings on adequate farms; amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to make and insure loans for housing and buildings on adequate farms; amounts The Secretary may insure loans meeting the requirements of section 1472 of this title, and may make loans in accordance with the requirements of such section to be sold and insured. The amount of such a loan to a low income person or family shall not exceed the amount necessary to provide adequate housing which is modest in size, design, and cost (as determined by the Secretary).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make and insure loans for housing and related facilities for domestic farm labor and elderly persons; transfer of notes, contracts, and mortgages from Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to make and insure loans for housing and related facilities for domestic farm labor and elderly persons; transfer of notes, contracts, and mortgages from Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund; compensation The Secretary may insure loans in accordance with the requirements of section 1484 of this title (exclusive of subsections (a)(3), (a)(5), and (b) thereof), 1485 of this title (exclusive of subsections (a) and (b)(3) thereof), 1490d, and 1490f of this title, and may make loans meeting such requirements to be sold and insured. Upon the expiration of ninety days after the original capitalization of the Rural Housing Insurance Fund, created by subsection (e) of this section, no new loans shall be made or insured under section 1484 or 1485(b) of this title, except in conformity with this section. The notes held in the Agricultural Credit Insurance Fund (section 1929 of title 7) which evidence loans made or insured by the Secretary under section 1484 or 1485(b) of this title, t</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds from Rural Housing Insurance Fund for loans; sale of insured and guaranteed loans to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds from Rural Housing Insurance Fund for loans; sale of insured and guaranteed loans to public The Secretary may use the Rural Housing Insurance Fund for the purpose of making loans to be sold and insured under this section. Any loan made and sold by the Secretary under this section after April 7, 1986 (and any loan made by other lenders under this subchapter that is insured or guaranteed in accordance with this section, is purchased by the Secretary, and is sold by the Secretary under this section after such date) shall be sold to the public and may not be sold to the Federal Financing Bank, unless such sale to the Federal Financing Bank is required to service transactions under this subchapter between the Secretary and the Federal Financing Bank occurring on or before such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to insure payment of interest and principal; liens; assignability of notes evidencing loans; interest subsidy on insured and guaranteed loans offered for sale to public; protection of borrowers under loans sold to public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority to insure payment of interest and principal; liens; assignability of notes evidencing loans; interest subsidy on insured and guaranteed loans offered for sale to public; protection of borrowers under loans sold to public</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural Housing Insurance Fund; creation; authorization of appropriations; separate operation of guaranteed and insured loan programs: transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rural Housing Insurance Fund; creation; authorization of appropriations; separate operation of guaranteed and insured loan programs: transfer of funds There is hereby created the Rural Housing Insurance Fund (hereinafter referred to as the “Fund”) which shall be used by the Secretary as a revolving fund for carrying out the provisions of this section. There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary for the purposes of the Fund. The guaranteed loan program under this subchapter shall be operated separately from the insured loan program operated under this subchapter and no funds designated for one program may be transferred to another program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment of excess Fund moneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Investment of excess Fund moneys Money in the Fund not needed for current operations shall be invested in direct obligations of the United States or obligations guaranteed by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund assets and liabilities; sale of loans; agreements for servicing and purchasing loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fund assets and liabilities; sale of loans; agreements for servicing and purchasing loans All funds, claims, notes, mortgages, contracts, and property acquired by the Secretary under this section, and all collections and proceeds therefrom, shall constitute assets of the Fund; and all liabilities and obligations of such assets shall be liabilities and obligations of the Fund. Loans may be held in the Fund and collected in accordance with their terms or may be sold by the Secretary with or without agreements for insurance thereof. The Secretary is authorized to make agreements with respect to servicing loans held or insured by him under this section and purchasing such insured loans on such terms and conditions as he may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of notes; form and denominations; interest rate; purchase by Secretary of the Treasury; debt transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Issuance of notes; form and denominations; interest rate; purchase by Secretary of the Treasury; debt transactions The Secretary is authorized to issue notes to the Secretary of the Treasury to obtain funds necessary for discharging obligations under this section and for authorized expenditures out of the Fund, but, except as may be authorized in appropriation Acts, not for the original or any additional capital of the Fund. Such notes shall be in such form and denominations and have such maturities and be subject to such terms and conditions as may be prescribed by the Secretary with the approval of the Secretary of the Treasury. Each note shall bear interest at the average rate, as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, payable by the Treasury upon its marketable public obligations outstanding at the beginning of the fiscal year in which such note is issued, which are neither due nor callable for redemption for fifteen years from their date of issue. The Secretary of the Tr</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention of annual charge; administrative expenses; merger of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Retention of annual charge; administrative expenses; merger of funds The Secretary may retain out of interest payments by the borrower an annual charge in an amount specified in the insurance or sale agreement applicable to the loan. Of the charges retained by the Secretary, if any, not to exceed 1 per centum per annum of the unpaid balance of the loan shall be deposited in the Fund. Any retained charges not deposited in the Fund shall be available for administrative expenses in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter, to be transferred annually, and become merged with any appropriation for administrative expenses of the Farmers Home Administration, when and in such amounts as may be authorized in appropriation Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1487_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional uses of Fund moneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Additional uses of Fund moneys The Secretary may also utilize the Fund—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>