<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1490n"><akn:num>1490n</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1490n. Review of rules and regulations(a) Publication for public comment in Federal RegisterNotwithstanding any other provision of law, no rule or regulation pursuant to this subchapter may become effective unless it has first been published for public comment in the Federal Register for at least 60 days, and published in final form for at least 30 days.


(b) Transmittal to Congressional committee members prior to publication in Federal RegisterThe Secretary shall transmit to the chairman and ranking Member of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House, all rules and regulations at least 15 days before they are sent to the Federal Register for purposes of subsection (a).


(c) Rules and regulations issued on emergency basisThe provisions of this section shall not apply to a rule or regulation which the Secretary certifies is issued on an emergency basis.


(d) Regulatory authorityThe Secretary shall include with each rule or regulation required to be transmitted to the Committees under this section a detailed summary of all changes required by the Office of Management and Budget that prohibit, modify, postpone, or disapprove such rule or regulation in whole or part.


(July 15, 1949, ch. 338, title V, § 534, as added Pub. L. 98–181, title I [title V, § 523], Nov. 30, 1983, 97 Stat. 1254; amended Pub. L. 100–242, title V, § 563(b), Feb. 5, 1988, 101 Stat. 1944.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Subsec. (d). Pub. L. 100–242 added subsec. (d).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of House of Representatives treated as referring to Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives by section 1(a) of Pub. L. 104–14, set out as a note preceding section 21 of Title 2, The Congress. Committee on Banking and Financial Services of House of Representatives abolished and replaced by Committee on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication for public comment in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Publication for public comment in Federal Register Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no rule or regulation pursuant to this subchapter may become effective unless it has first been published for public comment in the Federal Register for at least 60 days, and published in final form for at least 30 days.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transmittal to Congressional committee members prior to publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transmittal to Congressional committee members prior to publication in Federal Register The Secretary shall transmit to the chairman and ranking Member of the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs of the House, all rules and regulations at least 15 days before they are sent to the Federal Register for purposes of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations issued on emergency basis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rules and regulations issued on emergency basis The provisions of this section shall not apply to a rule or regulation which the Secretary certifies is issued on an emergency basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulatory authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulatory authority The Secretary shall include with each rule or regulation required to be transmitted to the Committees under this section a detailed summary of all changes required by the Office of Management and Budget that prohibit, modify, postpone, or disapprove such rule or regulation in whole or part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>