<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1490a"><akn:num>1490a</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to provide occupant owned, rental, and cooperative housing for low and moderate income, elderl</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1490a. Loans to provide occupant owned, rental, and cooperative housing for low and moderate income, elderly or handicapped persons or families(a) Interest rates; additional assistance; payments to owners; rent limitations(1)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of sections 1472, 1487(a) and 1485 of this title, loans to persons of low or moderate income under section 1472 or 1487(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, loans under section 1485 of this title to provide rental or cooperative housing and related facilities for persons and families of low or moderate income or elderly or handicapped persons or families and loans under section 1490f of this title to provide condominium housing for persons and families of low or moderate income, shall bear interest at a rate prescribed by the Secretary at not less than a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury upon the request of the Secretary taking into consideration the current average market yield on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States with remaining periods to maturity comparable to the average maturities of such loans, adjusted to the nearest one-eighth of 1 per centum. Any loan guaranteed under this subchapter shall bear interest at such rate as may be agreed upon by the borrower and the lender.

(B) From the interest rate so determined, the Secretary may provide the borrower with assistance in the form of credits so as to reduce the effective interest rate to a rate not less than 1 per centum per annum for such periods of time as the Secretary may determine for applicants described in subparagraph (A) if without such assistance such applicants could not afford the dwelling or make payments on the indebtedness of the rental or cooperative housing. In the case of assistance provided under this subparagraph with respect to a loan under section 1472 of this title, the Secretary may not reduce, cancel, or refuse to renew the assistance due to an increase in the adjusted in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest rates; additional assistance; payments to owners; rent limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interest rates; additional assistance; payments to owners; rent limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location in rural areas; inclusion of qualified nonrural residents who will become rural residents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Location in rural areas; inclusion of qualified nonrural residents who will become rural residents Housing and related facilities provided with loans described in subsection (a) shall be located in rural areas; and applicants eligible for such loans under section 1472, 1487(a)(1),1 or 1490f(a) of this title, or for occupancy of housing provided with such loans under section 1485 or 1490f(c) of this title, shall include otherwise qualified nonrural residents who will become rural residents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of Rural Housing Insurance Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reimbursement of Rural Housing Insurance Fund There shall be reimbursed to the Rural Housing Insurance Fund by annual appropriations (1) the amounts by which nonprincipal payments made from the fund during each fiscal year to the holders of insured loans described in subsection (a)(1) exceed interest due from the borrowers during each year, and (2) the amount of assistance payments described in subsections (a)(2) and (a)(5). There are authorized to be appropriated to the Rural Housing Insurance Fund such sums as may be necessary to reimburse such fund for the amount of assistance payments described in subsection (a)(1)(C). The Secretary may from time to time issue notes to the Secretary of the Treasury under section 1487(h) and of this title and section 1490f of this title to obtain amounts equal to such unreimbursed payments, pending the annual reimbursement by appropriation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rental assistance contract authority; preconditions, limitations, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rental assistance contract authority; preconditions, limitations, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increases in rent or contribution of any recipient</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Increases in rent or contribution of any recipient Any rent or contribution of any recipient or any tenant in a project assisted under subsection (a)(5) shall not increase as a result of this section, any amendment thereto, or any other provision of Federal law or regulation by more than 10 per centum during any twelve-month period, unless the increase above 10 per centum is attributable to increases in income which are unrelated to this subsection or other law or regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>