<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490s" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490s/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490s/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1490s"><akn:num>1490s</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1490s. Enforcement provisions(a) Equity skimming(1) Criminal penaltyWhoever, as an owner, agent, employee, or manager, or is otherwise in custody, control, or possession of property that is security for a loan made or guaranteed under this subchapter, willfully uses, or authorizes the use, of any part of the rents, assets, proceeds, income, or other funds derived from such property, for any purpose other than to meet actual, reasonable, and necessary expenses of the property, or for any other purpose not authorized by this subchapter or the regulations adopted pursuant to this subchapter, shall be fined under title 18 or imprisoned not more than 5 years, or both.


(2) Civil sanctionsAn entity or individual who as an owner, operator, employee, or manager, or who acts as an agent for a property that is security for a loan made or guaranteed under this subchapter where any part of the rents, assets, proceeds, income, or other funds derived from such property are used for any purpose other than to meet actual, reasonable, and necessary expenses of the property, or for any other purpose not authorized by this subchapter or the regulations adopted pursuant to this subchapter, shall be subject to a fine of not more than $25,000 per violation. The sanctions provided in this paragraph may be imposed in addition to any other civil sanctions or civil monetary penalties authorized by law.



(b) Civil monetary penalties(1) In generalThe Secretary may, after notice and opportunity for a hearing, impose a civil monetary penalty in accordance with this subsection against any individual or entity, including its owners, officers, directors, general partners, limited partners, or employees, who knowingly and materially violate, or participate in the violation of, the provisions of this subchapter, the regulations issued by the Secretary pursuant to this subchapter, or agreements made in accordance with this subchapter, by—(A) submitting information to the Secretary that is false;
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490s_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equity skimming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Equity skimming</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490s_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil monetary penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil monetary penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>