<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1490p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1490p"><akn:num>1490p</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1490p. Accountability(a) Notice regarding assistance(1) Publication of notice of availabilityThe Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the availability of any assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary under this subchapter.


(2) Publication of application proceduresThe Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a description of the form and procedures by which application for the assistance may be made, and any deadlines relating to the award or allocation of the assistance. Such description shall be sufficient to enable any eligible applicant to apply for such assistance.


(3) Publication of selection criteriaNot less than 30 days before any deadline by which applications or requests for assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary must be submitted, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the criteria by which selection for the assistance will be made. Such criteria shall include any objective measures of housing need, project merit, or efficient use of resources that the Secretary determines are appropriate and consistent with the statute under which the assistance is made available.


(4) Documentation of decisions(A) The Secretary shall award or allocate assistance only in response to a written application in a form approved in advance by the Secretary, except where other award or allocation procedures are specified in statute.

(B) The Secretary shall ensure that documentation and other information regarding each application for assistance is sufficient to indicate the basis on which any award or allocation was made or denied. The preceding sentence shall apply to—(i) any application for an award or allocation of assistance made by the Secretary to a State, unit of general local government, or other recipient of assistance, and

(ii) any application for a subsequent award or allocation of such assistance by such State, unit of general local gover</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice regarding assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice regarding assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures by applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosures by applicants The Secretary shall require the disclosure of information with respect to any application for assistance under this subchapter submitted by any applicant who has received or, in the determination of the Secretary, can reasonably be expected to receive assistance under this subchapter in excess of $200,000 in the aggregate during any fiscal year. Such information shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updating of disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Updating of disclosure During the period when an application is pending or assistance is being provided, the applicant shall update the disclosure required under the previous subsection within 30 days of any substantial change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 104–65, § 11(b)(2), Dec. 19, 1995, 109 Stat. 701</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedies and penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Remedies and penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation of assistance The Secretary shall certify that assistance provided by the Secretary to any housing project shall not be more than is necessary to provide affordable housing after taking account of assistance from all Federal, State, and local sources. The Secretary shall adjust the amount of assistance provided to an applicant to compensate for any changes reported under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations Not less than 180 days following December 15, 1989, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Assistance” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Assistance” defined For purposes of this section, the term “assistance” means any housing grant, loan, guarantee, insurance, rebate, subsidy, tax credit benefit, or other form of direct or indirect assistance, for the original construction or development of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1490p_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report by Secretary The Secretary shall submit to the Congress, not later than 180 days following December 15, 1989, a report describing actions taken to carry out this section, including actions to inform and educate officers and employees of the Department of Agriculture regarding the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>