<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14923" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14923/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14923/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14923"><akn:num>14923</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards and procedures for providing accreditation or approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14923. Standards and procedures for providing accreditation or approval(a) In general(1) Promulgation of regulationsThe Secretary, shall, by regulation, prescribe the standards and procedures to be used by accrediting entities for the accreditation of agencies and the approval of persons to provide adoption services in the United States in cases subject to the Convention.


(2) Consideration of viewsIn developing such regulations, the Secretary shall consider any standards or procedures developed or proposed by, and the views of, individuals and entities with interest and expertise in international adoptions and family social services, including public and private entities with experience in licensing and accrediting adoption agencies.


(3) Applicability of notice and comment rulesSubsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 553 of title 5 shall apply in the development and issuance of regulations under this section.



(b) Minimum requirements(1) AccreditationThe standards prescribed under subsection (a) shall include the requirement that accreditation of an agency may not be provided or continued under this subchapter unless the agency meets the following requirements:(A) Specific requirements(i) The agency provides prospective adoptive parents of a child in a prospective Convention adoption a copy of the medical records of the child (which, to the fullest extent practicable, shall include an English-language translation of such records) on a date which is not later than the earlier of the date that is 2 weeks before: (I) the adoption; or (II) the date on which the prospective parents travel to a foreign country to complete all procedures in such country relating to the adoption.

(ii) The agency ensures that a thorough background report (home study) on the prospective adoptive parent or parents has been completed in accordance with the Convention and with applicable Federal and State requirements and transmitted to the Attorney General with respect to each Convent</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14923_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14923_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimum requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14923_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary registration of community based agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary registration of community based agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>