<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14944" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14944/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/14944/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_14944"><akn:num>14944</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 14944. Enforcement(a) Civil penaltiesAny person who—(1) violates section 14921 of this title;

(2) makes a false or fraudulent statement, or misrepresentation, with respect to a material fact, or offers, gives, solicits, or accepts inducement by way of compensation, intended to influence or affect in the United States or a foreign country—(A) a decision by an accrediting entity with respect to the accreditation of an agency or approval of a person under subchapter II;

(B) the relinquishment of parental rights or the giving of parental consent relating to the adoption of a child in a case subject to the Convention; or

(C) a decision or action of any entity performing a central authority function; or


(3) engages another person as an agent, whether in the United States or in a foreign country, who in the course of that agency takes any of the actions described in paragraph (1) or (2),


shall be subject, in addition to any other penalty that may be prescribed by law, to a civil money penalty of not more than $50,000 for a first violation, and not more than $100,000 for each succeeding violation.

(b) Civil enforcement(1) Authority of Attorney GeneralThe Attorney General may bring a civil action to enforce subsection (a) against any person in any United States district court.


(2) Factors to be considered in imposing penaltiesIn imposing penalties the court shall consider the gravity of the violation, the degree of culpability of the defendant, and any history of prior violations by the defendant.



(c) Criminal penaltiesWhoever knowingly and willfully violates paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine of not more than $250,000, imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.


(Pub. L. 106–279, title IV, § 404, Oct. 6, 2000, 114 Stat. 842.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSubchapter II, referred to in subsec. (a)(2)(A), was in the original “title II”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 106–279, Oct. 6, 2000, 114 Stat. 830, which enacted su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14944_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Civil penalties Any person who— shall be subject, in addition to any other penalty that may be prescribed by law, to a civil money penalty of not more than $50,000 for a first violation, and not more than $100,000 for each succeeding violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14944_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_14944_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criminal penalties Whoever knowingly and willfully violates paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) shall be subject to a fine of not more than $250,000, imprisonment for not more than 5 years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>