<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15025/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15025/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15025"><akn:num>15025</akn:num><akn:heading>State Councils on Developmental Disabilities and designated State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15025. State Councils on Developmental Disabilities and designated State agencies(a) In generalEach State that receives assistance under this part shall establish and maintain a Council to undertake advocacy, capacity building, and systemic change activities (consistent with subsections (b) and (c) of section 15001 of this title) that contribute to a coordinated, consumer- and family-centered, consumer- and family-directed, comprehensive system of community services, individualized supports, and other forms of assistance that contribute to the achievement of the purpose of this part. The Council shall have the authority to fulfill the responsibilities described in subsection (c).


(b) Council membership(1) Council appointments(A) In generalThe members of the Council of a State shall be appointed by the Governor of the State from among the residents of that State.


(B) RecommendationsThe Governor shall select members of the Council, at the discretion of the Governor, after soliciting recommendations from organizations representing a broad range of individuals with developmental disabilities and individuals interested in individuals with developmental disabilities, including the non-State agency members of the Council. The Council may, at the initiative of the Council, or on the request of the Governor, coordinate Council and public input to the Governor regarding all recommendations.


(C) RepresentationThe membership of the Council shall be geographically representative of the State and reflect the diversity of the State with respect to race and ethnicity.



(2) Membership rotationThe Governor shall make appropriate provisions to rotate the membership of the Council. Such provisions shall allow members to continue to serve on the Council until such members’ successors are appointed. The Council shall notify the Governor regarding membership requirements of the Council, and shall notify the Governor when vacancies on the Council remain unfilled for a significant</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15025_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each State that receives assistance under this part shall establish and maintain a Council to undertake advocacy, capacity building, and systemic change activities (consistent with subsections (b) and (c) of section 15001 of this title) that contribute to a coordinated, consumer- and family-centered, consumer- and family-directed, comprehensive system of community services, individualized supports, and other forms of assistance that contribute to the achievement of the purpose of this part. The Council shall have the authority to fulfill the responsibilities described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15025_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Council membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15025_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Council responsibilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15025_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designated State agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>