<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15023" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15023/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15023/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15023"><akn:num>15023</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to the States for planning, administration, and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15023. Payments to the States for planning, administration, and services(a) State plan expendituresFrom each State’s allotments for a fiscal year under section 15022 of this title, the Secretary shall pay to the State the Federal share of the cost, other than the cost for construction, incurred during such year for activities carried out under the State plan approved under section 15024 of this title. The Secretary shall make such payments from time to time in advance on the basis of estimates by the Secretary of the sums the State will expend for the cost under the State plan. The Secretary shall make such adjustments as may be necessary to the payments on account of previously made underpayments or overpayments under this section.


(b) Designated State agency expendituresThe Secretary may make payments to a State for the portion described in section 15024(c)(5)(B)(vi) of this title in advance or by way of reimbursement, and in such installments as the Secretary may determine.


(Pub. L. 106–402, title I, § 123, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1696.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15023_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State plan expenditures From each State’s allotments for a fiscal year under section 15022 of this title, the Secretary shall pay to the State the Federal share of the cost, other than the cost for construction, incurred during such year for activities carried out under the State plan approved under section 15024 of this title. The Secretary shall make such payments from time to time in advance on the basis of estimates by the Secretary of the sums the State will expend for the cost under the State plan. The Secretary shall make such adjustments as may be necessary to the payments on account of previously made underpayments or overpayments under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15023_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated State agency expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designated State agency expenditures The Secretary may make payments to a State for the portion described in section 15024(c)(5)(B)(vi) of this title in advance or by way of reimbursement, and in such installments as the Secretary may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>