<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15024" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15024/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15024/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15024"><akn:num>15024</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15024. State plan(a) In generalAny State desiring to receive assistance under this part shall submit to the Secretary, and obtain approval of, a 5-year strategic State plan under this section.


(b) Planning cycleThe plan described in subsection (a) shall be updated as appropriate during the 5-year period.


(c) State plan requirementsIn order to be approved by the Secretary under this section, a State plan shall meet each of the following requirements:(1) State CouncilThe plan shall provide for the establishment and maintenance of a Council in accordance with section 15025 of this title and describe the membership of such Council.


(2) Designated State agencyThe plan shall identify the agency or office within the State designated to support the Council in accordance with this section and section 15025(d) of this title (referred to in this part as a “designated State agency”).


(3) Comprehensive review and analysisThe plan shall describe the results of a comprehensive review and analysis of the extent to which services, supports, and other assistance are available to individuals with developmental disabilities and their families, and the extent of unmet needs for services, supports, and other assistance for those individuals and their families, in the State. The results of the comprehensive review and analysis shall include—(A) a description of the services, supports, and other assistance being provided to individuals with developmental disabilities and their families under other federally assisted State programs, plans, and policies under which the State operates and in which individuals with developmental disabilities are or may be eligible to participate, including particularly programs relating to the areas of emphasis, including—(i) medical assistance, maternal and child health care, services for children with special health care needs, children’s mental health services, comprehensive health and mental health services, and institutional care options;

(ii) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15024_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Any State desiring to receive assistance under this part shall submit to the Secretary, and obtain approval of, a 5-year strategic State plan under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15024_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning cycle</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Planning cycle The plan described in subsection (a) shall be updated as appropriate during the 5-year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15024_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State plan requirements In order to be approved by the Secretary under this section, a State plan shall meet each of the following requirements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15024_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public input and review, submission, and approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public input and review, submission, and approval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>