<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15063" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15063/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15063/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15063"><akn:num>15063</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose and scope of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15063. Purpose and scope of activities(a) National network of University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities Education, Research, and Service(1) In generalIn order to provide leadership in, advise Federal, State, and community policymakers about, and promote opportunities for individuals with developmental disabilities to exercise self-determination, be independent, be productive, and be integrated and included in all facets of community life, the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities designated as Centers in each State to pay for the Federal share of the cost of the administration and operation of the Centers. The Centers shall be interdisciplinary education, research, and public service units of universities (as defined by the Secretary) or public or not-for-profit entities associated with universities that engage in core functions, described in paragraph (2), addressing, directly or indirectly, 1 or more of the areas of emphasis.


(2) Core functionsThe core functions referred to in paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) Provision of interdisciplinary pre-service preparation and continuing education of students and fellows, which may include the preparation and continuing education of leadership, direct service, clinical, or other personnel to strengthen and increase the capacity of States and communities to achieve the purpose of this subchapter.

(B) Provision of community services—(i) that provide training or technical assistance for individuals with developmental disabilities, their families, professionals, paraprofessionals, policymakers, students, and other members of the community; and

(ii) that may provide services, supports, and assistance for the persons described in clause (i) through demonstration and model activities.


(C) Conduct of research, which may include basic or applied research, evaluation, and the analysis of public policy in areas that affect or could affect, either positively or negatively, individu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15063_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National network of University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities Education, Research, and Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National network of University Centers for Excellence in Developmental Disabilities Education, Research, and Service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15063_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National training initiatives on critical and emerging needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National training initiatives on critical and emerging needs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15063_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance In order to strengthen and support the national network of Centers, the Secretary may enter into 1 or more cooperative agreements or contracts to— to promote the viability and use of the resources and expertise of the Centers nationally and internationally.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>