<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15095" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15095/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15095/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15095"><akn:num>15095</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of the lead entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15095. Designation of the lead entity(a) DesignationThe Chief Executive Officer of a State that desires to receive a grant under section 15093 of this title, shall designate the office or entity (referred to in this subchapter as the “lead entity”) responsible for—(1) submitting the application described in section 15094 of this title on behalf of the State;

(2) administering and supervising the use of the amounts made available under the grant;

(3) coordinating efforts related to and supervising the preparation of the application;

(4) coordinating the planning, development, implementation (or expansion and enhancement), and evaluation of a statewide system of family support services for families of children with disabilities among public agencies and between public agencies and private agencies, including coordinating efforts related to entering into interagency agreements;

(5) coordinating efforts related to the participation by families of children with disabilities in activities carried out under a grant made under this subchapter; and

(6) submitting the report described in section 15097 of this title on behalf of the State.


(b) QualificationsIn designating the lead entity, the Chief Executive Officer may designate—(1) an office of the Chief Executive Officer;

(2) a commission appointed by the Chief Executive Officer;

(3) a public agency;

(4) a council established under Federal or State law; or

(5) another appropriate office, agency, or entity.


(Pub. L. 106–402, title II, § 206, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1731.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15095_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation The Chief Executive Officer of a State that desires to receive a grant under section 15093 of this title, shall designate the office or entity (referred to in this subchapter as the “lead entity”) responsible for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15095_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications In designating the lead entity, the Chief Executive Officer may designate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>