<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15091" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15091/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15091/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15091"><akn:num>15091</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings, purposes, and policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15091. Findings, purposes, and policy(a) FindingsCongress makes the following findings:(1) It is in the best interest of our Nation to preserve, strengthen, and maintain the family.

(2) Families of children with disabilities provide support, care, and training to their children that can save States millions of dollars. Without the efforts of family caregivers, many persons with disabilities would receive care through State-supported out-of-home placements.

(3) Most families of children with disabilities, especially families in unserved and underserved populations, do not have access to family-centered and family-directed services to support such families in their efforts to care for such children at home.

(4) Medical advances and improved health care have increased the life span of many people with disabilities, and the combination of the longer life spans and the aging of family caregivers places a continually increasing demand on the finite service delivery systems of the States.

(5) In 1996, 49 States provided family support initiatives in response to the needs of families of children with disabilities. Such initiatives included the provision of cash subsidies, respite care, and other forms of support. There is a need in each State, however, to strengthen, expand, and coordinate the activities of a system of family support services for families of children with disabilities that is easily accessible, avoids duplication, uses resources efficiently, and prevents gaps in services to families in all areas of the State.

(6) The goals of the Nation properly include the goal of providing to families of children with disabilities the family support services necessary—(A) to support the family;

(B) to enable families of children with disabilities to nurture and enjoy their children at home;

(C) to enable families of children with disabilities to make informed choices and decisions regarding the nature of supports, resources, services, and other assistance made av</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15091_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress makes the following findings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15091_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of this subchapter are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15091_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Policy It is the policy of the United States that all programs, projects, and activities funded under this subchapter shall be family-centered and family-directed, and shall be provided in a manner consistent with the goal of providing families of children with disabilities with the support the families need to raise their children at home.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>