<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15208" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15208/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15208/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15208"><akn:num>15208</akn:num><akn:heading>Law enforcement tribute acts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15208. Law enforcement tribute acts(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Law Enforcement Tribute Act”.


(b) FindingsCongress finds the following:(1) The well-being of all citizens of the United States is preserved and enhanced as a direct result of the vigilance and dedication of law enforcement and public safety personnel.

(2) More than 700,000 law enforcement officers, both men and women, at great risk to their personal safety, serve their fellow citizens as guardians of peace.

(3) Nationwide, 51 law enforcement officers were killed in the line of duty in 2000, according to statistics released by the Federal Bureau of Investigation. This number is an increase of 9 from the 1999 total of 42.

(4) In 1999, 112 firefighters died while on duty, an increase of 21 deaths from the previous year.

(5) Every year, 1 in 9 peace officers is assaulted, 1 in 25 is injured, and 1 in 4,400 is killed in the line of duty.

(6) In addition, recent statistics indicate that 83 officers were accidentally killed in the performance of their duties in 2000, an increase of 18 from the 65 accidental deaths in 1999.

(7) A permanent tribute is a powerful means of honoring the men and women who have served our Nation with distinction. However, many law enforcement and public safety agencies lack the resources to honor their fallen colleagues.


(c) Program authorizedFrom amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General may make grants to States, units of local government, and Indian tribes to carry out programs to honor, through permanent tributes, men and women of the United States who were killed or disabled while serving as law enforcement or public safety officers.


(d) Uses of fundsGrants awarded under this section shall be distributed directly to the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe, and shall be used for the purposes specified in subsection (c).


(e) $150,000 limitationA grant under this section may not exceed $150,000 to any sin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Law Enforcement Tribute Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings Congress finds the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program authorized From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Attorney General may make grants to States, units of local government, and Indian tribes to carry out programs to honor, through permanent tributes, men and women of the United States who were killed or disabled while serving as law enforcement or public safety officers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Uses of funds Grants awarded under this section shall be distributed directly to the State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe, and shall be used for the purposes specified in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>$150,000 limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) $150,000 limitation A grant under this section may not exceed $150,000 to any single recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applications To request a grant under this section, the chief executive of a State, unit of local government, or Indian tribe shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Attorney General may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual report to Congress Not later than November 30 of each year, the Attorney General shall submit a report to the Congress regarding the activities carried out under this section. Each such report shall include, for the preceding fiscal year, the number of grants funded under this section, the amount of funds provided under those grants, and the activities for which those funds were used.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15208_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2002 through 2009.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>