<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15706"><akn:num>15706</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15706. Authorization of appropriations(a) Federal Emergency Management AgencyThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Emergency Management Agency for carrying out this chapter—(1) $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2015;

(2) $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2016; and

(3) $5,332,000 for fiscal year 2017.


(b) National Science FoundationThere are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation for carrying out this chapter—(1) $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2015;

(2) $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2016; and

(3) $9,682,000 for fiscal year 2017.


(c) National Institute of Standards and TechnologyThere are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology for carrying out this chapter—(1) $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2015;

(2) $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2016; and

(3) $4,120,000 for fiscal year 2017.


(d) National Oceanic and Atmospheric AdministrationThere are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for carrying out this chapter—(1) $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2015;

(2) $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2016; and

(3) $2,266,000 for fiscal year 2017.


(Pub. L. 108–360, title II, § 207, Oct. 25, 2004, 118 Stat. 1679; Pub. L. 114–52, § 5, Sept. 30, 2015, 129 Stat. 500.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this title”, meaning title II of Pub. L. 108–360, Oct. 25, 2004, 118 Stat. 1675, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of title II to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 15701 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2015—Pub. L. 114–52 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section authorized appropriations for fiscal years 2006 to 2008.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of all functions, personnel, assets, components, authorities, grant programs, and liabilities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including the func</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Emergency Management Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal Emergency Management Agency There are authorized to be appropriated to the Federal Emergency Management Agency for carrying out this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Science Foundation There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Science Foundation for carrying out this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Institute of Standards and Technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Institute of Standards and Technology There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology for carrying out this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for carrying out this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>