<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15854" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15854/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15854/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15854"><akn:num>15854</akn:num><akn:heading>Sugar Cane Ethanol Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15854. Sugar Cane Ethanol Program(a) Definition of programIn this section, the term “program” means the Sugar Cane Ethanol Program established by subsection (b).


(b) EstablishmentThere is established within the Environmental Protection Agency a program to be known as the “Sugar Cane Ethanol Program”.


(c) Project(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations under subsection (d), in carrying out the program, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall establish a project that is—(A) carried out in multiple States—(i) in each of which is produced cane sugar that is eligible for loans under section 7272 of title 7, or a similar subsequent authority; and

(ii) at the option of each such State, that have an incentive program that requires the use of ethanol in the State; and


(B) designed to study the production of ethanol from cane sugar, sugarcane, and sugarcane byproducts.


(2) RequirementsA project described in paragraph (1) shall—(A) be limited to sugar producers and the production of ethanol in the States of Florida, Louisiana, Texas, and Hawaii, divided equally among the States, to demonstrate that the process may be applicable to cane sugar, sugarcane, and sugarcane byproducts;

(B) include information on the ways in which the scale of production may be replicated once the sugar cane industry has located sites for, and constructed, ethanol production facilities; and

(C) not last more than 3 years.



(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $36,000,000, to remain available until expended.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title II, § 208, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 656.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15854_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of program In this section, the term “program” means the Sugar Cane Ethanol Program established by subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15854_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established within the Environmental Protection Agency a program to be known as the “Sugar Cane Ethanol Program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15854_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Project</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15854_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $36,000,000, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>