<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15852" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15852/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15852/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15852"><akn:num>15852</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal purchase requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15852. Federal purchase requirement(a) RequirementThe President, acting through the Secretary, shall seek to ensure that, to the extent economically feasible and technically practicable, of the total amount of electric energy the Federal Government consumes during any fiscal year, the following amounts shall be renewable energy:(1) Not less than 3 percent in fiscal years 2007 through 2009.

(2) Not less than 5 percent in fiscal years 2010 through 2012.

(3) Not less than 7.5 percent in fiscal year 2013 and each fiscal year thereafter.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BiomassThe term “biomass” means any lignin waste material that is segregated from other waste materials and is determined to be nonhazardous by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and any solid, nonhazardous, cellulosic material that is derived from—(A) any of the following forest-related resources: mill residues, precommercial thinnings, slash, and brush, or nonmerchantable material;

(B) solid wood waste materials, including waste pallets, crates, dunnage, manufacturing and construction wood wastes (other than pressure-treated, chemically-treated, or painted wood wastes), and landscape or right-of-way tree trimmings, but not including municipal solid waste (garbage), gas derived from the biodegradation of solid waste, or paper that is commonly recycled;

(C) agriculture wastes, including orchard tree crops, vineyard, grain, legumes, sugar, and other crop by-products or residues, and livestock waste nutrients; or

(D) a plant that is grown exclusively as a fuel for the production of electricity.


(2) Renewable energyThe term “renewable energy” means marine energy (as defined in section 17211 of this title), or electric energy produced from solar, wind, biomass, landfill gas, geothermal, municipal solid waste, or new hydroelectric generation capacity achieved from increased efficiency or additions of new capacity at an existing hydroelectric project.



(c) Calculation(1) In </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15852_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement The President, acting through the Secretary, shall seek to ensure that, to the extent economically feasible and technically practicable, of the total amount of electric energy the Federal Government consumes during any fiscal year, the following amounts shall be renewable energy:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15852_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15852_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Calculation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15852_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than April 15, 2007, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall provide a report to Congress on the progress of the Federal Government in meeting the goals established by this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>