<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1589a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1589a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1589a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1589a"><akn:num>1589a</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension by President of dates for disposal and other actions relating to housing under this subcha</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1589a. Extension by President of dates for disposal and other actions relating to housing under this subchapter
Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President is authorized to extend, for such period or periods as he shall specify, the time within which any action is required or permitted to be taken by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or others under the provisions of this subchapter or section 1553 of this title (or any contract entered into pursuant thereto), upon a determination by him, after considering the needs of national defense and the effect of such extension upon the general housing situation and the national economy, that such extension is in the public interest.
(Oct. 14, 1940, ch. 862, title VI, § 611, as added Sept. 1, 1951, ch. 378, title VI, § 603(d), 65 Stat. 314; amended July 14, 1952, ch. 723, § 6, 66 Stat. 603; Pub. L. 89–174, § 5(a), Sept. 9, 1965, 79 Stat. 669.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1952—Act July 14, 1952, inserted “or section 1553 of this title” immediately before parenthetical clause, and substituted “thereto” for “of this subchapter” in parenthetical clause.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Transfer of Functions
For transfer of functions to Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, see note set out under section 1581 of this title.

Executive Documents

Executive Order No. 10284
Ex. Ord. No. 10284, Sept. 1, 1951, 16 F.R. 8971, was superseded by Ex. Ord. No. 10339, Apr. 5, 1952, 17 F.R. 3012.


Ex. Ord. No. 10339. Extensions of Time
Ex. Ord. No. 10339, Apr. 7, 1952, 17 F.R. 3012, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 10425, Jan. 16, 1953, 18 F.R. 405, provided:
1. [Superseded. Ex. Ord. No. 10425, Jan. 16, 1953, 18 F.R. 405.]
2. The time stipulated in subsection (c) of section 601 of the Act [section 1581(c) of this title] on or before which all conditions to relinquishments or transfers pursuant to requests made under subsections (a), (b) and (g) of that section must be complied with is extended to June 30,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>