<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15902" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15902/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15902/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15902"><akn:num>15902</akn:num><akn:heading>Program on oil and gas royalties in-kind</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15902. Program on oil and gas royalties in-kind(a) Applicability of sectionNotwithstanding any other provision of law, this section applies to all royalty in-kind accepted by the Secretary on or after August 8, 2005, under any Federal oil or gas lease or permit under—(1) section 192 of title 30;

(2) section 1353 of title 43; or

(3) any other Federal law governing leasing of Federal land for oil and gas development.


(b) Terms and conditionsAll royalty accruing to the United States shall, on the demand of the Secretary, be paid in-kind. If the Secretary makes such a demand, the following provisions apply to the payment:(1) Satisfaction of royalty obligationDelivery by, or on behalf of, the lessee of the royalty amount and quality due under the lease satisfies royalty obligation of the lessee for the amount delivered, except that transportation and processing reimbursements paid to, or deductions claimed by, the lessee shall be subject to review and audit.


(2) Marketable condition(A) Definition of marketable conditionIn this paragraph, the term “in marketable condition” means sufficiently free from impurities and otherwise in a condition that the royalty production will be accepted by a purchaser under a sales contract typical of the field or area in which the royalty production was produced.


(B) RequirementRoyalty production shall be placed in marketable condition by the lessee at no cost to the United States.



(3) Disposition by the SecretaryThe Secretary may—(A) sell or otherwise dispose of any royalty production taken in-kind (other than oil or gas transferred under section 1353(a)(3) of title 43 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a closing parenthesis. for not less than the market price; and

(B) transport or process (or both) any royalty production taken in-kind.


(4) Retention by the SecretaryThe Secretary may, notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, retain and use a portion of the revenues from the sale of oil and gas taken in-kind</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of section Notwithstanding any other provision of law, this section applies to all royalty in-kind accepted by the Secretary on or after August 8, 2005, under any Federal oil or gas lease or permit under—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions All royalty accruing to the United States shall, on the demand of the Secretary, be paid in-kind. If the Secretary makes such a demand, the following provisions apply to the payment:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement of cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reimbursement of cost If the lessee, pursuant to an agreement with the United States or as provided in the lease, processes the royalty gas or delivers the royalty oil or gas at a point not on or adjacent to the lease area, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit to the United States required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Benefit to the United States required The Secretary may receive oil or gas royalties in-kind only if the Secretary determines that receiving royalties in-kind provides benefits to the United States that are greater than or equal to the benefits that are likely to have been received had royalties been taken in-value.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deduction of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deduction of expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Consultation with States The Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small refineries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Small refineries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition to Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disposition to Federal agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal low-income energy assistance programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Federal low-income energy assistance programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15902_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>McAlester Army Ammunition Plant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) McAlester Army Ammunition Plant At the request of the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>