<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1592d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1592d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1592d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1592d"><akn:num>1592d</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary’s powers with respect to housing, facilities, and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1592d. Secretary’s powers with respect to housing, facilities, and services(a) Planning, acquisition, construction, etc.With respect to any housing or community facilities or services which the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized to provide, or any property which he is authorized to acquire, under this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized by contract or otherwise (without regard to section 6101 of title 41, section 322 of the Act of June 30, 1932 (47 Stat. 412), as amended,11 See References in Text note below. chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, and prior to the approval of the Attorney General) to make plans, surveys, and investigations; to acquire (by purchase, donation, condemnation or otherwise), construct, erect, extend, remodel, operate, rent, lease, exchange, repair, deal with, insure, maintain, convey, sell for cash or credit, demolish, or otherwise dispose of any property, land, improvement, or interest therein; to provide approaches, utilities, and transportation facilities; to procure necessary materials, supplies, articles, equipment, and machinery; to make advance payments for leased property; to pursue to final disposition by way of compromise or otherwise, claims both for and against the United States (exclusive of claims in excess of $5,000 arising out of contracts for construction, repairs, and the purchase of supplies and materials, and claims involving administrative expenses) which are not in litigation and which have not been referred to the Department of Justice; and to convey without cost to States and political subdivisions and instrumentalities thereof property for streets and other public thoroughfares and easements for public purposes: Provided, That any instrument executed by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and purporting to convey any right, title or interest in any pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1592d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning, acquisition, construction, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Planning, acquisition, construction, etc. With respect to any housing or community facilities or services which the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized to provide, or any property which he is authorized to acquire, under this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development is authorized by contract or otherwise (without regard to section 6101 of title 41, section 322 of the Act of June 30, 1932 (47 Stat. 412), as amended,11 See References in Text note below. chapters 1 to 11 of title 40 and division C (except sections 3302, 3307(e), 3501(b), 3509, 3906, 4710, and 4711) of subtitle I of title 41, and prior to the approval of the Attorney General) to make plans, surveys, and investigations; to acquire (by purchase, donation, condemnation or otherwise), construct, erect, extend, remodel, operate, rent, lease, exchange, repair, deal with, insure, maintain, convey, sell for cash or credit, demolish, or otherwise dispose of any property, land, improvement, or int</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1592d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condemnation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Condemnation Before condemnation proceedings are instituted pursuant to this subchapter or subchapter X an effort shall be made to acquire the property involved by negotiation unless, because of reasonable doubt as to the identity of the owner or owners, because of the large number of persons with whom it would be necessary to negotiate, or for other reasons, the effort to acquire by negotiation would involve, in the judgment of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, such delay in acquiring the property as to be contrary to the interest of national defense. In any condemnation proceeding instituted pursuant to this subchapter or subchapter X, the court shall not order the party in possession to surrender possession in advance of final judgment unless a declaration of taking has been filed, and a deposit of the amount estimated to be just compensation has been made, under section 3114(a) to (d) of title 40, providing for such declarations. Unless title is in dispute, the co</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1592d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Return to original owner in certain cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Return to original owner in certain cases If any real property acquired under this subchapter or subchapter X is retained after June 30, 1954, without having been used for the purposes of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall, if the original owner desires the property and pays the fair value thereof, return such property to the owner. In the event the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the original owner do not agree as to the fair value of the property, the fair value shall be determined by three appraisers, one of whom shall be chosen by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, one by the original owner, and the third by the first two appraisers; the expenses of such determination shall be paid in equal shares by the Government and the original owner.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>