<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15924" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15924/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15924/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15924"><akn:num>15924</akn:num><akn:heading>Project to improve Federal permit coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15924. Project to improve Federal permit coordination(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a Federal Permit Streamlining Project (referred to in this section as the “Project”).


(b) Memorandum of understanding(1) In generalNot later than 90 days after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall enter into a memorandum of understanding for purposes of this section with—(A) the Secretary of Agriculture;

(B) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; and

(C) the Chief of Engineers.


(2) State participationThe Secretary may request that the Governors of the States in which Project offices are located be signatories to the memorandum of understanding.



(c) Designation of qualified staff(1) In generalNot later than 30 days after the date of the signing of the memorandum of understanding under subsection (b), all Federal signatory parties shall, if appropriate, assign to each of the field offices identified in subsection (d) an employee who has expertise in the regulatory issues relating to the office in which the employee is employed, including, as applicable, particular expertise in—(A) the consultations and the preparation of biological opinions under section 1536 of title 16;

(B) permits under section 1344 of title 33;

(C) regulatory matters under the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.);

(D) planning under the National Forest Management Act of 1976 (16 U.S.C. 472a et seq.); and

(E) the preparation of analyses under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(2) DutiesEach employee assigned under paragraph (1) shall—(A) not later than 90 days after the date of assignment, report to the Bureau of Land Management Field Managers in the office to which the employee is assigned;

(B) be responsible for all issues relating to the jurisdiction of the home office or agency of the employee; and

(C) participate as part of the team of personnel working on</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a Federal Permit Streamlining Project (referred to in this section as the “Project”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Memorandum of understanding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Memorandum of understanding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of qualified staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of qualified staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project offices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project offices The following Bureau of Land Management Offices shall serve as the Project offices:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report to Congress Not later than February 1 of the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 and each February 1 thereafter, the Secretary shall report to the Chairman and ranking minority Member of the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, which shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional personnel The Secretary shall assign to each field office identified in subsection (d) any additional personnel that are necessary to ensure the effective implementation of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Transfer of funds For the purposes of coordination and processing of oil and gas use authorizations on Federal land under the administration of the Project offices identified in subsection (d), the Secretary may authorize the expenditure or transfer of such funds as are necessary to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15924_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Savings provision Nothing in this section affects—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>