<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15927" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15927/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15927/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15927"><akn:num>15927</akn:num><akn:heading>Oil shale, tar sands, and other strategic unconventional fuels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15927. Oil shale, tar sands, and other strategic unconventional fuels(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Oil Shale, Tar Sands, and Other Strategic Unconventional Fuels Act of 2005”.


(b) Declaration of policyCongress declares that it is the policy of the United States that—(1) United States oil shale, tar sands, and other unconventional fuels are strategically important domestic resources that should be developed to reduce the growing dependence of the United States on politically and economically unstable sources of foreign oil imports;

(2) the development of oil shale, tar sands, and other strategic unconventional fuels, for research and commercial development, should be conducted in an environmentally sound manner, using practices that minimize impacts; and

(3) development of those strategic unconventional fuels should occur, with an emphasis on sustainability, to benefit the United States while taking into account affected States and communities.


(c) Leasing program for research and development of oil shale and tar sandsIn accordance with section 241 of title 30 and any other applicable law, except as provided in this section, not later than 180 days after August 8, 2005, from land otherwise available for leasing, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall make available for leasing such land as the Secretary considers to be necessary to conduct research and development activities with respect to technologies for the recovery of liquid fuels from oil shale and tar sands resources on public lands. Prospective public lands within each of the States of Colorado, Utah, and Wyoming shall be made available for such research and development leasing.


(d) Programmatic environmental impact statement and commercial leasing program for oil shale and tar sands(1) Programmatic environmental impact statementNot later than 18 months after August 8, 2005, in accordance with section 4332(2)(C) of this title, the Secr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Oil Shale, Tar Sands, and Other Strategic Unconventional Fuels Act of 2005”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Declaration of policy Congress declares that it is the policy of the United States that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing program for research and development of oil shale and tar sands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Leasing program for research and development of oil shale and tar sands In accordance with section 241 of title 30 and any other applicable law, except as provided in this section, not later than 180 days after August 8, 2005, from land otherwise available for leasing, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall make available for leasing such land as the Secretary considers to be necessary to conduct research and development activities with respect to technologies for the recovery of liquid fuels from oil shale and tar sands resources on public lands. Prospective public lands within each of the States of Colorado, Utah, and Wyoming shall be made available for such research and development leasing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programmatic environmental impact statement and commercial leasing program for oil shale and tar sands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Programmatic environmental impact statement and commercial leasing program for oil shale and tar sands</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commencement of commercial leasing of oil shale and tar sands</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Commencement of commercial leasing of oil shale and tar sands Not later than 180 days after publication of the final regulation required by subsection (d), the Secretary shall consult with the Governors of States with significant oil shale and tar sands resources on public lands, representatives of local governments in such States, interested Indian tribes, and other interested persons, to determine the level of support and interest in the States in the development of tar sands and oil shale resources. If the Secretary finds sufficient support and interest exists in a State, the Secretary may conduct a lease sale in that State under the commercial leasing program regulations. Evidence of interest in a lease sale under this subsection shall include, but not be limited to, appropriate areas nominated for leasing by potential lessees and other interested parties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diligent development requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Diligent development requirements The Secretary shall, by regulation, designate work requirements and milestones to ensure the diligent development of the lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial report by the Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Initial report by the Secretary of the Interior Within 90 days after August 8, 2005, the Secretary of the Interior shall report to the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Task Force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Petroleum Reserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Office of Petroleum Reserves</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15927_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>