<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15921" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15921/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15921/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15921"><akn:num>15921</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of Federal oil and gas leasing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15921. Management of Federal oil and gas leasing programs(a) Timely action on leases and permits(1) Secretary of the InteriorTo ensure timely action on oil and gas leases and applications for permits to drill on land otherwise available for leasing, the Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall—(A) ensure expeditious compliance with section 4332(2)(C) of this title and any other applicable environmental and cultural resources laws;

(B) improve consultation and coordination with the States and the public; and

(C) improve the collection, storage, and retrieval of information relating to the oil and gas leasing activities.


(2) Secretary of AgricultureTo ensure timely action on oil and gas lease applications for permits to drill on land otherwise available for leasing, the Secretary of Agriculture shall—(A) ensure expeditious compliance with all applicable environmental and cultural resources laws; and

(B) improve the collection, storage, and retrieval of information relating to the oil and gas leasing activities.



(b) Best management practices(1) In generalNot later than 18 months after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall develop and implement best management practices to—(A) improve the administration of the onshore oil and gas leasing program under the Mineral Leasing Act (30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.); and

(B) ensure timely action on oil and gas leases and applications for permits to drill on land otherwise available for leasing.


(2) ConsiderationsIn developing the best management practices under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider any recommendations from the review under section 361.11 See References in Text note below.


(3) RegulationsNot later than 180 days after the development of the best management practices under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall publish, for public comment, proposed regulations that set forth specific timeframes for processing leases and applications in accordance with the best managemen</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15921_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely action on leases and permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Timely action on leases and permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15921_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best management practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Best management practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15921_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Improved enforcement The Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall improve inspection and enforcement of oil and gas activities, including enforcement of terms and conditions in permits to drill on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15921_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations In addition to amounts made available to carry out activities relating to oil and gas leasing on public land administered by the Secretary and National Forest System land administered by the Secretary of Agriculture, there are authorized to be appropriated for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2010—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>