<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1594a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1594a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1594a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1594a"><akn:num>1594a</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of military housing financed under Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Fund and re</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1594a. Acquisition of military housing financed under Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Fund and rental housing at military bases(a) Purchase priceWhenever the Secretary of Defense or his designee deems it necessary for the purpose of this subchapter, he may acquire, by purchase, donation, condemnation, or other means of transfer, any land or (with the approval of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development) (1) any housing financed with mortgages insured under title VIII of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1748 et seq.] as in effect prior to August 11, 1955, or (2) any housing situated adjacent to a military installation which was (A) completed prior to July 1, 1952, (B) certified by the Department of Defense, prior to construction, as being necessary to meet an existing military family housing need and considered as military housing by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and (C) financed with mortgages insured under section 207 of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1713], or (3) any housing situated on or adjacent to a military installation which was (A) completed prior to July 1, 1952, (B) considered by the Department of Defense, prior to construction, as being necessary to meet an existing military family housing need and considered as military housing by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and (C) financed with mortgages insured under section 608 of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1743], including adjacent property constructed primarily to provide commercial facilities for the occupants of such housing. The purchase price of any such housing shall not exceed the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development’s estimate of the replacement cost of such housing and related property (not including the value of any improvements installed or constructed with appropriated funds) as of the date of final endorsement for mortgage insurance reduced by an appropriate allowance representing the estimated cost of repairs and replaceme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase price</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purchase price Whenever the Secretary of Defense or his designee deems it necessary for the purpose of this subchapter, he may acquire, by purchase, donation, condemnation, or other means of transfer, any land or (with the approval of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development) (1) any housing financed with mortgages insured under title VIII of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1748 et seq.] as in effect prior to August 11, 1955, or (2) any housing situated adjacent to a military installation which was (A) completed prior to July 1, 1952, (B) certified by the Department of Defense, prior to construction, as being necessary to meet an existing military family housing need and considered as military housing by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and (C) financed with mortgages insured under section 207 of the National Housing Act [12 U.S.C. 1713], or (3) any housing situated on or adjacent to a military installation which was (A) completed prior to July 1, 1952, (B)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing at or near a military installation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Housing at or near a military installation Notwithstanding any provision of subsection (a) to the contrary, the Secretary of Defense or his designee shall, in the manner provided in subsection (a), acquire by purchase, donation, or other means of transfer or, if the parties cannot agree upon terms for acquisition by such means, by condemnation, any housing described in clause (1) or (2) of subsection (a) of this section which is located at or near a military installation where the construction of housing under the Armed Services Housing Mortgage Insurance Program has been approved by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condemnation; procedures; deposit; payment; interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Condemnation; procedures; deposit; payment; interest</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Occupancy; use, or improvement of property before approval of title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Occupancy; use, or improvement of property before approval of title Property acquired under this section may be occupied, used, and improved for the purposes of this section prior to the approval of title by the Attorney General as required by sections 3111 and 3112 of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Release of accrual requirements for replacement, taxes, and hazard insurance reserves</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Release of accrual requirements for replacement, taxes, and hazard insurance reserves The Secretary of Defense or his designee may, in the case of any housing acquired or to be acquired under this section, make arrangements with the mortgage whereby such mortgage will agree to release and waive all requirements of accruals for reserves for replacement, taxes, and hazard insurance provided for under the corporate charter and indenture agreement with respect to such housing, upon the execution of a written agreement by the Secretary or his designee that the purposes for which such reserves and other funds were accrued will be carried out.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1594a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use as public quarters or lease of housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use as public quarters or lease of housing Any housing acquired under this section may be (1) assigned as public quarters to military personnel and their dependents; or (2) leased to military and civilian personnel for occupancy by them and their dependents, upon such terms and conditions as will in the judgment of the Secretary of Defense or his designee be in the best interest of the United States, without loss to military personnel of their basic allowance for quarters or appropriate allotments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>