<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15943" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15943/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/15943/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_15943"><akn:num>15943</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain gathering lines located on Federal land and Indian land</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 15943. Certain gathering lines located on Federal land and Indian land(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Federal land(A) In generalThe term “Federal land” means land the title to which is held by the United States.


(B) ExclusionsThe term “Federal land” does not include—(i) a unit of the National Park System;

(ii) a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System;

(iii) a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;

(iv) a wilderness study area within the National Forest System; or

(v) Indian land.



(2) Gathering line and associated field compression or pumping unit(A) In generalThe term “gathering line and associated field compression or pumping unit” means—(i) a pipeline that is installed to transport oil, natural gas and related constituents, or produced water from 1 or more wells drilled and completed to produce oil or gas; and

(ii) if necessary, 1 or more compressors or pumps to raise the pressure of the transported oil, natural gas and related constituents, or produced water to higher pressures necessary to enable the oil, natural gas and related constituents, or produced water to flow into pipelines and other facilities.


(B) InclusionsThe term “gathering line and associated field compression or pumping unit” includes a pipeline or associated compression or pumping unit that is installed to transport oil or natural gas from a processing plant to a common carrier pipeline or facility.


(C) ExclusionsThe term “gathering line and associated field compression or pumping unit” does not include a common carrier pipeline.



(3) Indian landThe term “Indian land” means land the title to which is held by—(A) the United States in trust for an Indian Tribe or an individual Indian; or

(B) an Indian Tribe or an individual Indian subject to a restriction by the United States against alienation.


(4) Produced waterThe term “produced water” means water produced from an oil or gas well bore that is not a fluid prepared at, or transported to, the well si</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15943_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15943_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain gathering lines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certain gathering lines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_15943_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effect on other law Nothing in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>