<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16062" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16062/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16062/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16062"><akn:num>16062</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic manufacturing conversion grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16062. Domestic manufacturing conversion grant program(a) Program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program to encourage domestic production and sales of efficient hybrid and advanced diesel vehicles and components of those vehicles.


(2) InclusionsThe program shall include grants and loan guarantees under section 16513 of this title to automobile manufacturers and suppliers and hybrid component manufacturers to encourage domestic production of efficient hybrid, plug-in electric hybrid, plug-in electric drive, and advanced diesel vehicles.


(3) PriorityPriority shall be given to the refurbishment or retooling of manufacturing facilities that have recently ceased operation or will cease operation in the near future.



(b) Coordination with State and local programsThe Secretary may coordinate implementation of this section with State and local programs designed to accomplish similar goals, including the retention and retraining of skilled workers from the manufacturing facilities, including by establishing matching grant arrangements.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title VII, § 712, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 818; Pub. L. 110–140, title I, §§ 132, 134(a), Dec. 19, 2007, 121 Stat. 1511, 1513.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Pub. L. 110–140, § 132, amended section generally. Prior to amendment, section related to program to encourage domestic production and sales of efficient hybrid and advanced diesel vehicles and authorization of appropriations.
Subsec. (a)(2). Pub. L. 110–140, § 134(a), inserted “and loan guarantees under section 16513 of this title” after “grants”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2007 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 110–140 effective on the date that is 1 day after Dec. 19, 2007, see section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140, set out as an Effective Date note under section 1824 of Ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16062_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16062_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with State and local programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination with State and local programs The Secretary may coordinate implementation of this section with State and local programs designed to accomplish similar goals, including the retention and retraining of skilled workers from the manufacturing facilities, including by establishing matching grant arrangements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16062_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>