<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16072" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16072/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16072/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16072"><akn:num>16072</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16072. Reports to Congress(a) Initial reportNot later than 60 days after the date on which grants are awarded under this subpart, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing—(1) an identification of the grant recipients and a description of the projects to be funded;

(2) an identification of other applicants that submitted applications for the pilot program; and

(3) a description of the mechanisms used by the Secretary to ensure that the information and knowledge gained by participants in the pilot program are transferred among the pilot program participants and to other interested parties, including other applicants that submitted applications.


(b) EvaluationNot later than 3 years after August 8, 2005, and annually thereafter until the pilot program ends, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing an evaluation of the effectiveness of the pilot program, including—(1) an assessment of the benefits to the environment derived from the projects included in the pilot program; and

(2) an estimate of the potential benefits to the environment to be derived from widespread application of alternative fueled vehicles and ultra-low sulfur diesel vehicles.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title VII, § 722, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 820.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16072_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initial report Not later than 60 days after the date on which grants are awarded under this subpart, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16072_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation Not later than 3 years after August 8, 2005, and annually thereafter until the pilot program ends, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report containing an evaluation of the effectiveness of the pilot program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>