<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16092" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16092/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16092/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16092"><akn:num>16092</akn:num><akn:heading>Diesel truck retrofit and fleet modernization program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16092. Diesel truck retrofit and fleet modernization program(a) EstablishmentThe Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish a program for awarding grants on a competitive basis to public agencies and entities for fleet modernization programs including installation of retrofit technologies for diesel trucks.


(b) Eligible recipientsA grant shall be awarded under this section only to a State or local government or an agency or instrumentality of a State or local government or of two or more State or local governments who will allocate funds, with preference to ports and other major hauling operations.


(c) Awards(1) In generalThe Administrator shall seek, to the maximum extent practicable, to ensure a broad geographic distribution of grants under this section.


(2) PreferencesIn making awards of grants under this section, the Administrator shall give preference to proposals that—(A) will achieve the greatest reductions in emissions of nonmethane hydrocarbons, oxides of nitrogen, and/or particulate matter per proposal or per truck; or

(B) involve the use of Environmental Protection Agency or California Air Resources Board verified emissions control retrofit technology on diesel trucks that operate solely on ultra-low sulfur diesel fuel after September 2006.



(d) Conditions of grantA grant shall be provided under this section on the conditions that—(1) trucks which are replacing scrapped trucks and on which retrofit emissions-control technology are to be demonstrated—(A) will operate on ultra-low sulfur diesel fuel where such fuel is reasonably available or required for sale by State or local law or regulation;

(B) were manufactured in model year 1998 and before; and

(C) will be used for the transportation of cargo goods especially in port areas or used in goods movement and major hauling operations;


(2) grant funds will be used for the purchase of emission control retrofit technology, including State taxes and contract fees; and

(3)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish a program for awarding grants on a competitive basis to public agencies and entities for fleet modernization programs including installation of retrofit technologies for diesel trucks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible recipients A grant shall be awarded under this section only to a State or local government or an agency or instrumentality of a State or local government or of two or more State or local governments who will allocate funds, with preference to ports and other major hauling operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions of grant A grant shall be provided under this section on the conditions that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Verification Not later than 90 days after August 8, 2005, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register procedures to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16092_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section, to remain available until expended the following sums:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>