<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16091" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16091/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16091/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16091"><akn:num>16091</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean school bus program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16091. Clean school bus program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(2) Alternative fuelThe term “alternative fuel” means liquefied natural gas, compressed natural gas, hydrogen, propane, or biofuels.


(3) Clean school busThe term “clean school bus” means a school bus that—(A) the Administrator certifies reduces emissions and is operated entirely or in part using an alternative fuel; or

(B) is a zero-emission school bus.


(4) Eligible contractorThe term “eligible contractor” means a contractor that is a for-profit, not-for-profit, or nonprofit entity that has the capacity—(A) to sell, lease, license, or contract for service clean school buses, zero-emission school buses, charging or fueling infrastructure, or other equipment needed to charge, fuel, or maintain clean school buses or zero-emission school buses, to individuals or entities that own, lease, license, or contract for service a school bus or a fleet of school buses; or

(B) to arrange financing for such a sale, lease, license, or contract for service.


(5) Eligible recipient(A) In generalSubject to subparagraph (B), the term “eligible recipient” means—(i) 1 or more local or State governmental entities responsible for—(I) providing school bus service to 1 or more public school systems; or

(II) the purchase, lease, license, or contract for service of school buses;


(ii) an eligible contractor;

(iii) a nonprofit school transportation association;

(iv) a charter school (as defined in section 7221i of title 20) responsible for the purchase, lease, license, or contract for service of school buses for that charter school; or

(v) an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 5304 of title 25), Tribal organization (as defined in that section), or tribally controlled school (as defined in section 2511 of title 25) that is responsible for—(I) providing school bus service to 1 or more Bureau-funded schools (as defi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for replacement of existing school buses with clean school buses and zero-emission school buses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program for replacement of existing school buses with clean school buses and zero-emission school buses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Education and outreach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative costs The Administrator may use, for the administrative costs of carrying out this section, not more than 3 percent of the amounts made available to carry out this section for any fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Regulations The Administrator shall have the authority to issue such regulations or other guidance, forms, instructions, and publications as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the programs, projects, or activities authorized under this section, including to ensure that such programs, projects, or activities are completed in a timely and effective manner, result in emissions reductions, and maximize public health benefits.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16091_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section, to remain available until expended, $1,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>