<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16121" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16121/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16121/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16121"><akn:num>16121</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16121. Definitions
In this part:(1) Fuel cellThe term “fuel cell” means a device that directly converts the chemical energy of a fuel and an oxidant into electricity by electrochemical processes occurring at separate electrodes in the device.


(2) Light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleetThe term “light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleet” does not include any vehicle designed or procured for combat or combat-related missions.


(3) Stationary; portableThe terms “stationary” and “portable”, when used in reference to a fuel cell, include—(A) continuous electric power; and

(B) backup electric power.


(4) Task ForceThe term “Task Force” means the Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Technical Task Force established under section 16155 of this title.


(5) Technical Advisory CommitteeThe term “Technical Advisory Committee” means the independent Technical Advisory Committee selected under section 16156 of this title.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title VII, § 781, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 835.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16121_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fuel cell</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Fuel cell The term “fuel cell” means a device that directly converts the chemical energy of a fuel and an oxidant into electricity by electrochemical processes occurring at separate electrodes in the device.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16121_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleet</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleet The term “light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleet” does not include any vehicle designed or procured for combat or combat-related missions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16121_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stationary; portable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Stationary; portable The terms “stationary” and “portable”, when used in reference to a fuel cell, include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16121_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Task Force The term “Task Force” means the Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Technical Task Force established under section 16155 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16121_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Technical Advisory Committee The term “Technical Advisory Committee” means the independent Technical Advisory Committee selected under section 16156 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>