<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16122" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16122/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16122/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16122"><akn:num>16122</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal and State procurement of fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16122. Federal and State procurement of fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems(a) PurposesThe purposes of this section are—(1) to stimulate acceptance by the market of fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems;

(2) to support development of technologies relating to fuel cell vehicles, public refueling stations, and hydrogen energy systems; and

(3) to require the Federal government, 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. which is the largest single user of energy in the United States, to adopt those technologies as soon as practicable after the technologies are developed, in conjunction with private industry partners.


(b) Federal leases and purchases(1) Requirement(A) In generalNot later than January 1, 2010, the head of any Federal agency that uses a light-duty or heavy-duty vehicle fleet shall lease or purchase fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems to meet any applicable energy savings goal described in subsection (c).


(B) Learning demonstration vehiclesThe Secretary may lease or purchase appropriate vehicles developed under subsections (a)(10) and (b)(1)(A) of section 16157 of this title to meet the requirement in subparagraph (A).



(2) Costs of leases and purchases(A) In generalThe Secretary, in cooperation with the Task Force and the Technical Advisory Committee, shall pay to Federal agencies (or share the cost under interagency agreements) the difference in cost between—(i) the cost to the agencies of leasing or purchasing fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems under paragraph (1); and

(ii) the cost to the agencies of a feasible alternative to leasing or purchasing fuel cell vehicles and hydrogen energy systems, as determined by the Secretary.


(B) Competitive costs and management structuresIn carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary, in consultation with the agency, may use the General Services Administration or any commercial vendor to ensure—(i) a cost-effective purchase of a fuel cell vehicle or hydr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16122_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purposes of this section are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16122_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal leases and purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal leases and purchases</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16122_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy savings goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Energy savings goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16122_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative program with State agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperative program with State agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16122_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>