<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16134" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16134/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16134/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16134"><akn:num>16134</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16134. Evaluation and report(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after the date on which funds are made available under this part, and biennially thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report evaluating the implementation of the programs under this part.


(b) InclusionsThe report shall include a description of—(1) the total number of grant applications received;

(2) each grant, rebate, or loan made under this part, including the amount of the grant, rebate, or loan;

(3) each project for which a grant, rebate, or loan is provided under this part, including the criteria used to select the grant, rebate, or loan recipients;

(4) the actual and estimated air quality and diesel fuel conservation benefits, cost-effectiveness, and cost-benefits of the grant, rebate, and loan programs under this part;

(5) the problems encountered by projects for which a grant, rebate, or loan is provided under this part;

(6) any other information the Administrator considers to be appropriate; and

(7) in the last report sent to Congress before January 1, 2016, an analysis of the need to continue the program, including an assessment of the size of the vehicle and engine fleet that could provide benefits from being retrofit under this program and a description of the number and types of applications that were not granted in the preceding year.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title VII, § 794, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 843; Pub. L. 111–364, § 2(d), Jan. 4, 2011, 124 Stat. 4060.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2011—Subsec. (b)(2) to (5). Pub. L. 111–364, § 2(d)(1), inserted “, rebate,” after “grant” wherever appearing.
Subsec. (b)(7). Pub. L. 111–364, § 2(d)(2)–(4), added par. (7).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2011 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 111–364 effective Oct. 1, 2011, except as otherwise provided, see section 4 of Pub. L. 111–364, set out as a note under section 16131 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16134_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after the date on which funds are made available under this part, and biennially thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report evaluating the implementation of the programs under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16134_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inclusions The report shall include a description of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>