<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16132" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16132/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16132/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16132"><akn:num>16132</akn:num><akn:heading>National grant, rebate, and loan programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16132. National grant, rebate, and loan programs(a) In generalThe Administrator shall use 70 percent of the funds made available to carry out this part for each fiscal year to provide grants, rebates, or low-cost revolving loans, as determined by the Administrator, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities, including through contracts entered into under subsection (e) of this section, to achieve significant reductions in diesel emissions in terms of—(1) pollution produced; and

(2) diesel emissions exposure, particularly from fleets operating in areas designated by the Administrator as poor air quality areas.


(b) Distribution(1) In generalThe Administrator shall distribute funds made available for a fiscal year under this part in accordance with this section.


(2) Engine configurations and technologies(A) Certified engine configurations and verified technologiesThe Administrator shall provide not less than 95 percent of funds available for a fiscal year under this section to eligible entities for projects using—(i) a certified engine configuration; or

(ii) a verified technology.


(B) Emerging technologies(i) In generalThe Administrator shall provide not more than 5 percent of funds available for a fiscal year under this section to eligible entities for the development and commercialization of emerging technologies.


(ii) Application and test planTo receive funds under clause (i), a manufacturer, in consultation with an eligible entity, shall submit for verification to the Administrator or the California Air Resources Board a test plan for the emerging technology, together with a verification application.





(c) Applications(1) Expedited process(A) In generalThe Administrator shall develop a simplified application process for all applicants under this section to expedite the provision of funds.


(B) RequirementsIn developing the expedited process under subparagraph (A), the Administrator—(i) shall take into consideration the special circumstances affect</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator shall use 70 percent of the funds made available to carry out this part for each fiscal year to provide grants, rebates, or low-cost revolving loans, as determined by the Administrator, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities, including through contracts entered into under subsection (e) of this section, to achieve significant reductions in diesel emissions in terms of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contract programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16132_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public notification Not later than 60 days after the date of the award of a grant, rebate, or loan, the Administrator shall publish on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>