<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16183" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16183/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16183/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16183"><akn:num>16183</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy and water for sustainability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16183. Energy and water for sustainability(a) Nexus of energy and water for sustainability(1) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Energy.


(B) Energy-water nexusThe term “energy-water nexus” means the links between—(i) the water needed to produce fuels, electricity, and other forms of energy; and

(ii) the energy needed to transport, reclaim, and treat water and wastewater.


(C) Interagency RD&amp;D Coordination CommitteeThe term “Interagency RD&amp;D Coordination Committee” means the Interagency RD&amp;D Coordination Committee on the Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (or the “NEWS RD&amp;D Committee”) established under paragraph (3)(A).


(D) Nexus of Energy and Water Sustainability RD&amp;D Office; NEWS RD&amp;D OfficeThe term “Nexus of Energy and Water Sustainability RD&amp;D Office” or the “NEWS RD&amp;D Office” means an office located at the Department and managed in cooperation with the Department of the Interior pursuant to an agreement between the 2 agencies to carry out leadership and administrative functions for the Interagency RD&amp;D Coordination Committee.


(E) RD&amp;DThe term “RD&amp;D” means research, development, and demonstration.


(F) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.



(2) Statement of policyRecognizing States’ primacy over allocation and administration of water resources (except in specific instances where preempted under Federal law) and the siting of energy infrastructure within State boundaries on non-Federal lands, it is the national policy that the Federal government, in all energy-water nexus management activities, shall maximize coordination and consultation among Federal agencies and with State and local governments, and disseminate information to the public in the most effective manner.


(3) Interagency RD&amp;D Coordination Committee(A) EstablishmentNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall establish the joint NEWS RD&amp;D Office</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16183_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nexus of energy and water for sustainability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nexus of energy and water for sustainability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16183_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrating energy and water research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Integrating energy and water research The Secretary shall integrate the following considerations into energy RD&amp;D programs and projects of the Department by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16183_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional activities The Secretary may provide for such additional RD&amp;D activities as appropriate to integrate the considerations described in subsection (b) into the RD&amp;D activities of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>