<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16191" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16191/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16191/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16191"><akn:num>16191</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy efficiency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16191. Energy efficiency(a) In general(1) ObjectivesThe Secretary shall conduct programs of energy efficiency research, development, demonstration, and commercial application, including activities described in this part. Such programs shall take into consideration the following objectives:(A) Increasing the energy efficiency of vehicles, buildings, and industrial processes.

(B) Reducing the demand of the United States for energy, especially energy from foreign sources.

(C) Reducing the cost of energy and making the economy more efficient and competitive.

(D) Improving the energy security of the United States.

(E) Reducing the environmental impact of energy-related activities.


(2) ProgramsPrograms under this part shall include research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of—(A) advanced, cost-effective technologies to improve the energy efficiency and environmental performance of vehicles, including—(i) hybrid and electric propulsion systems;

(ii) plug-in hybrid systems;

(iii) advanced combustion engines;

(iv) weight and drag reduction technologies;

(v) whole-vehicle design optimization; and

(vi) advanced drive trains;


(B) cost-effective technologies, for new construction and retrofit, to improve the energy efficiency and environmental performance of buildings, using a whole-buildings approach, including onsite renewable energy generation;

(C) advanced technologies to improve the energy efficiency, environmental performance, and process efficiency of energy-intensive and waste-intensive industries;

(D) advanced control devices to improve the energy efficiency of electric motors, including those used in industrial processes, heating, ventilation, and cooling; and

(E) technologies to improve the energy efficiency of appliances and mechanical systems for buildings in cold climates, including combined heat and power units and increased use of renewable resources, including fuel.



(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authori</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16191_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16191_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out energy efficiency and conservation research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities, including activities authorized under this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16191_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocations From amounts authorized under subsection (b), the following sums are authorized:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16191_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extended authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Extended authorization There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out section 16192 of this title $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2013.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16191_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations None of the funds authorized to be appropriated under this section may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>