<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16251" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16251/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16251/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16251"><akn:num>16251</akn:num><akn:heading>Production incentives for cellulosic biofuels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16251. Production incentives for cellulosic biofuels(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to—(1) accelerate deployment and commercialization of biofuels;

(2) deliver the first 1,000,000,000 gallons in annual cellulosic biofuels production by 2015;

(3) ensure biofuels produced after 2015 are cost competitive with gasoline and diesel; and

(4) ensure that small feedstock producers and rural small businesses are full participants in the development of the cellulosic biofuels industry.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Cellulosic biofuelsThe term “cellulosic biofuels” means any fuel that is produced from cellulosic feedstocks.


(2) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a producer of fuel from cellulosic biofuels the production facility of which—(A) is located in the United States;

(B) meets all applicable Federal and State permitting requirements; and

(C) meets any financial criteria established by the Secretary.



(c) Program(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, shall establish an incentive program for the production of cellulosic biofuels.


(2) Basis of incentivesUnder the program, the Secretary shall award production incentives on a per gallon basis of cellulosic biofuels from eligible entities, through—(A) set payments per gallon of cellulosic biofuels produced in an amount determined by the Secretary, until initiation of the first reverse auction; and

(B) reverse auction thereafter.


(3) First reverse auctionThe first reverse auction shall be held on the earlier of—(A) not later than 1 year after the first year of annual production in the United States of 100,000,000 gallons of cellulosic biofuels, as determined by the Secretary; or

(B) not later than 3 years after August 8, 2005.


(4) Reverse auction procedure(A) In generalOn initiation of the first reverse auction, and each year thereafter until the ear</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitations Awards under this section shall be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In selecting a project under the program, the Secretary shall give priority to projects that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16251_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorizations of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $250,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>