<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16279a"><akn:num>16279a</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced reactor demonstration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16279a. Advanced reactor demonstration program(a) Demonstration project definedFor the purposes of this section, the term “demonstration project” means an advanced nuclear reactor operated in any manner, including as part of the power generation facilities of an electric utility system, for the purpose of demonstrating the suitability for commercial application of the advanced nuclear reactor.


(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program to advance the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of domestic advanced, affordable, nuclear energy technologies by—(1) demonstrating a variety of advanced nuclear reactor technologies, including those that could be used to produce—(A) safer, emissions-free power at a competitive cost of electricity compared to other new energy generation technologies on December 27, 2020;

(B) heat for community heating, industrial purposes, heat storage, or synthetic fuel production;

(C) remote or off-grid energy supply; or

(D) backup or mission-critical power supplies;


(2) identifying research areas that the private sector is unable or unwilling to undertake due to the cost of, or risks associated with, the research; and

(3) facilitating the access of the private sector—(A) to Federal research facilities and personnel; and

(B) to the results of research relating to civil nuclear technology funded by the Federal Government.



(c) Demonstration projectsIn carrying out demonstration projects under the program established in subsection (b), the Secretary shall—(1) include, as an evaluation criterion, diversity in designs for the advanced nuclear reactors demonstrated under this section, including designs using various—(A) primary coolants;

(B) fuel types and compositions; and

(C) neutron spectra;


(2) consider, as evaluation criterions—(A) the likelihood that the operating cost for future commercial units for each design implemented through a demonstration project under this subsection is cost-co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration project defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Demonstration project defined For the purposes of this section, the term “demonstration project” means an advanced nuclear reactor operated in any manner, including as part of the power generation facilities of an electric utility system, for the purpose of demonstrating the suitability for commercial application of the advanced nuclear reactor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program to advance the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of domestic advanced, affordable, nuclear energy technologies by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Demonstration projects In carrying out demonstration projects under the program established in subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Milestone-based demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Milestone-based demonstration projects The Secretary may carry out demonstration projects under subsection (c) as a milestone-based demonstration project under section 7256c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonduplication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nonduplication Entities may not receive funds under this program if receiving funds from another reactor demonstration program at the Department in the same fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the program under this subsection—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>