<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16279c"><akn:num>16279c</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization and administration of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16279c. Organization and administration of programs(a) CoordinationIn carrying out this part, the Secretary shall coordinate activities, and effectively manage crosscutting research priorities across programs of the Department and other relevant Federal agencies, including the National Laboratories.


(b) Collaboration(1) In generalIn carrying out this part, the Secretary shall collaborate with industry, National Laboratories, other relevant Federal agencies, institutions of higher education, including minority-serving institutions and research reactors, Tribal entities, including Alaska Native Corporations, and international bodies with relevant scientific and technical expertise.


(2) ParticipationTo the extent practicable, the Secretary shall encourage research projects that promote collaboration between entities specified in paragraph (1).



(c) Dissemination of results and public availabilityThe Secretary shall, except to the extent protected from disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5, publish the results of projects supported under this part through Department websites, reports, databases, training materials, and industry conferences, including information discovered after the completion of such projects.


(d) Education and outreachIn carrying out the activities described in this part, the Secretary shall support education and outreach activities to disseminate information and promote public understanding of nuclear energy.


(e) Technical assistanceIn carrying out this part, for the purposes of supporting technical, nonhardware, and information-based advances in nuclear energy development and operations, the Secretary shall also conduct technical assistance and analysis activities, including activities that support commercial application of nuclear energy in rural, Tribal, and low-income communities.


(f) Program reviewAt least annually, all programs in this part shall be subject to an annual review by the Nuclear Energy Advisory Committee of the D</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordination In carrying out this part, the Secretary shall coordinate activities, and effectively manage crosscutting research priorities across programs of the Department and other relevant Federal agencies, including the National Laboratories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collaboration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of results and public availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination of results and public availability The Secretary shall, except to the extent protected from disclosure under section 552(b) of title 5, publish the results of projects supported under this part through Department websites, reports, databases, training materials, and industry conferences, including information discovered after the completion of such projects.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Education and outreach In carrying out the activities described in this part, the Secretary shall support education and outreach activities to disseminate information and promote public understanding of nuclear energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance In carrying out this part, for the purposes of supporting technical, nonhardware, and information-based advances in nuclear energy development and operations, the Secretary shall also conduct technical assistance and analysis activities, including activities that support commercial application of nuclear energy in rural, Tribal, and low-income communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Program review At least annually, all programs in this part shall be subject to an annual review by the Nuclear Energy Advisory Committee of the Department or other independent entity, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sensitive information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sensitive information The Secretary shall not publish any information generated under this part that is detrimental to national security, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>