<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16279/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16279"><akn:num>16279</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16279. Budget plan(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after September 28, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives 2 alternative 10-year budget plans for civilian nuclear energy research and development by the Secretary, as described in subsections (b) through (d).


(b) Budget plan alternative 1One of the budget plans submitted under subsection (a) shall assume constant annual funding for 10 years at the appropriated level for the current fiscal year for the civilian nuclear energy research and development of the Department.


(c) Budget plan alternative 2One of the budget plans submitted under subsection (a) shall be an unconstrained budget.


(d) InclusionsEach alternative budget plan submitted under subsection (a) shall include—(1) a prioritized list of the programs, projects, and activities of the Department to best support the development of advanced nuclear reactor technologies;

(2) realistic budget requirements for the Department to implement sections 16275(c), 16277, and 16278 of this title;

(3) the justification of the Department for continuing or terminating existing civilian nuclear energy research and development programs; and

(4) a description of the progress made under the programs described in section 16279a of this title.


(e) UpdatesNot less frequently than once every 2 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate updated 10-year budget plans which shall identify, and provide a justification for, any major deviation from a previous budget plan submitted under this section.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title IX, § 959, as added Pub. L. 115–248, § 2(i), Sept. 28, 2018, 132 Stat. 3160; amended Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title II, § 2005, 134 Stat. 2470.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2020—S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after September 28, 2018, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives 2 alternative 10-year budget plans for civilian nuclear energy research and development by the Secretary, as described in subsections (b) through (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget plan alternative 1</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Budget plan alternative 1 One of the budget plans submitted under subsection (a) shall assume constant annual funding for 10 years at the appropriated level for the current fiscal year for the civilian nuclear energy research and development of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Budget plan alternative 2</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Budget plan alternative 2 One of the budget plans submitted under subsection (a) shall be an unconstrained budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusions Each alternative budget plan submitted under subsection (a) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16279_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Updates Not less frequently than once every 2 years, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate updated 10-year budget plans which shall identify, and provide a justification for, any major deviation from a previous budget plan submitted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>