<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16282" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16282/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16282/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16282"><akn:num>16282</akn:num><akn:heading>U.S. nuclear fuel security initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16282. U.S. nuclear fuel security initiative(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Nuclear Fuel Security Act of 2023”.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(1) the Department should—(A) support increased domestic production of low-enriched uranium; and

(B) accelerate efforts to establish a domestic high-assay, low-enriched uranium enrichment capability; and


(2) if domestic enrichment of high-assay, low-enriched uranium will not be commercially available at the scale needed in time to meet the needs of the advanced nuclear reactor demonstration projects of the Department, the Secretary shall consider and implement, as necessary—(A) all viable options to make high-assay, low-enriched uranium produced from inventories owned by the Department available in a manner that is sufficient to maximize the potential for the Department to meet the needs and schedules of advanced nuclear reactor developers, without impacting existing Department missions, until such time that commercial enrichment and deconversion capability for high-assay, low-enriched uranium exists at a scale sufficient to meet future needs; and

(B) all viable options for partnering with countries that are allies or partners of the United States to meet those needs and schedules until that time.



(c) ObjectivesThe objectives of this section are—(1) to support domestic production of low-enriched uranium;

(2) to expeditiously increase domestic production of high-assay, low-enriched uranium by an annual quantity, and in such form, determined by the Secretary to be sufficient to meet the needs of—(A) advanced nuclear reactor developers; and

(B) the consortium;


(3) to ensure the availability of domestically produced, converted, enriched, deconverted, and reduced uranium in a quantity determined by the Secretary, in consultation with U.S. nuclear energy companies, to be sufficient to address a reasonably anticipated supply disruption;

(4) to address gaps and deficiencies in t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Nuclear Fuel Security Act of 2023”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Objectives The objectives of this section are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and expansion of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Establishment and expansion of programs The Secretary, consistent with the objectives described in subsection (c), shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Fuel Security Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nuclear Fuel Security Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion of the American Assured Fuel Supply Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Expansion of the American Assured Fuel Supply Program The Secretary, in consultation with U.S. nuclear energy companies, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>HALEU for Advanced Nuclear Reactor Demonstration Projects Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) HALEU for Advanced Nuclear Reactor Demonstration Projects Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Domestic sourcing considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Domestic sourcing considerations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16282_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reasonable compensation In carrying out activities under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that any LEU and HALEU made available by the Secretary under 1 or more of the Programs is subject to reasonable compensation, taking into account the fair market value of the LEU or HALEU and the purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>