<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16280" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16280/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16280/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16280"><akn:num>16280</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced Nuclear Energy Licensing Cost-Share Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16280. Advanced Nuclear Energy Licensing Cost-Share Grant Program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) CommissionThe term “Commission” means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.


(2) ProgramThe term “program” means the Advanced Nuclear Energy Cost-Share Grant Program established under subsection (b).


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.



(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a grant program, to be known as the “Advanced Nuclear Energy Cost-Share Grant Program”, under which the Secretary shall make cost-share grants to applicants for the purpose of funding a portion of the Commission fees of the applicant for pre-application review activities and application review activities.


(c) RequirementThe Secretary shall seek out technology diversity in making grants under the program.


(d) Cost-share amountThe Secretary shall determine the cost-share amount for each grant under the program in accordance with section 16352 of this title.


(e) Use of fundsA recipient of a grant under the program may use the grant funds to cover Commission fees, including those fees associated with—(1) developing a licensing project plan;

(2) obtaining a statement of licensing feasibility;

(3) reviewing topical reports; and

(4) other—(A) pre-application review activities;

(B) application review activities; and

(C) interactions with the Commission.



(Pub. L. 115–248, § 3, Sept. 28, 2018, 132 Stat. 3160.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Nuclear Energy Innovation Capabilities Act of 2017, and not as part of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16280_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16280_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a grant program, to be known as the “Advanced Nuclear Energy Cost-Share Grant Program”, under which the Secretary shall make cost-share grants to applicants for the purpose of funding a portion of the Commission fees of the applicant for pre-application review activities and application review activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16280_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement The Secretary shall seek out technology diversity in making grants under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16280_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-share amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cost-share amount The Secretary shall determine the cost-share amount for each grant under the program in accordance with section 16352 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16280_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds A recipient of a grant under the program may use the grant funds to cover Commission fees, including those fees associated with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>