<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16298a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16298a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16298a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16298a"><akn:num>16298a</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbon utilization program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16298a. Carbon utilization program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, and demonstration for carbon utilization—(1) to assess and monitor—(A) potential changes in lifecycle carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions; and

(B) other environmental safety indicators of new technologies, practices, processes, or methods used in enhanced hydrocarbon recovery as part of the activities authorized under section 16293 of this title;


(2) to identify and assess novel uses for carbon, including the conversion of carbon and carbon oxides for commercial and industrial products and other products with potential market value;

(3) to develop or obtain, in coordination with other applicable Federal agencies and standard-setting organizations, standards and certifications, as appropriate, to facilitate the commercialization of the products and technologies described in paragraph (2);

(4) to identify and assess carbon capture technologies for industrial systems; and

(5) to identify and assess alternative uses for raw coal and processed coal products in all phases that result in no significant emissions of carbon dioxide or other pollutants, including products derived from carbon engineering, carbon fiber, and coal conversion methods.


(b) Demonstration programs for the purpose of commercialization(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, as part of the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish a 2-year demonstration program in each of the 2 major coal-producing regions of the United States for the purpose of partnering with private institutions in coal mining regions to accelerate the commercial deployment of coal-carbon products.


(2) Grant program(A) In generalNot later than 1 year after November 15, 2021, the Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible entities to use in accordance with subparagraph (D).


(B) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to receive </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16298a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, and demonstration for carbon utilization—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16298a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration programs for the purpose of commercialization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Demonstration programs for the purpose of commercialization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16298a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carbon Utilization Research Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Carbon Utilization Research Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16298a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16298a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination The Secretary shall coordinate the activities authorized in this section with the activities authorized in section 16298 of this title as part of one consolidated program at the Department. Nothing in section 16298 of this title shall be construed as limiting the authorities provided in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>