<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16291" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16291/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16291/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16291"><akn:num>16291</akn:num><akn:heading>Fossil energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16291. Fossil energy(a) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs in fossil energy, including activities under this part, with the goal of improving the efficiency, effectiveness, and environmental performance of fossil energy production, upgrading, conversion, and consumption.


(2) ObjectivesThe programs described in paragraph (1) shall take into consideration the following objectives:(A) Increasing the energy conversion efficiency of all forms of fossil energy through improved technologies.

(B) Decreasing the cost of all fossil energy production, generation, and delivery.

(C) Promoting diversity of energy supply.

(D) Decreasing the dependence of the United States on foreign energy supplies.

(E) Improving United States energy security.

(F) Decreasing the environmental impact of energy-related activities, including technology development to reduce emissions of carbon dioxide and associated emissions of heavy metals within coal combustion residues and gas streams resulting from fossil fuel use and production.

(G) Increasing the export of fossil energy-related equipment, technology, including emissions control technologies, and services from the United States.

(H) Decreasing the cost of emissions control technologies for fossil energy production, generation, and delivery.

(I) Significantly lowering greenhouse gas emissions for all fossil fuel production, generation, delivery, and utilization technologies.

(J) Developing carbon removal and utilization technologies, products, and methods that result in net reductions in greenhouse gas emissions, including direct air capture and storage, and carbon use and reuse for commercial application.

(K) Improving the conversion, use, and storage of carbon oxides produced from fossil fuels.

(L) Reducing water use, improving water reuse, and minimizing surface and subsurface environmental impact in the development of unconventional</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16291_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16291_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out fossil energy research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities, including activities authorized under this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16291_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocations From amounts authorized under subsection (a), the following sums are authorized:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16291_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extended authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Extended authorization There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for the Office of Arctic Energy established under section 7144d of this title $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16291_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>