<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16311"><akn:num>16311</akn:num><akn:heading>Science</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16311. Science(a) In generalThe Secretary shall conduct, through the Office of Science, programs of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in high energy physics, nuclear physics, biological and environmental research, basic energy sciences, advanced scientific computing research, and fusion energy sciences, including activities described in this part. The programs shall include support for facilities and infrastructure, education, outreach, information, analysis, and coordination activities.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities of the Office of Science, including activities authorized under this part (including the amounts authorized under the amendment made by section 976(b) 11 See References in Text note below. and including basic energy sciences, advanced scientific and computing research, biological and environmental research, fusion energy sciences, high energy physics, nuclear physics, research analysis, and infrastructure support)—(1) $4,153,000,000 for fiscal year 2007;

(2) $4,586,000,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(3) $5,200,000,000 for fiscal year 2009;

(4) $5,814,000,000 for fiscal year 2010;

(5) $5,247,000,000 for fiscal year 2011;

(6) $5,614,000,000 for fiscal year 2012; and

(7) $6,007,000,000 for fiscal year 2013.


(c) AllocationsFrom amounts authorized under subsection (b), the following sums are authorized:(1) For activities under the Fusion Energy Sciences program (including activities under section 16312 of this title)—(A) $355,500,000 for fiscal year 2007;

(B) $369,500,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(C) $384,800,000 for fiscal year 2009; and

(D) in addition to the amounts authorized under subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), such sums as may be necessary for ITER construction, consistent with the limitations of section 16312(c)(5) of this title.


(2) For activities under the cat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall conduct, through the Office of Science, programs of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in high energy physics, nuclear physics, biological and environmental research, basic energy sciences, advanced scientific computing research, and fusion energy sciences, including activities described in this part. The programs shall include support for facilities and infrastructure, education, outreach, information, analysis, and coordination activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities of the Office of Science, including activities authorized under this part (including the amounts authorized under the amendment made by section 976(b) 11 See References in Text note below. and including basic energy sciences, advanced scientific and computing research, biological and environmental research, fusion energy sciences, high energy physics, nuclear physics, research analysis, and infrastructure support)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocations From amounts authorized under subsection (b), the following sums are authorized:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16311_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Integrated bioenergy research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Integrated bioenergy research and development In addition to amounts otherwise authorized by this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for integrated bioenergy research and development programs, projects, and activities, $49,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2005 through 2009. Activities funded under this subsection shall be coordinated with ongoing related programs of other Federal agencies, including the Plant Genome Program of the National Science Foundation. Of the funds authorized under this subsection, at least $5,000,000 for each fiscal year shall be for training and education targeted to minority and socially disadvantaged farmers and ranchers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>