<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16317" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16317/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16317/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16317"><akn:num>16317</akn:num><akn:heading>Systems biology program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16317. Systems biology program(a) Program(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a research, development, and demonstration program in microbial and plant systems biology, protein science, computational biology, and environmental science to support the energy, national security, and environmental missions of the Department.


(2) GrantsThe program shall support individual researchers and multidisciplinary teams of researchers through competitive, merit-reviewed grants.


(3) ConsultationIn carrying out the program, the Secretary shall consult with other Federal agencies that conduct genetic and protein research.



(b) GoalsThe program shall have the goal of developing technologies and methods based on the biological functions of genomes, microbes, and plants that—(1) can facilitate the production of fuels, including hydrogen in sustainable production systems that reduce greenhouse gas emissions;

(2) convert carbon dioxide to organic carbon;

(3) detoxify soils and water, including at facilities of the Department, contaminated with heavy metals and radiological materials;

(4) develop cellulosic and other feedstocks that are less resource and land intensive and that promote sustainable use of resources, including soil, water, energy, forests, and land, and ensure protection of air, water, and soil quality; and

(5) address other Department missions as identified by the Secretary.


(c) Plan(1) Development of planNot later than 1 year after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall prepare and transmit to Congress a research plan describing how the program authorized pursuant to this section will be undertaken to accomplish the program goals established in subsection (b).


(2) Review of planThe Secretary shall contract with the National Academy of Sciences to review the research plan developed under this subsection. The Secretary shall transmit the review to Congress not later than 18 months after transmittal of the research plan under paragraph (1), along with </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Goals The program shall have the goal of developing technologies and methods based on the biological functions of genomes, microbes, and plants that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>User facilities and ancillary equipment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) User facilities and ancillary equipment Within the funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to this part, amounts shall be available for projects to develop, plan, construct, acquire, or operate special equipment, instrumentation, or facilities, including user facilities at National Laboratories, for researchers conducting research, development, demonstration, and commercial application in systems biology and proteomics and associated biological disciplines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on biomedical and human cell and human subject research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on biomedical and human cell and human subject research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16317_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bioenergy research centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Bioenergy research centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>