<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16352" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16352/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16352/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16352"><akn:num>16352</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16352. Cost sharing(a) ApplicabilityNotwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application program or activity that is initiated after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall require cost-sharing in accordance with this section.


(b) Research and development(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) and subsection (f), the Secretary shall require not less than 20 percent of the cost of a research or development activity described in subsection (a) to be provided by a non-Federal source.


(2) ExclusionParagraph (1) shall not apply to a research or development activity described in subsection (a) that is of a basic or fundamental nature, as determined by the appropriate officer of the Department.


(3) ReductionThe Secretary may reduce or eliminate the requirement of paragraph (1) for a research and development activity of an applied nature if the Secretary determines that the reduction is necessary and appropriate.


(4) Exemption for institutions of higher education and other nonprofit institutions(A) In generalParagraph (1) shall not apply to a research or development activity performed by an institution of higher education or nonprofit institution (as defined in section 4 of the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (15 U.S.C. 3703)).


(B) Termination dateThe exemption under subparagraph (A) shall apply during the 2-year period beginning on August 9, 2022.




(c) Demonstration and commercial application(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2) and subsection (f), the Secretary shall require that not less than 50 percent of the cost of a demonstration or commercial application activity described in subsection (a) to 11 So in original. The word “to” probably should not appear. be provided by a non-Federal source.


(2) Reduction of non-Federal shareThe Secretary may reduce the non-Federal share required under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in carrying out a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application program or activity that is initiated after August 8, 2005, the Secretary shall require cost-sharing in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research and development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration and commercial application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Demonstration and commercial application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Calculation of amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Calculation of amount In calculating the amount of a non-Federal contribution under this section, the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Repayment of Federal share The Secretary shall not require repayment of the Federal share of a cost-shared activity under this section as a condition of making an award.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16352_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exclusions This section shall not apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>