<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16354"><akn:num>16354</akn:num><akn:heading>External technical review of departmental programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16354. External technical review of departmental programs(a) National energy research and development advisory boards(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish one or more advisory boards to review research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs of the Department in energy efficiency, renewable energy, nuclear energy, and fossil energy.


(2) AlternativesThe Secretary may—(A) designate an existing advisory board within the Department to fulfill the responsibilities of an advisory board under this section; and

(B) enter into appropriate arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences to establish such an advisory board.



(b) Use of existing committeesThe Secretary shall continue to use the scientific program advisory committees chartered under chapter 10 of title 5 by the Office of Science to oversee research and development programs under that Office.


(c) MembershipEach advisory board under this section shall consist of persons with appropriate expertise representing a diverse range of interests.


(d) Meetings and goals(1) MeetingsEach advisory board under this section shall meet at least semiannually to review and advise on the progress made by the respective one or more research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs.


(2) GoalsThe advisory board shall review the measurable cost and performance-based goals for the programs as established under section 16181 of this title, and the progress on meeting the goals.



(e) Periodic reviews and assessments(1) In generalThe Secretary shall enter into appropriate arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct periodic reviews and assessments of—(A) the research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs authorized by this Act and amendments made by this Act;

(B) the measurable cost and performance-based goals for the programs as established under section 16181 of this title, if any; and

(C) the progress on meeting the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National energy research and development advisory boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National energy research and development advisory boards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of existing committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of existing committees The Secretary shall continue to use the scientific program advisory committees chartered under chapter 10 of title 5 by the Office of Science to oversee research and development programs under that Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16354_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership Each advisory board under this section shall consist of persons with appropriate expertise representing a diverse range of interests.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16354_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings and goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Meetings and goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16354_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reviews and assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Periodic reviews and assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>