<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16372" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16372/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16372/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16372"><akn:num>16372</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of eligibility and project selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16372. Determination of eligibility and project selection(a) Establishment of programThe Secretary shall establish and carry out a carbon dioxide transportation infrastructure finance and innovation program, under which the Secretary shall provide for eligible projects in accordance with this part—(1) a Federal credit instrument under section 16373 of this title;

(2) a grant under section 16374 of this title; or

(3) both a Federal credit instrument and a grant.


(b) Eligibility(1) In generalA project shall be eligible to receive a Federal credit instrument or a grant under the CIFIA program if—(A) the entity proposing to carry out the project submits a letter of interest prior to submission of an application under paragraph (3) for the project; and

(B) the project meets the criteria described in this subsection.


(2) Creditworthiness(A) In generalEach project and obligor that receives a Federal credit instrument or a grant under the CIFIA program shall be creditworthy, such that there exists a reasonable prospect of repayment of the principal and interest on the Federal credit instrument, as determined by the Secretary under subparagraph (B).


(B) Reasonable prospect of repaymentThe Secretary shall base a determination of whether there is a reasonable prospect of repayment under subparagraph (A) on a comprehensive evaluation of whether the obligor has a reasonable prospect of repaying the Federal credit instrument for the eligible project, including evaluation of—(i) the strength of the contractual terms of an eligible project (if available for the applicable market segment);

(ii) the forecast of noncontractual cash flows supported by market projections from reputable sources, as determined by the Secretary, and cash sweeps or other structural enhancements;

(iii) the projected financial strength of the obligor—(I) at the time of loan close; and

(II) throughout the loan term, including after the project is completed;


(iv) the financial strength of the in</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program The Secretary shall establish and carry out a carbon dioxide transportation infrastructure finance and innovation program, under which the Secretary shall provide for eligible projects in accordance with this part—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection among eligible projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection among eligible projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of American iron, steel, and manufactured goods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of American iron, steel, and manufactured goods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application processing procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Application processing procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16372_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development-phase activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Development-phase activities Any Federal credit instrument provided under the CIFIA program may be used to finance up to 100 percent of the cost of development-phase activities, as described in section 16371(4)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>