<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16371" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16371/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16371/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16371"><akn:num>16371</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16371. Definitions
In this part:(1) CIFIA programThe term “CIFIA program” means the carbon dioxide transportation infrastructure finance and innovation program established under section 16372(a) of this title.


(2) Common carrierThe term “common carrier” means a transportation infrastructure operator or owner that—(A) publishes a publicly available tariff containing the just and reasonable rates, terms, and conditions of nondiscriminatory service; and

(B) holds itself out to provide transportation services to the public for a fee.


(3) Contingent commitmentThe term “contingent commitment” means a commitment to obligate funds from future available budget authority that is—(A) contingent on those funds being made available in law at a future date; and

(B) not an obligation of the Federal Government.


(4) Eligible project costsThe term “eligible project costs” means amounts substantially all of which are paid by, or for the account of, an obligor in connection with a project, including—(A) the cost of—(i) development-phase activities, including planning, feasibility analysis, revenue forecasting, environmental review, permitting, preliminary engineering and design work, and other preconstruction activities;

(ii) construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, replacement, and acquisition of real property (including land relating to the project and improvements to land), environmental mitigation, construction contingencies, and acquisition and installation of equipment (including labor); and

(iii) capitalized interest necessary to meet market requirements, reasonably required reserve funds, capital issuance expenses, and other carrying costs during construction; and


(B) transaction costs associated with financing the project, including—(i) the cost of legal counsel and technical consultants; and

(ii) any subsidy amount paid in accordance with section 16372(c)(3)(B)(ii) of this title or section 16373(b)(6)(B)(ii) of this title.



(5) Federal credit instrumentT</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>CIFIA program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) CIFIA program The term “CIFIA program” means the carbon dioxide transportation infrastructure finance and innovation program established under section 16372(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common carrier</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Common carrier The term “common carrier” means a transportation infrastructure operator or owner that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingent commitment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Contingent commitment The term “contingent commitment” means a commitment to obligate funds from future available budget authority that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible project costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Eligible project costs The term “eligible project costs” means amounts substantially all of which are paid by, or for the account of, an obligor in connection with a project, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal credit instrument</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Federal credit instrument The term “Federal credit instrument” means a secured loan or loan guarantee authorized to be provided under the CIFIA program with respect to a project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lender</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Lender The term “lender” means a qualified institutional buyer (as defined in section 230.144A(a) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), commonly known as Rule 144A(a) of the Securities and Exchange Commission and issued under the Securities Act of 1933 (15 U.S.C. 77a et seq.)), that is not a Federal qualified institutional buyer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Letter of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Letter of interest The term “letter of interest” means a letter submitted by a potential applicant prior to an application for credit assistance in a format prescribed by the Secretary on the website of the CIFIA program that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Loan guarantee The term “loan guarantee” means any guarantee or other pledge by the Secretary to pay all or part of the principal of, and interest on, a loan made to an obligor, or debt obligation issued by an obligor, in each case funded by a lender.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Master credit agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Master credit agreement The term “master credit agreement” means a conditional agreement that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16371_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Obligor The term “obligor” means a corporation, partnership, joint venture, trust, non-Federal governmental entity, agency, or instrumentality, or other entity that is liable for payment of the principal of, or interest on, a Federal credit instrument.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>