<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16392" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16392/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16392/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16392"><akn:num>16392</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology Infrastructure Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16392. Technology Infrastructure Program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ProgramThe term “Program” means the Technology Infrastructure Program established under subsection (b).


(2) Technology clusterThe term “technology cluster” means a concentration of technology-related business concerns, institutions of higher education, or nonprofit institutions, that reinforce each other’s performance in the areas of technology development through formal or informal relationships.


(3) Technology-related business concernThe term “technology-related business concern” means a for-profit corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, or small business concern that—(A) conducts scientific or engineering research;

(B) develops new technologies;

(C) manufactures products based on new technologies; or

(D) performs technological services.



(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a Technology Infrastructure Program in accordance with this section.


(c) PurposeThe purpose of the Program shall be to improve the ability of National Laboratories and single-purpose research facilities to support departmental missions by—(1) stimulating the development of technology clusters that can support departmental missions at the National Laboratories or single-purpose research facilities;

(2) improving the ability of National Laboratories and single-purpose research facilities to leverage and benefit from commercial research, technology, products, processes, and services; and

(3) encouraging the exchange of scientific and technological expertise between—(A) National Laboratories or single-purpose research facilities; and

(B) entities that can support departmental missions at the National Laboratories or single-purpose research facilities, such as—(i) institutions of higher education;

(ii) technology-related business concerns;

(iii) nonprofit institutions; and

(iv) agencies of State, tribal, or local governments.




(d) ProjectsThe Secretary shall authorize the directo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a Technology Infrastructure Program in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose The purpose of the Program shall be to improve the ability of National Laboratories and single-purpose research facilities to support departmental missions by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Projects The Secretary shall authorize the director of each National Laboratory or single-purpose research facility to implement the Program at the National Laboratory or facility through one or more projects that meet the requirements of subsections (e) and (f).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Selection criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Allocation In allocating funds for projects approved under this section, the Secretary shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not later than July 1, 2008, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on whether the Program should be continued and, if so, how the program should be managed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16392_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for activities under this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2008.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>