<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16391" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16391/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16391/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16391"><akn:num>16391</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved technology transfer of energy technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16391. Improved technology transfer of energy technologies(a) Office of Technology Transitions(1) EstablishmentThere is established within the Department an Office of Technology Transitions (referred to in this section as the “Office”).


(2) MissionThe mission of the Office shall be—(A) to expand the commercial impact of the research investments of the Department; and

(B) to focus on commercializing technologies that support the missions of the Department, including reducing greenhouse gas emissions and other pollutants.


(3) Goals(A) In generalIn carrying out the mission and activities of the Office, the Chief Commercialization Officer appointed under paragraph (4) shall, with respect to commercialization activities, meet all of the goals described in subparagraph (B).


(B) Goals describedThe goals referred to in subparagraph (A) are the following:(i) Reduction of greenhouse gas emissions and other pollutants.

(ii) Ensuring economic competitiveness.

(iii) Enhancement of domestic energy security and national security.

(iv) Enhancement of domestic jobs.

(v) Improvement of energy efficiency.

(vi) Any other goals to support the transfer of technology developed by Department-funded programs to the private sector, as consistent with missions of the Department.



(4) Chief Commercialization Officer(A) In generalThe Office shall be headed by an officer, who shall be known as the “Chief Commercialization Officer”, and who shall report directly to, and be appointed by, the Secretary.


(B) Principal advisorThe Chief Commercialization Officer shall be the principal advisor to the Secretary on all matters relating to technology transfer and commercialization.


(C) QualificationsThe Chief Commercialization Officer shall be an individual who, by reason of professional background and experience, is specially qualified to advise the Secretary on matters pertaining to technology transfer at the Department.


(D) DutiesThe Chief Commercialization Officer shall oversee—(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Technology Transitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office of Technology Transitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology Transfer Working Group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Technology Transfer Working Group The Secretary shall establish a Technology Transfer Working Group, which shall consist of representatives of the National Laboratories and single-purpose research facilities, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology Commercialization Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technology Commercialization Fund The Secretary shall establish an Energy Technology Commercialization Fund, using 0.9 percent of the amount made available to the Department for applied energy research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for each fiscal year based on future planned activities and the amount of the appropriations for the fiscal year, to be used to provide matching funds with private partners to promote promising energy technologies for commercial purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology transfer responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technology transfer responsibility Nothing in this section affects the technology transfer responsibilities of Federal employees under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 (15 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology Commercialization Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technology Commercialization Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Annual report The Secretary shall include in the annual report required under section 16391a(a) of this title—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology commercialization fund report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technology commercialization fund report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Planning and reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16391_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional technology transfer programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Additional technology transfer programs The Secretary may develop additional programs to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>