<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16421" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16421/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16421/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16421"><akn:num>16421</akn:num><akn:heading>Third-party finance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16421. Third-party finance(a) Existing facilitiesThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration (hereinafter in this section referred to as “WAPA”), or through the Administrator of the Southwestern Power Administration (hereinafter in this section referred to as “SWPA”), or both, may design, develop, construct, operate, maintain, or own, or participate with other entities in designing, developing, constructing, operating, maintaining, or owning, an electric power transmission facility and related facilities (“Project”) needed to upgrade existing transmission facilities owned by SWPA or WAPA if the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Administrator, determines that the proposed Project—(1)(A) is located in a national interest electric transmission corridor designated under section 216(a) of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 824p(a)] and will reduce congestion of electric transmission in interstate commerce; or

(B) is necessary to accommodate an actual or projected increase in demand for electric transmission capacity;


(2) is consistent with—(A) transmission needs identified, in a transmission expansion plan or otherwise, by the appropriate Transmission Organization (as defined in the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.]), if any, or approved regional reliability organization; and

(B) efficient and reliable operation of the transmission grid; and


(3) would be operated in conformance with prudent utility practice.


(b) New facilitiesThe Secretary, acting through WAPA or SWPA, or both, may design, develop, construct, operate, maintain, or own, or participate with other entities in designing, developing, constructing, operating, maintaining, or owning, a new electric power transmission facility and related facilities (“Project”) located within any State in which WAPA or SWPA operates if the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Administrator, determines that the proposed Project—(1)(A) is located </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing facilities The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration (hereinafter in this section referred to as “WAPA”), or through the Administrator of the Southwestern Power Administration (hereinafter in this section referred to as “SWPA”), or both, may design, develop, construct, operate, maintain, or own, or participate with other entities in designing, developing, constructing, operating, maintaining, or owning, an electric power transmission facility and related facilities (“Project”) needed to upgrade existing transmission facilities owned by SWPA or WAPA if the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Administrator, determines that the proposed Project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>New facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) New facilities The Secretary, acting through WAPA or SWPA, or both, may design, develop, construct, operate, maintain, or own, or participate with other entities in designing, developing, constructing, operating, maintaining, or owning, a new electric power transmission facility and related facilities (“Project”) located within any State in which WAPA or SWPA operates if the Secretary, in consultation with the applicable Administrator, determines that the proposed Project—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to other laws Nothing in this section affects any requirement of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Savings clause Nothing in this section shall constrain or restrict an Administrator in the utilization of other authority delegated to the Administrator of WAPA or SWPA.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Secretarial determinations Any determination made pursuant to subsections 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection”. (a) or (b) shall be based on findings by the Secretary using the best available data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16421_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum funding amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Maximum funding amount The Secretary shall not accept and use more than $100,000,000 under subsection (c)(1) for the period encompassing fiscal years 2006 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>