<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16431" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16431/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16431/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16431"><akn:num>16431</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal utility participation in transmission organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16431. Federal utility participation in transmission organizations(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Appropriate Federal regulatory authorityThe term “appropriate Federal regulatory authority” means—(A) in the case of a Federal power marketing agency, the Secretary, except that the Secretary may designate the Administrator of a Federal power marketing agency to act as the appropriate Federal regulatory authority with respect to the transmission system of the Federal power marketing agency; and

(B) in the case of the Tennessee Valley Authority, the Board of Directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority.


(2) Federal power marketing agencyThe term “Federal power marketing agency” has the meaning given the term in section 796 of title 16.


(3) Federal utilityThe term “Federal utility” means—(A) a Federal power marketing agency; or

(B) the Tennessee Valley Authority.


(4) Transmission OrganizationThe term “Transmission Organization” has the meaning given the term in section 796 of title 16.


(5) Transmission systemThe term “transmission system” means an electric transmission facility owned, leased, or contracted for by the United States and operated by a Federal utility.



(b) TransferThe appropriate Federal regulatory authority may enter into a contract, agreement, or other arrangement transferring control and use of all or part of the transmission system of a Federal utility to a Transmission Organization.


(c) ContentsThe contract, agreement, or arrangement shall include—(1) performance standards for operation and use of the transmission system that the head of the Federal utility determines are necessary or appropriate, including standards that ensure—(A) recovery of all of the costs and expenses of the Federal utility related to the transmission facilities that are the subject of the contract, agreement, or other arrangement;

(B) consistency with existing contracts and third-party financing arrangements; and

(C) consistency with the statutory authorities,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16431_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16431_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer The appropriate Federal regulatory authority may enter into a contract, agreement, or other arrangement transferring control and use of all or part of the transmission system of a Federal utility to a Transmission Organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16431_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents The contract, agreement, or arrangement shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16431_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Commission Neither this section, actions taken pursuant to this section, nor any other transaction of a Federal utility participating in a Transmission Organization shall confer on the Commission jurisdiction or authority over—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16431_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing statutory and other obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Existing statutory and other obligations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>