<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16493" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16493/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16493/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16493"><akn:num>16493</akn:num><akn:heading>National Priority Project Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16493. National Priority Project Designation(a) Designation of National Priority Projects(1) In generalThere is established the National Priority Project Designation (referred to in this section as the “Designation”), which shall be evidenced by a medal bearing the inscription “National Priority Project”.


(2) Design and materialsThe medal shall be of such design and materials and bear such additional inscriptions as the President may prescribe.



(b) Making and presentation of Designation(1) In generalThe President, on the basis of recommendations made by the Secretary, shall annually designate organizations that have—(A) advanced the field of renewable energy technology and contributed to North American energy independence; and

(B) been certified by the Secretary under subsection (e).


(2) PresentationThe President shall designate projects with such ceremonies as the President may prescribe.


(3) Use of DesignationAn organization that receives a Designation under this section may publicize the Designation of the organization as a National Priority Project in advertising.


(4) Categories in which the Designation may be givenSeparate Designations shall be made to qualifying projects in each of the following categories:(A) Wind and biomass energy generation projects.

(B) Photovoltaic and fuel cell energy generation projects.

(C) Energy efficient building and renewable energy projects.

(D) First-in-Class projects.



(c) Selection criteria(1) In generalCertification and selection of the projects to receive the Designation shall be based on criteria established under this subsection.


(2) Wind, biomass, and building projectsIn the case of a wind, biomass, or building project, the project shall demonstrate that the project will install not less than 30 megawatts of renewable energy generation capacity.


(3) Solar photovoltaic and fuel cell projectsIn the case of a solar photovoltaic or fuel cell project, the project shall demonstrate that the project will i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of National Priority Projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of National Priority Projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Making and presentation of Designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Making and presentation of Designation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Selection criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16493_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>