<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16494" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16494/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16494/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16494"><akn:num>16494</akn:num><akn:heading>Oxygen-fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16494. Oxygen-fuel(a) ProgramThe Secretary shall establish a program on oxygen-fuel systems. If feasible, the program shall include renovation of at least one existing large unit and one existing small unit, and construction of one new large unit and one new small unit.


(b) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section—(1) $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2006;

(2) $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2007; and

(3) $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2008.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section—(1) the term “large unit” means a unit with a generating capacity of 100 megawatts or more;

(2) the term “oxygen-fuel systems” means systems that utilize fuel efficiency benefits of oil, gas, coal, and biomass combustion using substantially pure oxygen, with high flame temperatures and the exclusion of air from the boiler, in industrial or electric utility steam generating units; and

(3) the term “small unit” means a unit with a generating capacity in the 10–50 megawatt range.


(Pub. L. 109–58, title XIV, § 1407, Aug. 8, 2005, 119 Stat. 1064.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16494_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program The Secretary shall establish a program on oxygen-fuel systems. If feasible, the program shall include renovation of at least one existing large unit and one existing small unit, and construction of one new large unit and one new small unit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16494_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16494_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>