<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1651" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1651/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1651/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1651"><akn:num>1651</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1651. Compensation authorized(a) Places of employmentExcept as herein modified, the provisions of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act, approved March 4, 1927 (44 Stat. 1424), as amended [33 U.S.C. 901 et seq.], shall apply in respect to the injury or death of any employee engaged in any employment—(1) at any military, air, or naval base acquired after January 1, 1940, by the United States from any foreign government; or

(2) upon any lands occupied or used by the United States for military or naval purposes in any Territory or possession outside the continental United States (including the United States Naval Operating Base, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; and the Canal Zone); or

(3) upon any public work in any Territory or possession outside the continental United States (including the United States Naval Operating Base, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; and the Canal Zone), if such employee is engaged in employment at such place under the contract of a contractor (or any subcontractor or subordinate subcontractor with respect to the contract of such contractor) with the United States; but nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to apply to any employee of such a contractor or subcontractor who is engaged exclusively in furnishing materials or supplies under his contract;

(4) under a contract entered into with the United States or any executive department, independent establishment, or agency thereof (including any corporate instrumentality of the United States), or any subcontract, or subordinate contract with respect to such contract, where such contract is to be performed outside the continental United States and at places not within the areas described in subparagraphs (1)–(3) of this subdivision, for the purpose of engaging in public work, and every such contract shall contain provisions requiring that the contractor (and subcontractor or subordinate contractor with respect to such contract) (1) shall, before commencing performance of such contract, provide </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Places of employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Places of employment Except as herein modified, the provisions of the Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act, approved March 4, 1927 (44 Stat. 1424), as amended [33 U.S.C. 901 et seq.], shall apply in respect to the injury or death of any employee engaged in any employment— irrespective of the place where the injury or death occurs, and shall include any injury or death occurring to any such employee during transportation to or from his place of employment, where the employer or the United States provides the transportation or the cost thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability as exclusive</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liability as exclusive The liability of an employer, contractor (or any subcontractor or subordinate subcontractor with respect to the contract of such contractor) under this chapter shall be exclusive and in place of all other liability of such employer, contractor, subcontractor, or subordinate contractor to his employees (and their dependents) coming within the purview of this chapter, under the workmen’s compensation law of any State, Territory, or other jurisdiction, irrespective of the place where the contract of hire of any such employee may have been made or entered into.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Contractor” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Contractor” defined As used in this section, the term “contractor” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association, and includes any trustee, receiver, assignee, successor, or personal representative thereof, and the rights, obligations, liability, and duties of the employer under such Longshore and Harbor Workers’ Compensation Act [33 U.S.C. 901 et seq.] shall be applicable to such contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts within section; waiver of application of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contracts within section; waiver of application of section The liability under this chapter of a contractor, subcontractor, or subordinate contractor engaged in public work under subparagraphs (3) and (4), subdivision (a) of this section, and the conditions set forth therein, shall become applicable to contracts and subcontracts heretofore entered into but not completed at August 16, 1941, and the liability under this chapter of a contractor, subcontractor, or subordinate contractor engaged in performance of contracts, subcontracts, or subordinate contracts specified in subparagraph (5), subdivision (a) of this section, and the conditions set forth therein, shall hereafter be applicable to the remaining terms of such contracts, subcontracts, and subordinate contracts entered into prior to but not completed on the date of enactment of any successor Act to the Mutual Security Act of 1954, as amended, and contracting officers of the United States are authorized to make such modificati</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1651_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability to prisoners of war and protected persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Liability to prisoners of war and protected persons The liability under this chapter of a contractor, subcontractor, or subordinate contractor engaged in public work under paragraphs (1), (2), (3), and (4) of subsection (a) of this section or in any work under paragraph (5) of subsection (a) of this section does not apply with respect to any person who is a prisoner of war or a protected person under the Geneva Conventions of 1949 and who is detained or utilized by the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>