<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16534" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16534/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16534/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16534"><akn:num>16534</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy early career awards for science, engineering, and mathematics researchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16534. Department of Energy early career awards for science, engineering, and mathematics researchers(a) Grant awardsThe Director of the Office of Science of the Department (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall carry out a program to award grants to scientists and engineers at an early career stage at institutions of higher education and organizations described in subsection (c) to conduct research in fields relevant to the mission of the Department.


(b) Amount and duration(1) AmountThe amount of a grant awarded under this section shall be—(A) not less than $80,000; and

(B) not more than $125,000.


(2) DurationThe term of a grant awarded under this section shall be not more than 5 years.



(c) Eligibility(1) In generalTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an individual shall, as determined by the Director—(A) subject to paragraph (2), have completed a doctorate or other terminal degree not more than 10 years before the date on which the proposal for a grant is submitted under subsection (e)(1);

(B) have demonstrated promise in a science, engineering, or mathematics field relevant to the missions of the Department; and

(C) be employed—(i) in a tenure track-position as an assistant professor or equivalent title at an institution of higher education in the United States;

(ii) at an organization in the United States that is a nonprofit, nondegree-granting research organization such as a museum, observatory, or research laboratory; or

(iii) as a scientist at a National Laboratory.



(2) WaiverNotwithstanding paragraph (1)(A), the Director may determine that an individual who has completed a doctorate more than 10 years before the date of submission of a proposal under subsection (e)(1) is eligible to receive a grant under this section if the individual was unable to conduct research for a period of time because of extenuating circumstances, including military service or family responsibilities, as determined by the Director.


</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant awards The Director of the Office of Science of the Department (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall carry out a program to award grants to scientists and engineers at an early career stage at institutions of higher education and organizations described in subsection (c) to conduct research in fields relevant to the mission of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount and duration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection Grant recipients shall be selected on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection process and criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Selection process and criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diversity requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Diversity requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on recruiting and retaining early career science and engineering researchers at National Laboratories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report on recruiting and retaining early career science and engineering researchers at National Laboratories</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16534_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, acting through the Director, to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2013.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>