<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16537" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16537/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16537/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16537"><akn:num>16537</akn:num><akn:heading>Distinguished scientist program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16537. Distinguished scientist program(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to promote scientific and academic excellence through collaborations between institutions of higher education and National Laboratories.


(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program to support the joint appointment of distinguished scientists by institutions of higher education and National Laboratories.


(c) QualificationsTo be eligible for appointment as a distinguished scientist under this section, an individual, by reason of professional background and experience, shall be able to bring international recognition to the appointing institution of higher education or National Laboratory in the field of scientific endeavor of the individual.


(d) SelectionA distinguished scientist appointed under this section shall be selected through an open, competitive process.


(e) Appointment(1) Institution of higher educationAn appointment by an institution of higher education under this section shall be filled within the tenure allotment of the institution of higher education, at a minimum rank of professor.


(2) National LaboratoryAn appointment by a National Laboratory under this section shall be at the rank of the highest grade of distinguished scientist or technical staff of the National Laboratory.



(f) DurationAn appointment under this section shall—(1) be for a term of 6 years; and

(2) consist of 2 3-year funding allotments.


(g) Use of fundsFunds made available under this section may be used for—(1) the salary of the distinguished scientist and support staff;

(2) undergraduate, graduate, and post-doctoral appointments;

(3) research-related equipment;

(4) professional travel; and

(5) such other requirements as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out the purpose of the program.


(h) Review(1) In generalThe appointment of a distinguished scientist under this section shall be reviewed at the end of the first 3-year allotment for the distinguished scie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to promote scientific and academic excellence through collaborations between institutions of higher education and National Laboratories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a program to support the joint appointment of distinguished scientists by institutions of higher education and National Laboratories.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualifications To be eligible for appointment as a distinguished scientist under this section, an individual, by reason of professional background and experience, shall be able to bring international recognition to the appointing institution of higher education or National Laboratory in the field of scientific endeavor of the individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection A distinguished scientist appointed under this section shall be selected through an open, competitive process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duration An appointment under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of funds Funds made available under this section may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Cost sharing To be eligible for assistance under this section, an appointing institution of higher education shall pay at least 50 percent of the total costs of the appointment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16537_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>