<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16538" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16538/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16538/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16538"><akn:num>16538</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16538. Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ARPA-EThe term “ARPA–E” means the Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy established by subsection (b).


(2) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of ARPA-E appointed under subsection (d).


(3) FundThe term “Fund” means the Energy Transformation Acceleration Fund established under subsection (o)(1).



(b) EstablishmentThere is established the Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy within the Department to overcome the long-term and high-risk technological barriers in the development of transformative science and technology solutions to address the energy and environmental missions of the Department.


(c) Goals(1) In generalThe goals of ARPA-E shall be—(A) to enhance the economic and energy security of the United States through the development of energy technologies that—(i) reduce imports of energy from foreign sources;

(ii) reduce energy-related emissions, including greenhouse gases;

(iii) improve the energy efficiency of all economic sectors;

(iv) provide transformative solutions to improve the management, clean-up, and disposal of radioactive waste and spent nuclear fuel; and

(v) improve the resilience, reliability, and security of infrastructure to produce, deliver, and store energy; and


(B) to ensure that the United States maintains a technological lead in developing and deploying advanced energy technologies.


(2) MeansARPA-E shall achieve the goals established under paragraph (1) through advanced technology projects by—(A) identifying and promoting revolutionary advances in fundamental and applied sciences;

(B) translating scientific discoveries and cutting-edge inventions into technological innovations; and

(C) accelerating transformational technological advances in areas that industry by itself is not likely to undertake because of technical and financial uncertainty.



(d) Director(1) AppointmentThere shall be in the Department of Energy a Directo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is established the Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy within the Department to overcome the long-term and high-risk technological barriers in the development of transformative science and technology solutions to address the energy and environmental missions of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Responsibilities The responsibilities of the Director shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Awards In carrying out this section, the Director may provide awards in the form of grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, cash prizes, and other transactions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and roadmaps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports and roadmaps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and nonduplication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Coordination and nonduplication</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16538_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal demonstration of technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Federal demonstration of technologies The Director shall seek opportunities to partner with purchasing and procurement programs of Federal agencies to demonstrate energy technologies resulting from activities funded through ARPA–E.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>