<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16539" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16539/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/16539/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_16539"><akn:num>16539</akn:num><akn:heading>National Laboratory Jobs ACCESS Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 16539. National Laboratory Jobs ACCESS Program(a) In generalOn or after the date that is 180 days after December 20, 2019, the Secretary may establish a program, to be known as the “Department of Energy National Lab Jobs ACCESS Program”, under which the Secretary may award, on a competitive basis, 5-year grants to eligible entities described in subsection (c) for the Federal share of the costs of pre-apprenticeship programs and apprenticeship programs described in subsection (b).


(b) Pre-apprenticeship and apprenticeship programs describedA pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program described in this subsection is a pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program that—(1) leads to recognized postsecondary credentials for secondary school and postsecondary students;

(2) is focused on skills and qualifications needed, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with the directors of the National Laboratories, to meet the immediate and ongoing needs of traditional and emerging technician positions (including machinists and cybersecurity technicians) at the National Laboratories and covered facilities of the National Nuclear Security Administration;

(3) is established in consultation with a National Laboratory or covered facility of the National Nuclear Security Administration;

(4) is registered with and approved by the Secretary of Labor or a State apprenticeship agency; and

(5) ensures that participants in the pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program do not displace paid employees.


(c) Eligible entities describedAn eligible entity described in this subsection is a workforce intermediary or an eligible sponsor of a pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program that—(1) demonstrates experience in implementing and providing career planning and career pathways toward pre-apprenticeship programs or apprenticeship programs;

(2)(A) has a relationship with a National Laboratory or covered facility of the National Nuclear Securit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general On or after the date that is 180 days after December 20, 2019, the Secretary may establish a program, to be known as the “Department of Energy National Lab Jobs ACCESS Program”, under which the Secretary may award, on a competitive basis, 5-year grants to eligible entities described in subsection (c) for the Federal share of the costs of pre-apprenticeship programs and apprenticeship programs described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-apprenticeship and apprenticeship programs described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pre-apprenticeship and apprenticeship programs described A pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program described in this subsection is a pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities described An eligible entity described in this subsection is a workforce intermediary or an eligible sponsor of a pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applications If the Secretary establishes the program described in subsection (a), an eligible entity described in subsection (c) seeking a grant under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In selecting eligible entities described in subsection (c) to receive grants under this section, the Secretary may prioritize an eligible entity that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional consideration In making grants under this section, the Secretary may consider regional diversity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation on applications An eligible entity described in subsection (c) may not submit, either individually or as part of a joint application, more than one application for a grant under this section during any one fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations on amount of grant The amount of a grant provided under this section may not, for any 24-month period of the 5-year grant period, exceed $500,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Non-Federal share The non-Federal share of the cost of a pre-apprenticeship program or apprenticeship program carried out using a grant under this section shall be not less than 25 percent of the total cost of the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_16539_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Technical assistance The Secretary may provide technical assistance to eligible entities described in subsection (c) to leverage the existing job training and education programs of the Department of Labor and other relevant programs at appropriate Federal agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>