<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17013"><akn:num>17013</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced technology vehicles manufacturing incentive program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17013. Advanced technology vehicles manufacturing incentive program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Advanced technology vehicleThe term “advanced technology vehicle” means—(A) an ultra efficient vehicle or a light duty vehicle that meets—(i) the Bin 5 Tier II emission standard established in regulations issued by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under section 202(i) of the Clean Air Act (42 U.S.C. 7521(i)), or a lower-numbered Bin emission standard;

(ii) any new emission standard in effect for fine particulate matter prescribed by the Administrator under that Act (42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.); and

(iii) at least 125 percent of the average base year combined fuel economy for vehicles with substantially similar attributes;


(B) a medium duty vehicle or a heavy duty vehicle that exceeds 125 percent of the greenhouse gas emissions and fuel efficiency standards established by the final rule of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled “Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Fuel Efficiency Standards for Medium- and Heavy-Duty Engines and Vehicles—Phase 2” (81 Fed. Reg. 73478 (October 25, 2016));

(C) a train or locomotive;

(D) a maritime vessel;

(E) an aircraft; and

(F) hyperloop technology.


(2) Combined fuel economyThe term “combined fuel economy” means—(A) the combined city/highway miles per gallon values, as reported in accordance with section 32904 of title 49; and

(B) in the case of an electric drive vehicle with the ability to recharge from an off-board source, the reported mileage, as determined in a manner consistent with the Society of Automotive Engineers recommended practice for that configuration or a similar practice recommended by the Secretary.


(3) Engineering integration costsThe term “engineering integration costs” includes the cost of engineering tasks relating to—(A) incorporating qualifying components into the design of advanced technology vehicles; and

(B) designing tooling and equipment and developing manufacturing proces</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced vehicles manufacturing facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advanced vehicles manufacturing facility The Secretary shall provide facility funding awards under this section to automobile manufacturers, ultra efficient vehicle manufacturers, advanced technology vehicle manufacturers, and component suppliers to pay not more than 30 percent of the cost of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period of availability An award under subsection (b) shall apply to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct loan program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Direct loan program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Improvement Not later than 60 days after September 30, 2008, the Secretary shall promulgate an interim final rule establishing regulations that the Secretary deems necessary to administer this section and any loans made by the Secretary pursuant to this section. Such interim final rule shall require that, in order for an automobile manufacturer to be eligible for an award or loan under this section during a particular year, the adjusted average fuel economy of the manufacturer for light duty vehicles produced by the manufacturer during the most recent year for which data are available shall be not less than the average fuel economy for all light duty vehicles of the manufacturer for model year 2005. In order to determine fuel economy baselines for eligibility of a new manufacturer or a manufacturer that has not produced previously produced equivalent vehicles, the Secretary may substitute industry averages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Fees Administrative costs shall be no more than $100,000 or 10 basis point 22 So in original. Probably should be “points”. of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Priority The Secretary shall, in making awards or loans to those manufacturers that have existing facilities, give priority to those facilities that are oldest or have been in existence for at least 20 years or are utilized primarily for the manufacture of ultra efficient vehicles. Such facilities can currently be sitting idle.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set aside for small advanced technology vehicle manufacturers and component suppliers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Set aside for small advanced technology vehicle manufacturers and component suppliers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and pay of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Appointment and pay of personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17013_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate with relevant vehicle, bioenergy, and hydrogen and fuel cell demonstration project activities supported by the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>