<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17052"><akn:num>17052</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable fuel infrastructure grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17052. Renewable fuel infrastructure grants(a) Definition of renewable fuel blendFor purposes of this section, the term “renewable fuel blend” means a gasoline blend that contains not less than 11 percent, and not more than 85 percent, renewable fuel or diesel fuel that contains at least 10 percent renewable fuel.


(b) Infrastructure development grants(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a program for making grants for providing assistance to retail and wholesale motor fuel dealers or other entities for the installation, replacement, or conversion of motor fuel storage and dispensing infrastructure to be used exclusively to store and dispense renewable fuel blends.


(2) Selection criteriaNot later than 12 months after December 19, 2007, the Secretary shall establish criteria for evaluating applications for grants under this subsection that will maximize the availability and use of renewable fuel blends, and that will ensure that renewable fuel blends are available across the country. Such criteria shall provide for—(A) consideration of the public demand for each renewable fuel blend in a particular geographic area based on State registration records showing the number of flexible-fuel vehicles;

(B) consideration of the opportunity to create or expand corridors of renewable fuel blend stations along interstate or State highways;

(C) consideration of the experience of each applicant with previous, similar projects;

(D) consideration of population, number of flexible-fuel vehicles, number of retail fuel outlets, and saturation of flexible-fuel vehicles; and

(E) priority consideration to applications that—(i) are most likely to maximize displacement of petroleum consumption, measured as a total quantity and a percentage;

(ii) are best able to incorporate existing infrastructure while maximizing, to the extent practicable, the use of renewable fuel blends; and

(iii) demonstrate the greatest commitment on the part of the applicant to ensure funding for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of renewable fuel blend</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of renewable fuel blend For purposes of this section, the term “renewable fuel blend” means a gasoline blend that contains not less than 11 percent, and not more than 85 percent, renewable fuel or diesel fuel that contains at least 10 percent renewable fuel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Infrastructure development grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Infrastructure development grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retail technical and marketing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Retail technical and marketing assistance The Secretary shall enter into contracts with entities with demonstrated experience in assisting retail fueling stations in installing refueling systems and marketing renewable fuel blends nationally, for the provision of technical and marketing assistance to recipients of grants under this section. Such assistance shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refueling infrastructure corridors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Refueling infrastructure corridors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restriction No grant shall be provided under subsection (b) or (c) to a large, vertically integrated oil company.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17052_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for carrying out this section $200,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2008 through 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>