<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17062" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17062/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17062/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17062"><akn:num>17062</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy efficiency in Federal and other buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17062. Energy efficiency in Federal and other buildings(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.


(2) Cost-effective energy efficiency measureThe term “cost-effective energy efficiency measure” means any building product, material, equipment, or service, and the installing, implementing, or operating thereof, that provides energy savings in an amount that is not less than the cost of such installing, implementing, or operating.


(3) Cost-effective water efficiency measureThe term “cost-effective water efficiency measure” means any building product, material, equipment, or service, and the installing, implementing, or operating thereof, that provides water savings in an amount that is not less than the cost of such installing, implementing, or operating.



(b) Model provisions, policies, and best practices(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after April 30, 2015, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and after providing the public with an opportunity for notice and comment, shall develop model commercial leasing provisions and best practices in accordance with this subsection.


(2) Commercial leasing(A) In generalThe model commercial leasing provisions developed under this subsection shall, at a minimum, align the interests of building owners and tenants with regard to investments in cost-effective energy efficiency measures and cost-effective water efficiency measures to encourage building owners and tenants to collaborate to invest in such measures.


(B) Use of model provisionsThe Administrator may use the model commercial leasing provisions developed under this subsection in any standard leasing document that designates a Federal agency (or other client of the Administrator) as a landlord or tenant.


(C) PublicationThe Administrator shall periodically publish the model commercial leasing provisions developed under this subsection, along with explanatory m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17062_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17062_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model provisions, policies, and best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Model provisions, policies, and best practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>