<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17085" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17085/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17085/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17085"><akn:num>17085</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant Star program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17085. Tenant Star program(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) High-performance energy efficiency measureThe term “high-performance energy efficiency measure” has the meaning given the term in section 17084 of this title.


(2) Separate spacesThe term “separate spaces” has the meaning given the term in section 17084 of this title.



(b) Tenant StarThe Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall develop a voluntary program within the Energy Star program established by section 6294a of this title, which may be known as “Tenant Star”, to promote energy efficiency in separate spaces leased by tenants or otherwise occupied within commercial buildings.


(c) Expanding survey dataThe Secretary of Energy, acting through the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall—(1) collect, through each Commercial Buildings Energy Consumption Survey of the Energy Information Administration that is conducted after April 30, 2015, data on—(A) categories of building occupancy that are known to consume significant quantities of energy, such as occupancy by data centers, trading floors, and restaurants; and

(B) other aspects of the property, building operation, or building occupancy determined by the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to be relevant in lowering energy consumption;


(2) with respect to the first Commercial Buildings Energy Consumption Survey conducted after April 30, 2015, to the extent full compliance with the requirements of paragraph (1) is not feasible, conduct activities to develop the capability to collect such data and begin to collect such data; and

(3) make data collected under paragraphs (1) and (2) available to the public in aggregated form and provide such data, and any associated results, to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency for use in accordance with subsec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17085_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17085_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tenant Star</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Tenant Star The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall develop a voluntary program within the Energy Star program established by section 6294a of this title, which may be known as “Tenant Star”, to promote energy efficiency in separate spaces leased by tenants or otherwise occupied within commercial buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17085_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding survey data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expanding survey data The Secretary of Energy, acting through the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17085_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of owners and tenants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recognition of owners and tenants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>