<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17082"><akn:num>17082</akn:num><akn:heading>Zero Net Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17082. Zero Net Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ConsortiumThe term “consortium” means a High-Performance Green Building Consortium selected by the Commercial Director.


(2) InitiativeThe term “initiative” means the Zero-Net-Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative established under subsection (b)(1).


(3) Zero-net-energy commercial buildingThe term “zero-net-energy commercial building” means a high-performance commercial building that is designed, constructed, and operated—(A) to require a greatly reduced quantity of energy to operate;

(B) to meet the balance of energy needs from sources of energy that do not produce greenhouse gases;

(C) in a manner that will result in no net emissions of greenhouse gases; and

(D) to be economically viable.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Commercial Director shall establish an initiative, to be known as the “Zero-Net-Energy Commercial Buildings Initiative”—(A) to reduce the quantity of energy consumed by commercial buildings located in the United States; and

(B) to achieve the development of zero net energy commercial buildings in the United States.


(2) Consortium(A) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 19, 2007, the Commercial Director shall competitively select, and enter into an agreement with, a consortium to develop and carry out the initiative.


(B) AgreementsIn entering into an agreement with a consortium under subparagraph (A), the Commercial Director shall use the authority described in section 7256(g) of this title, to the maximum extent practicable.




(c) Goal of initiativeThe goal of the initiative shall be to develop and disseminate technologies, practices, and policies for the development and establishment of zero net energy commercial buildings for—(1) any commercial building newly constructed in the United States by 2030;

(2) 50 percent of the commercial building stock of the United States by 2040; and

(3) all commercial buildings in the United </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Goal of initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Goal of initiative The goal of the initiative shall be to develop and disseminate technologies, practices, and policies for the development and establishment of zero net energy commercial buildings for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Components In carrying out the initiative, the Commercial Director, in consultation with the consortium, may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost sharing In carrying out this section, the Commercial Director shall require cost sharing in accordance with section 16352 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17082_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>