<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17092" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17092/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17092/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17092"><akn:num>17092</akn:num><akn:heading>High-performance green Federal buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17092. High-performance green Federal buildings(a) Establishment of OfficeNot later than 60 days after December 19, 2007, the Administrator shall establish within the General Services Administration an Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings, and appoint an individual to serve as Federal Director in, a position in the career-reserved Senior Executive service, to—(1) establish and manage the Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings; and

(2) carry out other duties as required under this part.


(b) CompensationThe compensation of the Federal Director shall not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382 of title 5, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under section 5304(h)(2)(C) of that title.


(c) DutiesThe Federal Director shall—(1) coordinate the activities of the Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings with the activities of the Office of Commercial High-Performance Green Buildings, and the Secretary, in accordance with section 6834(a)(3)(D) of this title;

(2) ensure full coordination of high-performance green building information and activities within the General Services Administration and all relevant agencies, including, at a minimum—(A) the Environmental Protection Agency;

(B) the Office of the Federal Environmental Executive;

(C) the Office of Federal Procurement Policy;

(D) the Department of Energy;

(E) the Department of Health and Human Services;

(F) the Department of Defense;

(G) the Department of Transportation;

(H) the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and

(I) the Office of Science and Technology Policy;


(3) establish a senior-level Federal Green Building Advisory Committee under section 474,11 See References in Text note below. which shall provide advice and recommendations in accordance with that section and subsection (d);

(4) identify and every 5 years reassess improved or higher rating standards </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Office Not later than 60 days after December 19, 2007, the Administrator shall establish within the General Services Administration an Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings, and appoint an individual to serve as Federal Director in, a position in the career-reserved Senior Executive service, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation The compensation of the Federal Director shall not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382 of title 5, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under section 5304(h)(2)(C) of that title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Federal Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional duties The Federal Director, in consultation with the Commercial Director and the Advisory Committee, and consistent with the requirements of section 6834(a)(3)(D) of this title shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Incentives Within 90 days after December 19, 2007, the Federal Director shall identify incentives to encourage the expedited use of high-performance green buildings and related technology in the operations of the Federal Government, in accordance with the requirements of section 6834(a)(3)(D) of this title, including through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 2 years after December 19, 2007, and biennially thereafter, the Federal Director, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to Congress a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Implementation The Office of Federal High-Performance Green Buildings shall carry out each plan for implementation of recommendations under subsection (f)(8).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17092_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of certification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Identification of certification system</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>