<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17095" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17095/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17095/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17095"><akn:num>17095</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-effective technology acceleration program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17095. Cost-effective technology acceleration program(a) Definition of AdministratorIn this section, the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.


(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Administrator shall establish a program to accelerate the use of more cost-effective technologies and practices at GSA facilities.


(2) RequirementsThe program established under this subsection shall—(A) ensure centralized responsibility for the coordination of cost reduction-related recommendations, practices, and activities of all relevant Federal agencies;

(B) provide technical assistance and operational guidance to applicable tenants to achieve the goal identified in subsection (c)(2)(B)(ii);

(C) establish methods to track the success of Federal departments and agencies with respect to that goal; and

(D) be fully coordinated with and no less stringent nor less energy-conserving or water-conserving than required by other provisions of this Act and other applicable law, including sections 321 through 324, 431 through 438, 461, 511 through 518, and 523 through 525 and amendments made by those sections.



(c) Accelerated use of technologies(1) Review(A) In generalAs part of the program under this section, not later than 90 days after December 19, 2007, the Administrator shall conduct a review of—(i) current use of cost-effective lighting technologies and geothermal heat pumps in GSA facilities; and

(ii) the availability to managers of GSA facilities of cost-effective lighting technologies and geothermal heat pumps.


(B) RequirementsThe review under subparagraph (A) shall—(i) examine the use of cost-effective lighting technologies, geothermal heat pumps, and other cost-effective technologies and practices by Federal agencies in GSA facilities; and

(ii) as prepared in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, identify cost-effective lighting technology and geothermal heat pump technology standards that could be used for </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17095_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of Administrator In this section, the term “Administrator” means the Administrator of General Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17095_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17095_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accelerated use of technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accelerated use of technologies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17095_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>GSA facility technologies and practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) GSA facility technologies and practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17095_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>