<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17091" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17091/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17091/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17091"><akn:num>17091</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17091. Leasing(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b), effective beginning on the date that is 3 years after December 19, 2007, no Federal agency shall enter into a contract to lease space in a building that has not earned the Energy Star label in the most recent year.


(b) Exception(1) ApplicationThis subsection applies if—(A) no space is available in a building described in subsection (a) that meets the functional requirements of an agency, including locational needs;

(B) the agency proposes to remain in a building that the agency has occupied previously;

(C) the agency proposes to lease a building of historical, architectural, or cultural significance (as defined in section 3306(a)(4) of title 40) or space in such a building; or

(D) the lease is for not more than 10,000 gross square feet of space.


(2) Buildings without Energy Star labelIf one of the conditions described in paragraph (1) is met, the agency may enter into a contract to lease space in a building that has not earned the Energy Star label in the most recent year if the lease contract includes provisions requiring that, prior to occupancy or, in the case of a contract described in paragraph (1)(B), not later than 1 year after signing the contract, the following requirements are met:(A) The space is renovated for all energy efficiency and conservation improvements that would be cost effective over the life of the lease, including improvements in lighting, windows, and heating, ventilation, and air conditioning systems.

(B)(i) Subject to clause (ii), the space is benchmarked under a nationally recognized, online, free benchmarking program, with public disclosure, unless the space is a space for which owners cannot access whole building utility consumption data, including spaces—(I) that are located in States with privacy laws that provide that utilities shall not provide such aggregated information to multitenant building owners; and

(II) for which tenants do not provide energy consu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17091_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (b), effective beginning on the date that is 3 years after December 19, 2007, no Federal agency shall enter into a contract to lease space in a building that has not earned the Energy Star label in the most recent year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17091_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17091_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision of Federal Acquisition Regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Revision of Federal Acquisition Regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>