<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17113b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17113b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17113b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17113b"><akn:num>17113b</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced industrial facilities deployment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17113b. Advanced industrial facilities deployment program(a) Office of Clean Energy DemonstrationsIn addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary, acting through the Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations, for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $5,812,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2026, to carry out this section.


(b) Financial assistanceThe Secretary shall use funds appropriated by subsection (a) to provide financial assistance, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to carry out projects for—(1) the purchase and installation, or implementation, of advanced industrial technology at an eligible facility;

(2) retrofits, upgrades to, or operational improvements at an eligible facility to install or implement advanced industrial technology; or

(3) engineering studies and other work needed to prepare an eligible facility for activities described in paragraph (1) or (2).


(c) ApplicationTo be eligible to receive financial assistance under subsection (b), an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the expected greenhouse gas emissions reductions to be achieved by carrying out the project.


(d) PriorityIn providing financial assistance under subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority consideration to projects on the basis of, as determined by the Secretary—(1) the expected greenhouse gas emissions reductions to be achieved by carrying out the project;

(2) the extent to which the project would provide the greatest benefit for the greatest number of people within the area in which the eligible facility is located; and

(3) whether the eligible entity participates or would participate in a partnership with purchasers of the output of the eligible facility.


(e) Cost shareThe Secretary shall require an eligible entity to provide not less</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary, acting through the Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations, for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $5,812,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2026, to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Financial assistance The Secretary shall use funds appropriated by subsection (a) to provide financial assistance, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to carry out projects for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application To be eligible to receive financial assistance under subsection (b), an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the expected greenhouse gas emissions reductions to be achieved by carrying out the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority In providing financial assistance under subsection (b), the Secretary shall give priority consideration to projects on the basis of, as determined by the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cost share The Secretary shall require an eligible entity to provide not less than 50 percent of the cost of a project carried out pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Administrative costs The Secretary shall reserve not more than $300,000,000 of amounts made available under subsection (a) for administrative costs of carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17113b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>