<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1711" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1711/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1711/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1711"><akn:num>1711</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1711. Definitions
When used in this chapter—(a) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.

(b) The term “war-risk hazard” means any hazard arising during a war in which the United States is engaged; during an armed conflict in which the United States is engaged, whether or not war has been declared; or during a war or armed conflict between military forces of any origin, occurring within any country in which a person covered by this chapter is serving; from—(1) the discharge of any missile (including liquids and gas) or the use of any weapon, explosive, or other noxious thing by a hostile force or person or in combating an attack or an imagined attack by a hostile force or person; or

(2) action of a hostile force or person, including rebellion or insurrection against the United States or any of its Allies; or

(3) the discharge or explosion of munitions intended for use in connection with a war or armed conflict with a hostile force or person as defined herein (except with respect to employees of a manufacturer, processor, or transporter of munitions during the manufacture, processing, or transporting thereof, or while stored on the premises of the manufacturer, processor, or transporter); or

(4) the collision of vessels in convoy or the operation of vessels or aircraft without running lights or without other customary peacetime aids to navigation; or

(5) the operation of vessels or aircraft in a zone of hostilities or engaged in war activities.


(c) The term “hostile force or person” means any nation, any subject of a foreign nation, or any other person serving a foreign nation (1) engaged in a war against the United States or any of its allies, (2) engaged in armed conflict, whether or not war has been declared, against the United States or any of its allies, or (3) engaged in a war or armed conflict between military forces of any origin in any country in which a person covered by this chapter is serving.

(d) The term “allies” means any nation with</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The term “war-risk hazard” means any hazard arising during a war in which the United States is engaged; during an armed conflict in which the United States is engaged, whether or not war has been declared; or during a war or armed conflict between military forces of any origin, occurring within any country in which a person covered by this chapter is serving; from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The term “hostile force or person” means any nation, any subject of a foreign nation, or any other person serving a foreign nation (1) engaged in a war against the United States or any of its allies, (2) engaged in armed conflict, whether or not war has been declared, against the United States or any of its allies, or (3) engaged in a war or armed conflict between military forces of any origin in any country in which a person covered by this chapter is serving.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The term “allies” means any nation with which the United States is engaged in a common military effort or with which the United States has entered into a common defensive military alliance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(e) The term “war activities” includes activities directly relating to military operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1711_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(f) the 11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. term “continental United States” means the States and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>