<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17194" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17194/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17194/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17194"><akn:num>17194</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced geothermal systems research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17194. Enhanced geothermal systems research and development(a) In generalThe Secretary shall support a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for enhanced geothermal systems, including the programs described in subsection (b).


(b) Enhanced geothermal systems technologiesIn collaboration with industry partners, institutions of higher education, and the national laboratories, the Secretary shall support a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of the technologies to achieve higher efficiency and lower cost enhanced geothermal systems, including—(1) reservoir stimulation;

(2) drilled, non-stimulated (e.g. closed-loop) reservoir technologies;

(3) reservoir characterization, monitoring, and modeling and understanding of the surface area and volume of fractures;

(4) stress and fracture mapping including real time monitoring and modeling;

(5) tracer development;

(6) three and four-dimensional seismic imaging and tomography;

(7) well placement and orientation;

(8) long-term reservoir management;

(9) drilling technologies, methods, and tools;

(10) improved exploration tools;

(11) zonal isolation; and

(12) understanding induced seismicity risks from reservoir engineering and stimulation.


(c) Frontier observatory for research in geothermal energy(1) In generalThe Secretary shall support the establishment and construction of up to 3 field research sites, which shall each be known as a “Frontier Observatory for Research in Geothermal Energy” or “FORGE” site to develop, test, and enhance techniques and tools for enhanced geothermal energy.


(2) DutiesThe Secretary shall—(A) provide financial assistance in support of research and development projects focused on advanced monitoring technologies, new technologies and approaches for implementing multi-zone stimulations, nonstimulation techniques, and dynamic reservoir modeling that incorporates all available high-fidelity characterization data</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17194_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall support a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for enhanced geothermal systems, including the programs described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17194_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced geothermal systems technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Enhanced geothermal systems technologies In collaboration with industry partners, institutions of higher education, and the national laboratories, the Secretary shall support a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of the technologies to achieve higher efficiency and lower cost enhanced geothermal systems, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17194_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Frontier observatory for research in geothermal energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Frontier observatory for research in geothermal energy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17194_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhanced geothermal systems demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Enhanced geothermal systems demonstrations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>