<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17196" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17196/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17196/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17196"><akn:num>17196</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization and administration of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17196. Organization and administration of programs(a) Federal shareThe Federal share of costs of projects funded under this part shall be in accordance with section 16352 of this title.


(b) Organization and administration of programsPrograms under this part shall incorporate the following elements:(1) The Secretary shall coordinate with, and where appropriate may provide funds in furtherance of the purposes of this part to, other Department of Energy research and development programs focused on drilling, subsurface characterization, and other related technologies.

(2) The Secretary shall coordinate and consult with the appropriate Federal land management agencies in selecting proposals for funding under this part.

(3) Nothing in this part shall be construed to alter or affect any law relating to the management or protection of Federal lands.


(c) Education and outreachIn carrying out the activities described in this part, the Secretary shall support education and outreach activities to disseminate information on geothermal energy technologies and the geothermal energy workforce, including activities at the Frontier Observatory for Research in Geothermal Energy site or sites.


(d) Technical assistanceIn carrying out this part, the Secretary shall also conduct technical assistance and analysis activities with eligible entities for the purpose of supporting the commercial application of advances in geothermal energy systems development and operations, which may include activities that support expanding access to advanced geothermal energy technologies for rural, Tribal, and low-income communities.


(e) ReportEvery 5 years after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate on advanced concepts and technologies to maximize the geothermal resource potential of the United States.


(f) Progress reportsNot later than 1 year aft</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal share The Federal share of costs of projects funded under this part shall be in accordance with section 16352 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organization and administration of programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Organization and administration of programs Programs under this part shall incorporate the following elements:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Education and outreach In carrying out the activities described in this part, the Secretary shall support education and outreach activities to disseminate information on geothermal energy technologies and the geothermal energy workforce, including activities at the Frontier Observatory for Research in Geothermal Energy site or sites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance In carrying out this part, the Secretary shall also conduct technical assistance and analysis activities with eligible entities for the purpose of supporting the commercial application of advances in geothermal energy systems development and operations, which may include activities that support expanding access to advanced geothermal energy technologies for rural, Tribal, and low-income communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Every 5 years after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall report to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate on advanced concepts and technologies to maximize the geothermal resource potential of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17196_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Progress reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Progress reports Not later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the results of projects undertaken under this part and other such information the Secretary considers appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>