<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17195" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17195/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17195/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17195"><akn:num>17195</akn:num><akn:heading>Geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields and recovery and production of geopressured gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17195. Geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields and recovery and production of geopressured gas resources(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to support development of geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields and production and recovery of energy, including electricity, from geopressured resources. In addition, the Secretary shall conduct such supporting activities including research, resource characterization, and technology development as necessary.


(b) Geothermal energy production from oil and gas fieldsThe Secretary shall implement a grant program in support of geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields. The program shall include grants for a total of not less than three demonstration projects of the use of geothermal techniques such as advanced organic rankine cycle systems at marginal, unproductive, and productive oil and gas wells. The Secretary shall, to the extent practicable and in the public interest, make awards that—(1) include not less than five oil or gas well sites per project award;

(2) use a range of oil or gas well hot water source temperatures from 150 degrees Fahrenheit to 300 degrees Fahrenheit;

(3) cover a range of sizes up to one megawatt;

(4) are located at a range of sites;

(5) can be replicated at a wide range of sites;

(6) facilitate identification of optimum techniques among competing alternatives;

(7) include business commercialization plans that have the potential for production of equipment at high volumes and operation and support at a large number of sites; and

(8) satisfy other criteria that the Secretary determines are necessary to carry out the program and collect necessary data and information.


The Secretary shall give preference to assessments that address multiple elements contained in paragraphs (1) through (8).

(c) Grant awardsEach grant award for demonstration of geothermal technology such as </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to support development of geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields and production and recovery of energy, including electricity, from geopressured resources. In addition, the Secretary shall conduct such supporting activities including research, resource characterization, and technology development as necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields The Secretary shall implement a grant program in support of geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields. The program shall include grants for a total of not less than three demonstration projects of the use of geothermal techniques such as advanced organic rankine cycle systems at marginal, unproductive, and productive oil and gas wells. The Secretary shall, to the extent practicable and in the public interest, make awards that— The Secretary shall give preference to assessments that address multiple elements contained in paragraphs (1) through (8).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant awards Each grant award for demonstration of geothermal technology such as advanced organic rankine cycle systems at oil and gas wells made by the Secretary under subsection (b) shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geopressured gas resource recovery and production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Geopressured gas resource recovery and production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grant selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Competitive grant selection Not less than 90 days after December 19, 2007, the Secretary shall conduct a national solicitation for applications for grants under the programs outlined in subsections (b) and (d). Grant recipients shall be selected on a competitive basis based on criteria in the respective subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17195_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Well drilling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Well drilling No funds may be used under this section for the purpose of drilling new wells.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>