<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17243"><akn:num>17243</akn:num><akn:heading>Bright Tomorrow Lighting Prizes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17243. Bright Tomorrow Lighting Prizes(a) EstablishmentNot later than 1 year after December 19, 2007, as part of the program carried out under section 16396 of this title, the Secretary shall establish and award Bright Tomorrow Lighting Prizes for solid state lighting in accordance with this section.


(b) Prize specifications(1) 60-Watt Incandescent Replacement Lamp PrizeThe Secretary shall award a 60-Watt Incandescent Replacement Lamp Prize to an entrant that produces a solid-state-light package simultaneously capable of—(A) producing a luminous flux greater than 900 lumens;

(B) consuming less than or equal to 10 watts;

(C) having an efficiency greater than 90 lumens per watt;

(D) having a color rendering index greater than 90;

(E) having a correlated color temperature of not less than 2,750, and not more than 3,000, degrees Kelvin;

(F) having 70 percent of the lumen value under subparagraph (A) exceeding 25,000 hours under typical conditions expected in residential use;

(G) having a light distribution pattern similar to a soft 60-watt incandescent A19 bulb;

(H) having a size and shape that fits within the maximum dimensions of an A19 bulb in accordance with American National Standards Institute standard C78.20–2003, figure C78.20–211;

(I) using a single contact medium screw socket; and

(J) mass production for a competitive sales commercial market satisfied by producing commercially accepted quality control lots of such units equal to or exceeding the criteria described in subparagraphs (A) through (I).


(2) PAR Type 38 Halogen Replacement Lamp PrizeThe Secretary shall award a Parabolic Aluminized Reflector Type 38 Halogen Replacement Lamp Prize (referred to in this section as the “PAR Type 38 Halogen Replacement Lamp Prize”) to an entrant that produces a solid-state-light package simultaneously capable of—(A) producing a luminous flux greater than or equal to 1,350 lumens;

(B) consuming less than or equal to 11 watts;

(C) having an efficiency greate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment Not later than 1 year after December 19, 2007, as part of the program carried out under section 16396 of this title, the Secretary shall establish and award Bright Tomorrow Lighting Prizes for solid state lighting in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prize specifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prize specifications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Private funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical review The Secretary shall establish a technical review committee composed of non-Federal officers to review entrant data submitted under this section to determine whether the data meets the prize specifications described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Third party administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Third party administration The Secretary may competitively select a third party to administer awards under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for prizes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligibility for prizes To be eligible to be awarded a prize under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Award amounts Subject to the availability of funds to carry out this section, the amount of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal procurement of solid-state-lights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal procurement of solid-state-lights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report Not later than 2 years after December 19, 2007, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of General Services shall submit to the Energy Information Agency a report describing the quantity, type, and cost of each lighting product purchased by the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17243_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bright Tomorrow Lighting Award Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Bright Tomorrow Lighting Award Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>