<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17282" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17282/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17282/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17282"><akn:num>17282</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable energy deployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17282. Renewable energy deployment(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Alaska small hydroelectric powerThe term “Alaska small hydroelectric power” means power that—(A) is generated—(i) in the State of Alaska;

(ii) without the use of a dam or impoundment of water; and

(iii) through the use of—(I) a lake tap (but not a perched alpine lake); or

(II) a run-of-river screened at the point of diversion; and



(B) has a nameplate capacity rating of a wattage that is not more than 15 megawatts.


(2) Eligible applicantThe term “eligible applicant” means any—(A) governmental entity;

(B) private utility;

(C) public utility;

(D) municipal utility;

(E) cooperative utility;

(F) Indian tribes; and

(G) Regional Corporation (as defined in section 1602 of title 43).


(3) Ocean energy(A) InclusionsThe term “ocean energy” includes current, wave, and tidal energy.


(B) ExclusionThe term “ocean energy” excludes thermal energy.



(4) Renewable energy projectThe term “renewable energy project” means a project—(A) for the commercial generation of electricity; and

(B) that generates electricity from—(i) solar, wind, or geothermal energy or ocean energy;

(ii) biomass (as defined in section 15852(b) of this title);

(iii) landfill gas; or

(iv) Alaska small hydroelectric power.




(b) Renewable energy construction grants(1) In generalThe Secretary shall use amounts appropriated under this section to make grants for use in carrying out renewable energy projects.


(2) CriteriaNot later than 180 days after December 19, 2007, the Secretary shall set forth criteria for use in awarding grants under this section.


(3) ApplicationTo receive a grant from the Secretary under paragraph (1), an eligible applicant shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a written assurance that—(A) all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors during construction, alteration, o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17282_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17282_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewable energy construction grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Renewable energy construction grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17282_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Fund such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>