<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17305" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17305/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17305/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17305"><akn:num>17305</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17305. Effect on other laws(a) Other authority of the CommissionNothing in this part limits or affects the authority of the Federal Trade Commission to bring an enforcement action or take any other measure under the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.) or any other provision of law.


(b) Antitrust lawNothing in this part shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws. For purposes of this subsection, the term “antitrust laws” shall have the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (15 U.S.C. 12), except that it includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 45) to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.


(c) State lawNothing in this part preempts any State law.


(Pub. L. 110–140, title VIII, § 815, Dec. 19, 2007, 121 Stat. 1724.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Trade Commission Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is act Sept. 26, 1914, ch. 311, 38 Stat. 717, which is classified generally to subchapter I (§ 41 et seq.) of chapter 2 of Title 15, Commerce and Trade. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 58 of Title 15 and Tables.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective on the date that is 1 day after Dec. 19, 2007, see section 1601 of Pub. L. 110–140, set out as a note under section 1824 of Title 2, The Congress.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17305_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other authority of the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Other authority of the Commission Nothing in this part limits or affects the authority of the Federal Trade Commission to bring an enforcement action or take any other measure under the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.) or any other provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17305_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Antitrust law Nothing in this part shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the operation of any of the antitrust laws. For purposes of this subsection, the term “antitrust laws” shall have the meaning given it in subsection (a) of the first section of the Clayton Act (15 U.S.C. 12), except that it includes section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (15 U.S.C. 45) to the extent that such section 5 applies to unfair methods of competition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17305_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State law Nothing in this part preempts any State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>