<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17356" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17356/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17356/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17356"><akn:num>17356</akn:num><akn:heading>General personnel authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17356. General personnel authorities(a) Detail of personnelUpon request of the Chief Executive Officer, the head of an agency may detail any employee of such agency to the Foundation on a reimbursable basis. Any employee so detailed remains, for the purpose of preserving such employee’s allowances, privileges, rights, seniority, and other benefits, an employee of the agency from which detailed.


(b) Reemployment rights(1) In generalAn employee of an agency who is serving under a career or career conditional appointment (or the equivalent), and who, with the consent of the head of such agency, transfers to the Foundation, is entitled to be reemployed in such employee’s former position or a position of like seniority, status, and pay in such agency, if such employee—(A) is separated from the Foundation for any reason, other than misconduct, neglect of duty, or malfeasance; and

(B) applies for reemployment not later than 90 days after the date of separation from the Foundation.


(2) Specific rightsAn employee who satisfies paragraph (1) is entitled to be reemployed (in accordance with such paragraph) within 30 days after applying for reemployment and, on reemployment, is entitled to at least the rate of basic pay to which such employee would have been entitled had such employee never transferred.



(c) Hiring authorityOf persons employed by the Foundation, no more than 30 persons may be appointed, compensated, or removed without regard to the civil service laws and regulations.


(d) Basic payThe Chief Executive Officer may fix the rate of basic pay of employees of the Foundation without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 of title 5 (relating to the classification of positions), subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title (relating to General Schedule pay rates), except that no employee of the Foundation may receive a rate of basic pay that exceeds the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title.


(e) DefinitionsIn this sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17356_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Detail of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Detail of personnel Upon request of the Chief Executive Officer, the head of an agency may detail any employee of such agency to the Foundation on a reimbursable basis. Any employee so detailed remains, for the purpose of preserving such employee’s allowances, privileges, rights, seniority, and other benefits, an employee of the agency from which detailed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17356_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reemployment rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reemployment rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17356_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hiring authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hiring authority Of persons employed by the Foundation, no more than 30 persons may be appointed, compensated, or removed without regard to the civil service laws and regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17356_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Basic pay The Chief Executive Officer may fix the rate of basic pay of employees of the Foundation without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 of title 5 (relating to the classification of positions), subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title (relating to General Schedule pay rates), except that no employee of the Foundation may receive a rate of basic pay that exceeds the rate for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of such title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17356_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>