<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17385" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17385/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17385/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17385"><akn:num>17385</akn:num><akn:heading>Smart grid interoperability framework</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17385. Smart grid interoperability framework(a) Interoperability frameworkThe Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall have primary responsibility to coordinate the development of a framework that includes protocols and model standards for information management to achieve interoperability of smart grid devices and systems. Such protocols and standards shall further align policy, business, and technology approaches in a manner that would enable all electric resources, including demand-side resources, to contribute to an efficient, reliable electricity network. In developing such protocols and standards—(1) the Director shall seek input and cooperation from the Commission, OEDER and its Smart Grid Task Force, the Smart Grid Advisory Committee, other relevant Federal and State agencies; and

(2) the Director shall also solicit input and cooperation from private entities interested in such protocols and standards, including but not limited to the Gridwise Architecture Council, the International Electrical and Electronics Engineers, the National Electric Reliability Organization recognized by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and National Electrical Manufacturer’s Association.


(b) Scope of frameworkThe framework developed under subsection (a) shall be flexible, uniform and technology neutral, including but not limited to technologies for managing smart grid information, and designed—(1) to accommodate traditional, centralized generation and transmission resources and consumer distributed resources, including distributed generation, renewable generation, energy storage, energy efficiency, and demand response and enabling devices and systems;

(2) to be flexible to incorporate—(A) regional and organizational differences; and

(B) technological innovations;


(3) to consider the use of voluntary uniform standards for certain classes of mass-produced electric appliances and equipment for homes and businesses that enable customers, at </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17385_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interoperability framework</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interoperability framework The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall have primary responsibility to coordinate the development of a framework that includes protocols and model standards for information management to achieve interoperability of smart grid devices and systems. Such protocols and standards shall further align policy, business, and technology approaches in a manner that would enable all electric resources, including demand-side resources, to contribute to an efficient, reliable electricity network. In developing such protocols and standards—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17385_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of framework</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of framework The framework developed under subsection (a) shall be flexible, uniform and technology neutral, including but not limited to technologies for managing smart grid information, and designed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17385_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing of framework development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Timing of framework development The Institute shall begin work pursuant to this section within 60 days of December 19, 2007. The Institute shall provide and publish an initial report on progress toward recommended or consensus standards and protocols within 1 year after December 19, 2007, further reports at such times as developments warrant in the judgment of the Institute, and a final report when the Institute determines that the work is completed or that a Federal role is no longer necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17385_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards for interoperability in Federal jurisdiction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standards for interoperability in Federal jurisdiction At any time after the Institute’s work has led to sufficient consensus in the Commission’s judgment, the Commission shall institute a rulemaking proceeding to adopt such standards and protocols as may be necessary to insure smart-grid functionality and interoperability in interstate transmission of electric power, and regional and wholesale electricity markets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17385_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this section $5,000,000 to the Institute to support the activities required by this subsection 22 So in original. Probably should be “section”. for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2012.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>