<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17383" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17383/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17383/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17383"><akn:num>17383</akn:num><akn:heading>Smart Grid Advisory Committee and Smart Grid Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17383. Smart Grid Advisory Committee and Smart Grid Task Force(a) Smart Grid Advisory Committee(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish, within 90 days of December 19, 2007, a Smart Grid Advisory Committee (either as an independent entity or as a designated sub-part of a larger advisory committee on electricity matters). The Smart Grid Advisory Committee shall include eight or more members appointed by the Secretary who have sufficient experience and expertise to represent the full range of smart grid technologies and services, to represent both private and non-Federal public sector stakeholders. One member shall be appointed by the Secretary to Chair the Smart Grid Advisory Committee.


(2) MissionThe mission of the Smart Grid Advisory Committee shall be to advise the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary, and other relevant Federal officials concerning the development of smart grid technologies, the progress of a national transition to the use of smart-grid technologies and services, the evolution of widely-accepted technical and practical standards and protocols to allow interoperability and inter-communication among smart-grid capable devices, and the optimum means of using Federal incentive authority to encourage such progress.


(3) Applicability of chapter 10 of title 5Chapter 10 of title 5 shall apply to the Smart Grid Advisory Committee.



(b) Smart Grid Task Force(1) EstablishmentThe Assistant Secretary of the Office of Electricity Delivery and Energy Reliability shall establish, within 90 days of December 19, 2007, a Smart Grid Task Force composed of designated employees from the various divisions of that office who have responsibilities related to the transition to smart-grid technologies and practices. The Assistant Secretary or his designee shall be identified as the Director of the Smart Grid Task Force. The Chairman of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall each desi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17383_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smart Grid Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Smart Grid Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17383_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smart Grid Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Smart Grid Task Force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17383_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated for the purposes of this section such sums as are necessary to the Secretary to support the operations of the Smart Grid Advisory Committee and Smart Grid Task Force for each of fiscal years 2008 through 2020.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>