<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1754" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1754/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1754/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1754"><akn:num>1754</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutrition promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1754. Nutrition promotion(a) In generalSubject to the availability of funds made available under subsection (g), the Secretary shall make payments to State agencies for each fiscal year, in accordance with this section, to promote nutrition in food service programs under this chapter and the school breakfast program established under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.).


(b) Total amount for each fiscal yearThe total amount of funds available for a fiscal year for payments under this section shall equal not more than the product obtained by multiplying—(1) ½ cent; by

(2) the number of lunches reimbursed through food service programs under this chapter during the second preceding fiscal year in schools, institutions, and service institutions that participate in the food service programs.


(c) Payments to States(1) AllocationSubject to paragraph (2), from the amount of funds available under subsection (g) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allocate to each State agency an amount equal to the greater of—(A) a uniform base amount established by the Secretary; or

(B) an amount determined by the Secretary, based on the ratio that—(i) the number of lunches reimbursed through food service programs under this chapter in schools, institutions, and service institutions in the State that participate in the food service programs; bears to

(ii) the number of lunches reimbursed through the food service programs in schools, institutions, and service institutions in all States that participate in the food service programs.



(2) ReductionsThe Secretary shall reduce allocations to State agencies qualifying for an allocation under paragraph (1)(B), in a manner determined by the Secretary, to the extent necessary to ensure that the total amount of funds allocated under paragraph (1) is not greater than the amount appropriated under subsection (g).



(d) Use of payments(1) Use by State agenciesA State agency may reserve, to support dissemination and use</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the availability of funds made available under subsection (g), the Secretary shall make payments to State agencies for each fiscal year, in accordance with this section, to promote nutrition in food service programs under this chapter and the school breakfast program established under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Total amount for each fiscal year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Total amount for each fiscal year The total amount of funds available for a fiscal year for payments under this section shall equal not more than the product obtained by multiplying—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payments to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Documentation A State agency, school food authority, and institution receiving funds under this section shall maintain documentation of nutrition promotion activities conducted under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reallocation The Secretary may reallocate, to carry out this section, any amounts made available to carry out this section that are not obligated or expended, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1754_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>