<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1755" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1755/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1755/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1755"><akn:num>1755</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct expenditures for agricultural commodities and other foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1755. Direct expenditures for agricultural commodities and other foods(a) Administrative expenses; nutritional education; pilot projects; cash-in-lieu of commodities study; refusal of commodities and receipt of other commodities available to the State in lieu of the refused commoditiesThe funds provided by appropriation or transfer from other accounts for any fiscal year for carrying out the provisions of this chapter, and for carrying out the provisions of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.], other than section 3 thereof [42 U.S.C. 1772] less(1) not to exceed 3½ per centum thereof which per centum is hereby made available to the Secretary for the Secretary’s administrative expenses under this chapter and under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.];

(2) the amount apportioned by the Secretary pursuant to section 1753 of this title and the amount appropriated pursuant to sections 1759a and 1761 of this title and sections 4 and 7 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1773 and 1776]; and

(3) not to exceed 1 per centum of the funds provided for carrying out the programs under this chapter and the programs under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.], other than section 3 [42 U.S.C. 1772], which per centum is hereby made available to the Secretary to supplement the nutritional benefits of these programs through grants to States and other means for nutritional training and education for workers, cooperators, and participants in these programs, for pilot projects and the cash-in-lieu of commodities study required to be carried out under section 1769 of this title, and for necessary surveys and studies of requirements for food service programs in furtherance of the purposes expressed in section 1751 of this title, and section 2 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771],


shall be available to the Secretary during such year for direct expenditure by the Secretary for agricultural commodities and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative expenses; nutritional education; pilot projects; cash-in-lieu of commodities study; refusal of commodities and receipt of other commodities available to the State in lieu of the refused commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative expenses; nutritional education; pilot projects; cash-in-lieu of commodities study; refusal of commodities and receipt of other commodities available to the State in lieu of the refused commodities The funds provided by appropriation or transfer from other accounts for any fiscal year for carrying out the provisions of this chapter, and for carrying out the provisions of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.], other than section 3 thereof [42 U.S.C. 1772] less shall be available to the Secretary during such year for direct expenditure by the Secretary for agricultural commodities and other foods to be distributed among the States and schools and service institutions participating in the food service programs under this chapter and under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.] in accordance with the needs as determined by the local school and service institution authorities. Except as provided in the next 2 sentences, any school part</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Delivery of commodities The Secretary shall deliver, to each State participating in the school lunch program under this chapter, commodities valued at the total level of assistance authorized under subsection (c) 11 See References in Text note below. for each school year for the school lunch program in the State, not later than September 30 of the following school year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Level of commodity assistance; computation of index; calculation of total assistance to each State; emphasis on high protein foods; per meal value of donated foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Level of commodity assistance; computation of index; calculation of total assistance to each State; emphasis on high protein foods; per meal value of donated foods</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of commodity assistance based upon school breakfast program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination of commodity assistance based upon school breakfast program Beginning with the school year ending June 30, 1981, the Secretary shall not offer commodity assistance based upon the number of breakfasts served to children under section 4 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1773].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum percentage of commodity assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Minimum percentage of commodity assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1755_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot project for procurement of unprocessed fruits and vegetables</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Pilot project for procurement of unprocessed fruits and vegetables</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>