<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1758b"><akn:num>1758b</akn:num><akn:heading>Local school wellness policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1758b. Local school wellness policy(a) In generalEach local educational agency participating in a program authorized by this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.) shall establish a local school wellness policy for all schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency.


(b) GuidelinesThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations that provide the framework and guidelines for local educational agencies to establish local school wellness policies, including, at a minimum,—(1) goals for nutrition promotion and education, physical activity, and other school-based activities that promote student wellness;

(2) for all foods available on each school campus under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency during the school day, nutrition guidelines that—(A) are consistent with sections 1758 and 1766 of this title, and sections 4 and 10 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1773, 1779); and

(B) promote student health and reduce childhood obesity;


(3) a requirement that the local educational agency permit parents, students, representatives of the school food authority, teachers of physical education, school health professionals, the school board, school administrators, and the general public to participate in the development, implementation, and periodic review and update of the local school wellness policy;

(4) a requirement that the local educational agency inform and update the public (including parents, students, and others in the community) about the content and implementation of the local school wellness policy; and

(5) a requirement that the local educational agency—(A) periodically measure and make available to the public an assessment on the implementation of the local school wellness policy, including—(i) the extent to which schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency are in compliance with the local school wellness policy;

(ii) the extent to which the local school wellness policy of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each local educational agency participating in a program authorized by this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.) shall establish a local school wellness policy for all schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guidelines The Secretary shall promulgate regulations that provide the framework and guidelines for local educational agencies to establish local school wellness policies, including, at a minimum,—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local discretion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Local discretion The local educational agency shall use the guidelines promulgated by the Secretary under subsection (b) to determine specific policies appropriate for the schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance and best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance and best practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>