<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1758/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1758"><akn:num>1758</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1758. Program requirements(a) Nutritional requirements(1)(A) Lunches served by schools participating in the school lunch program under this chapter shall meet minimum nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary on the basis of tested nutritional research, except that the minimum nutritional requirements—(i) shall not be construed to prohibit the substitution of foods to accommodate the medical or other special dietary needs of individual students; and

(ii) shall, at a minimum, be based on the weekly average of the nutrient content of school lunches.


(B) The Secretary shall provide technical assistance and training, including technical assistance and training in the preparation of lower-fat versions of foods commonly used in the school lunch program under this chapter, to schools participating in the school lunch program to assist the schools in complying with the nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary pursuant to subparagraph (A) and in providing appropriate meals to children with medically certified special dietary needs. The Secretary shall provide additional technical assistance to schools that are having difficulty maintaining compliance with the requirements.


(2) Fluid milk.—(A) In general.—Lunches served by schools participating in the school lunch program under this chapter—(i) shall offer students a variety of fluid milk. Such milk shall be consistent with the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans published under section 5341 of title 7;

(ii) may offer students flavored and unflavored fluid milk and lactose-free fluid milk; and

(iii) shall provide a substitute for fluid milk for students whose disability restricts their diet, on receipt of a written statement from a licensed physician that identifies the disability that restricts the student’s diet and that specifies the substitute for fluid milk.


(B) Substitutes.—(i) Standards for substitution.—A school may substitute for the fluid milk provided under subparagraph (A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutritional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nutritional requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation on nonprofit basis; donation of agricultural commodities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Operation on nonprofit basis; donation of agricultural commodities School lunch programs under this chapter shall be operated on a nonprofit basis. Commodities purchased under the authority of section 612c of title 7, may be donated by the Secretary to schools, in accordance with the needs as determined by local school authorities, for utilization in the school lunch program under this chapter as well as to other schools carrying out nonprofit school lunch programs and institutions authorized to receive such commodities. The requirements of this section relating to the service of meals without cost or at a reduced cost shall apply to the lunch program of any school utilizing commodities donated under any provision of law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Social Security numbers and other documentation required as condition of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Social Security numbers and other documentation required as condition of eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on meal contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on meal contracting A school or school food authority participating in a program under this chapter may not contract with a food service company to provide a la carte food service unless the company agrees to offer free, reduced price, and full-price reimbursable meals to all eligible children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutritional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Nutritional requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Justification of production records; paperwork reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Justification of production records; paperwork reduction Not later than 1 year after November 2, 1994, the Secretary shall provide a notification to Congress that justifies the need for production records required under section 210.10(b) of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations, and describes how the Secretary has reduced paperwork relating to the school lunch and school breakfast programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Food safety</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Food safety</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Single permanent agreement between State agency and school food authority; common claims form</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Single permanent agreement between State agency and school food authority; common claims form</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1758_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases of locally produced foods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Purchases of locally produced foods The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>