<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1760" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1760/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1760/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1760"><akn:num>1760</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1760. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Accounts and recordsStates, State educational agencies, and schools participating in the school lunch program under this chapter shall keep such accounts and records as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to determine whether the provisions of this chapter are being complied with. Such accounts and records shall be available at any reasonable time for inspection and audit by representatives of the Secretary and shall be preserved for such period of time, not in excess of five years, as the Secretary determines is necessary.


(b) Agreements(1) In generalThe Secretary shall incorporate, in the agreement of the Secretary with the State agencies and Indian Tribal organizations administering programs authorized under this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.), the express requirements with respect to the operation of the programs to the extent applicable and such other provisions as in the opinion of the Secretary are reasonably necessary or appropriate to effectuate the purposes of this chapter and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.).


(2) Expectations for use of fundsAgreements described in paragraph (1) shall include a provision that—(A) supports full use of Federal funds provided to State agencies and Indian Tribal organizations for the administration of programs authorized under this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.); and

(B) excludes the Federal funds from State and Indian Tribal organization budget restrictions or limitations including, at a minimum—(i) hiring freezes;

(ii) work furloughs; and

(iii) travel restrictions.




(c) Requirements with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, etc.In carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary shall not impose any requirement with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, methods of instruction, and materials of instruction in any school.


(d) Defin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accounts and records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Accounts and records States, State educational agencies, and schools participating in the school lunch program under this chapter shall keep such accounts and records as may be necessary to enable the Secretary to determine whether the provisions of this chapter are being complied with. Such accounts and records shall be available at any reasonable time for inspection and audit by representatives of the Secretary and shall be preserved for such period of time, not in excess of five years, as the Secretary determines is necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, etc. In carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary shall not impose any requirement with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, methods of instruction, and materials of instruction in any school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For the purposes of this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Value of assistance as income or resources under Federal or State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Value of assistance as income or resources under Federal or State laws The value of assistance to children under this chapter shall not be considered to be income or resources for any purposes under any Federal or State laws, including laws relating to taxation and welfare and public assistance programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustment of national average payment rate for Alaska, Hawaii, territories and possessions, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Adjustment of national average payment rate for Alaska, Hawaii, territories and possessions, etc. In providing assistance for breakfasts, lunches, suppers, and supplements served in Alaska, Hawaii, Guam, American Samoa, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Secretary may establish appropriate adjustments for each such State to the national average payment rates prescribed under sections 1753, 1759a, 1761, and 1766 of this title and section 4 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1773], to reflect the differences between the costs of providing meals and supplements in those States and the costs of providing meals and supplements in all other States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Criminal penalties Whoever embezzles, willfully misapplies, steals, or obtains by fraud any funds, assets, or property that are the subject of a grant or other form of assistance under this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.], whether received directly or indirectly from the United States Department of Agriculture, or whoever receives, conceals, or retains such funds, assets, or property to personal use or gain, knowing such funds, assets, or property have been embezzled, willfully misapplied, stolen, or obtained by fraud shall, if such funds, assets, or property are of the value of $100 or more, be fined not more than $25,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both, or, if such funds, assets, or property are of a value of less than $100, shall be fined not more than $1,000 or imprisoned for not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Combined allocation for breakfast and lunch</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Combined allocation for breakfast and lunch No provision of this chapter or of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.] shall require any school receiving funds under this chapter and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to account separately for the cost incurred in the school lunch and school breakfast programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of school lunch facilities for elderly programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Use of school lunch facilities for elderly programs Facilities, equipment, and personnel provided to a school food authority for a program authorized under this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.] may be used, as determined by a local educational agency, to support a nonprofit nutrition program for the elderly, including a program funded under the Older Americans Act of 1965 [42 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1760_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement for final claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reimbursement for final claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>