<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1762a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1762a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1762a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1762a"><akn:num>1762a</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity distribution program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1762a. Commodity distribution program(a) Use of funds for purchase of agricultural commodities and products for donationNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall—(1) use funds available to carry out the provisions of section 612c of title 7 which are not expended or needed to carry out such provisions, to purchase (without regard to the provisions of existing law governing the expenditure of public funds) agricultural commodities and their products of the types customarily purchased under such section (which may include domestic seafood commodities and their products), for donation to maintain the annually programmed level of assistance for programs carried on under this chapter, the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.], and title III of the Older Americans Act of 1965 [42 U.S.C. 3021 et seq.]; and

(2) if stocks of the Commodity Credit Corporation are not available, use the funds of such Corporation to purchase agricultural commodities and their products of the types customarily available under section 1431 of title 7, for such donation.


(b) Nutrition quality and content information(1) The Secretary shall maintain and continue to improve the overall nutritional quality of entitlement commodities provided to schools to assist the schools in improving the nutritional content of meals.

(2) The Secretary shall—(A) require that nutritional content information labels be placed on packages or shipments of entitlement commodities provided to the schools; or

(B) otherwise provide nutritional content information regarding the commodities provided to the schools.



(c) Authorization of appropriations for purchase of products or for cash payments in lieu of donationsThe Secretary may use funds appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury to purchase agricultural commodities and their products of the types customarily purchased for donation under section 311(a)(4) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Older Americans Act</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds for purchase of agricultural commodities and products for donation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Use of funds for purchase of agricultural commodities and products for donation Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutrition quality and content information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Nutrition quality and content information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations for purchase of products or for cash payments in lieu of donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations for purchase of products or for cash payments in lieu of donations The Secretary may use funds appropriated from the general fund of the Treasury to purchase agricultural commodities and their products of the types customarily purchased for donation under section 311(a)(4) 11 See References in Text note below. of the Older Americans Act of 1965 or for cash payments in lieu of such donations under section 311(b)(1) 1 of such Act. There are hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance procedures; cost and benefits, review; technical assistance; report to Congress; food quality standards contracting procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance procedures; cost and benefits, review; technical assistance; report to Congress; food quality standards contracting procedures In providing assistance under this chapter and the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 [42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.] for school lunch and breakfast programs, the Secretary shall establish procedures which will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with school representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with school representatives Each State agency that receives food assistance payments under this section for any school year shall consult with representatives of schools in the State that participate in the school lunch program with respect to the needs of such schools relating to the manner of selection and distribution of commodity assistance for such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commodity only schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Commodity only schools Commodity only schools shall be eligible to receive donated commodities equal in value to the sum of the national average value of donated foods established under section 1755(c) of this title and the national average payment established under section 1753 of this title. Such schools shall be eligible to receive up to 5 cents per meal of such value in cash for processing and handling expenses related to the use of such commodities. Lunches served in such schools shall consist of a combination of foods which meet the minimum nutritional requirements prescribed by the Secretary under section 1758(a) of this title, and shall represent the four basic food groups, including a serving of fluid milk.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of alternative means of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Extension of alternative means of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1762a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of irradiated food products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Notice of irradiated food products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>