<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1769a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1769a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1769a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1769a"><akn:num>1769a</akn:num><akn:heading>Fresh fruit and vegetable program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1769a. Fresh fruit and vegetable program(a) In generalFor the school year beginning July 2008 and each subsequent school year, the Secretary shall provide grants to States to carry out a program to make free fresh fruits and vegetables available in elementary schools (referred to in this section as the “program”).


(b) ProgramA school participating in the program shall make free fresh fruits and vegetables available to students throughout the school day (or at such other times as are considered appropriate by the Secretary) in 1 or more areas designated by the school.


(c) Funding to States(1) Minimum grantExcept as provided in subsection (i)(2), the Secretary shall provide to each of the 50 States and the District of Columbia an annual grant in an amount equal to 1 percent of the funds made available for a year to carry out the program.


(2) Additional fundingOf the funds remaining after grants are made under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall allocate additional funds to each State that is operating a school lunch program under section 1753 of this title based on the proportion that—(A) the population of the State; bears to

(B) the population of the United States.



(d) Selection of schools(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection and section 4304(a)(2) of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008, each year, in selecting schools to participate in the program, each State shall—(A) ensure that each school chosen to participate in the program is a school—(i) in which not less than 50 percent of the students are eligible for free or reduced price meals under this chapter; and

(ii) that submits an application in accordance with subparagraph (D);


(B) to the maximum extent practicable, give the highest priority to schools with the highest proportion of children who are eligible for free or reduced price meals under this chapter;

(C) ensure that each school selected is an elementary school (as defined in section 7801 11 See Refe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the school year beginning July 2008 and each subsequent school year, the Secretary shall provide grants to States to carry out a program to make free fresh fruits and vegetables available in elementary schools (referred to in this section as the “program”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program A school participating in the program shall make free fresh fruits and vegetables available to students throughout the school day (or at such other times as are considered appropriate by the Secretary) in 1 or more areas designated by the school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding to States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection of schools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of availability If selected to participate in the program, a school shall widely publicize within the school the availability of free fresh fruits and vegetables under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Per-student grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Per-student grant The per-student grant provided to a school under this section shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Limitation To the maximum extent practicable, each State agency shall ensure that in making the fruits and vegetables provided under this section available to students, schools offer the fruits and vegetables separately from meals otherwise provided at the school under this chapter or the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (42 U.S.C. 1771 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Evaluation and reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1769a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>