<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1773" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1773/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1773/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1773"><akn:num>1773</akn:num><akn:heading>School breakfast program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1773. School breakfast program(a) Establishment; authorization of appropriationsThere is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to enable the Secretary to carry out a program to assist the States and the Department of Defense through grants-in-aid and other means to initiate, maintain, or expand nonprofit breakfast programs in all schools which make application for assistance and agree to carry out a nonprofit breakfast program in accordance with this chapter. Appropriations and expenditures for this chapter shall be considered Health and Human Services functions for budget purposes rather than functions of Agriculture.


(b) Breakfast assistance payments to State educational agencies; calculation; national average payments for breakfasts, free breakfasts and reduced price breakfasts; maximum price for reduced cost breakfasts; minimum daily nutrition requirements criteria; additional payments for severe need schools; maximum severe need payments(1)(A)(i) The Secretary shall make breakfast assistance payments to each State educational agency each fiscal year, at such times as the Secretary may determine, from the sums appropriated for such purpose, in an amount equal to the product obtained by multiplying—(I) the number of breakfasts served during such fiscal year to children in schools in such States which participate in the school breakfast program under agreements with such State educational agency; by

(II) the national average breakfast payment for free breakfasts, for reduced price breakfasts, or for breakfasts served to children not eligible for free or reduced price meals, as appropriate, as prescribed in clause (B) of this paragraph.


(ii) The agreements described in clause (i)(I) shall be permanent agreements that may be amended as necessary. Nothing in the preceding sentence shall be construed to limit the ability of the State educational agency to suspend or terminate any such agreement in accordance with regulations prescribed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1773_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; authorization of appropriations There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to enable the Secretary to carry out a program to assist the States and the Department of Defense through grants-in-aid and other means to initiate, maintain, or expand nonprofit breakfast programs in all schools which make application for assistance and agree to carry out a nonprofit breakfast program in accordance with this chapter. Appropriations and expenditures for this chapter shall be considered Health and Human Services functions for budget purposes rather than functions of Agriculture.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1773_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breakfast assistance payments to State educational agencies; calculation; national average payments for breakfasts, free breakfasts and reduced price breakfasts; maximum price for reduced cost breakfasts; minimum daily nutrition requirements criteria; additional payments for severe need schools; maximum severe need payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Breakfast assistance payments to State educational agencies; calculation; national average payments for breakfasts, free breakfasts and reduced price breakfasts; maximum price for reduced cost breakfasts; minimum daily nutrition requirements criteria; additional payments for severe need schools; maximum severe need payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1773_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disbursement of apportioned funds by State; preference for schools in poor economic areas, for students traveling long distances daily, and for schools for improvement of nutrition and dietary practices of children of working mothers and from low-income families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disbursement of apportioned funds by State; preference for schools in poor economic areas, for students traveling long distances daily, and for schools for improvement of nutrition and dietary practices of children of working mothers and from low-income families Funds apportioned and paid to any State for the purpose of this section shall be disbursed by the State educational agency to schools selected by the State educational agency to assist such schools in operating a breakfast program and for the purpose of subsection (d). Disbursement to schools shall be made at such rates per meal or on such other basis as the Secretary shall prescribe. In selecting schools for participation, the State educational agency shall, to the extent practicable, give first consideration to those schools drawing attendance from areas in which poor economic conditions exist, to those schools in which a substantial proportion of the children enrolled must travel long distances daily, and to those school</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1773_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Severe need assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Severe need assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1773_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutritional requirements; service free or at reduced price; compliance assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nutritional requirements; service free or at reduced price; compliance assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>