<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1780" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1780/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1780/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1780"><akn:num>1780</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1780. Prohibitions(a) Interference with school personnel, curriculum, or instructionIn carrying out the provisions of sections 1772 and 1773 of this title, the Secretary shall not impose any requirements with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, methods of instruction, and materials of instruction.


(b) Inclusion of assistance in determining income or resourcesThe value of assistance to children under this chapter shall not be considered to be income or resources for any purpose under any Federal or State laws including, but not limited to, laws relating to taxation, welfare, and public assistance programs. Expenditures of funds from State and local sources for the maintenance of food programs for children shall not be diminished as a result of funds received under this chapter.


(c) Federal law not applicableSection 1693r of title 15 shall not apply to electronic benefit transfer systems established under this chapter or the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.).


(Pub. L. 89–642, § 11, Oct. 11, 1966, 80 Stat. 889; Pub. L. 97–35, title VIII, § 819(f), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 533; Pub. L. 104–193, title VII, § 726, Aug. 22, 1996, 110 Stat. 2302; Pub. L. 111–203, title X, § 1075(d), July 21, 2010, 124 Stat. 2074.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, referred to in subsec. (c), is act June 4, 1946, ch. 281, 60 Stat. 230, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1751 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2010—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 111–203 added subsec. (c).
1996—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 104–193 substituted “the Secretary shall not” for “neither the Secretary nor the State shall”.
1981—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 97–35 struck out reference to section 1774 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2010 AmendmentAmendme</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1780_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interference with school personnel, curriculum, or instruction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interference with school personnel, curriculum, or instruction In carrying out the provisions of sections 1772 and 1773 of this title, the Secretary shall not impose any requirements with respect to teaching personnel, curriculum, instruction, methods of instruction, and materials of instruction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1780_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of assistance in determining income or resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inclusion of assistance in determining income or resources The value of assistance to children under this chapter shall not be considered to be income or resources for any purpose under any Federal or State laws including, but not limited to, laws relating to taxation, welfare, and public assistance programs. Expenditures of funds from State and local sources for the maintenance of food programs for children shall not be diminished as a result of funds received under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1780_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal law not applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal law not applicable Section 1693r of title 15 shall not apply to electronic benefit transfer systems established under this chapter or the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>