<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1782" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1782/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1782/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1782"><akn:num>1782</akn:num><akn:heading>Centralization in Department of Agriculture of administration of food service programs for children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1782. Centralization in Department of Agriculture of administration of food service programs for children
Authority for the conduct and supervision of Federal programs to assist schools in providing food service programs for children is assigned to the Department of Agriculture. To the extent practicable, other Federal agencies administering programs under which funds are to be provided to schools for such assistance shall transfer such funds to the Department of Agriculture for distribution through the administrative channels and in accordance with the standards established under this chapter and the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act [42 U.S.C. 1751 et seq.].
(Pub. L. 89–642, § 13, Oct. 11, 1966, 80 Stat. 889; Pub. L. 106–78, title VII, § 752(b)(16), Oct. 22, 1999, 113 Stat. 1170.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act, referred to in text, is act June 4, 1946, ch. 281, 60 Stat. 230, which is classified generally to chapter 13 (§ 1751 et seq.) of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 1751 of this title and Tables.

Amendments1999—Pub. L. 106–78 substituted “Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act” for “National School Lunch Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>