<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1786" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1786/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1786/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1786"><akn:num>1786</akn:num><akn:heading>Special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1786. Special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children(a) Congressional findings and declaration of purposeCongress finds that substantial numbers of pregnant, postpartum, and breastfeeding women, infants, and young children from families with inadequate income are at special risk with respect to their physical and mental health by reason of inadequate nutrition or health care, or both. It is, therefore, the purpose of the program authorized by this section to provide, up to the authorization levels set forth in subsection (g) of this section, supplemental foods and nutrition education, including breastfeeding promotion and support, through any eligible local agency that applies for participation in the program. The program shall serve as an adjunct to good health care, during critical times of growth and development, to prevent the occurrence of health problems, including drug abuse, and improve the health status of these persons.


(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section—(1) “Breastfeeding women” means women up to one year postpartum who are breastfeeding their infants.

(2) “Children” means persons who have had their first birthday but have not yet attained their fifth birthday.

(3) “Competent professional authority” means physicians, nutritionists, registered nurses, dietitians, or State or local medically trained health officials, or persons designated by physicians or State or local medically trained health officials, in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary, as being competent professionally to evaluate nutritional risk.

(4) “Costs of nutrition services and administration” or “nutrition services and administration” means costs that shall include, but not be limited to, costs for certification of eligibility of persons for participation in the program (including centrifuges, measuring boards, spectrophotometers, and scales used for the certification), food delivery, monitoring, nutrition education, breastfeeding suppor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional findings and declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Congressional findings and declaration of purpose Congress finds that substantial numbers of pregnant, postpartum, and breastfeeding women, infants, and young children from families with inadequate income are at special risk with respect to their physical and mental health by reason of inadequate nutrition or health care, or both. It is, therefore, the purpose of the program authorized by this section to provide, up to the authorization levels set forth in subsection (g) of this section, supplemental foods and nutrition education, including breastfeeding promotion and support, through any eligible local agency that applies for participation in the program. The program shall serve as an adjunct to good health care, during critical times of growth and development, to prevent the occurrence of health problems, including drug abuse, and improve the health status of these persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants-in-aid; cash grants; ratable reduction of amount an agency may distribute; affirmative action; regulations relating to dual receipt of benefits under commodity supplemental food program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants-in-aid; cash grants; ratable reduction of amount an agency may distribute; affirmative action; regulations relating to dual receipt of benefits under commodity supplemental food program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible participants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutrition education and drug abuse education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Nutrition education and drug abuse education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan of operation and administration by State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Plan of operation and administration by State agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds for nutrition services and administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funds for nutrition services and administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Division of funds formula; reallocation of unspent funds; use of State allocation to buy supplemental foods; use of amounts available for succeeding fiscal year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Division of funds formula; reallocation of unspent funds; use of State allocation to buy supplemental foods; use of amounts available for succeeding fiscal year</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1786_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiative to provide program services at community and migrant health centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Initiative to provide program services at community and migrant health centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>