<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1791" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1791/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1791/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1791"><akn:num>1791</akn:num><akn:heading>Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1791. Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act”.


(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) Apparently fit grocery productThe term “apparently fit grocery product” means a grocery product that meets all quality and labeling standards imposed by Federal, State, and local laws and regulations even though the product may not be readily marketable due to appearance, age, freshness, grade, size, surplus, or other conditions.


(2) Apparently wholesome foodThe term “apparently wholesome food” means food that meets all quality and labeling standards imposed by Federal, State, and local laws and regulations even though the food may not be readily marketable due to appearance, age, freshness, grade, size, surplus, or other conditions.


(3) DonateThe term “donate” means to give without requiring anything of monetary value from the recipient, except that the term shall include giving by a nonprofit organization to another nonprofit organization, notwithstanding that the donor organization has charged a nominal fee to the donee organization, if the ultimate recipient or user is not required to give anything of monetary value or is charged a good Samaritan reduced price.


(4) FoodThe term “food” means any raw, cooked, processed, or prepared edible substance, ice, beverage, or ingredient used or intended for use in whole or in part for human consumption.


(5) GleanerThe term “gleaner” means a person who harvests for free distribution to the needy, or for donation to a nonprofit organization for ultimate distribution to the needy, an agricultural crop that has been donated by the owner.


(6) Good Samaritan reduced priceThe term “good Samaritan reduced price” means, with respect to the price of an apparently wholesome food or apparently fit grocery product, a price that is an amount not greater than the cost of handling, administering, harvesting, processing, packaging, transp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Bill Emerson Good Samaritan Food Donation Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability for damages from donated food and grocery products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liability for damages from donated food and grocery products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection or gleaning of donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Collection or gleaning of donations A person who allows the collection or gleaning of donations on property owned or occupied by the person by gleaners, or paid or unpaid representatives of a nonprofit organization, for ultimate distribution to needy individuals shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability that arises due to the injury or death of the gleaner or representative, except that this paragraph shall not apply to an injury or death that results from an act or omission of the person constituting gross negligence or intentional misconduct.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Partial compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Partial compliance If some or all of the donated food and grocery products do not meet all quality and labeling standards imposed by Federal, State, and local laws and regulations, the person or gleaner who donates the food and grocery products shall not be subject to civil or criminal liability in accordance with this section if the nonprofit organization that receives the donated food or grocery products—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1791_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction This section shall not be construed to create any liability. Nothing in this section shall be construed to supercede State or local health regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>