<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17921" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17921/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17921/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17921"><akn:num>17921</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17921. Definitions
In this subchapter, except as specified otherwise:(1) Breach(A) In generalThe term “breach” means the unauthorized acquisition, access, use, or disclosure of protected health information which compromises the security or privacy of such information, except where an unauthorized person to whom such information is disclosed would not reasonably have been able to retain such information.


(B) ExceptionsThe term “breach” does not include—(i) any unintentional acquisition, access, or use of protected health information by an employee or individual acting under the authority of a covered entity or business associate if—(I) such acquisition, access, or use was made in good faith and within the course and scope of the employment or other professional relationship of such employee or individual, respectively, with the covered entity or business associate; and

(II) such information is not further acquired, accessed, used, or disclosed by any person; or


(ii) any inadvertent disclosure from an individual who is otherwise authorized to access protected health information at a facility operated by a covered entity or business associate to another similarly situated individual at 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “the”. same facility; and

(iii) any such information received as a result of such disclosure is not further acquired, accessed, used, or disclosed without authorization by any person.



(2) Business associateThe term “business associate” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.


(3) Covered entityThe term “covered entity” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.


(4) DiscloseThe terms “disclose” and “disclosure” have the meaning given the term “disclosure” in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.


(5) Electronic health recordThe term “electronic health record” means an electronic record of health-related </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Breach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Business associate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Business associate The term “business associate” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Covered entity The term “covered entity” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Disclose The terms “disclose” and “disclosure” have the meaning given the term “disclosure” in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Electronic health record</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Electronic health record The term “electronic health record” means an electronic record of health-related information on an individual that is created, gathered, managed, and consulted by authorized health care clinicians and staff.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Health care operations The term “health care operation” has the meaning given such term in section 164.501 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Health care provider The term “health care provider” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Health plan The term “health plan” has the meaning given such term in section 160.103 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Coordinator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) National Coordinator The term “National Coordinator” means the head of the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology established under section 300jj–11(a) of this title, as added by section 13101.22 See References in Text note below.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17921_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Payment The term “payment” has the meaning given such term in section 164.501 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>