<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1792" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1792/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1792/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1792"><akn:num>1792</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting Federal food donation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1792. Promoting Federal food donation(a) In generalNot later than 180 days after June 20, 2008, the Federal Acquisition Regulation issued in accordance with section 1303 of title 41 shall be revised to provide that all contracts above $25,000 for the provision, service, or sale of food in the United States, or for the lease or rental of Federal property to a private entity for events at which food is provided in the United States, shall include a clause that—(1) encourages the donation of excess, apparently wholesome food to nonprofit organizations that provide assistance to food-insecure people in the United States; and

(2) states the terms and conditions described in subsection (b).


(b) Terms and conditions(1) CostsIn any case in which a contractor enters into a contract with an executive agency under which apparently wholesome food is donated to food-insecure people in the United States, the head of the executive agency shall not assume responsibility for the costs and logistics of collecting, transporting, maintaining the safety of, or distributing excess, apparently wholesome food to food-insecure people in the United States under this section.


(2) LiabilityAn executive agency (including an executive agency that enters into a contract with a contractor) and any contractor making donations pursuant to this section shall be exempt from civil and criminal liability to the extent provided under section 1791 of this title.



(Pub. L. 110–247, § 4, June 20, 2008, 122 Stat. 2314.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis section, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 110–247, June 20, 2008, 122 Stat. 2314, which enacted this section and provisions set out as notes under this section and section 1771 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2008 Amendment note set out under section 1771 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Federal Food Donat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1792_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 180 days after June 20, 2008, the Federal Acquisition Regulation issued in accordance with section 1303 of title 41 shall be revised to provide that all contracts above $25,000 for the provision, service, or sale of food in the United States, or for the lease or rental of Federal property to a private entity for events at which food is provided in the United States, shall include a clause that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1792_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>