<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17939" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17939/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/17939/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_17939"><akn:num>17939</akn:num><akn:heading>Improved enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 17939. Improved enforcement(a) In general(1) Omitted

(2) Enforcement under Social Security ActAny violation by a covered entity under thus 11 So in original. Probably should be “this”. subchapter is subject to enforcement and penalties under section 22 So in original. Probably should be “sections”. 1176 and 1177 of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1320d–5, 1320d–6].



(b) Effective date; regulations(1) The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to penalties imposed on or after the date that is 24 months after February 17, 2009.

(2) Not later than 18 months after February 17, 2009, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate regulations to implement such amendments.


(c) Distribution of certain civil monetary penalties collected(1) In generalSubject to the regulation promulgated pursuant to paragraph (3), any civil monetary penalty or monetary settlement collected with respect to an offense punishable under this subchapter or section 1176 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320d–5) insofar as such section relates to privacy or security shall be transferred to the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services to be used for purposes of enforcing the provisions of this subchapter and subparts C and E of part 164 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, as such provisions are in effect as of February 17, 2009.


(2) GAO reportNot later than 18 months after February 17, 2009, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Secretary a report including recommendations for a methodology under which an individual who is harmed by an act that constitutes an offense referred to in paragraph (1) may receive a percentage of any civil monetary penalty or monetary settlement collected with respect to such offense.


(3) Establishment of methodology to distribute percentage of CMPS collected to harmed individualsNot later than 3 years after February 17, 2009, the Secretary shall establish by regulation and based on the recomm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17939_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17939_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effective date; regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17939_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of certain civil monetary penalties collected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution of certain civil monetary penalties collected</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17939_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tiered increase in amount of civil monetary penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Tiered increase in amount of civil monetary penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_17939_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement through State attorneys general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Enforcement through State attorneys general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>