<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1793" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1793/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1793/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1793"><akn:num>1793</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for expansion of school breakfast programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1793. Grants for expansion of school breakfast programs(a) Definition of qualifying schoolIn this section, the term “qualifying school” means a school in severe need, as described in section 1773(d)(1) of this title.


(b) EstablishmentSubject to the availability of appropriations provided in advance in an appropriations Act specifically for the purpose of carrying out this section, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies for the purpose of providing subgrants to local educational agencies for qualifying schools to establish, maintain, or expand the school breakfast program in accordance with this section.


(c) Grants to State educational agencies(1) ApplicationTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a State educational agency shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(2) AdministrationIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—(A) develop an appropriate competitive application process; and

(B) make information available to State educational agencies concerning the availability of funds under this section.


(3) AllocationThe amount of grants provided by the Secretary to State educational agencies for a fiscal year under this section shall not exceed the lesser of—(A) the product obtained by multiplying—(i) the number of qualifying schools receiving subgrants or other benefits under subsection (d) for the fiscal year; and

(ii) the maximum amount of a subgrant provided to a qualifying school under subsection (d)(4)(B); or


(B) $2,000,000.



(d) Subgrants to qualifying schools(1) In generalA State educational agency receiving a grant under this section shall use funds made available under the grant to award subgrants to local educational agencies for a qualifying school or groups of qualifying schools to carry out activities in accordance with t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of qualifying school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of qualifying school In this section, the term “qualifying school” means a school in severe need, as described in section 1773(d)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment Subject to the availability of appropriations provided in advance in an appropriations Act specifically for the purpose of carrying out this section, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide grants, on a competitive basis, to State educational agencies for the purpose of providing subgrants to local educational agencies for qualifying schools to establish, maintain, or expand the school breakfast program in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to State educational agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants to State educational agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subgrants to qualifying schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Subgrants to qualifying schools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Best practices</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Maintenance of effort Grants made available under this section shall not diminish or otherwise affect the expenditure of funds from State and local sources for the maintenance of the school breakfast program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports Not later than 18 months following the end of a school year during which subgrants are awarded under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the activities of the qualifying schools awarded subgrants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Evaluation Not later than 180 days before the end of a grant term under this section, a local educational agency that receives a subgrant under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1793_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>