<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1801...1819" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1801...1819/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1801...1819/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1801___1819"><akn:num>1801...1819</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§§ 1801 to 1819. Transferred
Editorial Notes
Codification
The Atomic Energy Act of 1946, which was formerly classified to sections 1801 to 1819 of this title, was act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, 60 Stat. 755. Act Aug. 1, 1946, was renamed the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 and completely amended by act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 919, and is classified principally to chapter 23 (§ 2011 et seq.) of this title. Provisions enacted in the Aug. 30, 1954, amendment largely corresponded to and expanded upon the provisions in the original Atomic Energy Act of 1946, as described below.
Section 1801, act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, § 1, 60 Stat. 755, related to declaration of policy and purpose of chapter. For corresponding provisions from the Aug. 30, 1954, amendment, see sections 2011 to 2013 of this title.
Section 1802, acts Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, § 2, 60 Stat. 756; July 26, 1947, ch. 343, title II, § 205(a), 61 Stat. 501; July 3, 1948, ch. 828, 62 Stat. 1259; Oct. 11, 1949, ch. 673, §§ 1–3, 63 Stat. 762; Sept. 23, 1950, ch. 1000, §§ 1, 2, 64 Stat. 979; July 31, 1953, ch. 283, § 1, 67 Stat. 240, related to establishment of Atomic Energy Commission, its membership, tenure, compensation, and appointment of certain officers and committees. For corresponding provisions from the Aug. 30, 1954, amendment, see sections 2031 to 2038 of this title.
Section 1803, act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, § 3, 60 Stat. 758, related to research and development activities by Commission. For corresponding provisions from the Aug. 30, 1954, amendment, see sections 2051 to 2053 of this title.
Section 1804, act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, § 4, 60 Stat. 759, related to production of fissionable material, prohibited acts, ownership and operation of production facilities, irradiation of materials, and manufacture of production facilities. For corresponding provisions from the Aug. 30, 1954, amendment, see sections 2061 to 2112 of this title.
Section 1805, acts Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, § 5, 60 Stat. 760; Oct. 30, 1951,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>