<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18042" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18042/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18042/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18042"><akn:num>18042</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal program to assist establishment and operation of nonprofit, member-run health insurance issu</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18042. Federal program to assist establishment and operation of nonprofit, member-run health insurance issuers(a) Establishment of program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program to carry out the purposes of this section to be known as the Consumer Operated and Oriented Plan (CO–OP) program.


(2) PurposeIt is the purpose of the CO–OP program to foster the creation of qualified nonprofit health insurance issuers to offer qualified health plans in the individual and small group markets in the States in which the issuers are licensed to offer such plans.



(b) Loans and grants under the CO–OP program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall provide through the CO–OP program for the awarding to persons applying to become qualified nonprofit health insurance issuers of—(A) loans to provide assistance to such person in meeting its start-up costs; and

(B) grants to provide assistance to such person in meeting any solvency requirements of States in which the person seeks to be licensed to issue qualified health plans.


(2) Requirements for awarding loans and grants(A) In generalIn awarding loans and grants under the CO–OP program, the Secretary shall—(i) take into account the recommendations of the advisory board established under paragraph (3);

(ii) give priority to applicants that will offer qualified health plans on a Statewide basis, will utilize integrated care models, and have significant private support; and

(iii) ensure that there is sufficient funding to establish at least 1 qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer in each State, except that nothing in this clause shall prohibit the Secretary from funding the establishment of multiple qualified nonprofit health insurance issuers in any State if the funding is sufficient to do so.


(B) States without issuers in programIf no health insurance issuer applies to be a qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer within a State, the Secretary may use amounts appropriated under this section for the awarding</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans and grants under the CO–OP program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Loans and grants under the CO–OP program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of private purchasing council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Establishment of private purchasing council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on participation No representative of any Federal, State, or local government (or of any political subdivision or instrumentality thereof), and no representative of a person described in subsection (c)(2)(A), may serve on the board of directors of a qualified nonprofit health insurance issuer or with a private purchasing council established under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitations on Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appropriations There are hereby appropriated, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $6,000,000,000 to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18042_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) GAO study and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>