<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18054" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18054/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18054/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18054"><akn:num>18054</akn:num><akn:heading>Multi-State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18054. Multi-State plans(a) Oversight by the Office of Personnel Management(1) In generalThe Director of the Office of Personnel Management (referred to in this section as the “Director”) shall enter into contracts with health insurance issuers (which may include a group of health insurance issuers affiliated either by common ownership and control or by the common use of a nationally licensed service mark), without regard to section 6101 of title 41 or other statutes requiring competitive bidding, to offer at least 2 multi-State qualified health plans through each Exchange in each State. Such plans shall provide individual, or in the case of small employers, group coverage.


(2) TermsEach contract entered into under paragraph (1) shall be for a uniform term of at least 1 year, but may be made automatically renewable from term to term in the absence of notice of termination by either party. In entering into such contracts, the Director shall ensure that health benefits coverage is provided in accordance with the types of coverage provided for under section 2701(a)(1)(A)(i) of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 300gg(a)(1)(A)(i)].


(3) Non-profit entitiesIn entering into contracts under paragraph (1), the Director shall ensure that at least one contract is entered into with a non-profit entity.


(4) AdministrationThe Director shall implement this subsection in a manner similar to the manner in which the Director implements the contracting provisions with respect to carriers under the Federal employees health benefit program 11 So in original. The words “employees health benefit program” probably should be capitalized. under chapter 89 of title 5, including (through negotiating with each multi-state 22 So in original. Probably should be “multi-State”. plan)—(A) a medical loss ratio;

(B) a profit margin;

(C) the premiums to be charged; and

(D) such other terms and conditions of coverage as are in the interests of enrollees in such plans.


(5) Authority to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Oversight by the Office of Personnel Management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Oversight by the Office of Personnel Management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility A health insurance issuer shall be eligible to enter into a contract under subsection (a)(1) if such issuer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for multi-State qualified health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for multi-State qualified health plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plans deemed to be certified</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Plans deemed to be certified A multi-State qualified health plan that is offered under a contract under subsection (a) shall be deemed to be certified by an Exchange for purposes of section 18031(d)(4)(A) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Phase-in</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Phase-in Notwithstanding paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b), the Director shall enter into a contract with a health insurance issuer for the offering of a multi-State qualified health plan under subsection (a) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Applicability The requirements under chapter 89 of title 5 applicable to health benefits plans under such chapter shall apply to multi-State qualified health plans provided for under this section to the extent that such requirements do not conflict with a provision of this title.3</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued support for FEHBP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Continued support for FEHBP</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Advisory board The Director shall establish an advisory board to provide recommendations on the activities described in this section. A significant percentage of the members of such board shall be comprised of enrollees in a multi-State qualified health plan, or representatives of such enrollees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18054_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated, such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>