<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18053" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18053/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18053/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18053"><akn:num>18053</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions relating to offering of plans in more than one State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18053. Provisions relating to offering of plans in more than one State(a) Health care choice compacts(1) In generalNot later than July 1, 2013, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners, issue regulations for the creation of health care choice compacts under which 2 or more States may enter into an agreement under which—(A) 1 or more qualified health plans could be offered in the individual markets in all such States but, except as provided in subparagraph (B), only be subject to the laws and regulations of the State in which the plan was written or issued;

(B) the issuer of any qualified health plan to which the compact applies—(i) would continue to be subject to market conduct, unfair trade practices, network adequacy, and consumer protection standards (including standards relating to rating), including addressing disputes as to the performance of the contract, of the State in which the purchaser resides;

(ii) would be required to be licensed in each State in which it offers the plan under the compact or to submit to the jurisdiction of each such State with regard to the standards described in clause (i) (including allowing access to records as if the insurer were licensed in the State); and

(iii) must clearly notify consumers that the policy may not be subject to all the laws and regulations of the State in which the purchaser resides.



(2) State authorityA State may not enter into an agreement under this subsection unless the State enacts a law after March 23, 2010, that specifically authorizes the State to enter into such agreements.


(3) Approval of compactsThe Secretary may approve interstate health care choice compacts under paragraph (1) only if the Secretary determines that such health care choice compact—(A) will provide coverage that is at least as comprehensive as the coverage defined in section 18022(b) of this title and offered through Exchanges established under this title; 11 See References</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18053_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care choice compacts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Health care choice compacts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18053_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10104(p), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 902</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>