<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18052" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18052/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18052/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18052"><akn:num>18052</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver for State innovation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18052. Waiver for State innovation(a) Application(1) In generalA State may apply to the Secretary for the waiver of all or any requirements described in paragraph (2) with respect to health insurance coverage within that State for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2017. Such application shall—(A) be filed at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require;

(B) contain such information as the Secretary may require, including—(i) a comprehensive description of the State legislation and program to implement a plan meeting the requirements for a waiver under this section; and

(ii) a 10-year budget plan for such plan that is budget neutral for the Federal Government; and


(C) provide an assurance that the State has enacted the law described in subsection (b)(2).


(2) RequirementsThe requirements described in this paragraph with respect to health insurance coverage within the State for plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2014, are as follows:(A) Part A of this subchapter.

(B) Part B of this subchapter.

(C) Section 18071 of this title.

(D) Sections 36B, 4980H, and 5000A of title 26.


(3) Pass through of fundingWith respect to a State waiver under paragraph (1), under which, due to the structure of the State plan, individuals and small employers in the State would not qualify for the premium tax credits, cost-sharing reductions, or small business credits under sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 36B of title 26 or under part I of subtitle E for which they would otherwise be eligible, the Secretary shall provide for an alternative means by which the aggregate amount of such credits or reductions that would have been paid on behalf of participants in the Exchanges established under this title 22 See References in Text note below. had the State not received such waiver, shall be paid to the State for purposes of implementing the State plan under the waiver. Such amount shall be determined annually by the Secretary, ta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18052_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18052_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Granting of waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Granting of waivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18052_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Scope of waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18052_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determinations by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Determinations by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18052_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Term of waiver No waiver under this section may extend over a period of longer than 5 years unless the State requests continuation of such waiver, and such request shall be deemed granted unless the Secretary, within 90 days after the date of its submission to the Secretary, either denies such request in writing or informs the State in writing with respect to any additional information which is needed in order to make a final determination with respect to the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>