<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18061" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18061/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18061/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18061"><akn:num>18061</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional reinsurance program for individual market in each State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18061. Transitional reinsurance program for individual market in each State(a) In generalEach State shall, not later than January 1, 2014—(1) include in the Federal standards or State law or regulation the State adopts and has in effect under section 18041(b) of this title the provisions described in subsection (b); and

(2) establish (or enter into a contract with) 1 or more applicable reinsurance entities to carry out the reinsurance program under this section.


(b) Model regulation(1) In generalIn establishing the Federal standards under section 18041(a) of this title, the Secretary, in consultation with the National Association of Insurance Commissioners (the “NAIC”), shall include provisions that enable States to establish and maintain a program under which—(A) health insurance issuers, and third party administrators on behalf of group health plans, are required to make payments to an applicable reinsurance entity for any plan year beginning in the 3-year period beginning January 1, 2014 (as specified in paragraph (3); 11 So in original. A second closing parenthesis probably should precede the semicolon. and

(B) the applicable reinsurance entity collects payments under subparagraph (A) and uses amounts so collected to make reinsurance payments to health insurance issuers described in subparagraph (A) that cover high risk individuals in the individual market (excluding grandfathered health plans) for any plan year beginning in such 3-year period.


(2) High-risk individual; payment amountsThe Secretary shall include the following in the provisions under paragraph (1):(A) Determination of high-risk individualsThe method by which individuals will be identified as high risk individuals for purposes of the reinsurance program established under this section. Such method shall provide for identification of individuals as high-risk individuals on the basis of—(i) a list of at least 50 but not more than 100 medical conditions that are identified as high-risk conditi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18061_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Each State shall, not later than January 1, 2014—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18061_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Model regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Model regulation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18061_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable reinsurance entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applicable reinsurance entity For purposes of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18061_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with State high-risk pools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with State high-risk pools The State shall eliminate or modify any State high-risk pool to the extent necessary to carry out the reinsurance program established under this section. The State may coordinate the State high-risk pool with such program to the extent not inconsistent with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>