<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18071" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18071/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18071/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18071"><akn:num>18071</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduced cost-sharing for individuals enrolling in qualified health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18071. Reduced cost-sharing for individuals enrolling in qualified health plans(a) In generalIn the case of an eligible insured enrolled in a qualified health plan—(1) the Secretary shall notify the issuer of the plan of such eligibility; and

(2) the issuer shall reduce the cost-sharing under the plan at the level and in the manner specified in subsection (c).


(b) Eligible insuredIn this section, the term “eligible insured” means an individual—(1) who enrolls in a qualified health plan in the silver level of coverage in the individual market offered through an Exchange; and

(2) whose household income exceeds 100 percent but does not exceed 400 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved.


In the case of an individual described in section 36B(c)(1)(B) of title 26, the individual shall be treated as having household income equal to 100 percent for purposes of applying this section.

(c) Determination of reduction in cost-sharing(1) Reduction in out-of-pocket limit(A) In generalThe reduction in cost-sharing under this subsection shall first be achieved by reducing the applicable out-of pocket 11 So in original. Probably should be “out-of-pocket”. limit under section 18022(c)(1) of this title in the case of—(i) an eligible insured whose household income is more than 100 percent but not more than 200 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, by two-thirds;

(ii) an eligible insured whose household income is more than 200 percent but not more than 300 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, by one-half; and

(iii) an eligible insured whose household income is more than 300 percent but not more than 400 percent of the poverty line for a family of the size involved, by one-third.


(B) Coordination with actuarial value limits(i) In generalThe Secretary shall ensure the reduction under this paragraph shall not result in an increase in the plan’s share of the total allowed costs of benefits provided under th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of an eligible insured enrolled in a qualified health plan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible insured</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible insured In this section, the term “eligible insured” means an individual— In the case of an individual described in section 36B(c)(1)(B) of title 26, the individual shall be treated as having household income equal to 100 percent for purposes of applying this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of reduction in cost-sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination of reduction in cost-sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for Indians</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for Indians</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules for individuals not lawfully present</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules for individuals not lawfully present</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule for individuals who receive unemployment compensation during 2021</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule for individuals who receive unemployment compensation during 2021 For purposes of this section, in the case of an individual who has received, or has been approved to receive, unemployment compensation for any week beginning during 2021, for the plan year in which such week begins—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18071_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions and special rules In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>