<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18082" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18082/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18082/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18082"><akn:num>18082</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance determination and payment of premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18082. Advance determination and payment of premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions(a) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall establish a program under which—(1) upon request of an Exchange, advance determinations are made under section 18081 of this title with respect to the income eligibility of individuals enrolling in a qualified health plan in the individual market through the Exchange for the premium tax credit allowable under section 36B of title 26 and the cost-sharing reductions under section 18071 of this title;

(2) the Secretary notifies—(A) the Exchange and the Secretary of the Treasury of the advance determinations; and

(B) the Secretary of the Treasury of the name and employer identification number of each employer with respect to whom 1 or more employee 11 So in original. Probably should be “employees”. of the employer were determined to be eligible for the premium tax credit under section 36B of title 26 and the cost-sharing reductions under section 18071 of this title because—(i) the employer did not provide minimum essential coverage; or

(ii) the employer provided such minimum essential coverage but it was determined under section 36B(c)(2)(C) of title 26 to either be unaffordable to the employee or not provide the required minimum actuarial value; and



(3) the Secretary of the Treasury makes advance payments of such credit or reductions to the issuers of the qualified health plans in order to reduce the premiums payable by individuals eligible for such credit.


(b) Advance determinations(1) In generalThe Secretary shall provide under the program established under subsection (a) that advance determination of eligibility with respect to any individual shall be made—(A) during the annual open enrollment period applicable to the individual (or such other enrollment period as may be specified by the Secretary); and

(B) on the basis of the individual’s household income for the most recent taxa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18082_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall establish a program under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18082_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advance determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advance determinations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18082_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment of premium tax credits and cost-sharing reductions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18082_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Federal payments for individuals not lawfully present</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) No Federal payments for individuals not lawfully present Nothing in this subtitle or the amendments made by this subtitle allows Federal payments, credits, or cost-sharing reductions for individuals who are not lawfully present in the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18082_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State flexibility Nothing in this subtitle or the amendments made by this subtitle shall be construed to prohibit a State from making payments to or on behalf of an individual for coverage under a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange that are in addition to any credits or cost-sharing reductions allowable to the individual under this subtitle and such amendments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>