<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18302"><akn:num>18302</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18302. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.


(2) Appropriate committees of CongressThe term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—(A) the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and

(B) the Committee on Science 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by “and Technology”. of the House of Representatives.


(3) Cis-lunar spaceThe term “cis-lunar space” means the region of space from the Earth out to and including the region around the surface of the Moon.


(4) Deep spaceThe term “deep space” means the region of space beyond cis-lunar space.


(5) ISSThe term “ISS” means the International Space Station.


(6) NASAThe term “NASA” means the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.


(7) Near-Earth spaceThe term “near-Earth space” means the region of space that includes low-Earth orbit and extends out to and includes geo-synchronous orbit.


(8) NOAAThe term “NOAA” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.


(9) OSTPThe term “OSTP” means the Office of Science and Technology Policy.


(10) Space Launch SystemThe term “Space Launch System” means the follow-on government-owned civil launch system developed, managed, and operated by NASA to serve as a key component to expand human presence beyond low-Earth orbit.


(Pub. L. 111–267, § 3, Oct. 11, 2010, 124 Stat. 2808.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriate committees of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Appropriate committees of Congress The term “appropriate committees of Congress” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cis-lunar space</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Cis-lunar space The term “cis-lunar space” means the region of space from the Earth out to and including the region around the surface of the Moon.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deep space</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Deep space The term “deep space” means the region of space beyond cis-lunar space.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>ISS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) ISS The term “ISS” means the International Space Station.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>NASA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) NASA The term “NASA” means the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Near-Earth space</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Near-Earth space The term “near-Earth space” means the region of space that includes low-Earth orbit and extends out to and includes geo-synchronous orbit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>NOAA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) NOAA The term “NOAA” means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>OSTP</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) OSTP The term “OSTP” means the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18302_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Space Launch System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Space Launch System The term “Space Launch System” means the follow-on government-owned civil launch system developed, managed, and operated by NASA to serve as a key component to expand human presence beyond low-Earth orbit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>