<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18353" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18353/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18353/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18353"><akn:num>18353</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of the United States segment and assurance of continued operations of the International </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18353. Maintenance of the United States segment and assurance of continued operations of the International Space Station(a) In generalThe Administrator shall take all actions necessary to ensure the safe and effective operation, maintenance, and maximum utilization of the United States segment of the ISS through at least September 30, 2030.


(b) Vehicle and component review(1) In generalThe Administrator shall, as soon as is practicable after October 11, 2010, carry out a comprehensive assessment of the essential modules, operational systems and components, structural elements, and permanent scientific equipment on board or planned for delivery and installation aboard the ISS, including both United States and international partner elements, for purposes of identifying the spare or replacement modules, systems and components, elements, and equipment that are required to ensure complete, effective, and safe functioning and full scientific utilization of the ISS through September 30, 2020.11 See References in Text note below.


(2) DataIn carrying out the assessment, the Administrator shall assemble any existing data, and provide for the development of any data or analysis not currently available, that is necessary for purposes of the assessment.



(c) Reports(1) Report on assessment(A) Report requiredNot later than 90 days after October 11, 2010, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the assessment required by subsection (b).


(B) ElementsThe report required by this paragraph shall include, at minimum, the following:(i) A description of the spare or replacement modules, systems and components, elements, and equipment identified pursuant to the assessment that are currently produced, in inventory, or on order, a description of the state of their readiness, and a schedule for their delivery to the ISS (including the planned transportation means for such delivery), including for each such module, system or component, el</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Administrator shall take all actions necessary to ensure the safe and effective operation, maintenance, and maximum utilization of the United States segment of the ISS through at least September 30, 2030.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vehicle and component review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Vehicle and component review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of research facilities and capabilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Utilization of research facilities and capabilities Utilization of research facilities and capabilities aboard the ISS (other than exploration-related research and technology development facilities and capabilities, and associated ground support and logistics), shall be planned, managed, and supported as provided in section 18354 of this title. Exploration-related research and technology development facilities, capabilities, and associated ground support and logistics shall be planned, managed, and supported by the appropriate NASA organizations and officials in a manner that does not interfere with other activities under section 18354 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Space Shuttle mission to ISS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Space Shuttle mission to ISS</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18353_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Space Shuttle manifest flight assurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Space Shuttle manifest flight assurance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>