<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18354" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18354/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18354/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18354"><akn:num>18354</akn:num><akn:heading>Management of the ISS national laboratory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18354. Management of the ISS national laboratory(a) Cooperative agreement with not-for-profit entity for management of national laboratory(1) In generalThe Administrator shall provide initial financial assistance and enter into a cooperative agreement with an appropriate organization that is exempt from taxation under section 501(c)(3) of title 26 to manage the activities of the ISS national laboratory in accordance with this section.


(2) QualificationsThe organization with which the Administrator enters into the cooperative agreement shall develop the capabilities to implement research and development projects utilizing the ISS national laboratory and to otherwise manage the activities of the ISS national laboratory.


(3) Prohibition on other activitiesThe cooperative agreement shall require the organization entering into the agreement to engage exclusively in activities relating to the management of the ISS national laboratory and activities that promote its long term research and development mission as required by this section, without any other organizational objectives or responsibilities on behalf of the organization or any parent organization or other entity.



(b) NASA liaison(1) DesignationThe Administrator shall designate an official or employee of the Space Operations Mission Directorate of NASA to act as liaison between NASA and the organization with which the Administrator enters into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) with regard to the management of the ISS national laboratory.


(2) Consultation with liaisonThe cooperative agreement shall require the organization entering into the agreement to carry out its responsibilities under the agreement in cooperation and consultation with the official or employee designated under paragraph (1).



(c) Planning and coordination of ISS national laboratory research activitiesThe Administrator shall provide initial financial assistance to the organization with which the Administrator enters into a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18354_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreement with not-for-profit entity for management of national laboratory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperative agreement with not-for-profit entity for management of national laboratory</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18354_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>NASA liaison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) NASA liaison</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18354_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning and coordination of ISS national laboratory research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Planning and coordination of ISS national laboratory research activities The Administrator shall provide initial financial assistance to the organization with which the Administrator enters into a cooperative agreement under subsection (a), in order for the organization to initiate the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18354_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research capacity allocation and integration of research payloads</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Research capacity allocation and integration of research payloads</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>