<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862n_9"><akn:num>1862n–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Astronomy and Astrophysics Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862n–9. Astronomy and Astrophysics Advisory Committee(a) EstablishmentThe Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Department of Energy shall jointly establish an Astronomy and Astrophysics Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).


(b) DutiesThe Advisory Committee shall—(1) assess, and make recommendations regarding, the coordination of astronomy and astrophysics programs of the Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Department of Energy;

(2) assess, and make recommendations regarding, the status of the activities of the Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Department of Energy as they relate to the recommendations contained in the National Research Council’s 2001 report entitled “Astronomy and Astrophysics in the New Millennium”, and the recommendations contained in subsequent National Research Council reports of a similar nature; and

(3) not later than March 15 of each year, transmit a report to the Director, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the Secretary of Energy, the Committee on Science of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate on the Advisory Committee’s findings and recommendations under paragraphs (1) and (2).


(c) MembershipThe Advisory Committee shall consist of 13 members, none of whom shall be a Federal employee, including—(1) 4 members selected by the Director;

(2) 4 members selected by the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;

(3) 3 members selected by the Secretary of Energy; and

(4) 2 members selected by the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.


(d) Selection processInitial selections under subsection (c) shall be made within 3 months after December 19, 2002. Vacancies shall be filled in </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Foundation, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and the Department of Energy shall jointly establish an Astronomy and Astrophysics Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Committee”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Advisory Committee shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership The Advisory Committee shall consist of 13 members, none of whom shall be a Federal employee, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Selection process Initial selections under subsection (c) shall be made within 3 months after December 19, 2002. Vacancies shall be filled in the same manner as provided in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Chairperson The Advisory Committee shall select a chairperson from among its members.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination The Advisory Committee shall coordinate with other Federal advisory committees that advise Federal agencies that engage in related research activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation The members of the Advisory Committee shall serve without compensation, but shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with sections 5702 and 5703 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Meetings The Advisory Committee shall convene, in person or by electronic means, at least 4 times a year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Quorum A majority of the members serving on the Advisory Committee shall constitute a quorum for purposes of conducting the business of the Advisory Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_9_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Duration Section 1013 of title 5 shall not apply to the Advisory Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>