<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862n"><akn:num>1862n</akn:num><akn:heading>Mathematics and science education partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862n. Mathematics and science education partnerships(a) Program authorized(1) In general(A) The Director shall carry out a program to award grants to institutions of higher education or eligible nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations) to establish mathematics and science education partnership programs to improve elementary and secondary mathematics and science instruction.

(B) Grants shall be awarded under this subsection on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis.


(2) Partnerships(A) In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an institution of higher education or eligible nonprofit organization (or consortium of such institutions or organizations) shall enter into a partnership with one or more local educational agencies that may also include the department, college, or program of education at an institution of higher education, a State educational agency, or one or more businesses.

(B) A participating institution of higher education shall include mathematics, science, or engineering departments in the programs carried out through a partnership under this paragraph.


(3) Uses of fundsGrants awarded under this subsection shall be used for activities that draw upon the expertise of the partners to improve elementary or secondary education in mathematics or science and that are consistent with State mathematics and science student academic achievement standards, including—(A) recruiting and preparing students for careers in elementary or secondary mathematics or science education;

(B) offering professional development programs, including—(i) teacher institutes for the 21st century, as described in paragraph (10); and

(ii) academic year institutes or workshops that—(I) are designed to strengthen the capabilities of mathematics and science teachers; and

(II) may include professional development activities to prepare mathematics and science teachers to teach challenging mathematics, science, and technolog</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Accountability and dissemination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>