<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862s–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862s–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862s–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862s_5"><akn:num>1862s–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs to expand STEM opportunities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862s–5. Programs to expand STEM opportunities(a) FindingsCongress makes the following findings:(1) Economic projections by the Bureau of Labor Statistics indicate that by 2018, there could be 2,400,000 unfilled STEM jobs.

(2) Women represent slightly more than half the United States population, and projections indicate that 54 percent of the population will be a member of a racial or ethnic minority group by 2050.

(3) Despite representing half the population, women comprise only about 30 percent of STEM workers according to a 2015 report by the National Center for Science and Engineering Statistics.

(4) A 2014 National Center for Education Statistics study found that underrepresented populations leave the STEM fields at higher rates than their counterparts.

(5) The representation of women in STEM drops significantly at the faculty level. Overall, women hold only 25 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 17 percent of full professor positions in STEM fields in our Nation’s universities and 4-year colleges.

(6) Black and Hispanic faculty together hold about 6.5 percent of all tenured and tenure-track positions and 5 percent of full professor positions.

(7) Many of the numbers in the American Indian or Alaskan Native and Native Hawaiian or Other Pacific Islander categories for different faculty ranks were too small for the Foundation to report publicly without potentially compromising confidential information about the individuals being surveyed.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of Congress that—(1) it is critical to our Nation’s economic leadership and global competitiveness that the United States educate, train, and retain more scientists, engineers, and computer scientists;

(2) there is currently a disconnect between the availability of and growing demand for STEM-skilled workers;

(3) historically, underrepresented populations are the largest untapped STEM talent pools in the United States; and

(4) given the shifting demographic land</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress makes the following findings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reaffirmation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reaffirmation The Director of the Foundation shall continue to support programs designed to broaden participation of underrepresented populations in STEM fields.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to broaden participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grants to broaden participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for increasing diversity among STEM faculty at institutions of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Support for increasing diversity among STEM faculty at institutions of higher education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for broadening participation in undergraduate STEM education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Support for broadening participation in undergraduate STEM education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accountability and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Accountability and dissemination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862s_5_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Coordination In carrying out this section, the Director of the Foundation shall consult and cooperate with the programs and policies of other relevant Federal agencies to avoid duplication with and enhance the effectiveness of the program under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>