<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862t"><akn:num>1862t</akn:num><akn:heading>Supporting veterans in STEM education and computer science</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862t. Supporting veterans in STEM education and computer science(a) Supporting veteran involvement in scientific research and STEM educationThe Director shall, through the research and education activities of the Foundation, encourage veterans to study and pursue careers in STEM and computer science, in coordination with other Federal agencies that serve veterans.


(b) Veteran outreach planNot later than 180 days after February 11, 2020, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a plan for how the Foundation can enhance its outreach efforts to veterans. Such plan shall—(1) report on the Foundation’s existing outreach activities;

(2) identify the best method for the Foundation to leverage existing authorities and programs to facilitate and support veterans in STEM careers and studies, including teaching programs; and

(3) include options for how the Foundation could track veteran participation in research and education programs of the Foundation, and describe any barriers to collecting such information.


(c) National Science Board indicators reportThe National Science Board shall provide in its biennial report on indicators of the state of science and engineering in the United States any available and relevant data on veterans in science and engineering careers or education programs.


(d) to (g) Omitted

(h) Veterans and military families STEM education interagency working group(1) In generalThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall establish, or designate, an interagency working group to improve veteran and military spouse equity and representation in STEM fields.


(2) Duties of interagency working groupAn interagency working group established under paragraph (1) shall develop and facilitate the implementation by participating agencies of a strategic plan, which shall—(A) specify and prioritize sh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supporting veteran involvement in scientific research and STEM education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Supporting veteran involvement in scientific research and STEM education The Director shall, through the research and education activities of the Foundation, encourage veterans to study and pursue careers in STEM and computer science, in coordination with other Federal agencies that serve veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veteran outreach plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Veteran outreach plan Not later than 180 days after February 11, 2020, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a plan for how the Foundation can enhance its outreach efforts to veterans. Such plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Board indicators report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) National Science Board indicators report The National Science Board shall provide in its biennial report on indicators of the state of science and engineering in the United States any available and relevant data on veterans in science and engineering careers or education programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (g) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) to (g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862t_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Veterans and military families STEM education interagency working group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Veterans and military families STEM education interagency working group</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>