<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862p–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862p–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1862p–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1862p_7"><akn:num>1862p–7</akn:num><akn:heading>STEM industry internship programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1862p–7. STEM industry internship programs(a) In generalThe Director may award grants, on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, to institutions of higher education, or consortia thereof, to establish or expand partnerships with local or regional private sector entities, for the purpose of providing undergraduate students with integrated internship experiences that connect private sector internship experiences with the students’ STEM coursework. The partnerships may also include industry or professional associations.


(b) Internship programThe grants awarded under subsection (a) may include internship programs in the manufacturing sector.


(c) 11 So in original. Two subsecs. (c) have been enacted. Use of grant fundsGrants under this section may be used—(1) to develop and implement hands-on learning opportunities;

(2) to develop curricula and instructional materials related to industry, including the manufacturing sector;

(3) to perform outreach to secondary schools;

(4) to develop mentorship programs for students with partner organizations; and

(5) to conduct activities to support awareness of career opportunities and skill requirements.


(d) 22 So in original. Two subsecs. (d) have been enacted. PriorityIn awarding grants under this section, the Director shall give priority to institutions of higher education or consortia thereof that demonstrate significant outreach to and coordination with local or regional private sector entities and Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology established by section 278k(a) 33 See References in Text note below. of title 15 in developing academic courses designed to provide students with the skills or certifications necessary for employment in local or regional companies.


(c) 1 Outreach to rural communitiesThe Foundation shall conduct outreach to institutions of higher education and private sector entities in rural areas to encourage those entities to participate in partnerships under this section.


(d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director may award grants, on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, to institutions of higher education, or consortia thereof, to establish or expand partnerships with local or regional private sector entities, for the purpose of providing undergraduate students with integrated internship experiences that connect private sector internship experiences with the students’ STEM coursework. The partnerships may also include industry or professional associations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Internship program The grants awarded under subsection (a) may include internship programs in the manufacturing sector.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. Two subsecs. (c) have been enacted. Use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants under this section may be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Two subsecs. (d) have been enacted. Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) In awarding grants under this section, the Director shall give priority to institutions of higher education or consortia thereof that demonstrate significant outreach to and coordination with local or regional private sector entities and Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology established by section 278k(a) 33 See References in Text note below. of title 15 in developing academic courses designed to provide students with the skills or certifications necessary for employment in local or regional companies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>1 Outreach to rural communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) The Foundation shall conduct outreach to institutions of higher education and private sector entities in rural areas to encourage those entities to participate in partnerships under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>2 Cost-share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) The Director shall require a 50 percent non-Federal cost-share from partnerships established or expanded under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Restriction No Federal funds provided under this section may be used—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1862p_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not less than 3 years after January 4, 2011, the Director shall submit a report to Congress on the number and total value of awards made under this section, the number of students affected by those awards, any evidence of the effect of those awards on workforce preparation and jobs placement for participating students, and an economic and ethnic breakdown of the participating students.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>