<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18632" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18632/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18632/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18632"><akn:num>18632</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Innovation Hubs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18632. Energy Innovation Hubs(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Advanced energy technologyThe term “advanced energy technology” means—(A) an innovative technology—(i) that produces energy from solar, wind, geothermal, biomass, tidal, wave, ocean, or other renewable energy resources;

(ii) that produces nuclear energy;

(iii) for carbon capture and sequestration;

(iv) that enables advanced vehicles, vehicle components, and related technologies that result in significant energy savings;

(v) that generates, transmits, distributes, uses, or stores energy more efficiently than conventional technologies, including through Smart Grid technologies; or

(vi) that enhances the energy independence and security of the United States by enabling improved or expanded supply and production of domestic energy resources, including coal, oil, and natural gas;


(B) a research, development, demonstration, or commercial application activity necessary to ensure the long-term, secure, and sustainable supply of an energy-critical element; or

(C) any other innovative energy technology area identified by the Secretary.


(2) Hub(A) In generalThe term “Hub” means an Energy Innovation Hub established under this section.


(B) InclusionThe term “Hub” includes any Energy Innovation Hub in existence on September 28, 2018.



(3) Qualifying entityThe term “qualifying entity” means—(A) an institution of higher education;

(B) an appropriate State or Federal entity, including a federally funded research and development center of the Department;

(C) a nongovernmental organization with expertise in advanced energy technology research, development, demonstration, or commercial application; or

(D) any other relevant entity the Secretary determines appropriate.



(b) Authorization of program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out a program to enhance the economic, environmental, and energy security of the United States by making awards to consortia for establishing and operating hubs, to be k</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18632_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18632_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18632_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application process</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18632_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Term</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18632_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hub operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Hub operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>