<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18645" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18645/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18645/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18645"><akn:num>18645</akn:num><akn:heading>Fusion energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18645. Fusion energy(a) ProgramAs part of the activities authorized under section 7139 of this title and section 16312 of this title, the Director shall carry out a fusion energy sciences research and enabling technology development program to effectively address the scientific and engineering challenges to building a cost competitive fusion power plant and to support the development of a competitive fusion power industry in the United States. As part of this program, the Director shall carry out research activities to expand the fundamental understandings of plasma and matter at very high temperatures and densities for fusion applications and for other engineering and plasma science applications.


(b) Fusion materials research and development(1) In generalAs part of the activities authorized in section 16318 of this title—(A) the Director, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Nuclear Energy of the Department, shall carry out research and development activities to identify, characterize, and demonstrate materials that can endure the neutron, plasma, and heat fluxes expected in a fusion power system; and

(B) the Director shall provide an assessment of—(i) the need for one or more facilities that can examine and test potential fusion and next generation fission materials and other enabling technologies relevant to the development of fusion power; and

(ii) whether a single new facility that substantially addresses magnetic fusion and next generation fission materials research needs is feasible, in conjunction with the expected capabilities of facilities operational as of September 28, 2018.



(2) Authorization of appropriationsOut of funds authorized to be appropriated under subsection (q),11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (r),”. See References in Text note below. there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out activities described in paragraph (1) $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.



(c) Toka</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program As part of the activities authorized under section 7139 of this title and section 16312 of this title, the Director shall carry out a fusion energy sciences research and enabling technology development program to effectively address the scientific and engineering challenges to building a cost competitive fusion power plant and to support the development of a competitive fusion power industry in the United States. As part of this program, the Director shall carry out research activities to expand the fundamental understandings of plasma and matter at very high temperatures and densities for fusion applications and for other engineering and plasma science applications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fusion materials research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fusion materials research and development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tokamak research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Tokamak research and development The Director shall support research and development activities and facility operations to optimize the tokamak approach to fusion energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inertial fusion research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inertial fusion research and development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative and enabling concepts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Alternative and enabling concepts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with ARPA–E</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with ARPA–E The Director shall coordinate with the Director of the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (referred to in this subsection as “ARPA–E”) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Identification of priorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Milestone-based development program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Milestone-based development program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18645_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fusion reactor system design</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fusion reactor system design</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>