<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1865"><akn:num>1865</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1865. Executive Committee(a) Composition; powers and functions; membership; chairmanThere shall be an Executive Committee of the Board (referred to in this chapter as the “Executive Committee”), which shall be composed of five members and shall exercise such powers and functions as may be delegated to it by the Board. Four of the members shall be elected as provided in subsection (b), and the Director ex officio shall be the fifth member and the chairman of the Executive Committee.


(b) Election to membership; term of office; eligibility for reelectionAt each of its annual meetings the Board shall elect two of its members as members of the Executive Committee, and the Executive Committee members so elected shall hold office for two years from the date of their election. Any person, other than the Director, who has been a member of the Executive Committee for six consecutive years shall thereafter be ineligible for service as a member thereof during the two-year period following the expiration of such sixth year. For the purposes of this subsection, the period between any two consecutive annual meetings of the Board shall be deemed to be one year.


(c) Term of vacancy appointmentAny person elected as a member of the Executive Committee to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was elected shall be elected for the remainder of such term.


(d) Reports; minority viewsThe Executive Committee shall render an annual report to the Board, and such other reports as it may deem necessary, summarizing its activities and making such recommendations as it may deem appropriate. Minority views and recommendations, if any, of members of the Executive Committee shall be included in such reports.


(May 10, 1950, ch. 171, § 7, formerly § 6, 64 Stat. 151; Pub. L. 86–232, § 4, Sept. 8, 1959, 73 Stat. 467; renumbered and amended Pub. L. 90–407, §§ 4, 5, July 18, 1968, 82 Stat. 363, 364.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1968—Subsec. (a). Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition; powers and functions; membership; chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Composition; powers and functions; membership; chairman There shall be an Executive Committee of the Board (referred to in this chapter as the “Executive Committee”), which shall be composed of five members and shall exercise such powers and functions as may be delegated to it by the Board. Four of the members shall be elected as provided in subsection (b), and the Director ex officio shall be the fifth member and the chairman of the Executive Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election to membership; term of office; eligibility for reelection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election to membership; term of office; eligibility for reelection At each of its annual meetings the Board shall elect two of its members as members of the Executive Committee, and the Executive Committee members so elected shall hold office for two years from the date of their election. Any person, other than the Director, who has been a member of the Executive Committee for six consecutive years shall thereafter be ineligible for service as a member thereof during the two-year period following the expiration of such sixth year. For the purposes of this subsection, the period between any two consecutive annual meetings of the Board shall be deemed to be one year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of vacancy appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term of vacancy appointment Any person elected as a member of the Executive Committee to fill a vacancy occurring prior to the expiration of the term for which his predecessor was elected shall be elected for the remainder of such term.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1865_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports; minority views</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reports; minority views The Executive Committee shall render an annual report to the Board, and such other reports as it may deem necessary, summarizing its activities and making such recommendations as it may deem appropriate. Minority views and recommendations, if any, of members of the Executive Committee shall be included in such reports.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>