<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1866" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1866/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1866/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1866"><akn:num>1866</akn:num><akn:heading>Divisions within Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1866. Divisions within Foundation
There shall be within the Foundation such Divisions as the Director, in consultation with the Board, may from time to time determine.
(May 10, 1950, ch. 171, § 8, formerly § 7, 64 Stat. 152; renumbered § 8 and amended Pub. L. 90–407, §§ 4, 6, July 18, 1968, 82 Stat. 363, 364.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 8 of act May 10, 1950, which was classified to section 1867 of this title, was repealed by Pub. L. 90–407, § 4, July 18, 1968, 82 Stat. 363.

Amendments1968—Pub. L. 90–407, § 6, substituted provisions that there be within the Foundation such divisions as the Director, in consultation with the Board, may from time to time determine for provisions that, unless otherwise provided by the Board, there be within the Foundation a Division of Medical Research, a Division of Mathematical, Physical, and Engineering Sciences, a Division of Biological Sciences, a Division of Scientific Personnel and Education, and such other divisions as the Board deems necessary.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Consolidation of DirectoratesPub. L. 96–516, § 18, Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 3009, directed National Science Foundation to consolidate all Directorates, including Science Education Directorate, under one roof, in present location of central administrative offices, on or before Aug. 1, 1982.

Continuation of Existing Offices, Procedures, and Organization of the National Science FoundationAmendment by Pub. L. 90–407 intended to continue in effect the existing offices, procedures, and organization of the Foundation, see section 16 of Pub. L. 90–407, set out as a note under section 1862 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>