<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1875" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1875/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1875/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1875"><akn:num>1875</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1875. Appropriations
To enable the Foundation to carry out its powers and duties, only such sums may be appropriated as the Congress may authorize by law.
(May 10, 1950, ch. 171, § 16, 64 Stat. 157; Aug. 8, 1953, ch. 377, 67 Stat. 488; renumbered § 17, Pub. L. 85–510, § 2, July 11, 1958, 72 Stat. 353; renumbered § 16 and amended Pub. L. 90–407, §§ 11(2), (14), July 18, 1968, 82 Stat. 365, 366; Pub. L. 96–516, § 21(c), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 3010.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1980—Pub. L. 96–516 amended subsec. (a) generally, striking out specific dollar amounts for fiscal years ending June 30, 1969, and June 30, 1970, reference to subsequent fiscal years, and provisions relating to sums as additional to sums under section 1122(b)(1) of title 33, and struck out subsec. (b) which related to availability of sums for obligation and expenditure.
1968—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 90–407, § 14, substituted provisions authorizing the appropriation of funds for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1969, June 30, 1970, and each subsequent fiscal year, such sums to be in addition to sums authorized by section 1122(b)(1) of title 33, for provisions authorizing the appropriation of such sums as may be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated.
1953—Subsec. (a). Act Aug. 8, 1953, removed the $15 million limitation on the amount of the annual appropriations.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Drug-Free WorkplacePub. L. 100–570, title I, § 118, Oct. 31, 1988, 102 Stat. 2873, provided that:
“(a) No funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act, or under any other Act authorizing appropriations for fiscal year 1989 through 1993 for the Foundation, shall be obligated or expended unless the Foundation has in place, and will continue to administer in good faith, a written policy designed to ensure that all of its workplaces are free from the illegal use, possession, or distribution of controlled substances (as defi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>