<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18792" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18792/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18792/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18792"><akn:num>18792</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy efficiency revolving loan fund capitalization grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18792. Energy efficiency revolving loan fund capitalization grant program(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after November 15, 2021, under the State Energy Program, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide capitalization grants to States to establish a revolving loan fund under which the State shall provide loans and grants, as applicable, in accordance with this section.


(b) Distribution of funds(1) All States(A) In generalOf the amounts made available under subsection (j), the Secretary shall use 40 percent to provide capitalization grants to States that are eligible for funding under the State Energy Program, in accordance with the allocation formula established under section 420.11 of title 10, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).


(B) Remaining fundingAfter applying the allocation formula described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall redistribute any unclaimed funds to the remaining States seeking capitalization grants under that subparagraph.



(2) Priority States(A) In generalOf the amounts made available under subsection (j), the Secretary shall use 60 percent to provide supplemental capitalization grants to priority States in accordance with an allocation formula determined by the Secretary.


(B) Remaining fundingAfter applying the allocation formula described in subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall redistribute any unclaimed funds to the remaining priority States seeking supplemental capitalization grants under that subparagraph.


(C) Grant amount(i) Maximum amountThe amount of a supplemental capitalization grant provided to a State under this paragraph shall not exceed $15,000,000.


(ii) Supplement not supplantA supplemental capitalization grant received by a State under this paragraph shall supplement, not supplant, a capitalization grant received by that State under paragraph (1).





(c) Applications for capitalization grantsA State seeking a capitalization grant under the progr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after November 15, 2021, under the State Energy Program, the Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall provide capitalization grants to States to establish a revolving loan fund under which the State shall provide loans and grants, as applicable, in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Distribution of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for capitalization grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications for capitalization grants A State seeking a capitalization grant under the program shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Timing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of grant funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with existing programs A State receiving a capitalization grant under the program is encouraged to utilize and build on existing programs and infrastructure within the State that may aid the State in carrying out a revolving loan fund program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leveraging private capital</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Leveraging private capital A State receiving a capitalization grant under the program shall, to the maximum extent practicable, use the grant to leverage private capital.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Outreach The Secretary shall engage in outreach to inform States of the availability of capitalization grants under the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report Each State that receives a capitalization grant under the program shall, not later than 2 years after a grant is received, submit to the Secretary a report that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18792_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $250,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>