<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18803" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18803/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18803/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18803"><akn:num>18803</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial building energy consumption information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18803. Commercial building energy consumption information sharing(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration.


(2) AgreementThe term “Agreement” means the agreement entered into under subsection (b).


(3) SurveyThe term “Survey” means the Commercial Building Energy Consumption Survey.



(b) Authorization of AgreementNot later than 120 days after November 15, 2021, the Administrator and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall sign, and submit to Congress, an information sharing agreement relating to commercial building energy consumption data.


(c) Content of AgreementThe Agreement shall—(1) provide, to the extent permitted by law, that—(A) the Administrator shall have access to building-specific data in the Portfolio Manager database of the Environmental Protection Agency; and

(B) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall have access to building-specific data collected by the Survey;


(2) describe the manner in which the Administrator shall use the data described in paragraph (1) and subsection (d);

(3) describe and compare—(A) the methodologies that the Energy Information Administration, the Environmental Protection Agency, and State and local government managers use to maximize the quality, reliability, and integrity of data collected through the Survey, the Portfolio Manager database of the Environmental Protection Agency, and State and local building energy disclosure laws (including regulations), respectively, and the manner in which those methodologies can be improved; and

(B) consistencies and variations in data for the same buildings captured in—(i)(I) the 2018 Survey cycle; and

(II) each subsequent Survey cycle; and


(ii) the Portfolio Manager database of the Environmental Protection Agency; and



(4) consider whether, and the methods by which, the Administrator may collect and publish new iterations of Surve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18803_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18803_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization of Agreement Not later than 120 days after November 15, 2021, the Administrator and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall sign, and submit to Congress, an information sharing agreement relating to commercial building energy consumption data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18803_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content of Agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Content of Agreement The Agreement shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18803_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data The data referred in subsection (c)(2) includes data that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18803_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Protection of information In carrying out the agreement, the Administrator and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall protect information in accordance with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>