<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18811" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18811/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18811/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18811"><akn:num>18811</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18811. Definitions
In this part:(1) Energy management systemThe term “energy management system” means a business management process based on standards of the American National Standards Institute that enables an organization to follow a systematic approach in achieving continual improvement of energy performance, including energy efficiency, security, use, and consumption.


(2) Industrial research and assessment centerThe term “industrial research and assessment center” means a center located at an institution of higher education, a trade school, a community college, or a union training program that—(A) receives funding from the Department;

(B) provides an in-depth assessment of small- and medium-size manufacturer plant sites to evaluate the facilities, services, and manufacturing operations of the plant site; and

(C) identifies opportunities for potential savings for small- and medium-size manufacturer plant sites from energy efficiency improvements, waste minimization, pollution prevention, and productivity improvement.


(3) Information and communication technologyThe term “information and communication technology” means any electronic system or equipment (including the content contained in the system or equipment) used to create, convert, communicate, or duplicate data or information, including computer hardware, firmware, software, communication protocols, networks, and data interfaces.


(4) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001(a) of title 20.


(5) North American Industry Classification SystemThe term “North American Industry Classification System” means the standard used by Federal statistical agencies in classifying business establishments for the purpose of collecting, analyzing, and publishing statistical data relating to the business economy of the United States.


(6) Small and medium manufacturersThe term “small and medium manufacturers” means manufacturing firms—(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy management system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Energy management system The term “energy management system” means a business management process based on standards of the American National Standards Institute that enables an organization to follow a systematic approach in achieving continual improvement of energy performance, including energy efficiency, security, use, and consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industrial research and assessment center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Industrial research and assessment center The term “industrial research and assessment center” means a center located at an institution of higher education, a trade school, a community college, or a union training program that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and communication technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Information and communication technology The term “information and communication technology” means any electronic system or equipment (including the content contained in the system or equipment) used to create, convert, communicate, or duplicate data or information, including computer hardware, firmware, software, communication protocols, networks, and data interfaces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given the term in section 1001(a) of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>North American Industry Classification System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) North American Industry Classification System The term “North American Industry Classification System” means the standard used by Federal statistical agencies in classifying business establishments for the purpose of collecting, analyzing, and publishing statistical data relating to the business economy of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small and medium manufacturers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Small and medium manufacturers The term “small and medium manufacturers” means manufacturing firms—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18811_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Smart manufacturing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Smart manufacturing The term “smart manufacturing” means advanced technologies in information, automation, monitoring, computation, sensing, modeling, artificial intelligence, analytics, and networking that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>