<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1881" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1881/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1881/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1881"><akn:num>1881</akn:num><akn:heading>Award of National Medal of Science</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1881. Award of National Medal of Science(a) RecommendationsThe President shall from time to time award the medal, on the basis of recommendations received from the National Academy of Sciences or on the basis of such other information and evidence as he deems appropriate, to individuals who in his judgment are deserving of special recognition by reason of their outstanding contributions to knowledge in the physical, biological, mathematical, engineering, behavioral or social sciences.


(b) NumberNot more than twenty individuals may be awarded the medal in any one calendar year.


(c) CitizenshipAn individual may not be awarded the medal unless at the time such award is made he—(1) is a citizen or other national of the United States; or

(2) is an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence who (A) has filed an application for petition for naturalization in the manner prescribed by section 1445(b) of title 8 and (B) is not permanently ineligible to become a citizen of the United States.


(d) CeremoniesThe presentation of the award shall be made by the President with such ceremonies as he may deem proper, including attendance by appropriate Members of Congress.


(Pub. L. 86–209, § 2, Aug. 25, 1959, 73 Stat. 431; Pub. L. 96–516, § 22(a)(1), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 3010.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments1980—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 96–516 inserted applicability to behavioral and social sciences.

Executive Documents

Ex. Ord. No. 11287. Award and Presentation of National Medal of Science
Ex. Ord. No. 11287, eff. June 28, 1966, 31 F.R. 8995, as amended by Ex. Ord. No. 11502, eff. Dec. 22, 1969, 34 F.R. 20171; Ex. Ord. No. 11734, July 30, 1973, 38 F.R. 20433; Ex. Ord. No. 14048, § 4, Sept. 30, 2021, 86 F.R. 55466, provided:
By virtue of the authority vested in me by the Act of August 25, 1959, entitled “An Act To Establish a Nati</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recommendations The President shall from time to time award the medal, on the basis of recommendations received from the National Academy of Sciences or on the basis of such other information and evidence as he deems appropriate, to individuals who in his judgment are deserving of special recognition by reason of their outstanding contributions to knowledge in the physical, biological, mathematical, engineering, behavioral or social sciences.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Number</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Number Not more than twenty individuals may be awarded the medal in any one calendar year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Citizenship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Citizenship An individual may not be awarded the medal unless at the time such award is made he—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1881_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ceremonies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Ceremonies The presentation of the award shall be made by the President with such ceremonies as he may deem proper, including attendance by appropriate Members of Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>