<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18831" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18831/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18831/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18831"><akn:num>18831</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy improvements at public school facilit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18831. Grants for energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy improvements at public school facilities(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Alternative fueled vehicleThe term “alternative fueled vehicle” has the meaning given the term in section 13211 of this title.


(2) Alternative fueled vehicle infrastructureThe term “alternative fueled vehicle infrastructure” means infrastructure used to charge or fuel an alternative fueled vehicle.


(3) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a consortium of—(A) 1 local educational agency; and

(B) 1 or more—(i) schools;

(ii) nonprofit organizations that have the knowledge and capacity to partner and assist with energy improvements;

(iii) for-profit organizations that have the knowledge and capacity to partner and assist with energy improvements; or

(iv) community partners that have the knowledge and capacity to partner and assist with energy improvements.



(4) Energy improvementThe term “energy improvement” means—(A) any improvement, repair, or renovation to a school that results in a direct reduction in school energy costs, including improvements to the envelope, air conditioning system, ventilation system, heating system, domestic hot water heating system, compressed air system, distribution system, lighting system, power system, and controls of a building;

(B) any improvement, repair, or renovation to, or installation in, a school that—(i) leads to an improvement in teacher and student health, including indoor air quality; and

(ii) achieves energy savings;


(C) any improvement, repair, or renovation to a school involving the installation of renewable energy technologies;

(D) the installation of alternative fueled vehicle infrastructure on school grounds for—(i) exclusive use of school buses, school fleets, or students; or

(ii) the general public; and


(E) the purchase or lease of alternative fueled vehicles to be used by a school, including school buses, fleet vehicles, and other operational vehi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants The Secretary shall award competitive grants to eligible entities to make energy improvements in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Competitive criteria The competitive criteria used by the Secretary to award grants under this section shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of grant amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competition in contracting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Competition in contracting If an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section uses grant funds to carry out repair or renovation through a contract, the eligible entity shall be required to ensure that the contract process—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Best practices The Secretary shall develop and publish guidelines and best practices for activities carried out under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report by eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report by eligible entity An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary, at such time as the Secretary may require, a report describing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18831_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $500,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>