<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1885c"><akn:num>1885c</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1885c. Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering(a) Establishment; purposesThere is established within the Foundation a Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”). The Committee shall provide advice to the Foundation concerning (1) the implementation of the provisions of sections 1885 to 1885d of this title and (2) other policies and activities of the Foundation to encourage full participation of women, minorities, and persons with disabilities in scientific, engineering, and professional fields.


(b) Membership; Chairperson; term of membersEach member of the Committee shall be appointed by the Director. In addition, the Chairman of the National Science Board may designate a member of the Board as a member of the Committee. Members of the Committee shall be appointed to serve for a three-year term, and may be reappointed to serve one additional term of three years.


(c) Responsibilities of CommitteeThe Committee shall be responsible for reviewing and evaluating all Foundation matters relating to opportunities for the participation in, and the advancement of, women, minorities, and persons with disabilities in education, training, and science and engineering research programs.


(d) Standing or ad hoc subcommitteesThe Committee may organize such standing or ad hoc subcommittees as the Committee finds appropriate.


(e) Biennial reportEvery 2 years, the Committee shall prepare and submit to the Director a report on its activities during the previous 2 years and proposed activities for the next 2 years. The Director shall submit to Congress the report, unaltered, together with such comments as the Director considers appropriate, including—(1) review data on the participation in Foundation activities of institutions serving populations that are underrepresented in STEM disciplines, including poor, rural, and tribal populations; and

(2) recommendations regarding how the Foundation could </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; purposes There is established within the Foundation a Committee on Equal Opportunities in Science and Engineering (hereinafter referred to as the “Committee”). The Committee shall provide advice to the Foundation concerning (1) the implementation of the provisions of sections 1885 to 1885d of this title and (2) other policies and activities of the Foundation to encourage full participation of women, minorities, and persons with disabilities in scientific, engineering, and professional fields.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; Chairperson; term of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; Chairperson; term of members Each member of the Committee shall be appointed by the Director. In addition, the Chairman of the National Science Board may designate a member of the Board as a member of the Committee. Members of the Committee shall be appointed to serve for a three-year term, and may be reappointed to serve one additional term of three years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities of Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities of Committee The Committee shall be responsible for reviewing and evaluating all Foundation matters relating to opportunities for the participation in, and the advancement of, women, minorities, and persons with disabilities in education, training, and science and engineering research programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standing or ad hoc subcommittees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Standing or ad hoc subcommittees The Committee may organize such standing or ad hoc subcommittees as the Committee finds appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Biennial report Every 2 years, the Committee shall prepare and submit to the Director a report on its activities during the previous 2 years and proposed activities for the next 2 years. The Director shall submit to Congress the report, unaltered, together with such comments as the Director considers appropriate, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>