<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1885/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1885"><akn:num>1885</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional statement of findings and declaration of policy respecting equal opportunities in scie</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1885. Congressional statement of findings and declaration of policy respecting equal opportunities in science and engineering(a) The Congress finds that it is in the national interest to promote the full use of human resources in science and engineering and to insure the full development and use of the scientific and engineering talents and skills of men and women, equally, of all ethnic, racial, and economic backgrounds, including persons with disabilities.

(b) The Congress declares it is the policy of the United States to encourage men and women, equally, of all ethnic, racial, and economic backgrounds, including persons with disabilities, to acquire skills in science, engineering, and mathematics, to have equal opportunity in education, training, and employment in scientific and engineering fields, and thereby to promote scientific and engineering literacy and the full use of the human resources of the Nation in science and engineering. To this end, the Congress declares that the highest quality science and engineering over the long-term requires substantial support, from currently available research and educational funds, for increased participation in science and engineering by women, minorities, and persons with disabilities. The Congress further declares that the impact on women, minorities, and persons with disabilities which is produced by advances in science and engineering must be included as essential factors in national and international science, engineering, and economic policies.

(Pub. L. 96–516, § 32, Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 3010; Pub. L. 99–159, title I, § 111(b)(2)–(5), Nov. 22, 1985, 99 Stat. 892; Pub. L. 107–368, § 16, Dec. 19, 2002, 116 Stat. 3059.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Science and Engineering Equal Opportunities Act, and not as part of the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2002—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 107–368, § 16(1), substituted “backgrounds, including</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Congress finds that it is in the national interest to promote the full use of human resources in science and engineering and to insure the full development and use of the scientific and engineering talents and skills of men and women, equally, of all ethnic, racial, and economic backgrounds, including persons with disabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1885_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Congress declares it is the policy of the United States to encourage men and women, equally, of all ethnic, racial, and economic backgrounds, including persons with disabilities, to acquire skills in science, engineering, and mathematics, to have equal opportunity in education, training, and employment in scientific and engineering fields, and thereby to promote scientific and engineering literacy and the full use of the human resources of the Nation in science and engineering. To this end, the Congress declares that the highest quality science and engineering over the long-term requires substantial support, from currently available research and educational funds, for increased participation in science and engineering by women, minorities, and persons with disabilities. The Congress further declares that the impact on women, minorities, and persons with disabilities which is produced by advances in science and engineering must be included as essential factors in national and in</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>