<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18861" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18861/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18861/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18861"><akn:num>18861</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18861. Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Covered projectThe term “covered project” means a demonstration project of the Department that—(A) receives or is eligible to receive funding from the Secretary; and

(B) is authorized under—(i) this division; or

(ii) the Energy Act of 2020 (Public Law 116–260; 134 Stat. 1182).11 See References in Text note below.



(2) ProgramThe term “program” means the program established under subsection (b).



(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary, in coordination with the heads of relevant program offices of the Department, including the Office of Technology Transitions, the Loan Program Office, and all applied program offices, shall establish a program to conduct project management and oversight of covered projects, including by—(1) conducting evaluations of proposals for covered projects before the selection of a covered project for funding;

(2) conducting independent oversight of the execution of a covered project after funding has been awarded for that covered project; and

(3) ensuring a balanced portfolio of investments in covered projects.


(c) DutiesThe Secretary shall appoint a head of the program who shall, in coordination with the heads of relevant program offices of the Department—(1) evaluate proposals for covered projects, including scope, technical specifications, maturity of design, funding profile, estimated costs, proposed schedule, proposed technical and financial milestones, and potential for commercial success based on economic and policy projections;

(2) develop independent cost estimates for a proposal for a covered project, if appropriate;

(3) recommend to the head of a program office of the Department, as appropriate, whether to fund a proposal for a covered project;

(4) oversee the execution of covered projects that receive funding from the Secretary, including reconciling estimated costs as compared to actual costs;

(5) conduct reviews of ongoing covered projects, incl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary, in coordination with the heads of relevant program offices of the Department, including the Office of Technology Transitions, the Loan Program Office, and all applied program offices, shall establish a program to conduct project management and oversight of covered projects, including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Secretary shall appoint a head of the program who shall, in coordination with the heads of relevant program offices of the Department—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Employees To carry out the program, the Secretary may hire appropriate personnel, including by using the authorities in section 19321 of this title, to perform the duties of the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional authority The Secretary may solicit, select, and manage covered projects directly through the program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Project termination Should an ongoing covered project receive an unfavorable review under subsection (c)(5), the Secretary or their designee may cease funding the covered project and reallocate the remaining funds to new or existing covered projects carried out by that program office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination In carrying out the program, the head of the program shall coordinate with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18861_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>