<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18901" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18901/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18901/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18901"><akn:num>18901</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18901. Definitions
In this division:(1) Artificial intelligenceThe term “artificial intelligence” or “AI” has the meaning given such term in section 9401 of title 15.


(2) AwardeeThe term “awardee” means the legal entity to which Federal assistance is awarded and that is accountable to the Federal Government for the use of the funds provided.


(3) Award personnelThe term “award personnel” means principal investigators and co-principal investigators, faculty, postdoctoral researchers, and other employees supported by a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under Federal law.


(4) BiomanufacturingThe term “biomanufacturing” means the utilization of biological systems to develop new and advance existing products, tools, and processes at commercial scale.


(5) Emerging research institutionThe term “emerging research institution” means an institution of higher education with an established undergraduate or graduate program that has less than $50,000,000 in Federal research expenditures.


(6) Engineering biologyThe term “engineering biology” means the application of engineering design principles and practices to biological systems, including molecular and cellular systems, to advance fundamental understanding of complex natural systems and to enable novel or optimize functions and capabilities.


(7) EPSCoRThe term “EPSCoR” has the meaning given the term in section 502 of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (42 U.S.C. 1862p note).


(8) EPSCoR institutionThe term “EPSCoR institution” means an institution of higher education, nonprofit organization, or other institution located in a jurisdiction eligible to participate in the program under section 1862g of this title.


(9) Federal laboratoryThe term “Federal laboratory” has the meaning given such term in section 3703 of title 15.


(10) Federal research agencyThe term “Federal research agency” means any Federal agency with an annual extramural research expenditure of over $100,000,000 in fiscal yea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Artificial intelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Artificial intelligence The term “artificial intelligence” or “AI” has the meaning given such term in section 9401 of title 15.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awardee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Awardee The term “awardee” means the legal entity to which Federal assistance is awarded and that is accountable to the Federal Government for the use of the funds provided.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Award personnel The term “award personnel” means principal investigators and co-principal investigators, faculty, postdoctoral researchers, and other employees supported by a grant, cooperative agreement, or contract under Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomanufacturing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Biomanufacturing The term “biomanufacturing” means the utilization of biological systems to develop new and advance existing products, tools, and processes at commercial scale.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emerging research institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Emerging research institution The term “emerging research institution” means an institution of higher education with an established undergraduate or graduate program that has less than $50,000,000 in Federal research expenditures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Engineering biology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Engineering biology The term “engineering biology” means the application of engineering design principles and practices to biological systems, including molecular and cellular systems, to advance fundamental understanding of complex natural systems and to enable novel or optimize functions and capabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPSCoR</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) EPSCoR The term “EPSCoR” has the meaning given the term in section 502 of the America COMPETES Reauthorization Act of 2010 (42 U.S.C. 1862p note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPSCoR institution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) EPSCoR institution The term “EPSCoR institution” means an institution of higher education, nonprofit organization, or other institution located in a jurisdiction eligible to participate in the program under section 1862g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal laboratory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Federal laboratory The term “Federal laboratory” has the meaning given such term in section 3703 of title 15.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18901_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal research agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Federal research agency The term “Federal research agency” means any Federal agency with an annual extramural research expenditure of over $100,000,000 in fiscal year 2022 constant dollars.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>