<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18940" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18940/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18940/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18940"><akn:num>18940</akn:num><akn:heading>Dr. David Satcher Cybersecurity Education Grant Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18940. Dr. David Satcher Cybersecurity Education Grant Program(a) Authorization of grants(1) In generalSubject to the availability of appropriations, the Director shall carry out the Dr. David Satcher Cybersecurity Education Grant Program by—(A) awarding grants to assist institutions of higher education that have an enrollment of needy students, historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions, to establish or expand cybersecurity programs, to build and upgrade institutional capacity to better support new or existing cybersecurity programs, including cybersecurity partnerships with public and private entities, and to support such institutions on the path to producing qualified entrants in the cybersecurity workforce or becoming a National Center of Academic Excellence in Cybersecurity; and

(B) awarding grants to build capacity at institutions of higher education that have an enrollment of needy students, historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions, to expand cybersecurity education opportunities, cybersecurity programs, cybersecurity research, and cybersecurity partnerships with public and private entities.


(2) ReservationThe Director shall award not less than 50 percent of the amount available for grants under this section to historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and minority-serving institutions.


(3) CoordinationThe Director shall carry out this section in coordination with appropriate Federal agencies, including the Departments of Homeland Security, Education, and Labor.


(4) SunsetThe Director’s authority to award grants under paragraph (1) shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date the Director first awards a grant under paragraph (1).



(b) ApplicationsAn eligible institution seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Director at suc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications An eligible institution seeking a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Director at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director may reasonably require, including a statement of how the institution will use the funds awarded through the grant to expand cybersecurity education opportunities at the eligible institution.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section may use the funds awarded through such grant for increasing research, education, technical, partnership, and innovation capacity, including for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting requirements Not later than—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance metrics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Performance metrics The Director shall establish performance metrics for grants awarded under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18940_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date This section shall take effect 1 year after August 9, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>