<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18952" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18952/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18952/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18952"><akn:num>18952</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards development organization grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18952. Standards development organization grants(a) Nongovernmental standards development organization definedIn this section, the term “nongovernmental standards development organization” means a nongovernmental standards development organization (as defined in section 2(e) of the Office of Management and Budget Circular A–119 (relating to Federal participation in the development and use of voluntary consensus standards in conformity assessment activities), or any successor document) that adheres to the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) Essential Requirements for Due Process for American National Standards.


(b) Grant authorityThe Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director, shall establish a competitive program of grants for nongovernmental standards development organizations for the purposes described in subsection (c).


(c) PurposesA grant awarded under subsection (b) shall be used to develop, approve, disseminate, maintain, and review forensic science voluntary consensus standards and best practices that shall be available to the public free of charge.


(d) Additional requirementsThe Director may promulgate such requirements, guidelines, and procedures as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(e) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.


(Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title II, § 10248, Aug. 9, 2022, 136 Stat. 1495.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18952_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nongovernmental standards development organization defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Nongovernmental standards development organization defined In this section, the term “nongovernmental standards development organization” means a nongovernmental standards development organization (as defined in section 2(e) of the Office of Management and Budget Circular A–119 (relating to Federal participation in the development and use of voluntary consensus standards in conformity assessment activities), or any successor document) that adheres to the American National Standards Institute (ANSI) Essential Requirements for Due Process for American National Standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18952_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant authority The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director, shall establish a competitive program of grants for nongovernmental standards development organizations for the purposes described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18952_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purposes A grant awarded under subsection (b) shall be used to develop, approve, disseminate, maintain, and review forensic science voluntary consensus standards and best practices that shall be available to the public free of charge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18952_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional requirements The Director may promulgate such requirements, guidelines, and procedures as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18952_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>