<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18961" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18961/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18961/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18961"><akn:num>18961</akn:num><akn:heading>National Supply Chain Database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18961. National Supply Chain Database(a) Establishment of National Supply Chain DatabaseThe Director shall establish a voluntary National Supply Chain Database, subject to the availability of appropriations.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the voluntary National Supply Chain Database shall be to assist the Federal Government and industry sectors in minimizing disruptions to the United States supply chain by having an assessment of United States manufacturers’ capabilities.


(c) Study on National Supply Chain DatabaseIn establishing the National Supply Chain Database, the Director shall consider the findings and recommendations from the study authorized pursuant to section 9413 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (Public Law 116–283), including measures to secure and protect the Database from adversarial attacks and vulnerabilities.


(d) Database and Manufacturing Extension Partnership(1) In generalThe Director shall establish the infrastructure for the National Supply Chain Database through the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership, established pursuant to section 278k of title 15, by connecting information from the Centers (as such term is defined in such section) through the Database.


(2) National viewThe Director shall ensure that connections under paragraph (1)—(A) provide a national overview of the networks of supply chains of the United States; and

(B) support understanding of whether there is a need for some manufacturers to retool in some critical areas to meet the urgent need for key products.


(3) Individual Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership Center databases(A) In generalThe Director shall ensure that—(i) each Center is connected to the National Supply Chain Database; and

(ii) each supply chain database maintained by a Center is interoperable with the Database.


(B) Rule of constructionNothing in this section may be construed to require a State or territory of the United States to establish a new supply ch</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of National Supply Chain Database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of National Supply Chain Database The Director shall establish a voluntary National Supply Chain Database, subject to the availability of appropriations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the voluntary National Supply Chain Database shall be to assist the Federal Government and industry sectors in minimizing disruptions to the United States supply chain by having an assessment of United States manufacturers’ capabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on National Supply Chain Database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Study on National Supply Chain Database In establishing the National Supply Chain Database, the Director shall consider the findings and recommendations from the study authorized pursuant to section 9413 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (Public Law 116–283), including measures to secure and protect the Database from adversarial attacks and vulnerabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Database and Manufacturing Extension Partnership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Database and Manufacturing Extension Partnership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of National Supply Chain Database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maintenance of National Supply Chain Database The Director, acting through the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership program or a designee of the program—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Database content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Database content The National Supply Chain Database may include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard classification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Standard classification system The National Supply Chain Database may, where applicable, use the North American Industry Classification System (NAICS) Codes as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Levels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Levels The National Supply Chain Database shall be multi-leveled as agreed to under terms of mutual disclosure as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters relating to disclosure and access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Matters relating to disclosure and access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18961_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with National Technology and Industrial Base Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination with National Technology and Industrial Base Council The Director, acting through the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership program, may work with the National Defense Technology and Industrial Base Council established under section 4812 of title 10 as the Director considers appropriate, to include in the National Supply Chain Database information regarding the defense manufacturing supply chain.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>