<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18972" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18972/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18972/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18972"><akn:num>18972</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting domestic production of technologies developed under Manufacturing USA Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18972. Promoting domestic production of technologies developed under Manufacturing USA Program(a) Department of Commerce policies to promote domestic production of technologies developed under Manufacturing USA Network(1) Policies(A) In generalEach agency head (as such term is defined in section 278s(a) of title 15) and the Secretary of Defense shall, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, establish policies to promote the domestic production of technologies developed by the Manufacturing USA Network.


(B) ElementsThe policies established under subparagraph (A) shall include the following:(i) Measures to partner domestic developers of goods, services, or technologies by Manufacturing USA Network activities with domestic manufacturers and sources of financing.

(ii) Measures to develop and provide incentives to promote transfer of intellectual property and goods, services, or technologies developed by Manufacturing USA Network activities to domestic manufacturers.

(iii) Measures to assist with supplier scouting and other supply chain development, including the use of the Hollings Manufacturing Extension Partnership under section 278k of title 15 to carry out such measures.

(iv) A process to review and approve or deny membership in a Manufacturing USA institute by foreign-owned entities, especially from countries of concern, including the People’s Republic of China.

(v) Measures to prioritize Federal procurement of goods, services, or technologies developed by the Manufacturing USA Network activities from domestic sources, as appropriate.


(C) Processes for waiversThe policies established under this paragraph shall include processes to permit waivers, on a case by case basis, for policies that promote domestic production based on cost, availability, severity of technical and mission requirements, emergency requirements, operational needs, other legal or international treaty obligations, or other factors determined important to the success of the Manufa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18972_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Commerce policies to promote domestic production of technologies developed under Manufacturing USA Network</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Department of Commerce policies to promote domestic production of technologies developed under Manufacturing USA Network</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18972_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (d) Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) to (d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18972_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice from the United States Manufacturing Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advice from the United States Manufacturing Council The Secretary shall seek advice from the United States Manufacturing Council of the International Trade Administration of the Department of Commerce on matters concerning investment in and support of the manufacturing workforce within the Manufacturing USA Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>