<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18991" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18991/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18991/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18991"><akn:num>18991</akn:num><akn:heading>PreK–12 STEM education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18991. PreK–12 STEM education(a) National Academies studyNot later than 120 days after August 9, 2022, the Director shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies to conduct a study to—(1) review the research literature and identify research gaps regarding the interconnected factors that foster and hinder successful implementation of promising, evidence-based PreK–12 STEM education innovations at the local, regional, and national level;

(2) present a compendium of promising, evidence-based PreK–12 STEM education practices, models, programs, and technologies;

(3) identify barriers to widespread and sustained implementation of such innovations; and

(4) make recommendations to the Foundation, the Department of Education, the National Science and Technology Council’s Committee on Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education, State and local educational agencies, and other relevant stakeholders on measures to address such barriers.


(b) Omitted

(c) [Log 907 S2522] 11 So in original. National STEM Teacher Corps pilot(1) PurposeIt is the purpose of this subsection to elevate the profession of STEM teaching by establishing a National STEM Teacher Corps pilot program to recognize outstanding STEM teachers in our Nation’s classrooms, rewards 22 So in original. Probably should be “reward”. them for their accomplishments, elevates 33 So in original. Probably should be “elevate”. their public profile, and creates 44 So in original. Probably should be “create”. rewarding career paths to which all STEM teachers can aspire, both to prepare future STEM researchers and to create a scientifically literate public.


(2) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the National STEM Teacher Corps.


(B) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(i) an institution of higher education; or

(ii) a consortium consisting of an institution of higher education and one or more of the following:(I) A Sta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18991_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Academies study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Academies study Not later than 120 days after August 9, 2022, the Director shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies to conduct a study to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18991_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18991_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>[Log 907 S2522] 11 So in original. National STEM Teacher Corps pilot</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) [Log 907 S2522]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>