<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18993" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18993/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/18993/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_18993"><akn:num>18993</akn:num><akn:heading>Graduate STEM education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 18993. Graduate STEM education(a) Mentoring and professional development(1) Mentoring plans(A) Omitted

(B) EvaluationNot later than 120 days after August 9, 2022, the Director shall enter into an agreement with a qualified independent organization to evaluate the effectiveness of the postdoctoral mentoring plan requirement for improving mentoring for Foundation-supported postdoctoral researchers.



(2) Career exploration(A) In generalThe Director shall make awards, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education and nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations) to develop innovative approaches for facilitating career exploration of academic and nonacademic career options and for providing opportunity-broadening experiences, including work-integrated opportunities, for graduate students and postdoctoral scholars that can then be considered, adopted, or adapted by other institutions and to carry out research on the impact and outcomes of such activities.


(B) Review of proposalsIn selecting award recipients under this subparagraph, the Director shall consider, at a minimum—(i) the extent to which the administrators of the institution are committed to making the proposed activity a priority; and

(ii) the likelihood that the institution or organization will sustain or expand the proposed activity effort beyond the period of the award.



(3) Development plansThe Director shall require that annual project reports for awards that support graduate students and postdoctoral scholars include certification by the principal investigator that each graduate student and postdoctoral scholar receiving substantial support from such award, as determined by 11 So in original. has developed and annually updated an individual development plan to map educational goals, career exploration, and professional development.


(4) Professional development supplementThe Director shall carry out a five-year pilot initiative to award up to 2,500 ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18993_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mentoring and professional development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Mentoring and professional development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18993_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Graduate Research Fellowship Program update</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Graduate Research Fellowship Program update</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18993_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on graduate student funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Study on graduate student funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_18993_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>[LOG 165 H10304(g)/S2208] 1 AI scholarship-for-service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) [LOG 165 H10304(g)/S2208]</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>