<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19017" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19017/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19017/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19017"><akn:num>19017</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and dissemination to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19017. Research and dissemination to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM fields(a) In generalThe Director shall make awards on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, to institutions of higher education or non-profit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations), to enable such entities to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM studies and careers.


(b) Use of fundsAn eligible entity that receives an award under this subsection shall use such award funds to carry out one or more of the following activities designed to increase the participation of women or minorities historically underrepresented in STEM, or both:(1) Research to analyze the record-level data collected under sections 19152 and 19154 of this title, consistent with policies to ensure the privacy of individuals identifiable by such data.

(2) Research to study best practices for work-life accommodation.

(3) Research to study the impact of policies and practices that are implemented or are otherwise consistent with the purposes of this section.

(4) Mentoring programs that facilitate engagement of STEM professionals with students.

(5) Research experiences for undergraduate and graduate students in STEM fields.

(6) Outreach to elementary school and secondary school students to provide opportunities to increase their exposure to STEM fields.


(c) Dissemination activitiesThe Director shall carry out dissemination activities consistent with the purposes of this section, including—(1) collaboration with other Federal research agencies and professional associations to exchange best practices, harmonize work-life accommodation policies and practices, and overcoming common barriers to work-life accommodation; and

(2) collaboration with institutions of higher education in order to clarify and catalyze the adoption of a coherent and consistent set of work-life accommodation policies and practices.


(d) Authoriza</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19017_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall make awards on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, to institutions of higher education or non-profit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations), to enable such entities to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in STEM studies and careers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19017_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds An eligible entity that receives an award under this subsection shall use such award funds to carry out one or more of the following activities designed to increase the participation of women or minorities historically underrepresented in STEM, or both:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19017_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination activities The Director shall carry out dissemination activities consistent with the purposes of this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19017_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023, 2024, 2025, 2026, and 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>