<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19018" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19018/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19018/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19018"><akn:num>19018</akn:num><akn:heading>Intramural emerging research institutions pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19018. Intramural emerging research institutions pilot program(a) EstablishmentThe Director may conduct multiple pilot programs, including through existing programs or other programs authorized in this division or division A, within the Foundation to expand the number of institutions of higher education (including such institutions that are community colleges), and other eligible entities that the Director determines appropriate, that are able to successfully compete for Foundation awards.


(b) ComponentsPilot programs under this section may include—(1) a mentorship program;

(2) award application writing technical assistance;

(3) targeted outreach, including to a historically Black college or university, a Tribal college or university, or a minority-serving institution (including a Hispanic-serving institution or an institution of higher education with an established STEM capacity building program focused on Native Hawaiians or Alaska Natives);

(4) programmatic support or solutions for institutions or entities that do not have an experienced award management office;

(5) an increase in the number of award proposal reviewers from institutions of higher education that have not traditionally received funds from the Foundation; or

(6) an increase of the term and funding, for a period of 3 years or less, as appropriate, for awards with a first-time principal investigator, when paired with regular mentoring on the administrative aspects of award management.


(c) LimitationAs appropriate, each pilot program under this section shall work to reduce administrative burdens for recipients and award personnel.


(d) Agency-wide programsNot later than 5 years after August 9, 2022, the Director shall—(1) review the results of the pilot programs under this section; and

(2) develop agencywide best practices from the pilot programs for implementation across the Foundation, in order to fulfill the requirement under section 1862(e) of this title.


(Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19018_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Director may conduct multiple pilot programs, including through existing programs or other programs authorized in this division or division A, within the Foundation to expand the number of institutions of higher education (including such institutions that are community colleges), and other eligible entities that the Director determines appropriate, that are able to successfully compete for Foundation awards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19018_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Components</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Components Pilot programs under this section may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19018_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation As appropriate, each pilot program under this section shall work to reduce administrative burdens for recipients and award personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19018_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency-wide programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Agency-wide programs Not later than 5 years after August 9, 2022, the Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>