<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19038" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19038/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19038/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19038"><akn:num>19038</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan with respect to controlled information and background screening</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19038. Plan with respect to controlled information and background screening(a) In generalNot later than 180 days after August 9, 2022, the Director, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence and, as appropriate, other Federal agencies, shall develop a plan to—(1) identify research areas supported by the Foundation, including in the key technology focus areas, that may involve access to controlled unclassified or classified information, including in the key technology focus areas; and

(2) exercise due diligence in granting access, as appropriate, to the CUI or classified information identified under paragraph (1) to individuals working on such research who are employees of the Foundation or covered individuals on research and development awards funded by the Foundation.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Classified informationThe term “classified information” means any information that has been determined pursuant to Executive Order 13526, any predecessor or successor order, or sections 1-274, 275-321, and 1001-3115 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011-2021, 2022-2286i, 2296a-2297h-13) 11 See References in Text note below. to require protection against unauthorized disclosure and that is so designated.


(2) Controlled unclassified informationThe term “controlled unclassified information” or “CUI” means information described as “Controlled Unclassified Information” under Executive Order 13556 or any successor order, to require protection against unauthorized disclosure and that is so designated.



(Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title III, § 10339, Aug. 9, 2022, 136 Stat. 1554.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextExecutive Order 13526, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is set out as a note under section 3161 of Title 50, War and National Defense.
The Atomic Energy Act of 1954, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, as added by act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 919, which is classified principally to chapter 23</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19038_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 180 days after August 9, 2022, the Director, in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence and, as appropriate, other Federal agencies, shall develop a plan to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19038_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>