<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19068" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19068/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19068/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19068"><akn:num>19068</akn:num><akn:heading>Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Capabilities Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19068. Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Capabilities Act(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Act of 2021”.


(b) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to promote scientific research and development opportunities for connected technologies that advance precision agriculture capabilities.


(c) Foundation directive on agricultural sensor researchIn making awards under the sensor systems and networked systems programs of the Foundation, the Director shall include in consideration of portfolio balance research and development on sensor connectivity in environments of intermittent connectivity and intermittent computation—(1) to improve the reliable use of advance sensing systems in rural and agricultural areas; and

(2) that considers—(A) direct gateway access for locally stored data;

(B) attenuation of signal transmission;

(C) loss of signal transmission; and

(D) at-scale performance for wireless power.



(d) Omitted

(e) GAO reviewNot later than 18 months after August 9, 2022, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide—(1) a technology assessment of precision agriculture technologies, such as the existing use of—(A) sensors, scanners, radio-frequency identification, and related technologies that can monitor soil properties, irrigation conditions, and plant physiology;

(B) sensors, scanners, radio-frequency identification, and related technologies that can monitor livestock activity and health;

(C) network connectivity and wireless communications that can securely support digital agriculture technologies in rural and remote areas;

(D) aerial imagery generated by satellites or unmanned aerial vehicles;

(E) ground-based robotics;

(F) control systems design and connectivity, such as smart irrigation control systems;

(G) Global Positioning System-based applications; and

(H) data management software and advanced analytics that can assist decision making and improve agricultural outcom</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19068_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Advancing IoT for Precision Agriculture Act of 2021”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19068_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to promote scientific research and development opportunities for connected technologies that advance precision agriculture capabilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19068_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foundation directive on agricultural sensor research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Foundation directive on agricultural sensor research In making awards under the sensor systems and networked systems programs of the Foundation, the Director shall include in consideration of portfolio balance research and development on sensor connectivity in environments of intermittent connectivity and intermittent computation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19068_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19068_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>GAO review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) GAO review Not later than 18 months after August 9, 2022, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>