<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19105" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19105/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19105/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19105"><akn:num>19105</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19105. Assistant Director(a) In generalThe Director shall appoint an Assistant Director responsible for the management of the Directorate established under this part, in the same manner as other Assistant Directors of the Foundation are appointed.


(b) QualificationsThe Assistant Director shall be an individual, who by reason of professional background and experience, is specially qualified to—(1) advise the Director on all matters pertaining to use-inspired and translational research, development, and commercialization at the Foundation, including partnership with the private sector and other users of Foundation funded research; and

(2) develop and implement the necessary policies and procedures to promote a culture of use-inspired and translational research within the Directorate and across the Foundation and carry out the responsibilities under subsection (c).


(c) ResponsibilitiesThe responsibilities of the Assistant Director shall include—(1) advising the Director on all matters pertaining to use-inspired and translational research and development activities at the Foundation, including effective practices for convergence research, and the potential impact of Foundation research on United States societal, national and geostrategic challenges;

(2) identifying opportunities for and facilitating coordination and collaboration, where appropriate, on use-inspired and translational research, development, adoption, and commercialization—(A) among the offices, directorates, and divisions within the Foundation; and

(B) between the Foundation and stakeholders in academia, the private sector, including non-profit entities, labor organizations, Federal or State agencies, and international entities, as appropriate;


(3) ensuring that the activities carried out under this part do not substantially and unnecessarily duplicate activities supported by other parts of the Foundation or other relevant Federal agencies;

(4) approving all new programs within the Directorate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19105_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director shall appoint an Assistant Director responsible for the management of the Directorate established under this part, in the same manner as other Assistant Directors of the Foundation are appointed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19105_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Qualifications The Assistant Director shall be an individual, who by reason of professional background and experience, is specially qualified to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19105_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities The responsibilities of the Assistant Director shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19105_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to the Director The Assistant Director shall report to the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19105_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relationship to other programs No other directorate within the Foundation shall report to the Assistant Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>