<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19106"><akn:num>19106</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19106. Advisory committee(a) In generalIn accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) 11 See References in Text note below. the Director shall establish an advisory committee to assess, and make recommendations regarding, the activities carried out under this part.


(b) MembershipThe advisory committee members shall—(1) be individuals with relevant experience or expertise, including individuals from industry and national labs, educators, academic subject matter experts, including individuals with knowledge of key technology focus areas and their impact on United States national security and geostrategic leadership, the technical and social dimensions of science and technology, technology transfer experts, labor organizations, representatives of civil society, and other nongovernmental organizations; and

(2) consist of at least 10 members broadly representative of stakeholders, including no less than 3 members from the private sector, none of whom shall be an employee of the Federal Government, and no less than 1 member with significant expertise in United States national security and economic competitiveness.


(c) ResponsibilitiesThe Committee’s responsibilities shall include—(1) reviewing and advising on activities carried out under this part;

(2) proposing strategies for fulfilling the purposes in section 19102 of this title;

(3) proposing potential areas of research, particularly as relevant to United States societal, national, and geostrategic challenges; and

(4) other relevant issues as determined by the Director.


(Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title III, § 10386, Aug. 9, 2022, 136 Stat. 1578.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Advisory Committee Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 92–463, Oct. 6, 1972, 86 Stat. 770, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was substantially repealed and restated in chapter 10 (§ 1001 et seq.) of Title 5 by Pub. L. 117–286, §§ 3(a)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In accordance with the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) 11 See References in Text note below. the Director shall establish an advisory committee to assess, and make recommendations regarding, the activities carried out under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The advisory committee members shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19106_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Responsibilities The Committee’s responsibilities shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>