<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19113" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19113/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19113/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19113"><akn:num>19113</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarships and fellowships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19113. Scholarships and fellowships(a) In generalThe Director, acting through the Directorate, shall fund undergraduate scholarships (including at community colleges), graduate fellowships and traineeships, and postdoctoral awards in the key technology focus areas.


(b) ImplementationThe Director may carry out subsection (a) by making awards—(1) directly to students; and

(2) to institutions of higher education or consortia of institutions of higher education, including those institutions or consortia involved in operating Regional Innovation Engines established under section 19108 of this title.


(c) Broadening participationIn carrying out this section, the Director shall take steps to increase the participation of populations that are underrepresented in STEM, which may include—(1) establishing or augmenting programs targeted at populations that are underrepresented in STEM;

(2) supporting traineeships or other relevant programs at historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal Colleges or Universities, and minority-serving institutions;

(3) enabling low-income populations to pursue associate, undergraduate, or graduate level degrees in STEM;

(4) addressing current and expected gaps in the availability or skills of the STEM workforce, or addressing needs of the STEM workforce, including by increasing educational capacity at institutions and by prioritizing awards to United States citizens, permanent residents, and individuals that will grow the domestic workforce; and

(5) addressing geographic diversity in the STEM workforce.


(d) Encouraging innovationIn carrying out this section, the Director shall encourage innovation in graduate education, including through encouraging institutions of higher education to offer graduate students opportunities to gain experience in industry or Government as part of their graduate training, and through support for students in professional master’s programs related to the key technology focus areas or to the societa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director, acting through the Directorate, shall fund undergraduate scholarships (including at community colleges), graduate fellowships and traineeships, and postdoctoral awards in the key technology focus areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementation The Director may carry out subsection (a) by making awards—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Broadening participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Broadening participation In carrying out this section, the Director shall take steps to increase the participation of populations that are underrepresented in STEM, which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouraging innovation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Encouraging innovation In carrying out this section, the Director shall encourage innovation in graduate education, including through encouraging institutions of higher education to offer graduate students opportunities to gain experience in industry or Government as part of their graduate training, and through support for students in professional master’s programs related to the key technology focus areas or to the societal, national, and geostrategic challenges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Areas of funding support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Areas of funding support Subject to the availability of funds to carry out this section, the Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Low-income scholarship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Low-income scholarship program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19113_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Existing programs The Director may use or augment existing STEM education programs of the Foundation and leverage education or entrepreneurial partners to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>