<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19135"><akn:num>19135</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19135. Agency activities(a) National Science FoundationAs part of the Initiative, the National Science Foundation shall carry out the following:(1) Support research in engineering biology and biomanufacturing through individual grants, collaborative grants, and through interdisciplinary research centers.

(2) Support research on the environmental, legal, ethical, and social implications of engineering biology.

(3) Provide support for research instrumentation, equipment, and cyberinfrastructure for engineering biology disciplines, including support for research, development, optimization, and validation of novel technologies to enable the dynamic study of molecular processes in situ.

(4) Support curriculum development and research experiences for secondary, undergraduate, and graduate students in engineering biology and biomanufacturing, including through support for graduate fellowships and traineeships in engineering biology.

(5) Award grants, on a competitive basis, to enable institutions to support graduate students and postdoctoral fellows who perform some of their engineering biology research in an industry setting.


(b) Department of Commerce(1) National Institute of Standards and TechnologyAs part of the Initiative, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall carry out the following:(A) Advance the development of standard reference materials and measurements, including to promote interoperability between new component technologies and processes for engineering biology and biomanufacturing discovery, innovation, and production processes.

(B) Establish new data tools, techniques, and processes necessary to advance engineering biology and biomanufacturing.

(C) Provide access to user facilities with advanced or unique equipment, services, materials, and other resources to industry, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, and government agencies to perform research and testing.

(D) Provide technical expertis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Science Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National Science Foundation As part of the Initiative, the National Science Foundation shall carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Department of Commerce</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Department of Energy As part of the Initiative, the Secretary of Energy shall carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Defense</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Department of Defense As part of the Initiative, the Secretary of Defense shall carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Aeronautics and Space Administration As part of the Initiative, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Department of Agriculture As part of the Initiative, the Secretary of Agriculture shall support research and development in engineering biology through the Agricultural Research Service, the National Institute of Food and Agriculture programs and grants, and the Office of the Chief Scientist.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental Protection Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental Protection Agency As part of the Initiative, the Environmental Protection Agency shall support research on how products, processes, and systems of engineering biology will affect or can protect the environment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19135_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department of Health and Human Services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Department of Health and Human Services As part of the Initiative, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as appropriate and consistent with activities of the Department of Health and Human Services in effect on the day before August 9, 2022, shall carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>