<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19211"><akn:num>19211</akn:num><akn:heading>Early-career research fellowship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19211. Early-career research fellowship program(a) In generalThe Director of the National Science Foundation may establish a 2-year pilot program to make awards to highly qualified early-career investigators to carry out an independent research program at the institution of higher education or participating Federal research facility chosen by such investigator, to last for a period not greater than two years.


(b) Selection processThe Director of the National Science Foundation shall select recipients under subsection (a) from among citizens, nationals, and lawfully admitted permanent resident aliens of the United States.


(c) OutreachThe Director of the National Science Foundation shall conduct program outreach to recruit fellowship applicants—(1) from all regions of the country;

(2) from historically underrepresented populations in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and

(3) who graduate from or intend to carry out research at a variety of types of institutions of higher education, including—(A) historically Black colleges and universities;

(B) Tribal Colleges and Universities;

(C) minority-serving institutions;

(D) institutions of higher education that are not among the top 50 institutions in annual Federal funding for research; and

(E) EPSCoR institutions.



(d) Special considerationThe Director of the National Science Foundation shall give special consideration and priority to an application from an individual who graduated from or is intending to carry out research at an institution of the type specified in subsection (c)(3).


(e) Reports from fellowsNot later than 180 days after the end of the pilot program under this section, each early-career investigator who receives an award under the pilot program shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation a report that describes how the early-career investigator used the award funds.


(f) Report from the DirectorNot later than 90 days after the conclusion of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of the National Science Foundation may establish a 2-year pilot program to make awards to highly qualified early-career investigators to carry out an independent research program at the institution of higher education or participating Federal research facility chosen by such investigator, to last for a period not greater than two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection process The Director of the National Science Foundation shall select recipients under subsection (a) from among citizens, nationals, and lawfully admitted permanent resident aliens of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Outreach The Director of the National Science Foundation shall conduct program outreach to recruit fellowship applicants—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special consideration The Director of the National Science Foundation shall give special consideration and priority to an application from an individual who graduated from or is intending to carry out research at an institution of the type specified in subsection (c)(3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports from fellows</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports from fellows Not later than 180 days after the end of the pilot program under this section, each early-career investigator who receives an award under the pilot program shall submit to the Director of the National Science Foundation a report that describes how the early-career investigator used the award funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19211_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report from the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report from the Director Not later than 90 days after the conclusion of the second year of the pilot program, the Director of the National Science Foundation shall submit to Congress a report that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>