<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19234" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19234/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19234/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19234"><akn:num>19234</akn:num><akn:heading>Research security training requirement for Federal research award personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19234. Research security training requirement for Federal research award personnel(a) Annual training requirement(1) In generalNot later than 12 months after August 9, 2022, each Federal research agency shall establish a requirement that, as part of an application for a research and development award from the agency—(A) each covered individual listed on the application for a research and development award certify that each such individual has completed within one year of such application research security training that meets the guidelines developed under subsection (b); and

(B) each institution of higher education or other organization applying for such an award certify that each covered individual who is employed by such institution or organization and listed on the application has completed such training.


(2) ConsistencyThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall ensure that the training requirements established by Federal research agencies pursuant to paragraph (1) are consistent.



(b) Training guidelinesThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, acting through the National Science and Technology Council and in accordance with the authority provided under section 1746(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (Public Law 116–92; 42 U.S.C. 6601 note), shall, taking into consideration stakeholder input, develop guidelines for institutions of higher education and other organizations receiving Federal research and development funds to use in developing their own training programs to address the unique needs, challenges, and risk profiles of such institutions and other organizations, including adoption of security training modules developed under subsection (c), to ensure compliance with National Security Presidential Memorandum–33 (relating to strengthening protections of the United States Government-supported research and development against foreign government interference and exploitation) or a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19234_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual training requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual training requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19234_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Training guidelines The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, acting through the National Science and Technology Council and in accordance with the authority provided under section 1746(a) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (Public Law 116–92; 42 U.S.C. 6601 note), shall, taking into consideration stakeholder input, develop guidelines for institutions of higher education and other organizations receiving Federal research and development funds to use in developing their own training programs to address the unique needs, challenges, and risk profiles of such institutions and other organizations, including adoption of security training modules developed under subsection (c), to ensure compliance with National Security Presidential Memorandum–33 (relating to strengthening protections of the United States Government-supported research and development against foreign government interference and exploitation) or any successor documents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19234_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security training modules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Security training modules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>