<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19237" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19237/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19237/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19237"><akn:num>19237</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19237. Definitions
In this part:(1) Covered individualThe term “covered individual” means an individual who—(A) contributes in a substantive, meaningful way to the scientific development or execution of a research and development project proposed to be carried out with a research and development award from a Federal research agency; and

(B) is designated as a covered individual by the Federal research agency concerned.


(2) Foreign country of concernThe term “foreign country of concern” means the People’s Republic of China, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, or any other country determined to be a country of concern by the Secretary of State.


(3) Foreign entity of concernThe term “foreign entity of concern” means a foreign entity that is—(A) designated as a foreign terrorist organization by the Secretary of State under section 1189(a) of title 8;

(B) included on the list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury (commonly known as the SDN list);

(C) owned by, controlled by, or subject to the jurisdiction or direction of a government of a foreign country that is a covered nation (as such term is defined in section 4872 of title 10);

(D) alleged by the Attorney General to have been involved in activities for which a conviction was obtained under—(i) chapter 37 of title 18 (commonly known as the Espionage Act);

(ii) section 951 or 1030 of title 18;

(iii) chapter 90 of title 18 (commonly known as the Economic Espionage Act of 1996);

(iv) the Arms Export Control Act (22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.);

(v) section 2274, 2275, 2276, 2277, or 2284 of this title;

(vi) the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (50 U.S.C. 4801 et seq.); or

(vii) the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.); or


(E) determined by the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19237_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered individual</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Covered individual The term “covered individual” means an individual who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19237_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign country of concern</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Foreign country of concern The term “foreign country of concern” means the People’s Republic of China, the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, the Russian Federation, the Islamic Republic of Iran, or any other country determined to be a country of concern by the Secretary of State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19237_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign entity of concern</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Foreign entity of concern The term “foreign entity of concern” means a foreign entity that is—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19237_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Malign foreign talent recruitment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Malign foreign talent recruitment program The term “malign foreign talent recruitment program” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>