<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19291" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19291/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19291/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19291"><akn:num>19291</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19291. Definitions
In this part:(1) Clean energy technologyThe term “clean energy technology” means a technology that significantly reduces energy use, increases energy efficiency, reduces greenhouse gas emissions, reduces emissions of other pollutants, or mitigates other negative environmental consequences of energy production, transmission or use.


(2) DepartmentThe term “Department” means the Department of Energy.


(3) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director of each National Laboratory and the Director of each Department of Energy single-purpose research facility.


(4) Economically distressed areaThe term “economically distressed area” has the meaning described in section 3161(a) of this title.


(5) GrantThe term “grant” means a grant award, cooperative agreement award, or any other financial assistance arrangement that the Secretary of Energy determines to be appropriate.


(6) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 1001 of title 20.


(7) National LaboratoryThe term “National Laboratory” has the meaning given that term in section 15801 of this title.


(8) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.


(Pub. L. 117–167, div. B, title VI, § 10701, Aug. 9, 2022, 136 Stat. 1701.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis part, referred to in text, was in the original “this subtitle”, meaning subtitle J (§§ 10701–10727) of title VI of div. B of Pub. L. 117–167, which is classified principally to this part. For complete classification of subtitle J to the Code, see Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean energy technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Clean energy technology The term “clean energy technology” means a technology that significantly reduces energy use, increases energy efficiency, reduces greenhouse gas emissions, reduces emissions of other pollutants, or mitigates other negative environmental consequences of energy production, transmission or use.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Department The term “Department” means the Department of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Director The term “Director” means the Director of each National Laboratory and the Director of each Department of Energy single-purpose research facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Economically distressed area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Economically distressed area The term “economically distressed area” has the meaning described in section 3161(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Grant The term “grant” means a grant award, cooperative agreement award, or any other financial assistance arrangement that the Secretary of Energy determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Institution of higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Institution of higher education The term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 1001 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Laboratory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) National Laboratory The term “National Laboratory” has the meaning given that term in section 15801 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19291_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Secretary The term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>