<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/19302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_19302"><akn:num>19302</akn:num><akn:heading>Clean Energy Technology University Prize competition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 19302. Clean Energy Technology University Prize competition(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a nonprofit entity, an institution of higher education, or an entity working with one or more institutions of higher education.


(2) Minority-serving institutionThe term “minority-serving institution” means an institution described in section 1067q(a) of title 20.



(b) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a program, known as the “Clean Energy Technology University Prize”, to award funding for eligible entities to carry out regional and one national clean energy technology prize competitions, under section 3719 of title 15. In carrying out such prize competitions, students shall compete to develop a business model for furthering the commercial application of an innovative clean energy technology.


(c) Training fundingIn carrying out this program, the Secretary may provide funding to train participating students in skills needed for the successful commercial application of clean energy technologies, including through virtual training sessions.


(d) PrioritizationIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants to eligible entities that work with students at minority-serving institutions.


(e) CoordinationIn carrying out this program, the Secretary shall coordinate and partner with other clean energy technology prize competitions. In doing so, the Secretary may develop and disseminate best practices for administering prize competitions under this section.


(f) ReportIn accordance with section 16391a of this title, the Secretary shall report annually on the progress and implementation of the program established under section (b).


(g) EvaluationIn accordance with section 16391a of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an evaluation on t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general The Secretary shall establish a program, known as the “Clean Energy Technology University Prize”, to award funding for eligible entities to carry out regional and one national clean energy technology prize competitions, under section 3719 of title 15. In carrying out such prize competitions, students shall compete to develop a business model for furthering the commercial application of an innovative clean energy technology.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Training funding In carrying out this program, the Secretary may provide funding to train participating students in skills needed for the successful commercial application of clean energy technologies, including through virtual training sessions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prioritization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prioritization In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants to eligible entities that work with students at minority-serving institutions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination In carrying out this program, the Secretary shall coordinate and partner with other clean energy technology prize competitions. In doing so, the Secretary may develop and disseminate best practices for administering prize competitions under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report In accordance with section 16391a of this title, the Secretary shall report annually on the progress and implementation of the program established under section (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Evaluation In accordance with section 16391a of this title, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an evaluation on the long-term outcomes of the program established under this section and the progress towards achieving the purposes of the program in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_19302_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the activities authorized in this section $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>