<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962d–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962d–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962d–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1962d_16"><akn:num>1962d–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive plans for development, utilization, and conservation of water and related resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1962d–16. Comprehensive plans for development, utilization, and conservation of water and related resources(a) Federal State cooperation(1) Comprehensive plansThe Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, is authorized to cooperate with any State, group of States, non-Federal interest working with a State or group of States, local government, or regional coalition of governmental entities in the preparation of comprehensive plans for the development, utilization, and conservation of the water and related resources of drainage basins, watersheds, or ecosystems located within the boundaries of such State, interest, local government, or entity, including plans to comprehensively address water resources challenges, and to submit to Congress reports and recommendations with respect to appropriate Federal participation in carrying out such plans.


(2) Technical assistance(A) In generalAt the request of a governmental agency or non-Federal interest, the Secretary may provide technical assistance to such agency or non-Federal interest in managing water resources.


(B) Types of assistanceTechnical assistance under this paragraph may include provision and integration of hydrologic, economic, and environmental data and analyses and title research for abandoned structures.



(3) Institution of higher educationNotwithstanding section 4141 of title 10, in carrying out this subsection, the Secretary may work with an institution of higher education, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(4) PrioritizationTo the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall prioritize the provision of assistance under this subsection to address both inland and coastal life safety risks.



(b) Fees(1) Establishment and collectionFor the purpose of recovering 50 percent of the total cost of providing assistance pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of the Army is authorized to establish appropriate fees, as determined by the Secretary, and to collect such fees f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal State cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal State cooperation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual submission of proposed activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual submission of proposed activities Concurrent with the President’s submission to Congress of the President’s request for appropriations for the Civil Works Program for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report describing the individual activities proposed for funding under subsection (a)(1) for that fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “State” defined For the purposes of this section, the term “State” means the several States of the United States, Indian tribes, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962d_16_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>