<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1962_4"><akn:num>1962–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of water resources principles and requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1962–4. Implementation of water resources principles and requirements(a) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall issue final agency-specific procedures necessary to implement the principles and requirements and the interagency guidelines.


(b) Development of future water resources development projectsThe procedures required by subsection (a) shall ensure that the Secretary, in the formulation of future water resources development projects—(1) develops such projects in accordance with—(A) the guiding principles established by the principles and requirements; and

(B) the national water resources planning policy established by section 1962–3(a) of this title; and


(2) fully identifies and analyzes national economic development benefits, regional economic development benefits, environmental quality benefits, and other societal effects.


(c) Review and updateEvery 5 years, the Secretary shall review and, where appropriate, revise the procedures required by subsection (a).


(d) Public review, notice, and commentIn issuing, reviewing, and revising the procedures required by this section, the Secretary shall—(1) provide notice to interested non-Federal stakeholders of the Secretary’s intent to revise the procedures;

(2) provide opportunities for interested non-Federal stakeholders to engage with, and provide input and recommendations to, the Secretary on the revision of the procedures; and

(3) solicit and consider public and expert comments.


(e) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Interagency guidelinesThe term “interagency guidelines” means the interagency guidelines contained in the document finalized by the Council on Environmental Quality pursuant to section 1962–3 of this title in December 2014, to implement the principles and requirements.


(2) Principles and requirementsThe term “principles and requirements” means the principles and requirements contained in the document prepared by the Council on Environmental Quality pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall issue final agency-specific procedures necessary to implement the principles and requirements and the interagency guidelines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of future water resources development projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development of future water resources development projects The procedures required by subsection (a) shall ensure that the Secretary, in the formulation of future water resources development projects—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and update</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review and update Every 5 years, the Secretary shall review and, where appropriate, revise the procedures required by subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public review, notice, and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public review, notice, and comment In issuing, reviewing, and revising the procedures required by this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>