<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962b–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962b–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1962b–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1962b_5"><akn:num>1962b–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of members and chairmen</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1962b–5. Compensation of members and chairmen(a) Additional compensation prohibited to members appointed from Federal departments, agencies, and international commissionsAny member of a river basin commission appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(b) and (e) of this title shall receive no additional compensation by virtue of his membership on the commission, but shall continue to receive, from appropriations made for the agency from which he is appointed, the salary of his regular position when engaged in the performance of the duties vested in the commission.


(b) Compensation of members from States and interstate agenciesMembers of a commission, appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(c) and (d) of this title, shall each receive such compensation as may be provided by the States or the interstate agency respectively, which they represent.


(c) Compensation of chairmanThe per annum compensation of the chairman of each river basin commission shall be determined by the President, but when employed on a full-time annual basis shall not exceed the maximum scheduled rate for grade GS–18 or when engaged in the performance of the commission’s duties on an intermittent basis such compensation shall be not more than $100 per day and shall not exceed $12,000 in any year.


(Pub. L. 89–80, title II, § 206, July 22, 1965, 79 Stat. 250.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
References in Other Laws to GS–16, 17, or 18 Pay RatesReferences in laws to the rates of pay for GS–16, 17, or 18, or to maximum rates of pay under the General Schedule, to be considered references to rates payable under specified sections of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, see section 529 [title I, § 101(c)(1)] of Pub. L. 101–509, set out in a note under section 5376 of Title 5.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962b_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional compensation prohibited to members appointed from Federal departments, agencies, and international commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Additional compensation prohibited to members appointed from Federal departments, agencies, and international commissions Any member of a river basin commission appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(b) and (e) of this title shall receive no additional compensation by virtue of his membership on the commission, but shall continue to receive, from appropriations made for the agency from which he is appointed, the salary of his regular position when engaged in the performance of the duties vested in the commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962b_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of members from States and interstate agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation of members from States and interstate agencies Members of a commission, appointed pursuant to section 1962b–1(c) and (d) of this title, shall each receive such compensation as may be provided by the States or the interstate agency respectively, which they represent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1962b_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of chairman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compensation of chairman The per annum compensation of the chairman of each river basin commission shall be determined by the President, but when employed on a full-time annual basis shall not exceed the maximum scheduled rate for grade GS–18 or when engaged in the performance of the commission’s duties on an intermittent basis such compensation shall be not more than $100 per day and shall not exceed $12,000 in any year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>