<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1975b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1975b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/1975b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_1975b"><akn:num>1975b</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 1975b. Administrative provisions(a) Staff(1) DirectorThere shall be a full-time staff director for the Commission who shall—(A) serve as the administrative head of the Commission; and

(B) be appointed by the President with the concurrence of a majority of the Commission.


(2) Other personnelWithin the limitation of its appropriations, the Commission may—(A) appoint such other personnel as it deems advisable, under the civil service and classification laws; and

(B) procure services, as authorized in section 3109 of title 5, but at rates for individuals not in excess of the daily equivalent paid for positions at the maximum rate for GS–15 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5.



(b) Compensation of members(1) GenerallyEach member of the Commission who is not otherwise in the service of the Government of the United States shall receive a sum equivalent to the compensation paid at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, prorated on a daily basis for time spent in the work of the Commission.


(2) Persons otherwise in Government serviceEach member of the Commission who is otherwise in the service of the Government of the United States shall serve without compensation in addition to that received for such other service, but while engaged in the work of the Commission shall be paid actual travel expenses and per diem in lieu of subsistence expenses when away from such member’s usual place of residence, under subchapter I of chapter 57 of title 5.



(c) Voluntary or uncompensated personnelThe Commission shall not accept or use the services of voluntary or uncompensated persons. This limitation shall apply with respect to services of members of the Commission as it does with respect to services by other persons.


(d) Rules(1) GenerallyThe Commission may make such rules as are necessary to carry out the purposes of this chapter.


(2) Continuation of old rulesExcept as inconsistent with this chapter, and until modified by the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1975b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1975b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation of members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1975b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary or uncompensated personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Voluntary or uncompensated personnel The Commission shall not accept or use the services of voluntary or uncompensated persons. This limitation shall apply with respect to services of members of the Commission as it does with respect to services by other persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1975b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_1975b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Cooperation All Federal agencies shall cooperate fully with the Commission to the end that it may effectively carry out its functions and duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>