<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000cc_5"><akn:num>2000cc–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000cc–5. Definitions
In this chapter:(1) ClaimantThe term “claimant” means a person raising a claim or defense under this chapter.


(2) DemonstratesThe term “demonstrates” means meets the burdens of going forward with the evidence and of persuasion.


(3) Free Exercise ClauseThe term “Free Exercise Clause” means that portion of the first amendment to the Constitution that proscribes laws prohibiting the free exercise of religion.


(4) GovernmentThe term “government”—(A) means—(i) a State, county, municipality, or other governmental entity created under the authority of a State;

(ii) any branch, department, agency, instrumentality, or official of an entity listed in clause (i); and

(iii) any other person acting under color of State law; and


(B) for the purposes of sections 2000cc–2(b) and 2000cc–3 of this title, includes the United States, a branch, department, agency, instrumentality, or official of the United States, and any other person acting under color of Federal law.


(5) Land use regulationThe term “land use regulation” means a zoning or landmarking law, or the application of such a law, that limits or restricts a claimant’s use or development of land (including a structure affixed to land), if the claimant has an ownership, leasehold, easement, servitude, or other property interest in the regulated land or a contract or option to acquire such an interest.


(6) Program or activityThe term “program or activity” means all of the operations of any entity as described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 2000d–4a of this title.


(7) Religious exercise(A) In generalThe term “religious exercise” includes any exercise of religion, whether or not compelled by, or central to, a system of religious belief.


(B) RuleThe use, building, or conversion of real property for the purpose of religious exercise shall be considered to be religious exercise of the person or entity that uses or intends to use the property for that purpose.



(Pub. L. 106–274, § 8, Sept.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Claimant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Claimant The term “claimant” means a person raising a claim or defense under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstrates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Demonstrates The term “demonstrates” means meets the burdens of going forward with the evidence and of persuasion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Free Exercise Clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Free Exercise Clause The term “Free Exercise Clause” means that portion of the first amendment to the Constitution that proscribes laws prohibiting the free exercise of religion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Government The term “government”—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use regulation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Land use regulation The term “land use regulation” means a zoning or landmarking law, or the application of such a law, that limits or restricts a claimant’s use or development of land (including a structure affixed to land), if the claimant has an ownership, leasehold, easement, servitude, or other property interest in the regulated land or a contract or option to acquire such an interest.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program or activity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Program or activity The term “program or activity” means all of the operations of any entity as described in paragraph (1) or (2) of section 2000d–4a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_5_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious exercise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Religious exercise</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>