<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000cc/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000cc"><akn:num>2000cc</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of land use as religious exercise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000cc. Protection of land use as religious exercise(a) Substantial burdens(1) General ruleNo government shall impose or implement a land use regulation in a manner that imposes a substantial burden on the religious exercise of a person, including a religious assembly or institution, unless the government demonstrates that imposition of the burden on that person, assembly, or institution—(A) is in furtherance of a compelling governmental interest; and

(B) is the least restrictive means of furthering that compelling governmental interest.


(2) Scope of applicationThis subsection applies in any case in which—(A) the substantial burden is imposed in a program or activity that receives Federal financial assistance, even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability;

(B) the substantial burden affects, or removal of that substantial burden would affect, commerce with foreign nations, among the several States, or with Indian tribes, even if the burden results from a rule of general applicability; or

(C) the substantial burden is imposed in the implementation of a land use regulation or system of land use regulations, under which a government makes, or has in place formal or informal procedures or practices that permit the government to make, individualized assessments of the proposed uses for the property involved.



(b) Discrimination and exclusion(1) Equal termsNo government shall impose or implement a land use regulation in a manner that treats a religious assembly or institution on less than equal terms with a nonreligious assembly or institution.


(2) NondiscriminationNo government shall impose or implement a land use regulation that discriminates against any assembly or institution on the basis of religion or religious denomination.


(3) Exclusions and limitsNo government shall impose or implement a land use regulation that—(A) totally excludes religious assemblies from a jurisdiction; or

(B) unreasonably limits religious assemblies, instituti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial burdens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Substantial burdens</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000cc_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination and exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discrimination and exclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>