<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ee" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ee/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ee/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000ee"><akn:num>2000ee</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000ee. Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board(a) In generalThere is established as an independent agency within the executive branch a Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board (referred to in this section as the “Board”).


(b) FindingsConsistent with the report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, Congress makes the following findings:(1) In conducting the war on terrorism, the Government may need additional powers and may need to enhance the use of its existing powers.

(2) This shift of power and authority to the Government calls for an enhanced system of checks and balances to protect the precious liberties that are vital to our way of life and to ensure that the Government uses its powers for the purposes for which the powers were given.

(3) The National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States correctly concluded that “The choice between security and liberty is a false choice, as nothing is more likely to endanger America’s liberties than the success of a terrorist attack at home. Our history has shown us that insecurity threatens liberty. Yet, if our liberties are curtailed, we lose the values that we are struggling to defend.”.


(c) PurposeThe Board shall—(1) analyze and review actions the executive branch takes to protect the Nation from terrorism, ensuring that the need for such actions is balanced with the need to protect privacy and civil liberties; and

(2) ensure that liberty concerns are appropriately considered in the development and implementation of laws, regulations, and policies related to efforts to protect the Nation against terrorism.


(d) Functions(1) Advice and counsel on policy development and implementationThe Board shall—(A) review proposed legislation, regulations, and policies related to efforts to protect the Nation from terrorism, including the development and adoption of information sharing guidelines under subsections (d) and (f) of section 485 of title 6;

(B) review th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established as an independent agency within the executive branch a Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board (referred to in this section as the “Board”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Findings Consistent with the report of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States, Congress makes the following findings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Purpose The Board shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informing the public</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Informing the public The Board—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Access to information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and travel expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Compensation and travel expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ee_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>