<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000dd" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000dd/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000dd/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000dd"><akn:num>2000dd</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment of persons under custody or cont</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000dd. Prohibition on cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment of persons under custody or control of the United States Government(a) In generalNo individual in the custody or under the physical control of the United States Government, regardless of nationality or physical location, shall be subject to cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment.


(b) ConstructionNothing in this section shall be construed to impose any geographical limitation on the applicability of the prohibition against cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment under this section.


(c) Limitation on supersedureThe provisions of this section shall not be superseded, except by a provision of law enacted after December 30, 2005, which specifically repeals, modifies, or supersedes the provisions of this section.


(d) Cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment definedIn this section, the term “cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment” means the cruel, unusual, and inhumane treatment or punishment prohibited by the Fifth, Eighth, and Fourteenth Amendments to the Constitution of the United States, as defined in the United States Reservations, Declarations and Understandings to the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Forms of Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment done at New York, December 10, 1984.


(Pub. L. 109–148, div. A, title X, § 1003, Dec. 30, 2005, 119 Stat. 2739; Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XIV, § 1403, Jan. 6, 2006, 119 Stat. 3475.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe date “December 30, 2005”, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “the date of the enactment of this Act” and was translated as the date of enactment of Pub. L. 109–148.

Codification
Pub. L. 109–148 and Pub. L. 109–163 enacted identical sections.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Short TitlePub. L. 109–148, div. A, title X, § 1001, Dec. 30, 2005, 119 Stat. 2739, and Pub. L. 109–163, div. A, title XIV, § 1401, Jan. 6,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000dd_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general No individual in the custody or under the physical control of the United States Government, regardless of nationality or physical location, shall be subject to cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000dd_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to impose any geographical limitation on the applicability of the prohibition against cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000dd_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on supersedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation on supersedure The provisions of this section shall not be superseded, except by a provision of law enacted after December 30, 2005, which specifically repeals, modifies, or supersedes the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000dd_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment defined In this section, the term “cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment” means the cruel, unusual, and inhumane treatment or punishment prohibited by the Fifth, Eighth, and Fourteenth Amendments to the Constitution of the United States, as defined in the United States Reservations, Declarations and Understandings to the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Forms of Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment done at New York, December 10, 1984.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>