<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ff–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ff–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2000ff–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2000ff_8"><akn:num>2000ff–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2000ff–8. Construction(a) In generalNothing in this chapter shall be construed to—(1) limit the rights or protections of an individual under any other Federal or State statute that provides equal or greater protection to an individual than the rights or protections provided for under this chapter, including the protections of an individual under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.) (including coverage afforded to individuals under section 102 of such Act (42 U.S.C. 12112)), or under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.);

(2)(A) limit the rights or protections of an individual to bring an action under this chapter against an employer, employment agency, labor organization, or joint labor-management committee for a violation of this chapter; or

(B) provide for enforcement of, or penalties for violation of, any requirement or prohibition applicable to any employer, employment agency, labor organization, or joint labor-management committee subject to enforcement for a violation under—(i) the amendments made by title I of this Act;

(ii)(I) subsection (a) of section 1181 of title 29 as such section applies with respect to genetic information pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section;

(II) section 1182(a)(1)(F) of title 29; or

(III) section 1182(b)(1) of title 29 as such section applies with respect to genetic information as a health status-related factor;


(iii)(I) subsection (a) of section 2701 11 See References in Text note below. of the Public Health Service Act as such section applies with respect to genetic information pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) of such section;

(II) section 2702(a)(1)(F) 1 of such Act; or

(III) section 2702(b)(1) 1 of such Act as such section applies with respect to genetic information as a health status-related factor; or


(iv)(I) subsection (a) of section 9801 of title 26 as such section applies with respect to genetic information pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) of such sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ff_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ff_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Genetic information of a fetus or embryo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Genetic information of a fetus or embryo Any reference in this chapter to genetic information concerning an individual or family member of an individual shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2000ff_8_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to authorities under title I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Relation to authorities under title I With respect to a group health plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, this chapter does not prohibit any activity of such plan or issuer that is authorized for the plan or issuer under any provision of law referred to in clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection (a)(2)(B).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>