<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2015b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2015b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2015b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2015b"><akn:num>2015b</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship and fellowship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2015b. Scholarship and fellowship program(a) Scholarship programTo enable students to study, for at least 1 academic semester or equivalent term, science, engineering, or another field of study that the Commission determines is in a critical skill area related to the regulatory mission of the Commission, the Commission may carry out a program to—(1) 11 So in original. No par. (2) has been enacted. award scholarships to undergraduate students who—(A) are United States citizens; and

(B) enter into an agreement under subsection (c) to be employed by the Commission in the area of study for which the scholarship is awarded.



(b) Fellowship programTo enable students to pursue education in science, engineering, or another field of study that the Commission determines is in a critical skill area related to its regulatory mission, in a graduate or professional degree program offered by an institution of higher education in the United States, the Commission may carry out a program to—(1) 1 award fellowships to graduate students who—(A) are United States citizens; and

(B) enter into an agreement under subsection (c) to be employed by the Commission in the area of study for which the fellowship is awarded.



(c) Requirements(1) In generalAs a condition of receiving a scholarship or fellowship under subsection (a) or (b), a recipient of the scholarship or fellowship shall enter into an agreement with the Commission under which, in return for the assistance, the recipient shall—(A) maintain satisfactory academic progress in the studies of the recipient, as determined by criteria established by the Commission;

(B) agree that failure to maintain satisfactory academic progress shall constitute grounds on which the Commission may terminate the assistance;

(C) on completion of the academic course of study in connection with which the assistance was provided, and in accordance with criteria established by the Commission, engage in employment by the Commission for a period spec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Scholarship program To enable students to study, for at least 1 academic semester or equivalent term, science, engineering, or another field of study that the Commission determines is in a critical skill area related to the regulatory mission of the Commission, the Commission may carry out a program to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fellowship program To enable students to pursue education in science, engineering, or another field of study that the Commission determines is in a critical skill area related to its regulatory mission, in a graduate or professional degree program offered by an institution of higher education in the United States, the Commission may carry out a program to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Competitive process Recipients of scholarships or fellowships under this section shall be selected through a competitive process primarily on the basis of academic merit and such other criteria as the Commission may establish, with consideration given to financial need and the goal of promoting the participation of individuals identified in section 1885a or 1885b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2015b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Direct appointment The Commission may appoint directly, with no further competition, public notice, or consideration of any other potential candidate, an individual who has—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>