<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021"><akn:num>2021</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021. Cooperation with States(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section—(1) to recognize the interests of the States in the peaceful uses of atomic energy, and to clarify the respective responsibilities under this chapter of the States and the Commission with respect to the regulation of byproduct, source, and special nuclear materials;

(2) to recognize the need, and establish programs for, cooperation between the States and the Commission with respect to control of radiation hazards associated with use of such materials;

(3) to promote an orderly regulatory pattern between the Commission and State governments with respect to nuclear development and use and regulation of byproduct, source, and special nuclear materials;

(4) to establish procedures and criteria for discontinuance of certain of the Commission’s regulatory responsibilities with respect to byproduct, source, and special nuclear materials, and the assumption thereof by the States;

(5) to provide for coordination of the development of radiation standards for the guidance of Federal agencies and cooperation with the States; and

(6) to recognize that, as the States improve their capabilities to regulate effectively such materials, additional legislation may be desirable.


(b) Agreements with StatesExcept as provided in subsection (c), the Commission is authorized to enter into agreements with the Governor of any State providing for discontinuance of the regulatory authority of the Commission under subchapters V, VI, and VII of this division, and section 2201 of this title, with respect to any one or more of the following materials within the State:(1) Byproduct materials (as defined in section 2014(e) of this title).

(2) Source materials.

(3) Special nuclear materials in quantities not sufficient to form a critical mass.


During the duration of such an agreement it is recognized that the State shall have authority to regulate the materials covered by the agreement for the protection of the publ</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Agreements with States Except as provided in subsection (c), the Commission is authorized to enter into agreements with the Governor of any State providing for discontinuance of the regulatory authority of the Commission under subchapters V, VI, and VII of this division, and section 2201 of this title, with respect to any one or more of the following materials within the State: During the duration of such an agreement it is recognized that the State shall have authority to regulate the materials covered by the agreement for the protection of the public health and safety from radiation hazards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission regulation of certain activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Commission regulation of certain activities No agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (b) shall provide for discontinuance of any authority and the Commission shall retain authority and responsibility with respect to regulation of— The Commission shall also retain authority under any such agreement to make a determination that all applicable standards and requirements have been met prior to termination of a license for byproduct material, as defined in section 2014(e)(2) of this title. Notwithstanding any agreement between the Commission and any State pursuant to subsection (b), the Commission is authorized by rule, regulation, or order to require that the manufacturer, processor, or producer of any equipment, device, commodity, or other product containing source, byproduct, or special nuclear material shall not transfer possession or control of such product except pursuant to a license issued by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Conditions The Commission shall enter into an agreement under subsection (b) of this section with any State if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register; comment of interested persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Publication in Federal Register; comment of interested persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exemptions The Commission is authorized and directed, by regulation or order, to grant such exemptions from the licensing requirements contained in subchapters V, VI, and VII, and from its regulations applicable to licensees as the Commission finds necessary or appropriate to carry out any agreement entered into pursuant to subsection (b) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compatible radiation standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compatible radiation standards The Commission is authorized and directed to cooperate with the States in the formulation of standards for protection against hazards of radiation to assure that State and Commission programs for protection against hazards of radiation will be coordinated and compatible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultative, advisory, and miscellaneous functions of Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Consultative, advisory, and miscellaneous functions of Administrator of Environmental Protection Agency The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall consult qualified scientists and experts in radiation matters, including the President of the National Academy of Sciences, the Chairman of the National Committee on Radiation Protection and Measurement, and qualified experts in the field of biology and medicine and in the field of health physics. The Special Assistant to the President for Science and Technology, or his designee, is authorized to attend meetings with, participate in the deliberations of, and to advise the Administrator. The Administrator shall advise the President with respect to radiation matters, directly or indirectly affecting health, including guidance for all Federal agencies in the formulation of radiation standards and in the establishment and execution of programs of cooperation with States. The Administrator shall also perform such other fun</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections and other functions; training and other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Inspections and other functions; training and other assistance The Commission in carrying out its licensing and regulatory responsibilities under this chapter is authorized to enter into agreements with any State, or group of States, to perform inspections or other functions on a cooperative basis as the Commission deems appropriate. The Commission is also authorized to provide training, with or without charge, to employees of, and such other assistance to, any State or political subdivision thereof or group of States as the Commission deems appropriate. Any such provision or assistance by the Commission shall take into account the additional expenses that may be incurred by a State as a consequence of the State’s entering into an agreement with the Commission pursuant to subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reserve power to terminate or suspend agreements; emergency situations; State nonaction on causes of danger; authority exercisable only during emergency and commensurate with danger</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reserve power to terminate or suspend agreements; emergency situations; State nonaction on causes of danger; authority exercisable only during emergency and commensurate with danger</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>