<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2021e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2021e"><akn:num>2021e</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited availability of certain regional disposal facilities during transition and licensing periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2021e. Limited availability of certain regional disposal facilities during transition and licensing periods(a) Availability of disposal capacity(1) Pressurized water and boiling water reactorsDuring the seven-year period beginning January 1, 1986 and ending December 31, 1992, subject to the provisions of subsections (b) through (g), each State in which there is located a regional disposal facility referred to in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b) shall make disposal capacity available for low-level radioactive waste generated by pressurized water and boiling water commercial nuclear power reactors in accordance with the allocations established in subsection (c).


(2) Other sources of low-level radioactive wasteDuring the seven-year period beginning January 1, 1986 and ending December 31, 1992, subject to the provisions of subsections (b) through (g), each State in which there is located a regional disposal facility referred to in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b) shall make disposal capacity available for low-level radioactive waste generated by any source not referred to in paragraph (1).


(3) Allocation of disposal capacity(A) During the seven-year period beginning January 1, 1986 and ending December 31, 1992, low-level radioactive waste generated within a sited compact region shall be accorded priority under this section in the allocation of available disposal capacity at a regional disposal facility referred to in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b) and located in the sited compact region in which such waste is generated.

(B) Any State in which a regional disposal facility referred to in paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (b) is located may, subject to the provisions of its compact, prohibit the disposal at such facility of low-level radioactive waste generated outside of the compact region if the disposal of such waste in any given calendar year, together with all other low-level radioactive waste disposed of at such fac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of disposal capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability of disposal capacity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations The availability of disposal capacity for low-level radioactive waste from any source shall be subject to the following limitations:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Commercial nuclear power reactor allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Commercial nuclear power reactor allocations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of surcharge funds for milestone incentives; consequences of failure to meet disposal deadline</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of surcharge funds for milestone incentives; consequences of failure to meet disposal deadline</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for access to regional disposal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements for access to regional disposal facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of compliance and denial of access to non-Federal facilities for noncompliance; information requirements of certain States; proprietary information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Monitoring of compliance and denial of access to non-Federal facilities for noncompliance; information requirements of certain States; proprietary information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2021e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nondiscrimination Except as provided in subsections (b) through (e), low-level radioactive waste disposed of under this section shall be subject without discrimination to all applicable legal requirements of the compact region and State in which the disposal facility is located as if such low-level radioactive waste were generated within such compact region.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>