<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2023" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2023/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2023/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2023"><akn:num>2023</akn:num><akn:heading>State authority to regulate radiation below level of regulatory concern of Nuclear Regulatory Commis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2023. State authority to regulate radiation below level of regulatory concern of Nuclear Regulatory Commission(a) In generalNo provision of this chapter, or of the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act [42 U.S.C. 2021b et seq.], may be construed to prohibit or otherwise restrict the authority of any State to regulate, on the basis of radiological hazard, the disposal or off-site incineration of low-level radioactive waste, if the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, after October 24, 1992, exempts such waste from regulation.


(b) Relation to other State authorityThis section may not be construed to imply preemption of existing State authority. Except as expressly provided in subsection (a), this section may not be construed to confer on any State any additional authority to regulate activities licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “low-level radioactive waste” means radioactive material classified by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission as low-level radioactive waste on October 24, 1992.

(2) The term “off-site incineration” means any incineration of radioactive materials at a facility that is located off the site where such materials were generated.

(3) The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States.


(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 276, as added Pub. L. 102–486, title XXIX, § 2901(a), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3122.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, as added by act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 919, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2011 of this title and Tables.
The Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act, referred to in subsec. (a), i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2023_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general No provision of this chapter, or of the Low-Level Radioactive Waste Policy Act [42 U.S.C. 2021b et seq.], may be construed to prohibit or otherwise restrict the authority of any State to regulate, on the basis of radiological hazard, the disposal or off-site incineration of low-level radioactive waste, if the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, after October 24, 1992, exempts such waste from regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2023_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to other State authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relation to other State authority This section may not be construed to imply preemption of existing State authority. Except as expressly provided in subsection (a), this section may not be construed to confer on any State any additional authority to regulate activities licensed by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2023_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>