<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2034" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2034/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2034/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2034"><akn:num>2034</akn:num><akn:heading>General Manager, Deputy and Assistant General Managers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2034. General Manager, Deputy and Assistant General Managers
There is established within the Commission—(a) General Manager; chief executive officer; duties; appointment; removala General Manager, who shall be the chief executive officer of the Commission, and who shall discharge such of the administrative and executive functions of the Commission as the Commission may direct. The General Manager shall be appointed by the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the Commission and shall be removable by the Commission.


(b) Deputy General Manager; duties; appointment; removala Deputy General Manager, who shall act in the stead of the General Manager during his absence when so directed by the General Manager, and who shall perform such other administrative and executive functions as the General Manager shall direct. The Deputy General Manager shall be appointed by the General Manager with the approval of the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the General Manager, and shall be removable by the General Manager.


(c) Assistant General Managers; duties; appointment; removalAssistant General Managers, or their equivalents (not to exceed a total of three positions), who shall perform such administrative and executive functions as the General Manager shall direct. They shall be appointed by the General Manager with the approval of the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the General Manager, and shall be removable by the General Manager.


(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 24, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 925; amended Pub. L. 85–287, § 2, Sept. 4, 1957, 71 Stat. 612; Pub. L. 88–426, title III, § 306(f)(1)–(3), Aug. 14, 1964, 78 Stat. 429; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to this section were contained in section 1802(a)(4)(A) of this title, prior to the general amendment and renumbering of act Aug. 1, 1946, by act Aug. 30, 195</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2034_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General Manager; chief executive officer; duties; appointment; removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General Manager; chief executive officer; duties; appointment; removal a General Manager, who shall be the chief executive officer of the Commission, and who shall discharge such of the administrative and executive functions of the Commission as the Commission may direct. The General Manager shall be appointed by the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the Commission and shall be removable by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2034_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy General Manager; duties; appointment; removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Deputy General Manager; duties; appointment; removal a Deputy General Manager, who shall act in the stead of the General Manager during his absence when so directed by the General Manager, and who shall perform such other administrative and executive functions as the General Manager shall direct. The Deputy General Manager shall be appointed by the General Manager with the approval of the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the General Manager, and shall be removable by the General Manager.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2034_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant General Managers; duties; appointment; removal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistant General Managers; duties; appointment; removal Assistant General Managers, or their equivalents (not to exceed a total of three positions), who shall perform such administrative and executive functions as the General Manager shall direct. They shall be appointed by the General Manager with the approval of the Commission, shall serve at the pleasure of the General Manager, and shall be removable by the General Manager.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>