<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2053" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2053/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2053/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2053"><akn:num>2053</akn:num><akn:heading>Research for others; charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2053. Research for others; charges
In this section, with respect to international research projects, the term “private facilities or laboratories” means facilities or laboratories located in the United States. Where the Commission finds private facilities or laboratories are inadequate for the purpose, it is authorized to conduct for other persons, through its own facilities, such of those activities and studies of the types specified in section 2051 of this title as it deems appropriate to the development of energy. To the extent the Commission determines that private facilities or laboratories are inadequate for the purpose, and that the Commission’s facilities, or scientific or technical resources have the potential of lending significant assistance to other persons in the fields of protection of public health and safety, the Commission may also assist other persons in these fields by conducting for such persons, through the Commission’s own facilities, research and development or training activities and studies. The Commission is authorized to determine and make such charges as in its discretion may be desirable for the conduct of the activities and studies referred to in this section.
(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 33, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 928; amended Pub. L. 90–190, § 7, Dec. 14, 1967, 81 Stat. 577; Pub. L. 92–84, title II, § 201(b), Aug. 11, 1971, 85 Stat. 307; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944; Pub. L. 115–246, title III, § 307(g), formerly § 307(f), Sept. 28, 2018, 132 Stat. 3149, renumbered § 307(g), Pub. L. 116–260, div. Z, title II, § 2008(a)(1), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2474.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–246 inserted “In this section, with respect to international research projects, the term ‘private facilities or laboratories’ means facilities or laboratories located in the United States.” before “Where the Commission”.
1971—Pub. L. 92–84 substitut</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>