<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2075" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2075/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2075/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2075"><akn:num>2075</akn:num><akn:heading>Acquisition of special nuclear material; payments; just compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2075. Acquisition of special nuclear material; payments; just compensation
The Commission is authorized, to the extent it deems necessary to effectuate the provisions of this chapter, to purchase without regard to the limitations in section 2074 of this title or any guaranteed purchase prices established pursuant to section 2076 of this title, and to take, requisition, condemn, or otherwise acquire any special nuclear material or any interest therein. Any contract of purchase made under this section may be made without regard to the provisions of section 6101 of title 41, upon certification by the Commission that such action is necessary in the interest of the common defense and security, or upon a showing by the Commission that advertising is not reasonably practicable. Partial and advance payments may be made under contracts for such purposes. Just compensation shall be made for any right, property, or interest in property taken, requisitioned, or condemned under this section: Providing, That the authority in this section to commit United States funds for any activities pursuant to any subsequent arrangement under section 2160(a)(2)(E) of this title shall be subject to the requirements of section 2160 of this title.
(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 55, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 931; amended Pub. L. 88–489, § 10, Aug. 26, 1964, 78 Stat. 604; Pub. L. 95–242, title III, § 303(b)(2), Mar. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 131; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, as added by act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 919, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 2011 of this title and Tables.

Codification
In text, “section 61</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>