<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/209" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/209/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/209/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_209"><akn:num>209</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 209. Appointment of personnel(a) Original appointments to Regular and Ready Reserve Corps; limitation on appointment and call to active duty(1) Except as provided in subsections (b) and (e) of this section, original appointments to the Regular Corps may be made only in the warrant officer (W–1), chief warrant officer (W–2), chief warrant officer (W–3), chief warrant officer (W–4), junior assistant, assistant, and senior assistant grades and original appointments to a grade above junior assistant shall be made only after passage of an examination, given in accordance with regulations of the President, in one or more of the several branches of medicine, dentistry, hygiene, sanitary engineering, pharmacy, psychology, nursing, or related scientific specialties in the field of public health.

(2) Original appointments to the Ready Reserve Corps may be made to any grade up to and including the director grade but only after passage of an examination given in accordance with regulations of the President. Reserve commissions shall be for an indefinite period and may be terminated at any time, as the President may direct.

(3) No individual who has attained the age of forty-four shall be appointed to the Regular Corps, or called to active duty in the Ready Reserve Corps for a period in excess of one year, unless (A) he has had a number of years of active service (as defined in section 212(d) of this title) equal to the number of years by which his age exceeds forty-four, or (B) the Surgeon General determines that he possesses exceptional qualifications, not readily available elsewhere in the Commissioned Corps of the Public Health Service, for the performance of special duties with the Service, or (C) in the case of an officer of the Ready Reserve Corps, the Commissioned Corps of the Service has been declared by the President to be a military service.


(b) Grade and number of original appointments(1) Not more than 10 per centum of the original appointments to the Regular C</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Original appointments to Regular and Ready Reserve Corps; limitation on appointment and call to active duty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Original appointments to Regular and Ready Reserve Corps; limitation on appointment and call to active duty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grade and number of original appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grade and number of original appointments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of commissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance of commissions Commissions evidencing the appointment by the President of officers of the Regular Corps or Ready Reserve Corps shall be issued by the Secretary under the seal of the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date of appointment; credit for service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Date of appointment; credit for service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reappointment; credit for service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reappointment; credit for service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Special consultants In accordance with regulations, special consultants may be employed to assist and advise in the operations of the Service. Such consultants may be appointed without regard to the civil-service laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation for fellowships; duties; pay</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Designation for fellowships; duties; pay In accordance with regulations, individual scientists, other than commissioned officers of the Service, may be designated by the Surgeon General to receive fellowships, appointed for duty with the Service without regard to the civil-service laws, may hold their fellowships under conditions prescribed therein, and may be assigned for studies or investigations either in this country or abroad during the terms of their fellowships.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Aliens</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Aliens Persons who are not citizens may be employed as consultants pursuant to subsection (f) and may be appointed to fellowships pursuant to subsection (g). Unless otherwise specifically provided, any prohibition in any other Act against the employment of aliens, or against the payment of compensation to them, shall not be applicable in the case of persons employed or appointed pursuant to such subsections.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_209_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil service appointments by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Civil service appointments by Secretary The appointment of any officer or employee of the Service made in accordance with the civil-service laws shall be made by the Secretary, and may be made effective as of the date on which such officer or employee enters upon duty.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>