<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2094" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2094/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2094/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2094"><akn:num>2094</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign distribution of source material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2094. Foreign distribution of source material
The Commission is authorized to cooperate with any nation by distributing source material and to distribute source material pursuant to the terms of an agreement for cooperation to which such nation is a party and which is made in accordance with section 2153 of this title. The Commission is also authorized to distribute source material outside of the United States upon a determination by the Commission that such activity will not be inimical to the interests of the United States. The authority to distribute source material under this section other than under an export license granted by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall in no case extend to quantities of source material in excess of three metric tons per year per recipient.
(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 64, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 933; amended Pub. L. 95–242, title III, § 301(b), Mar. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 125; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Pub. L. 95–242 provided that the authority to distribute source material under this section other than under an export license granted by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall in no case extend to quantities of source material in excess of three metric tons per year per recipient.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1978 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 95–242 effective Mar. 10, 1978, except as otherwise provided and regardless of any requirement for the promulgation of implementing regulations, see section 603(c) of Pub. L. 95–242, set out as an Effective Date note under section 3201 of Title 22, Foreign Relations and Intercourse.

Executive Documents
Performance of Functions Pending Development of ProceduresThe performance of functions under this chapter, as amended by the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978, Pub. L. 95–242, Mar. 10, 1978, 92 Stat. 120, not to be delayed pending de</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>