<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_211"><akn:num>211</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of commissioned officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 211. Promotion of commissioned officers(a) Permanent or temporary promotions; examinationPromotions of officers of the Regular Corps to any grade up to and including the director grade shall be either permanent promotions based on length of service, other permanent promotions to fill vacancies, or temporary promotions. Permanent promotions shall be made by the President, and temporary promotions shall be made by the President. Each permanent promotion shall be to the next higher grade, and shall be made only after examination given in accordance with regulations of the President.


(b) Promotion to certain grades only to fill vacancies; regulations; “restricted grade” definedThe President may by regulation provide that in a specified professional category permanent promotions to the senior grade, or to both the full grade and the senior grade, shall be made only if there are vacancies in such grade. A grade in any category with respect to which such regulations have been issued is referred to in this section as a “restricted grade”.


(c) ExaminationsExaminations to determine qualification for permanent promotions may be either noncompetitive or competitive, as the Surgeon General shall in each case determine; except that examinations for promotions to the assistant or senior assistant grade shall in all cases be noncompetitive. The officers to be examined shall be selected by the Surgeon General from the professional category, and in the order of seniority in the grade, from which promotion is to be recommended. In the case of a competitive examination the Surgeon General shall determine in advance of the examination the number (which may be one or more) of officers who, after passing the examination, will be recommended to the President for promotion; but if the examination is one for promotions based on length of service, or is one for promotions to fill vacancies other than vacancies in the director grade or in a restricted grade, such number shall not be less</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent or temporary promotions; examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permanent or temporary promotions; examination Promotions of officers of the Regular Corps to any grade up to and including the director grade shall be either permanent promotions based on length of service, other permanent promotions to fill vacancies, or temporary promotions. Permanent promotions shall be made by the President, and temporary promotions shall be made by the President. Each permanent promotion shall be to the next higher grade, and shall be made only after examination given in accordance with regulations of the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion to certain grades only to fill vacancies; regulations; “restricted grade” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Promotion to certain grades only to fill vacancies; regulations; “restricted grade” defined The President may by regulation provide that in a specified professional category permanent promotions to the senior grade, or to both the full grade and the senior grade, shall be made only if there are vacancies in such grade. A grade in any category with respect to which such regulations have been issued is referred to in this section as a “restricted grade”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Examinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Examinations Examinations to determine qualification for permanent promotions may be either noncompetitive or competitive, as the Surgeon General shall in each case determine; except that examinations for promotions to the assistant or senior assistant grade shall in all cases be noncompetitive. The officers to be examined shall be selected by the Surgeon General from the professional category, and in the order of seniority in the grade, from which promotion is to be recommended. In the case of a competitive examination the Surgeon General shall determine in advance of the examination the number (which may be one or more) of officers who, after passing the examination, will be recommended to the President for promotion; but if the examination is one for promotions based on length of service, or is one for promotions to fill vacancies other than vacancies in the director grade or in a restricted grade, such number shall not be less than 80 per centum of the number of officers to be </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent promotions to qualified officers on length of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Permanent promotions to qualified officers on length of service Officers of the Regular Corps, found pursuant to subsection (c) to be qualified, shall be given permanent promotions based on length of service, as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion of professional category officers to fill certain vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Promotion of professional category officers to fill certain vacancies Officers in a professional category of the Regular Corps, found pursuant to subsection (c) to be qualified, may be given permanent promotions to fill any or all vacancies in such category in the senior assistant grade, the full grade, the senior grade, or the director grade; but no officer who has not had one year of service with permanent or temporary rank in the next lower grade shall be promoted to any restricted grade or to the director grade.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reexamination upon failure of promotion; effective date of promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reexamination upon failure of promotion; effective date of promotion If an officer who has completed the years of service required for promotion to a grade under paragraph (2) of subsection (d) fails to receive such promotion, he shall (unless he has already been twice examined for promotion to such grade) be once reexamined for promotion to such grade. If he is thereupon promoted (otherwise than under subsection (e)), the effective date of such promotion shall be one year later than it would have been but for such failure. Upon the effective date of any permanent promotion of such officer to such grade, he shall be considered as having had only the length of service required for such promotion which he previously failed to receive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation from service upon failure of promotion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Separation from service upon failure of promotion If, for reasons other than physical disability, an officer of the Regular Corps in the warrant officer (W–1) grade or junior assistant grade is found pursuant to subsection (c) not to be qualified for promotion he shall be separated from the Service. If, for reasons other than physical disability, an officer of the Regular Corps in the chief warrant officer (W–2), chief warrant officer (W–3), assistant, senior assistant, or full grade, after having been twice examined for promotion (other than promotion to a restricted grade), fails to be promoted—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Separation from service upon refusal to stand examination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Separation from service upon refusal to stand examination If an officer of the Regular Corps, eligible to take an examination for promotion, refuses to take such examination, he may be separated from the Service in accordance with regulations of the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of record; separation from service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Review of record; separation from service At the end of his first three years of service, the record of each officer of the Regular Corps originally appointed to the senior assistant grade or above, shall be reviewed in accordance with regulations of the President and, if found not qualified for further service, he shall be separated from the Service and paid six months’ pay and allowances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of order of seniority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Determination of order of seniority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>