<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/211c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_211c"><akn:num>211c</akn:num><akn:heading>Promotion credit for medical officers in assistant grade</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 211c. Promotion credit for medical officers in assistant grade
Any medical officer of the Regular Corps of the Public Health Service who—(1)(A) was appointed to the assistant grade in the Regular Corps and whose service in such Corps has been continuous from the date of appointment or (B) may hereafter be appointed to the assistant grade in the Regular Corps, and


(2) had or will have completed a medical internship on the date of such appointment,


shall be credited with one year for purposes of promotion and seniority in grade, except that no such credit shall be authorized if the officer has received or will receive similar credit for his internship under other provisions of law. In the case of an officer on active duty on the effective date of this section who is entitled to the credit authorized herein, the one year shall be added to the promotion and seniority-in-grade credits with which he is credited on such date.
(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title II, § 220, as added Apr. 30, 1956, ch. 223, § 3, 70 Stat. 121.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextFor “the effective date of this section”, referred to in text, see section 7 of act Apr. 30, 1956, which provided in part that this section shall become effective the first day of the month following the day of enactment, Apr. 30, 1956.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88, which is classified to section 3508(b) of Title 20, Education.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
Functions of Public Health Service, Surgeon General of Public Health Service, and all other officers and employees of Public Health Service, and functions of all agencies of or in Public Health Service transferred to Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare by Reorg. Plan No. 3 of 1966, eff. June 25, 1966, 31 F.R. 8855, 80 Stat. 1610, set out as a note under section 202 of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211c_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_211c_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) had or will have completed a medical internship on the date of such appointment,</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>