<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2153c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2153c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2153c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2153c"><akn:num>2153c</akn:num><akn:heading>Renegotiation of agreements for cooperation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2153c. Renegotiation of agreements for cooperation(a) Application to existing agreements of undertakings required of new agreements after March 10, 1978The President shall initiate a program immediately to renegotiate agreements for cooperation in effect on March 10, 1978, or otherwise to obtain the agreement of parties to such agreements for cooperation to the undertakings that would be required for new agreements under the 1954 Act. To the extent that an agreement for cooperation in effect on March 10, 1978, with a cooperating party contains provisions equivalent to any or all of the criteria set forth in section 127 of the 1954 Act [42 U.S.C. 2156] with respect to materials and equipment transferred pursuant thereto or with respect to any special nuclear material used in or produced through the use of any such material or equipment, any renegotiated agreement with that cooperating party shall continue to contain an equivalent provision with respect to such transferred materials and equipment and such special nuclear material. To the extent that an agreement for cooperation in effect on March 10, 1978, with a cooperating party does not contain provisions with respect to any nuclear materials and equipment which have previously been transferred under an agreement for cooperation with the United States and which are under the jurisdiction or control of the cooperating party and with respect to any special nuclear material which is used in or produced through the use thereof and which is under the jurisdiction or control of the cooperating party, which are equivalent to any or all of those required for new and amended agreements for cooperation under section 123 a. of the 1954 Act [42 U.S.C. 2153(a)], the President shall vigorously seek to obtain the application of such provisions with respect to such nuclear materials and equipment and such special nuclear material. Nothing in this Act or in the 1954 Act shall be deemed to relinquish any rights which the United St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2153c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to existing agreements of undertakings required of new agreements after March 10, 1978</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Application to existing agreements of undertakings required of new agreements after The President shall initiate a program immediately to renegotiate agreements for cooperation in effect on March 10, 1978, or otherwise to obtain the agreement of parties to such agreements for cooperation to the undertakings that would be required for new agreements under the 1954 Act. To the extent that an agreement for cooperation in effect on March 10, 1978, with a cooperating party contains provisions equivalent to any or all of the criteria set forth in section 127 of the 1954 Act [42 U.S.C. 2156] with respect to materials and equipment transferred pursuant thereto or with respect to any special nuclear material used in or produced through the use of any such material or equipment, any renegotiated agreement with that cooperating party shall continue to contain an equivalent provision with respect to such transferred materials and equipment and such special nuclear material. To the extent that </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2153c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential review of export agreement conditions and policy goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Presidential review of export agreement conditions and policy goals The President shall annually review each of requirements (1) through (9) set forth for inclusion in agreements for cooperation under section 123 a. of the 1954 Act [42 U.S.C. 2153(a)] and the export policy goals set forth in section 2153b of this title to determine whether it is in the interest of United States non-proliferation objectives for any such requirements or export policies which are not already being applied as export criteria to be enacted as additional export criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2153c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential proposals for additional export criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Presidential proposals for additional export criteria If the President proposes enactment of any such requirements or export policies as additional export criteria or to take any other action with respect to such requirements or export policy goals for the purpose of encouraging adherence by nations and groups of nations to such requirements and policies, he shall submit such a proposal together with an explanation thereof to the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2153c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Congressional action If the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate or the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, after reviewing the President’s annual report or any proposed legislation, determines that it is in the interest of United States non-proliferation objectives to take any action with respect to such requirements or export policy goals, it shall report a joint resolution to implement such determination. Any joint resolution so reported shall be considered in the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, under applicable procedures provided for the consideration of resolutions pursuant to subsection 11 So in original. 130 b. through g. of the 1954 Act [42 U.S.C. 2159(b) through (g)].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>