<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2159" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2159/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2159/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2159"><akn:num>2159</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional review procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2159. Congressional review procedures(a) Committee consideration of Presidential submissions; reportsNot later than forty-five days of continuous session of Congress after the date of transmittal to the Congress of any submission of the President required by section 2155(a)(2), 2155(b)(2), 2157(b), 2158, 2160(a)(3), or 2160(f)(1)(A) of this title, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives shall each submit a report to its respective House on its views and recommendations respecting such Presidential submission together with a resolution, as defined in subsection (f), stating in substance that the Congress approves or disapproves such submission, as the case may be: Provided, That if any such committee has not reported such a resolution at the end of such forty-five day period, such committee shall be deemed to be discharged from further consideration of such submission. If no such resolution has been reported at the end of such period, the first resolution, as defined in subsection (f), which is introduced within five days thereafter within such House shall be placed on the appropriate calendar of such House.


(b) Consideration of resolution by respective Houses of CongressWhen the relevant committee or committees have reported such a resolution (or have been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution pursuant to subsection (a)) or when a resolution has been introduced and placed on the appropriate calendar pursuant to subsection (a), as the case may be, it is at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for any Member of the respective House to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution. The motion is highly privileged and is not debatable. The motion shall not be subject to amendment, or to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee consideration of Presidential submissions; reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Committee consideration of Presidential submissions; reports Not later than forty-five days of continuous session of Congress after the date of transmittal to the Congress of any submission of the President required by section 2155(a)(2), 2155(b)(2), 2157(b), 2158, 2160(a)(3), or 2160(f)(1)(A) of this title, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives shall each submit a report to its respective House on its views and recommendations respecting such Presidential submission together with a resolution, as defined in subsection (f), stating in substance that the Congress approves or disapproves such submission, as the case may be: Provided, That if any such committee has not reported such a resolution at the end of such forty-five day period, such committee shall be deemed to be discharged from further consideration of such submission. If no such resolution has been reported at the end of such period, the first </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of resolution by respective Houses of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consideration of resolution by respective Houses of Congress When the relevant committee or committees have reported such a resolution (or have been discharged from further consideration of such a resolution pursuant to subsection (a)) or when a resolution has been introduced and placed on the appropriate calendar pursuant to subsection (a), as the case may be, it is at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for any Member of the respective House to move to proceed to the consideration of the resolution. The motion is highly privileged and is not debatable. The motion shall not be subject to amendment, or to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is agreed to, the resolution shall remain the unfinished busine</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Debate Debate on the resolution, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than ten hours, which shall be divided equally between individuals favoring and individuals opposing the resolution. A motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to a motion to postpone, or a motion to recommit the resolution, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business is not in order. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the resolution is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. No amendment to any concurrent resolution pursuant to the procedures of this section is in order except as provided in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vote on final approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Vote on final approval Immediately following (1) the conclusion of the debate on such concurrent resolution, (2) a single quorum call at the conclusion of debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the appropriate House, and (3) the consideration of an amendment introduced by the Majority Leader or his designee to insert the phrase, “does not” in lieu of the word “does” if the resolution under consideration is a concurrent resolution of approval, the vote on final approval of the resolution shall occur.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appeals from decisions of Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Appeals from decisions of Chair Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate or the House of Representatives, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to such a resolution shall be decided without debate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Resolution For the purposes of subsections (a) through (e) of this section, the term “resolution” means a concurrent resolution of the Congress, the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: “That the Congress (does or does not) favor the        transmitted to the Congress by the President on    ,        .”, the blank spaces therein to be appropriately filled, and the affirmative or negative phrase within the parenthetical to be appropriately selected.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuity of Congressional sessions; computation of time</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Continuity of Congressional sessions; computation of time</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supersedure or change in rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Supersedure or change in rules This section is enacted by Congress—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2159_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint resolutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Joint resolutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>