<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2160d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2160d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2160d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2160d"><akn:num>2160d</akn:num><akn:heading>Further restrictions on exports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2160d. Further restrictions on exports(a) In generalExcept as provided in subsection (b), the Commission may issue a license for the export of highly enriched uranium to be used as a fuel or target in a nuclear research or test reactor only if, in addition to any other requirement of this chapter, the Commission determines that—(1) there is no alternative nuclear reactor fuel or target enriched in the isotope 235 to a lesser percent than the proposed export, that can be used in that reactor;

(2) the proposed recipient of that uranium has provided assurances that, whenever an alternative nuclear reactor fuel or target can be used in that reactor, it will use that alternative in lieu of highly enriched uranium; and

(3) the United States Government is actively developing an alternative nuclear reactor fuel or target that can be used in that reactor.


(b) Medical isotope production(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Highly enriched uraniumThe term “highly enriched uranium” means uranium enriched to include concentration of U–235 above 20 percent.


(B) Medical isotopeThe term “medical isotope” includes Molybdenum 99, Iodine 131, Xenon 133, and other radioactive materials used to produce a radiopharmaceutical for diagnostic, therapeutic procedures or for research and development.


(C) RadiopharmaceuticalThe term “radiopharmaceutical” means a radioactive isotope that—(i) contains byproduct material combined with chemical or biological material; and

(ii) is designed to accumulate temporarily in a part of the body for therapeutic purposes or for enabling the production of a useful image for use in a diagnosis of a medical condition.


(D) Recipient countryThe term “recipient country” means Canada, Belgium, France, Germany, and the Netherlands.



(2) LicensesThe Commission may issue a license authorizing the export (including shipment to and use at intermediate and ultimate consignees specified in the license) to a recipient country of highly enriched uranium for m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in subsection (b), the Commission may issue a license for the export of highly enriched uranium to be used as a fuel or target in a nuclear research or test reactor only if, in addition to any other requirement of this chapter, the Commission determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical isotope production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Medical isotope production</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical production license sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Medical production license sunset Effective 7 years after January 2, 2013, the Commission may not issue a license for the export of highly enriched uranium from the United States for the purposes of medical isotope production.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical production license extension</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Medical production license extension The period referred to in subsection (c) may be extended for no more than 6 years if, no earlier than 6 years after January 2, 2013, the Secretary of Energy certifies to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public notice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Public notice To ensure public review and comment, the development of the certification described in subsection (d) shall be carried out through announcement in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Joint certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension of medical production license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Suspension of medical production license At any time after the restriction of export licenses provided for in subsection (c) becomes effective, if there is a critical shortage in the supply of molybdenum-99 available to satisfy the domestic United States medical isotope needs, the restriction of export licenses may be suspended for a period of no more than 12 months, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2160d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions As used in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>