<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/217" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/217/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/217/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_217"><akn:num>217</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Service in time of war or emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 217. Use of Service in time of war or emergency
In time of war, or of emergency proclaimed by the President, he may utilize the Service to such extent and in such manner as shall in his judgment promote the public interest. In time of war, or of emergency involving the national defense proclaimed by the President, he may by Executive order declare the commissioned corps of the Service to be a military service. Upon such declaration, and during the period of such war or such emergency or such part thereof as the President shall prescribe, the commissioned corps (a) shall constitute a branch of the land and naval forces of the United States, (b) shall, to the extent prescribed by regulations of the President, be subject to the Uniform Code of Military Justice [10 U.S.C. 801 et seq.], and (c) shall continue to operate as part of the Service except to the extent that the President may direct as Commander in Chief.
(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title II, § 216, 58 Stat. 690; Apr. 27, 1956, ch. 211, § 1, 70 Stat. 116.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Uniform Code of Military Justice, referred to in text, is classified to chapter 47 (§ 801 et seq.) of Title 10, Armed Forces.

Amendments1956—Act Apr. 27, 1956, empowered President to declare commissioned corps of the Service to be a military service in time of emergency involving national defense, and substituted “the Uniform Code of Military Justice” for “the Articles of War and to the Articles for the Government of the Navy”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Secretary of Health and Human Services” substituted for “Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare” pursuant to section 509(b) of Pub. L. 96–88, which is classified to section 3508(b) of Title 20, Education.

Repeal of Prior Acts Continuing SectionSection 6 of Joint Res. July 3, 1952, ch. 570, 66 Stat. 334, repealed Joint Res. Apr. 14, 1952, ch. 204, 66 Stat. 54 as amended by Joint Res. May 28, 1952, ch. 339, 66 Stat. 96; Joint Res. June</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>