<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2201b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2201b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2201b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2201b"><akn:num>2201b</akn:num><akn:heading>Commission workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2201b. Commission workforce(a) Direct hire authority(1) In generalNotwithstanding section 2201(d) of this title and any provision of Reorganization Plan No. 1 of 1980 (94 Stat. 3585; 5 U.S.C. app.),11 So in original. Probably should be capitalized. and without regard to any provision of title 5 (except section 3328) governing appointments in the civil service, the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the “Chairman”) may, in order to carry out the Nuclear Regulatory Commission’s (in this section referred to as the “Commission”) responsibilities and activities in a timely, efficient, and effective manner and subject to the limitations described in paragraphs (2), (3), and (4)—(A) recruit and directly appoint exceptionally well-qualified individuals into the excepted service for covered positions; and

(B) establish in the excepted service term-limited covered positions and recruit and directly appoint exceptionally well-qualified individuals into such term-limited covered positions, which may not exceed a term of 4 years.


(2) Limitations(A) Number(i) In generalThe number of exceptionally well-qualified individuals serving in covered positions pursuant to paragraph (1)(A) may not exceed 210 at any one time.


(ii) Term-limited covered positionsThe Chairman may not appoint more than 20 exceptionally well-qualified individuals into term-limited covered positions pursuant to paragraph (1)(B) during any fiscal year.



(B) Compensation(i) Annual rateThe annual basic rate of pay for any individual appointed under paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B) may not exceed the annual basic rate of pay for level III of the Executive Schedule under section 5314 of title 5.


(ii) Experience and qualificationsAny individual recruited and directly appointed into a covered position or a term-limited covered position shall be compensated at a rate of pay that is commensurate with such individual’s experience and qualifications.



(C) Senior ex</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Direct hire authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Direct hire authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Addressing insufficient compensation of employees and other personnel of the Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Addressing insufficient compensation of employees and other personnel of the Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional compensation authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Additional compensation authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation plan and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Delegation The Chairman shall delegate, subject to the direction and supervision of the Chairman, the authority provided by subsections (a), (b), and (c) to the Executive Director for Operations of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information on hiring, vacancies, and compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information on hiring, vacancies, and compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered position</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Covered position In this section, the term “covered position” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2201b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Sunset</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>