<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2210"><akn:num>2210</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification and limitation of liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2210. Indemnification and limitation of liability(a) Requirement of financial protection for licenseesEach license issued under section 2133 or 2134 of this title and each construction permit issued under section 2235 of this title shall, and each license issued under section 2073, 2093, or 2111 of this title may, for the public purposes cited in section 2012(i) of this title, have as a condition of the license a requirement that the licensee have and maintain financial protection of such type and in such amounts as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”) in the exercise of its licensing and regulatory authority and responsibility shall require in accordance with subsection (b) to cover public liability claims. Whenever such financial protection is required, it may be a further condition of the license that the licensee execute and maintain an indemnification agreement in accordance with subsection (c). The Commission may require, as a further condition of issuing a license, that an applicant waive any immunity from public liability conferred by Federal or State law.


(b) Amount and type of financial protection for licensees(1) The amount of primary financial protection required shall be the amount of liability insurance available from private sources, except that the Commission may establish a lesser amount on the basis of criteria set forth in writing, which it may revise from time to time, taking into consideration such factors as the following: (A) the cost and terms of private insurance, (B) the type, size, and location of the licensed activity and other factors pertaining to the hazard, and (C) the nature and purpose of the licensed activity: Provided, That for facilities designed for producing substantial amounts of electricity and having a rated capacity of 100,000 electrical kilowatts or more, the amount of primary financial protection required shall be the maximum amount available at reasonable cost and on rea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of financial protection for licensees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of financial protection for licensees Each license issued under section 2133 or 2134 of this title and each construction permit issued under section 2235 of this title shall, and each license issued under section 2073, 2093, or 2111 of this title may, for the public purposes cited in section 2012(i) of this title, have as a condition of the license a requirement that the licensee have and maintain financial protection of such type and in such amounts as the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”) in the exercise of its licensing and regulatory authority and responsibility shall require in accordance with subsection (b) to cover public liability claims. Whenever such financial protection is required, it may be a further condition of the license that the licensee execute and maintain an indemnification agreement in accordance with subsection (c). The Commission may require, as a further condition of issuing a license, that an applic</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount and type of financial protection for licensees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount and type of financial protection for licensees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification of licensees by Nuclear Regulatory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indemnification of licensees by Nuclear Regulatory Commission The Commission shall, with respect to licenses issued between August 30, 1954, and December 31, 2065, for which it requires financial protection of less than $560,000,000, agree to indemnify and hold harmless the licensee and other persons indemnified, as their interest may appear, from public liability arising from nuclear incidents which is in excess of the level of financial protection required of the licensee. The aggregate indemnity for all persons indemnified in connection with each nuclear incident shall not exceed $500,000,000 excluding costs of investigating and settling claims and defending suits for damage: Provided, however, That this amount of indemnity shall be reduced by the amount that the financial protection required shall exceed $60,000,000. Such a contract of indemnification shall cover public liability arising out of or in connection with the licensed activity. With respect to any production or utili</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification of contractors by Department of Energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Indemnification of contractors by Department of Energy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on aggregate public liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on aggregate public liability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of fees by Nuclear Regulatory Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Collection of fees by Nuclear Regulatory Commission The Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, is authorized to collect a fee from all persons with whom an indemnification agreement is executed under this section. This fee shall be $30 per year per thousand kilowatts of thermal energy capacity for facilities licensed under section 2133 of this title: Provided, That the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, is authorized to reduce the fee for such facilities in reasonable relation to increases in financial protection required above a level of $60,000,000. For facilities licensed under section 2134 of this title, and for construction permits under section 2235 of this title, the Commission is authorized to reduce the fee set forth above. The Commission shall establish criteria in writing for determination of the fee for facilities licensed under section 2134 of this title, taking into consideration such factors as (1) the type, size, and location of facility involved, an</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of services of private insurers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of services of private insurers In administering the provisions of this section, the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, shall use, to the maximum extent practicable, the facilities and services of private insurance organizations, and the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, may contract to pay a reasonable compensation for such services. Any contract made under the provisions of this subsection may be made without regard to the provisions of section 6101 of title 41 upon a showing by the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, that advertising is not reasonably practicable and advance payments may be made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions of agreements of indemnification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Conditions of agreements of indemnification The agreement of indemnification may contain such terms as the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, deems appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. Such agreement shall provide that, when the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, makes a determination that the United States will probably be required to make indemnity payments under this section, the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, shall collaborate with any person indemnified and may approve the payment of any claim under the agreement of indemnification, appear through the Attorney General on behalf of the person indemnified, take charge of such action, and settle or defend any such action. The Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, shall have final authority on behalf of the United States to settle or approve the settlement of any such claim on a fair and reasonable basis with due regard for the purposes of this chapter. Such settlement sha</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Compensation plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts in advance of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Contracts in advance of appropriations In administering the provisions of this section, the Commission or the Secretary, as appropriate, may make contracts in advance of appropriations and incur obligations without regard to sections 1341, 1342, 1349, 1350, and 1351, and subchapter II of chapter 15, of title 31.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>