<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2210b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2210b"><akn:num>2210b</akn:num><akn:heading>Uranium supply</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2210b. Uranium supply(a) Assessment of domestic uranium industry viability; monitoring and reporting requirements; criteria; implementation by rules and regulationsThe Secretary of Energy shall monitor and for the years 1983 to 1992 report annually to the Congress and to the President a determination of the viability of the domestic uranium mining and milling industry and shall establish by rule, after public notice and in accordance with the requirements of section 2231 of this title, within 9 months of January 4, 1983, specific criteria which shall be assessed in the annual reports on the domestic uranium industry’s viability. The Secretary of Energy is authorized to issue regulations providing for the collection of such information as the Secretary of Energy deems necessary to carry out the monitoring and reporting requirements of this section.


(b) Disclosure of informationUpon a satisfactory showing to the Secretary of Energy by any person that any information, or portion thereof obtained under this section, would, if made public, divulge proprietary information of such person, the Secretary shall not disclose such information and disclosure thereof shall be punishable under section 1905 of title 18.


(c) Criteria for monitoring and reporting requirementsThe criteria referred to in subsection (a) shall also include, but not be limited to—(1) an assessment of whether executed contracts or options for source material or special nuclear material will result in greater than 37½ percent of actual or projected domestic uranium requirements for any two-consecutive-year period being supplied by source material or special nuclear material from foreign sources;

(2) projections of uranium requirements and inventories of domestic utilities for a 10 year period;

(3) present and probable future use of the domestic market by foreign imports;

(4) whether domestic economic reserves can supply all future needs for a future 10 year period;

(5) present and projected domest</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of domestic uranium industry viability; monitoring and reporting requirements; criteria; implementation by rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessment of domestic uranium industry viability; monitoring and reporting requirements; criteria; implementation by rules and regulations The Secretary of Energy shall monitor and for the years 1983 to 1992 report annually to the Congress and to the President a determination of the viability of the domestic uranium mining and milling industry and shall establish by rule, after public notice and in accordance with the requirements of section 2231 of this title, within 9 months of January 4, 1983, specific criteria which shall be assessed in the annual reports on the domestic uranium industry’s viability. The Secretary of Energy is authorized to issue regulations providing for the collection of such information as the Secretary of Energy deems necessary to carry out the monitoring and reporting requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure of information Upon a satisfactory showing to the Secretary of Energy by any person that any information, or portion thereof obtained under this section, would, if made public, divulge proprietary information of such person, the Secretary shall not disclose such information and disclosure thereof shall be punishable under section 1905 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for monitoring and reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for monitoring and reporting requirements The criteria referred to in subsection (a) shall also include, but not be limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excessive imports; investigation by United States International Trade Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Excessive imports; investigation by United States International Trade Commission The Secretary or 11 So in original. Probably should be “of”. Energy, at any time, may determine on the basis of the monitoring and annual reports required under this section that source material or special nuclear material from foreign sources is being imported in such increased quantities as to be a substantial cause of serious injury, or threat thereof, to the United States uranium mining and milling industry. Based on that determination, the United States Trade Representative shall request that the United States International Trade Commission initiate an investigation under section 2251 22 See References in Text note below. of title 19.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2210b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Excessive imports for contracts or options as threatening national security; investigation by Secretary of Commerce; recommendation for further investigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Excessive imports for contracts or options as threatening national security; investigation by Secretary of Commerce; recommendation for further investigation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>