<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2215" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2215/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2215/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2215"><akn:num>2215</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear Regulatory Commission user fees and annual charges for fiscal year 2021 and each fiscal year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2215. Nuclear Regulatory Commission user fees and annual charges for fiscal year 2021 and each fiscal year thereafter(a) Annual budget justification(1) In generalIn the annual budget justification submitted by the Commission to Congress, the Commission shall expressly identify anticipated expenditures necessary for completion of the requested activities of the Commission anticipated to occur during the applicable fiscal year.


(2) RestrictionBudget authority granted to the Commission for purposes of the requested activities of the Commission shall be used, to the maximum extent practicable, solely for conducting requested activities of the Commission.


(3) Limitation on corporate support costsWith respect to the annual budget justification submitted to Congress, corporate support costs, to the maximum extent practicable, shall not exceed the following percentages of the total budget authority of the Commission requested in the annual budget justification:(A) 30 percent for each of fiscal years 2021 and 2022.

(B) 30 percent for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter.


(4) International nuclear export and innovation activitiesThe Commission shall identify in the annual budget justification international nuclear export and innovation activities described in section 2155b(a) of this title.



(b) Fees and charges(1) Annual assessment(A) In generalEach fiscal year, the Commission shall assess and collect fees and charges in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) in a manner that ensures that, to the maximum extent practicable, the amount assessed and collected is equal to an amount that approximates—(i) the total budget authority of the Commission for that fiscal year; less

(ii) the budget authority of the Commission for the activities described in subparagraph (B).


(B) Excluded activities describedThe activities referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) are the following:(i) Any fee relief activity, as identified by the Commission.

(ii) Amounts appropriate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual budget justification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual budget justification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fees and charges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance and reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Performance and reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accurate invoicing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Accurate invoicing With respect to invoices for fees described in subsection (b)(2), the Commission shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report Not later than September 30, 2021, the Commission shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing the implementation of this section, including any impacts and recommendations for improvement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effective date Except as provided in subsection (c), this section takes effect on October 1, 2020.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2215_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cessation of effectiveness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cessation of effectiveness Paragraphs (1)(B)(vi) and (2)(C) of subsection (b) shall cease to be effective on September 30, 2030.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>