<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2221" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2221/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2221/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2221"><akn:num>2221</akn:num><akn:heading>Just compensation for requisitioned property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2221. Just compensation for requisitioned property
The United States shall make just compensation for any property or interests therein taken or requisitioned pursuant to sections 2063, 2075, 2096, and 2138 of this title. Except in case of real property or any interest therein, the Commission shall determine and pay such just compensation. If the compensation so determined is unsatisfactory to the person entitled thereto, such person shall be paid 75 per centum of the amount so determined, and shall be entitled to sue the United States in the United States Court of Federal Claims or in any district court of the United States for the district in which such claimant is a resident in the manner provided by section 1346 of title 28 to recover such further sum as added to said 75 per centum will constitute just compensation.
(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 171, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 952; amended Pub. L. 88–489, § 17, Aug. 26, 1964, 78 Stat. 606; Pub. L. 97–164, title I, § 160(a)(16), Apr. 2, 1982, 96 Stat. 48; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944; Pub. L. 102–572, title IX, § 902(b)(1), Oct. 29, 1992, 106 Stat. 4516.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsProvisions similar to this section were contained in section 1813(a) of this title, prior to the general amendment and renumbering of act Aug. 1, 1946, by act Aug. 30, 1954.

Amendments1992—Pub. L. 102–572 substituted “United States Court of Federal Claims” for “United States Claims Court”.
1982—Pub. L. 97–164 substituted “United States Claims Court” for “Court of Claims”.
1964—Pub. L. 88–489 substituted “2075” for “2072 (with respect to the material for which the United States is required to pay just compensation),”.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1992 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 102–572 effective Oct. 29, 1992, see section 911 of Pub. L. 102–572, set out as a note under section 171 of Title 28, Judiciary and J</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>