<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2231" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2231/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2231/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2231"><akn:num>2231</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of administrative procedure provisions; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2231. Applicability of administrative procedure provisions; definitions(a) In generalThe provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5 shall apply to all agency action taken under this chapter, and the terms “agency” and “agency action” shall have the meaning specified in section 551 of title 5: Provided, however, That in the case of agency proceedings or actions which involve Restricted Data, defense information, safeguards information protected from disclosure under the authority of section 2167 of this title or information protected from dissemination under the authority of section 2168 of this title, the Commission shall provide by regulation for such parallel procedures as will effectively safeguard and prevent disclosure of Restricted Data, defense information, such safeguards information, or information protected from dissemination under the authority of section 2168 of this title to unauthorized persons with minimum impairment of the procedural rights which would be available if Restricted Data, defense information, such safeguards information, or information protected from dissemination under the authority of section 2168 of this title were not involved.


(b) Efficient licensing reviewsThe Commission shall provide for efficient and timely reviews and proceedings for the granting, suspending, revoking, or amending of any—(1) license or construction permit; or

(2) application to transfer control.


(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 181, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 953; amended Pub. L. 96–295, title II, § 207(b), June 30, 1980, 94 Stat. 789; Pub. L. 97–90, title II, § 210(b), Dec. 4, 1981, 95 Stat. 1170; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944; Pub. L. 118–67, div. B, title V, § 505(b), July 9, 2024, 138 Stat. 1478.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, as ad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5, and chapter 7, of title 5 shall apply to all agency action taken under this chapter, and the terms “agency” and “agency action” shall have the meaning specified in section 551 of title 5: Provided, however, That in the case of agency proceedings or actions which involve Restricted Data, defense information, safeguards information protected from disclosure under the authority of section 2167 of this title or information protected from dissemination under the authority of section 2168 of this title, the Commission shall provide by regulation for such parallel procedures as will effectively safeguard and prevent disclosure of Restricted Data, defense information, such safeguards information, or information protected from dissemination under the authority of section 2168 of this title to unauthorized persons with minimum impairment of the procedural rights which would be available if Restricted Data, defense information, such saf</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2231_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Efficient licensing reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Efficient licensing reviews The Commission shall provide for efficient and timely reviews and proceedings for the granting, suspending, revoking, or amending of any—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>