<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2236" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2236/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2236/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2236"><akn:num>2236</akn:num><akn:heading>Revocation of licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2236. Revocation of licenses(a) False applications; failure of performanceAny license may be revoked for any material false statement in the application or any statement of fact required under section 2232 of this title, or because of conditions revealed by such application or statement of fact or any report, record, or inspection or other means which would warrant the Commission to refuse to grant a license on an original application, or for failure to construct or operate a facility in accordance with the terms of the construction permit or license or the technical specifications in the application, or for violation of, or failure to observe any of the terms and provisions of this chapter or of any regulation of the Commission.


(b) ProcedureThe Commission shall follow the provisions of section 558(c) of title 5 in revoking any license.


(c) Repossession of materialUpon revocation of the license, the Commission may immediately retake possession of all special nuclear material held by the licensee. In cases found by the Commission to be of extreme importance to the national defense and security or to the health and safety of the public, the Commission may recapture any special nuclear material held by the licensee or may enter upon and operate the facility prior to any of the procedures provided under subchapter II of chapter 5 and chapter 7 of title 5. Just compensation shall be paid for the use of the facility.


(Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, title I, § 186, as added Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 955; renumbered title I, Pub. L. 102–486, title IX, § 902(a)(8), Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 2944.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (a), was in the original “this Act”, meaning act Aug. 1, 1946, ch. 724, as added by act Aug. 30, 1954, ch. 1073, § 1, 68 Stat. 919, known as the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2236_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>False applications; failure of performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) False applications; failure of performance Any license may be revoked for any material false statement in the application or any statement of fact required under section 2232 of this title, or because of conditions revealed by such application or statement of fact or any report, record, or inspection or other means which would warrant the Commission to refuse to grant a license on an original application, or for failure to construct or operate a facility in accordance with the terms of the construction permit or license or the technical specifications in the application, or for violation of, or failure to observe any of the terms and provisions of this chapter or of any regulation of the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2236_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure The Commission shall follow the provisions of section 558(c) of title 5 in revoking any license.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2236_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repossession of material</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repossession of material Upon revocation of the license, the Commission may immediately retake possession of all special nuclear material held by the licensee. In cases found by the Commission to be of extreme importance to the national defense and security or to the health and safety of the public, the Commission may recapture any special nuclear material held by the licensee or may enter upon and operate the facility prior to any of the procedures provided under subchapter II of chapter 5 and chapter 7 of title 5. Just compensation shall be paid for the use of the facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>