<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2242" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2242/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2242/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2242"><akn:num>2242</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary operating license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2242. Temporary operating license(a) Fuel loading, testing, and operation at specific power level; petition, affidavit, etc.In any proceeding upon an application for an operating license for a utilization facility required to be licensed under section 2133 or 2134(b) of this title, in which a hearing is otherwise required pursuant to section 2239(a) of this title, the applicant may petition the Commission for a temporary operating license for such facility authorizing fuel loading, testing, and operation at a specific power level to be determined by the Commission, pending final action by the Commission on the application. The initial petition for a temporary operating license for each such facility, and any temporary operating license issued for such facility based upon the initial petition, shall be limited to power levels not to exceed 5 percent of rated full thermal power. Following issuance by the Commission of the temporary operating license for each such facility, the licensee may file petitions with the Commission to amend the license to allow facility operation in staged increases at specific power levels, to be determined by the Commission, exceeding 5 percent of rated full thermal power. The initial petition for a temporary operating license for each such facility may be filed at any time after the filing of: (1) the report of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards required by section 2232(b) of this title; (2) the filing of the initial Safety Evaluation Report by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission staff and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission staff’s first supplement to the report prepared in response to the report of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards for the facility; (3) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission staff’s final detailed statement on the environmental impact of the facility prepared pursuant to section 4332(2)(C) of this title; and (4) a State, local, or utility emergency preparedness plan for the facility. Petitions for the issua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fuel loading, testing, and operation at specific power level; petition, affidavit, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Fuel loading, testing, and operation at specific power level; petition, affidavit, etc. In any proceeding upon an application for an operating license for a utilization facility required to be licensed under section 2133 or 2134(b) of this title, in which a hearing is otherwise required pursuant to section 2239(a) of this title, the applicant may petition the Commission for a temporary operating license for such facility authorizing fuel loading, testing, and operation at a specific power level to be determined by the Commission, pending final action by the Commission on the application. The initial petition for a temporary operating license for each such facility, and any temporary operating license issued for such facility based upon the initial petition, shall be limited to power levels not to exceed 5 percent of rated full thermal power. Following issuance by the Commission of the temporary operating license for each such facility, the licensee may file petitions with the Commi</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Operation at greater power level; criteria, effect, terms and conditions, etc.; procedures applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Operation at greater power level; criteria, effect, terms and conditions, etc.; procedures applicable With respect to any petition filed pursuant to subsection (a) of this section, the Commission may issue a temporary operating license, or amend the license to authorize temporary operation at each specific power level greater than that authorized in the initial temporary operating license, as determined by the Commission, upon finding that— The temporary operating license shall become effective upon issuance and shall contain such terms and conditions as the Commission may deem necessary, including the duration of the license and any provision for the extension thereof. Any final order authorizing the issuance or amendment of any temporary operating license pursuant to this section shall recite with specificity the facts and reasons justifying the findings under this subsection, and shall be transmitted upon such issuance to the Committees on Natural Resources and on Energy and Com</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing for final operating license; suspension, issuance, compliance, etc., with temporary operating license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hearing for final operating license; suspension, issuance, compliance, etc., with temporary operating license Any hearing on the application for the final operating license for a facility required pursuant to section 2239(a) of this title shall be concluded as promptly as practicable. The Commission shall suspend the temporary operating license if it finds that the applicant is not prosecuting the application for the final operating license with due diligence. Issuance of a temporary operating license under subsection (b) of this section shall be without prejudice to the right of any party to raise any issue in a hearing required pursuant to section 2239(a) of this title; and failure to assert any ground for denial or limitation of a temporary operating license shall not bar the assertion of such ground in connection with the issuance of a subsequent final operating license. Any party to a hearing required pursuant to section 2239(a) of this title on the final operating license for</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative remedies for minimization of need for license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative remedies for minimization of need for license The Commission is authorized and directed to adopt such administrative remedies as the Commission deems appropriate to minimize the need for issuance of temporary operating licenses pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2242_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expiration of issuing authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Expiration of issuing authority The authority to issue new temporary operating licenses under this section shall expire on December 31, 1983.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>