<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2243"><akn:num>2243</akn:num><akn:heading>Licensing of uranium enrichment facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2243. Licensing of uranium enrichment facilities(a) Environmental impact statement(1) Major Federal actionThe issuance of a license under sections 2073 and 2093 of this title for the construction and operation of any uranium enrichment facility shall be considered a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for purposes of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(2) TimingAn environmental impact statement prepared under paragraph (1) shall be prepared before the hearing on the issuance of a license for the construction and operation of a uranium enrichment facility is completed.



(b) Adjudicatory hearing(1) In generalThe Commission shall conduct a single adjudicatory hearing on the record with regard to the licensing of the construction and operation of a uranium enrichment facility under sections 2073 and 2093 of this title.


(2) TimingSuch hearing shall be completed and a decision issued before the issuance of a license for such construction and operation.


(3) Single proceedingNo further Commission licensing action shall be required to authorize operation.



(c) Inspection and operationPrior to commencement of operation of a uranium enrichment facility licensed hereunder, the Commission shall verify through inspection that the facility has been constructed in accordance with the requirements of the license for construction and operation. The Commission shall publish notice of the inspection results in the Federal Register.


(d) Insurance and decommissioning(1) The Commission shall require, as a condition of the issuance of a license under sections 2073 and 2093 of this title for a uranium enrichment facility, that the licensee have and maintain liability insurance of such type and in such amounts as the Commission judges appropriate to cover liability claims arising out of any occurrence within the United States, causing, within or outside the United States, bodily injury, sickness,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Environmental impact statement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjudicatory hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Adjudicatory hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection and operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inspection and operation Prior to commencement of operation of a uranium enrichment facility licensed hereunder, the Commission shall verify through inspection that the facility has been constructed in accordance with the requirements of the license for construction and operation. The Commission shall publish notice of the inspection results in the Federal Register.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance and decommissioning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Insurance and decommissioning</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No Price-Anderson coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No Price-Anderson coverage Section 2210 of this title shall not apply to any license under section 2073 or 2093 of this title for a uranium enrichment facility constructed after November 15, 1990.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2243_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation No license or certificate of compliance may be issued to the United States Enrichment Corporation or its successor under this section or sections 11 So in original. Probably should be “section”. 2073, 2093, or 2297f of this title, if the Commission determines that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>