<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2284" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2284/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2284/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2284"><akn:num>2284</akn:num><akn:heading>Sabotage of nuclear facilities or fuel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2284. Sabotage of nuclear facilities or fuel(a) Physical damage to facilities, etc.Any person who knowingly destroys or causes physical damage to—(1) any production facility or utilization facility licensed under this chapter;

(2) any nuclear waste treatment, storage, or disposal facility licensed under this chapter;

(3) any nuclear fuel for a utilization facility licensed under this chapter, or any spent nuclear fuel from such a facility;

(4) any uranium enrichment, uranium conversion, or nuclear fuel fabrication facility licensed or certified by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission;

(5) any production, utilization, waste storage, waste treatment, waste disposal, uranium enrichment, uranium conversion, or nuclear fuel fabrication facility subject to licensing or certification under this chapter during construction of the facility, if the destruction or damage caused or attempted to be caused could adversely affect public health and safety during the operation of the facility;

(6) any primary facility or backup facility from which a radiological emergency preparedness alert and warning system is activated; or

(7) any radioactive material or other property subject to regulation by the Commission that, before the date of the offense, the Commission determines, by order or regulation published in the Federal Register, is of significance to the public health and safety or to common defense and security; 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a comma.


or attempts or conspires to do such an act, shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both, and, if death results to any person, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.

(b) Unauthorized use or tampering with facilities, etc.Any person who knowingly causes an interruption of normal operation of any such facility through the unauthorized use of or tampering with the machinery, components, or controls of any such facility, or attempts or conspires to d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2284_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Physical damage to facilities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Physical damage to facilities, etc. Any person who knowingly destroys or causes physical damage to— or attempts or conspires to do such an act, shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both, and, if death results to any person, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2284_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unauthorized use or tampering with facilities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Unauthorized use or tampering with facilities, etc. Any person who knowingly causes an interruption of normal operation of any such facility through the unauthorized use of or tampering with the machinery, components, or controls of any such facility, or attempts or conspires to do such an act, shall be fined not more than $10,000 or imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both, and, if death results to any person, shall be imprisoned for any term of years or for life.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>