<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2286d"><akn:num>2286d</akn:num><akn:heading>Board recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2286d. Board recommendations(a) Submission of recommendations(1) Subject to subsections (h) and (i), not later than 30 days before the date on which the Board transmits a recommendation to the Secretary of Energy under section 2286a of this title, the Board shall transmit to the Secretary in writing a draft of such recommendation and any related findings, supporting data, and analyses to ensure the Secretary is adequately informed of a formal recommendation and to provide the Secretary an opportunity to provide input to the Board before such recommendation is finalized.

(2) The Secretary may provide to the Board comments on a draft recommendation transmitted by the Board under paragraph (1) by not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the draft recommendation. The Board may grant, upon request by the Secretary, additional time for the Secretary to transmit comments to the Board.

(3) After the period of time in which the Secretary may provide comments under paragraph (2) elapses, the Board may transmit a final recommendation to the Secretary.


(b) Public availability and commentSubject to subsections (h) and (i), after the Secretary of Energy receives a recommendation from the Board under subsection (a)(3), the Board shall promptly make available to the public such recommendation and any related correspondence from the Secretary by—(1) providing such recommendation and correspondence to the public in the regional public reading rooms of the Department of Energy; and

(2) publishing in the Federal Register—(A) such recommendation and correspondence; and

(B) a request for the submission to the Board of public comments on such recommendation that provides interested persons with 30 days after the date of the publication in which to submit comments, data, views, or arguments to the Board concerning the recommendation.



(c) Response by Secretary(1) The Secretary of Energy shall transmit to the Board, in writing, a statement on whether t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission of recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public availability and comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public availability and comment Subject to subsections (h) and (i), after the Secretary of Energy receives a recommendation from the Board under subsection (a)(3), the Board shall promptly make available to the public such recommendation and any related correspondence from the Secretary by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Response by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of information to Secretary The Board shall furnish the Secretary of Energy with copies of all comments, data, views, and arguments submitted to it under subsection (b) or (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final decision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Final decision If the Secretary of Energy, in a response under subsection (c)(1), rejects (in whole or part) any recommendation made by the Board under section 2286a of this title, the Board shall either reaffirm its original recommendation or make a revised recommendation and shall notify the Secretary of its action. Within 30 days after receiving the notice of the Board’s action under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider the Board’s action and make a final decision on whether to implement all or part of the Board’s recommendations. Subject to subsection (i), the Secretary shall publish the final decision and the reasoning for such decision in the Federal Register and shall transmit to the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a written report containing that decision and reasoning.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation plan The Secretary of Energy shall prepare a plan for the implementation of each Board recommendation, or part of a recommendation, that is accepted by the Secretary in his final decision. The Secretary shall transmit the implementation plan to the Board within 90 days after the date of the publication of the Secretary’s final decision on such recommendation in the Federal Register. The Secretary may have an additional 45 days to transmit the plan if the Secretary submits to the Board and to the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Armed Services, Appropriations, and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a notification setting forth the reasons for the delay and describing the actions the Secretary is taking to prepare an implementation plan under this subsection. The Secretary may implement any such recommendation (or part of any such recommendation) before, on, or after the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Imminent or severe threat</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Imminent or severe threat</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitation Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the requirements to make information available to the public under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>