<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2286b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2286b"><akn:num>2286b</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2286b. Powers of Board(a) Hearings(1) The Board or a member authorized by the Board may, for the purpose of carrying out this subchapter, hold such hearings and sit and act at such times and places, and require, by subpoena or otherwise, the attendance and testimony of such witnesses and the production of such evidence as the Board or an authorized member may find advisable.

(2)(A) Subpoenas may be issued only under the signature of the Chairperson or any member of the Board designated by him and shall be served by any person designated by the Chairperson, any member, or any person as otherwise provided by law. The attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence may be required from any place in the United States at any designated place of hearing in the United States.

(B) Any member of the Board may administer oaths or affirmations to witnesses appearing before the Board.

(C) If a person issued a subpoena under paragraph (1) refuses to obey such subpoena or is guilty of contumacy, any court of the United States within the judicial district within which the hearing is conducted or within the judicial district within which such person is found or resides or transacts business may (upon application by the Board) order such person to appear before the Board to produce evidence or to give testimony relating to the matter under investigation. Any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt of the court.

(D) The subpoenas of the Board shall be served in the manner provided for subpoenas issued by a United States district court under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for the United States district courts.

(E) All process of any court to which application may be made under this section may be served in the judicial district in which the person required to be served resides or may be found.



(b) Staff(1) The Board may, for the purpose of performing its responsibilities under this subchapter—(A) in accordance with sec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Hearings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Staff</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Regulations The Board may prescribe regulations to carry out the responsibilities of the Board under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting requirements The Board may establish reporting requirements for the Secretary of Energy which shall be binding upon the Secretary. The information which the Board may require the Secretary of Energy to report under this subsection may include any information designated as classified information, or any information designated as safeguards information and protected from disclosure under section 2167 or 2168 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Government facilities, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of Government facilities, etc. The Board may, for the purpose of carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter, use any facility, contractor, or employee of any other department or agency of the Federal Government with the consent of and under appropriate support arrangements with the head of such department or agency and, in the case of a contractor, with the consent of the contractor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance from certain agencies of Federal Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assistance from certain agencies of Federal Government With the consent of and under appropriate support arrangements with the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Board may obtain the advice and recommendations of the staff of the Commission on matters relating to the Board’s responsibilities and may obtain the advice and recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards on such matters.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance from organizations outside Federal Government</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance from organizations outside Federal Government Notwithstanding any other provision of law relating to the use of competitive procedures, the Board may enter into an agreement with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences or any other appropriate group or organization of experts outside the Federal Government chosen by the Board to assist the Board in carrying out its responsibilities under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resident inspectors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Resident inspectors The Board may assign staff to be stationed at any Department of Energy defense nuclear facility to carry out the functions of the Board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Special studies The Board may conduct special studies pertaining to adequate protection of public health and safety at any Department of Energy defense nuclear facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2286b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Evaluation of information The Board may evaluate information received from the scientific and industrial communities, and from the interested public, with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>