<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2297h_13"><akn:num>2297h–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of certain laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2297h–13. Application of certain laws(a) OSHA(1) As of the privatization date, the private corporation shall be subject to and comply with the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (29 U.S.C. 651 et seq.).

(2) The Nuclear Regulatory Commission and the Occupational Safety and Health Administration shall, within 90 days after April 26, 1996, enter into a memorandum of agreement to govern the exercise of their authority over occupational safety and health hazards at the gaseous diffusion plants, including inspection, investigation, enforcement, and rulemaking relating to such hazards.


(b) Antitrust lawsFor purposes of the antitrust laws, the performance by the private corporation of a “matched import” contract under the Suspension Agreement shall be considered to have occurred prior to the privatization date, if at the time of privatization, such contract had been agreed to by the parties in all material terms and confirmed by the Secretary of Commerce under the Suspension Agreement.


(c) Energy Reorganization Act requirements(1) The private corporation and its contractors and subcontractors shall be subject to the provisions of section 5851 of this title to the same extent as an employer subject to such section.

(2) With respect to the operation of the facilities leased by the private corporation, section 5846 of this title shall apply to the directors and officers of the private corporation.


(Pub. L. 104–134, title III, § 3115, Apr. 26, 1996, 110 Stat. 1321–348.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), is Pub. L. 91–596, Dec. 29, 1970, 84 Stat. 1590, which is classified principally to chapter 15 (§ 651 et seq.) of Title 29, Labor. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 651 of Title 29 and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the USEC Privatization Act and also as part of the Omnibus Consolidated Rescissions </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>OSHA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) OSHA</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Antitrust laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Antitrust laws For purposes of the antitrust laws, the performance by the private corporation of a “matched import” contract under the Suspension Agreement shall be considered to have occurred prior to the privatization date, if at the time of privatization, such contract had been agreed to by the parties in all material terms and confirmed by the Secretary of Commerce under the Suspension Agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Reorganization Act requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Energy Reorganization Act requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>