<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2297h–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2297h_5"><akn:num>2297h–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing of gaseous diffusion facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2297h–5. Leasing of gaseous diffusion facilities(a) Transfer of leaseConcurrent with privatization, the Corporation shall transfer to the private corporation the lease of the gaseous diffusion plants and related property for the remainder of the term of such lease in accordance with the terms of such lease.


(b) RenewalThe private corporation shall have the exclusive option to lease the gaseous diffusion plants and related property for additional periods following the expiration of the initial term of the lease.


(c) Exclusion of facilities for production of highly enriched uraniumThe Secretary shall not lease to the private corporation any facilities necessary for the production of highly enriched uranium but may, subject to the requirements of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), grant the Corporation access to such facilities for purposes other than the production of highly enriched uranium.


(d) DOE responsibility for preexisting conditionsThe payment of any costs of decontamination and decommissioning, response actions, or corrective actions with respect to conditions existing before July 1, 1993, at the gaseous diffusion plants shall remain the sole responsibility of the Secretary.


(e) Environmental auditFor purposes of subsection (d), the conditions existing before July 1, 1993, at the gaseous diffusion plants shall be determined from the environmental audit conducted pursuant to section 1403(e) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2297c–2(e)).


(f) Treatment under Price-Anderson provisionsAny lease executed between the Secretary and the Corporation or the private corporation, and any extension or renewal thereof, under this section shall be deemed to be a contract for purposes of section 170d. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2210(d)).


(g) Waiver of EIS requirementThe execution or transfer of the lease between the Secretary and the Corporation or the private corporation, and any extension or renewal thereof, sha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of lease Concurrent with privatization, the Corporation shall transfer to the private corporation the lease of the gaseous diffusion plants and related property for the remainder of the term of such lease in accordance with the terms of such lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Renewal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Renewal The private corporation shall have the exclusive option to lease the gaseous diffusion plants and related property for additional periods following the expiration of the initial term of the lease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of facilities for production of highly enriched uranium</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exclusion of facilities for production of highly enriched uranium The Secretary shall not lease to the private corporation any facilities necessary for the production of highly enriched uranium but may, subject to the requirements of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.), grant the Corporation access to such facilities for purposes other than the production of highly enriched uranium.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>DOE responsibility for preexisting conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) DOE responsibility for preexisting conditions The payment of any costs of decontamination and decommissioning, response actions, or corrective actions with respect to conditions existing before July 1, 1993, at the gaseous diffusion plants shall remain the sole responsibility of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental audit For purposes of subsection (d), the conditions existing before July 1, 1993, at the gaseous diffusion plants shall be determined from the environmental audit conducted pursuant to section 1403(e) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2297c–2(e)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment under Price-Anderson provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment under Price-Anderson provisions Any lease executed between the Secretary and the Corporation or the private corporation, and any extension or renewal thereof, under this section shall be deemed to be a contract for purposes of section 170d. of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2210(d)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of EIS requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Waiver of EIS requirement The execution or transfer of the lease between the Secretary and the Corporation or the private corporation, and any extension or renewal thereof, shall not be considered to be a major Federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for purposes of section 4332 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2297h_5_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maintenance of security</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>