<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2311" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2311/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2311/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2311"><akn:num>2311</akn:num><akn:heading>Community Disposal Operations Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2311. Community Disposal Operations Fund(a) EstablishmentThere is established as of June 30, 1956, a Community Disposal Operations Fund, and the Commission (or the head of such agency as may be carrying out the sales and financing functions of the Commission pursuant to a delegation by the President under section 2313 of this title) is authorized to credit said fund with all moneys hereafter obtained or now held by it and to account under said fund for all assets and liabilities held or acquired by it in connection with its sales and financing functions under this chapter, and to make temporary advances to such fund, from any other funds available for expenses of operations of such Commission or agency, as may be required to carry out such functions pending the realization of sufficient proceeds under the provisions of this chapter: Provided, That any such advances shall be repaid to the source appropriation or fund, to the extent of any unobligated balances available in the Community Disposal Operations Fund, prior to the close of the fiscal year during which such advances are made.


(b) AvailabilityThe Community Disposal Operations Fund shall be available to pay for all necessary costs, expenses (including administrative expenses), losses or obligations incurred in connection with the aforesaid functions, including expenses incident to sale, or other transfer and any financing under section 2362 of this title, indemnities under sections 2363 to 2366 of this title, and expenses authorized by section 2310 of this title, and expenses in connection with the defense and payment of any claims for breaches of warranties and covenants of title of any property disposed of pursuant to this chapter.


(c) Liquidating dividendsAny amount in said fund which is determined to be in excess of requirements for the purposes thereof shall be declared and paid as liquidating dividends to the Treasury, not less often than annually.


(Aug. 4, 1955, ch. 543, ch. 11, § 117, 69 Stat. </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2311_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established as of June 30, 1956, a Community Disposal Operations Fund, and the Commission (or the head of such agency as may be carrying out the sales and financing functions of the Commission pursuant to a delegation by the President under section 2313 of this title) is authorized to credit said fund with all moneys hereafter obtained or now held by it and to account under said fund for all assets and liabilities held or acquired by it in connection with its sales and financing functions under this chapter, and to make temporary advances to such fund, from any other funds available for expenses of operations of such Commission or agency, as may be required to carry out such functions pending the realization of sufficient proceeds under the provisions of this chapter: Provided, That any such advances shall be repaid to the source appropriation or fund, to the extent of any unobligated balances available in the Community Disposal Operations Fund, prior to the </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2311_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability The Community Disposal Operations Fund shall be available to pay for all necessary costs, expenses (including administrative expenses), losses or obligations incurred in connection with the aforesaid functions, including expenses incident to sale, or other transfer and any financing under section 2362 of this title, indemnities under sections 2363 to 2366 of this title, and expenses authorized by section 2310 of this title, and expenses in connection with the defense and payment of any claims for breaches of warranties and covenants of title of any property disposed of pursuant to this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2311_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liquidating dividends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Liquidating dividends Any amount in said fund which is determined to be in excess of requirements for the purposes thereof shall be declared and paid as liquidating dividends to the Treasury, not less often than annually.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>