<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_238m"><akn:num>238m</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of fiscal agents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 238m. Use of fiscal agents(a) Contracting authorityThe Secretary may enter into contracts with fiscal agents—(1)(A) to determine the amounts payable to persons who, on behalf of the Indian Health Service, furnish health services to eligible Indians,

(B) to determine the amounts payable to persons who, on behalf of the Public Health Service, furnish health services to individuals pursuant to section 247d or 249 of this title,


(2) to receive, disburse, and account for funds in making payments described in paragraph (1),

(3) to make such audits of records as may be necessary to assure that these payments are proper, and

(4) to perform such additional functions as may be necessary to carry out the functions described in paragraphs (1) through (3).


(b) Contracting prerequisites(1) Contracts under subsection (a) may be entered into without regard to section 6101 of title 41 or any other provision of law requiring competition.

(2) No such contract shall be entered into with an entity unless the Secretary finds that the entity will perform its obligations under the contract efficiently and effectively and will meet such requirements as to financial responsibility, legal authority, and other matters as he finds pertinent.


(c) Advances under contractsA contract under subsection (a) may provide for advances of funds to enable entities to make payments under the contract.


(d) Applicable statutory provisionsSubsections (d) and (e) 11 See References in Text note below. of section 1395u of this title shall apply to contracts with entities under subsection (a) in the same manner as they apply to contracts with carriers under that section.


(e) “Fiscal agent” definedIn this section, the term “fiscal agent” means a carrier described in section 1395u(f)(1) 1 of this title and includes, with respect to contracts under subsection (a)(1)(A), an Indian tribe or tribal organization acting under contract with the Secretary under the Indian Self-Determination Act (Public Law 9</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracting authority The Secretary may enter into contracts with fiscal agents—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracting prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contracting prerequisites</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advances under contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advances under contracts A contract under subsection (a) may provide for advances of funds to enable entities to make payments under the contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicable statutory provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicable statutory provisions Subsections (d) and (e) 11 See References in Text note below. of section 1395u of this title shall apply to contracts with entities under subsection (a) in the same manner as they apply to contracts with carriers under that section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Fiscal agent” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Fiscal agent” defined In this section, the term “fiscal agent” means a carrier described in section 1395u(f)(1) 1 of this title and includes, with respect to contracts under subsection (a)(1)(A), an Indian tribe or tribal organization acting under contract with the Secretary under the Indian Self-Determination Act (Public Law 93–638) [25 U.S.C. 5321 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>