<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/238p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_238p"><akn:num>238p</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations and guidelines regarding automated external defibrillators for Federal buildings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 238p. Recommendations and guidelines regarding automated external defibrillators for Federal buildings(a) Guidelines on placementThe Secretary shall establish guidelines with respect to placing automated external defibrillator devices in Federal buildings. Such guidelines shall take into account the extent to which such devices may be used by lay persons, the typical number of employees and visitors in the buildings, the extent of the need for security measures regarding the buildings, buildings or portions of buildings in which there are special circumstances such as high electrical voltage or extreme heat or cold, and such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.


(b) Related recommendationsThe Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the recommendations of the Secretary on the appropriate implementation of the placement of automated external defibrillator devices under subsection (a), including procedures for the following:(1) Implementing appropriate training courses in the use of such devices, including the role of cardiopulmonary resuscitation.

(2) Proper maintenance and testing of the devices.

(3) Ensuring coordination with appropriate licensed professionals in the oversight of training of the devices.

(4) Ensuring coordination with local emergency medical systems regarding the placement and incidents of use of the devices.


(c) Consultations; consideration of certain recommendationsIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—(1) consult with appropriate public and private entities;

(2) consider the recommendations of national and local public-health organizations for improving the survival rates of individuals who experience cardiac arrest in nonhospital settings by minimizing the time elapsing between the onset of cardiac arrest and the initial medical response, including defibrillation as necessary; and

(3) consult with and counsel other Federal agencies where such devices are to be used.


(d) Date certain for est</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines on placement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Guidelines on placement The Secretary shall establish guidelines with respect to placing automated external defibrillator devices in Federal buildings. Such guidelines shall take into account the extent to which such devices may be used by lay persons, the typical number of employees and visitors in the buildings, the extent of the need for security measures regarding the buildings, buildings or portions of buildings in which there are special circumstances such as high electrical voltage or extreme heat or cold, and such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Related recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Related recommendations The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the recommendations of the Secretary on the appropriate implementation of the placement of automated external defibrillator devices under subsection (a), including procedures for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultations; consideration of certain recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consultations; consideration of certain recommendations In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date certain for establishing guidelines and recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Date certain for establishing guidelines and recommendations The Secretary shall comply with this section not later than 180 days after November 13, 2000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_238p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>