<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_239b"><akn:num>239b</akn:num><akn:heading>Smallpox vaccine injury table</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 239b. Smallpox vaccine injury table(a) 11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. Smallpox vaccine injury table(1) Establishment requiredThe Secretary shall establish by interim final regulation a table identifying adverse effects (including injuries, disabilities, illnesses, conditions, and deaths) that shall be presumed to result from the administration of (or exposure to) a smallpox vaccine, and the time period in which the first symptom or manifestation of onset of each such adverse effect must manifest in order for such presumption to apply.


(2) AmendmentsThe Secretary may by regulation amend the table established under paragraph (1). An amendment to the table takes effect on the date of the promulgation of the final rule that makes the amendment, and applies to all requests for benefits or compensation under this part that are filed on or after such date or are pending as of such date. In addition, the amendment applies retroactively to an individual who was not with respect to the injury involved an eligible individual under the table as in effect before the amendment but who with respect to such injury is an eligible individual under the table as amended. With respect to a request for benefits or compensation under this part by an individual who becomes an eligible individual as described in the preceding sentence, the Secretary may not provide such benefits or compensation unless the request (or amendment to a request, as applicable) is filed before the expiration of one year after the effective date of the amendment to the table in the case of an individual to whom the vaccine was administered and before the expiration of two years after such effective date in the case of a request based on accidental vaccinia inoculation.



(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title II, § 263, as added Pub. L. 108–20, § 2, Apr. 30, 2003, 117 Stat. 641.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. Smallpox vaccine injury table</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>