<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_239e"><akn:num>239e</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment for death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 239e. Payment for death(a) Death benefit(1) In generalThe Secretary shall pay, in the case of an eligible individual whose death is determined to have resulted from a covered injury or injuries, a death benefit in the amount determined under paragraph (2) to the survivor or survivors in the same manner as death benefits are paid pursuant to the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program under subpart 1 of part L of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 3796 et seq.) 11 See References in Text note below. with respect to an eligible deceased (except that in the case of an eligible individual who is a minor with no living parent, the legal guardian shall be considered the survivor in the place of the parent).


(2) Benefit amount(A) In generalThe amount of the death benefit under paragraph (1) in a fiscal year shall equal the amount of the comparable benefit calculated under the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program under subpart 1 of part L of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 3796 et seq.) 1 in such fiscal year, without regard to any reduction attributable to a limitation on appropriations, but subject to subparagraph (B).


(B) Reduction for payments for lost employment incomeThe amount of the benefit as determined under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the total amount of any benefits paid under section 239d of this title with respect to lost employment income.



(3) Limitations(A) In generalNo benefit is payable under paragraph (1) with respect to the death of an eligible individual if—(i) a disability benefit is paid with respect to such individual under the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program under subpart 1 of part L of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 3796 et seq.); 1 or

(ii) a death benefit is paid or payable with respect to such individual under the Public Safety Officers’ Benefits Program under subpart 1 of part L of ti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death benefit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Death benefit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election in case of dependents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Election in case of dependents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Benefit in addition to medical benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Benefit in addition to medical benefits A benefit under subsection (a) or (b) shall be in addition to any amounts received by an eligible individual under section 239c of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>