<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_239l_2"><akn:num>239l–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Students; selection; obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 239l–2. Students; selection; obligation(a) Student selection(1) In generalMedical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students at the Track shall be selected under procedures prescribed by the Surgeon General. In so prescribing, the Surgeon General shall consider the recommendations of the National Health Care Workforce Commission.


(2) PriorityIn developing admissions procedures under paragraph (1), the Surgeon General shall ensure that such procedures give priority to applicant medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students from rural communities and underrepresented minorities.



(b) Contract and service obligation(1) ContractUpon being admitted to the Track, a medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, or nursing student shall enter into a written contract with the Surgeon General that shall contain—(A) an agreement under which—(i) subject to subparagraph (B), the Surgeon General agrees to provide the student with tuition (or tuition remission) and a student stipend (described in paragraph (2)) in each school year for a period of years (not to exceed 4 school years) determined by the student, during which period the student is enrolled in the Track at an affiliated or other participating health professions institution pursuant to an agreement between the Track and such institution; and

(ii) subject to subparagraph (B), the student agrees—(I) to accept the provision of such tuition and student stipend to the student;

(II) to maintain enrollment at the Track until the student completes the course of study involved;

(III) while enrolled in such course of study, to maintain an acceptable level of academic standing (as determined by the Surgeon General);

(IV) if pursuing a degree from a school of medicine or osteopathic medicine, dental, public health, or nursing school or a physician</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student selection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Student selection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract and service obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract and service obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Second 2 years of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Second 2 years of service During the third and fourth years in which a medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, or nursing student is enrolled in the Track, training should be designed to prioritize clinical rotations in Federal medical facilities in health professional shortage areas, and emphasize a balance of hospital and community-based experiences, and training within interdisciplinary teams.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dentist, physician assistant, pharmacist, behavioral and mental health professional, public health professional, and nurse training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dentist, physician assistant, pharmacist, behavioral and mental health professional, public health professional, and nurse training The Surgeon General shall establish provisions applicable with respect to dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students that are comparable to those for medical students under this section, including service obligations, tuition support, and stipend support. The Surgeon General shall give priority to health professions training institutions that train medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students for some significant period of time together, but at a minimum have a discrete and shared core curriculum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elite Federal disaster teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Elite Federal disaster teams The Surgeon General, in consultation with the Secretary, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and other appropriate military and Federal government agencies, shall develop criteria for the appointment of highly qualified Track faculty, medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, and nursing students, and graduates to elite Federal disaster preparedness teams to train and to respond to public health emergencies, natural disasters, bioterrorism events, and other emergencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Student dropped from Track in affiliate school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Student dropped from Track in affiliate school A medical, dental, physician assistant, pharmacy, behavioral and mental health, public health, or nursing student who, under regulations prescribed by the Surgeon General, is dropped from the Track in an affiliated school for deficiency in conduct or studies, or for other reasons, shall be liable to the United States for all tuition and stipend support provided to the student.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>