<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/239l–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_239l_1"><akn:num>239l–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 239l–1. Administration(a) In generalThe business of the Track shall be conducted by the Surgeon General with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Health and Human Services. The National Health Care Workforce Commission shall assist the Surgeon General in an advisory capacity.


(b) Faculty(1) In generalThe Surgeon General, after considering the recommendations of the National Health Care Workforce Commission, shall obtain the services of such professors, instructors, and administrative and other employees as may be necessary to operate the Track, but utilize when possible, existing affiliated health professions training institutions. Members of the faculty and staff shall be employed under salary schedules and granted retirement and other related benefits prescribed by the Secretary so as to place the employees of the Track faculty on a comparable basis with the employees of fully accredited schools of the health professions within the United States.


(2) TitlesThe Surgeon General may confer academic titles, as appropriate, upon the members of the faculty.


(3) Nonapplication of provisionsThe limitations in section 5373 of title 5 shall not apply to the authority of the Surgeon General under paragraph (1) to prescribe salary schedules and other related benefits.



(c) AgreementsThe Surgeon General may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources located in the United States (or locations selected in accordance with section 239l(a)(2) of this title). Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Surgeon General may negotiate affiliation agreements with accredited universities and health professions training institutions in the United States. Such agreements may include provisions for payments for educational services provided students participating in Department of Health and Human Services ed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The business of the Track shall be conducted by the Surgeon General with funds appropriated for and provided by the Department of Health and Human Services. The National Health Care Workforce Commission shall assist the Surgeon General in an advisory capacity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Faculty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Faculty</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements The Surgeon General may negotiate agreements with agencies of the Federal Government to utilize on a reimbursable basis appropriate existing Federal medical resources located in the United States (or locations selected in accordance with section 239l(a)(2) of this title). Under such agreements the facilities concerned will retain their identities and basic missions. The Surgeon General may negotiate affiliation agreements with accredited universities and health professions training institutions in the United States. Such agreements may include provisions for payments for educational services provided students participating in Department of Health and Human Services educational programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Programs The Surgeon General may establish the following educational programs for Track students:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuing medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Continuing medical education The Surgeon General shall establish programs in continuing medical education for members of the health professions to the end that high standards of health care may be maintained within the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_239l_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of the Surgeon General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authority of the Surgeon General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>