<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_242c_1"><akn:num>242c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory committee to the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 242c–1. Advisory committee to the Director(a) In generalNot later than 60 days after December 29, 2022, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall maintain or establish an advisory committee within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to advise the Director on policy and strategies that enable the agency to fulfill its mission.


(b) Functions and activitiesThe Advisory Committee may—(1) make recommendations to the Director regarding ways to prioritize the activities of the agency in alignment with the CDC Strategic Plan required under section 242c(c) of this title;

(2) advise on ways to achieve or improve performance metrics in relation to the CDC Strategic Plan, and other relevant metrics, as appropriate;

(3) provide advice and recommendations on the development of the CDC Strategic Plan, and any subsequent updates, as appropriate;

(4) advise on grants, cooperative agreements, contracts, or other transactions, as applicable;

(5) provide other advice to the Director, as requested, to fulfill duties under sections 241 and 243 of this title; and

(6) appoint subcommittees.


(c) Membership(1) In generalThe Advisory Committee shall consist of not more than 15 non-Federal members, including the Chair, to be appointed by the Secretary under paragraph (3).


(2) Ex officio membersAny ex officio members of the Advisory Council 11 So in original. may consist of—(A) the Secretary;

(B) the Assistant Secretary for Health;

(C) the Director; and

(D) such additional officers or employees of the United States as the Secretary determines necessary for the advisory committee to effectively carry out its functions.


(3) Appointed membersIndividuals shall be appointed to the Advisory Committee under paragraph (1) as follows:(A) Twelve of the members shall be appointed by the Director from among the leading representatives of the health disciplines (including pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 60 days after December 29, 2022, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall maintain or establish an advisory committee within the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to advise the Director on policy and strategies that enable the agency to fulfill its mission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions and activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions and activities The Advisory Committee may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chair The Secretary shall select a member of the advisory committee to serve as the Chair of the committee. The Secretary may so select an individual from among the appointed members. The term of office of the chair shall be 2 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings The advisory committee shall meet at the call of the Chair or upon request of the Director, but in no event less than 2 times during each fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive secretary and staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Executive secretary and staff The Director shall designate a member of the staff of the agency to serve as the executive secretary of the advisory committee. The Director shall make available to the advisory committee such staff, information, and other assistance as it may require to carry out its functions. The Director shall provide orientation and training for new members of the advisory committee to provide for their effective participation in the functions of the advisory committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>