<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_242c"><akn:num>242c</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment and authority of the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 242c. Appointment and authority of the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention(a) In generalThe Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “CDC”) shall be headed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such individual shall also serve as the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry consistent with section 9604(i) of this title. The Director shall perform functions provided for in subsection (b) and such other functions as the Secretary may prescribe.


(b) FunctionsThe Secretary, acting through the Director, shall—(1) implement and exercise applicable authorities and responsibilities provided for in this chapter or other applicable law related to the investigation, detection, identification, prevention, or control of diseases or conditions to preserve and improve public health domestically and globally and address injuries and occupational and environmental hazards, as appropriate;

(2) be responsible for the overall direction of the CDC and for the establishment and implementation of policies related to the management and operation of programs and activities within the CDC;

(3) coordinate and oversee the operation of centers, institutes, and offices within the CDC;

(4) support, in consultation with the heads of such centers, institutes, and offices, program coordination across such centers, institutes, and offices, including through priority setting reviews and the development of strategic plans, to reduce unnecessary duplication and encourage collaboration between programs;

(5) oversee the development, implementation, and updating of the strategic plan established pursuant to subsection (c);

(6) ensure that appropriate strategic planning, including the use of performance metrics, is conducted by such centers, ins</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “CDC”) shall be headed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “Director”), who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Such individual shall also serve as the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry consistent with section 9604(i) of this title. The Director shall perform functions provided for in subsection (b) and such other functions as the Secretary may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Strategic plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appearances before Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Appearances before Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other transactions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Other transactions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>