<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242v" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242v/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/242v/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_242v"><akn:num>242v</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreign talent recruitment programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 242v. Foreign talent recruitment programs(a) Intramural research(1) In generalNot later than 60 days after December 29, 2022, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in sections 242v to 242v–3 of this title as the “Secretary”) shall prohibit personnel of the National Institutes of Health engaged in intramural research from participation in foreign talent recruitment programs.


(2) ExemptionParagraph (1) shall not apply to participation in international conferences or other international exchanges, partnerships, or programs, for which such participation has been approved by the National Institutes of Health. In such circumstances, the National Institutes of Health shall ensure appropriate training is provided to the participant on how to respond to overtures from individuals associated with foreign talent recruitment programs.



(b) Extramural researchThe Secretary shall require disclosure of participation in foreign talent recruitment programs, including the provision of copies of all grants, contracts, or other agreements related to such programs, and other supporting documentation related to such programs, as a condition of receipt of Federal extramural biomedical research funding awarded through the Department of Health and Human Services.


(c) ConsistencyThe Secretary shall ensure that the policies developed, updated, or issued pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) are, to the greatest extent practicable, consistent with the requirements of subtitle D of title VI of division B of Public Law 117–167 (42 U.S.C. 19231 et seq.) related to foreign talent recruitment programs.


(Pub. L. 117–328, div. FF, title II, § 2321, Dec. 29, 2022, 136 Stat. 5765.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSections 242v to 242v–3 of this title, referred to in subsec. (a)(1), was in the original “this chapter”, meaning chapter 3 (§§ 2321–2326) of title II of div. FF of Pub. L. 117–328, 136 Stat. 5765, which enacted this section and sections 242v–1 to 242v–3 of this t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242v_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intramural research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Intramural research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242v_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extramural research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Extramural research The Secretary shall require disclosure of participation in foreign talent recruitment programs, including the provision of copies of all grants, contracts, or other agreements related to such programs, and other supporting documentation related to such programs, as a condition of receipt of Federal extramural biomedical research funding awarded through the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_242v_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consistency The Secretary shall ensure that the policies developed, updated, or issued pursuant to subsections (a) and (b) are, to the greatest extent practicable, consistent with the requirements of subtitle D of title VI of division B of Public Law 117–167 (42 U.S.C. 19231 et seq.) related to foreign talent recruitment programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>