<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/244d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/244d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/244d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_244d"><akn:num>244d</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting student access to AEDs and CPR</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 244d. Promoting student access to AEDs and CPR(a) In generalThe Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to develop and implement a comprehensive program to promote student access to automated external defibrillators (in this section referred to as “AEDs”) and cardiopulmonary resuscitation (in this section referred to as “CPR”) in public elementary schools and secondary schools.


(b) Use of fundsAn eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) may use funds received through such grant to carry out any of the following activities:(1) Developing and providing comprehensive materials to establish AED and CPR programs in public elementary schools and secondary schools.

(2) Providing support for CPR and AED training programs in such schools for students, staff, and related sports volunteers.

(3) Providing support for developing a cardiac emergency response plan within such schools.

(4) Purchasing AEDs that have been approved under section 360e of title 21, cleared under section 360(k) of such title, or classified under section 360c(f)(2) of such title.

(5) Purchasing necessary AED batteries and performing necessary AED maintenance (such as by replacing AED pads) in accordance with the labeling of the AED involved.

(6) Replacing old and outdated AED and CPR equipment, machinery, and educational materials.


(c) Eligibility; applicationTo be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall—(1) be a local educational agency (including a public charter school operating as a local educational agency under State law), in consultation with a qualified health care entity; and

(2) submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) ESEA termsThe terms “elementary school”, “local educational agency”, and “secondary school” have the meanings given such terms in section 7801 of title 20.


(2) Qualified health care entityTh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_244d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to develop and implement a comprehensive program to promote student access to automated external defibrillators (in this section referred to as “AEDs”) and cardiopulmonary resuscitation (in this section referred to as “CPR”) in public elementary schools and secondary schools.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_244d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds An eligible entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) may use funds received through such grant to carry out any of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_244d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility; application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility; application To be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_244d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>