<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/245" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/245/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/245/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_245"><akn:num>245</akn:num><akn:heading>Public awareness campaign on the importance of vaccinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 245. Public awareness campaign on the importance of vaccinations(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with other offices and agencies, as appropriate, shall award competitive grants or contracts to one or more public or private entities to carry out a national, evidence-based campaign to increase awareness and knowledge of the safety and effectiveness of vaccines for the prevention and control of diseases, combat misinformation about vaccines, and disseminate scientific and evidence-based vaccine-related information, with the goal of increasing rates of vaccination across all ages, as applicable, particularly in communities with low rates of vaccination, to reduce and eliminate vaccine-preventable diseases.


(b) ConsultationIn carrying out the campaign under this section, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate public health and medical experts, including the National Academy of Medicine and medical and public health associations and nonprofit organizations, in the development, implementation, and evaluation of the evidence-based public awareness campaign.


(c) RequirementsThe campaign under this section shall—(1) be a nationwide, evidence-based media and public engagement initiative;

(2) include the development of resources for communities with low rates of vaccination, including culturally and linguistically appropriate resources, as applicable;

(3) include the dissemination of vaccine information and communication resources to public health departments, health care providers, and health care facilities, including such providers and facilities that provide prenatal and pediatric care;

(4) be complementary to, and coordinated with, any other Federal, State, local, or Tribal efforts, as appropriate; and

(5) assess the effectiveness of communication strategies to increase rates of vaccination.


(d) Additional activitiesThe campaign under this section may—(1) include</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with other offices and agencies, as appropriate, shall award competitive grants or contracts to one or more public or private entities to carry out a national, evidence-based campaign to increase awareness and knowledge of the safety and effectiveness of vaccines for the prevention and control of diseases, combat misinformation about vaccines, and disseminate scientific and evidence-based vaccine-related information, with the goal of increasing rates of vaccination across all ages, as applicable, particularly in communities with low rates of vaccination, to reduce and eliminate vaccine-preventable diseases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In carrying out the campaign under this section, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate public health and medical experts, including the National Academy of Medicine and medical and public health associations and nonprofit organizations, in the development, implementation, and evaluation of the evidence-based public awareness campaign.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The campaign under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional activities The campaign under this section may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluation The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Supplement not supplant Funds appropriated under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local public funds provided for activities described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_245_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and subsections (k) and (n) of section 247b of this title, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>