<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–13a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–13a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–13a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_13a"><akn:num>247b–13a</akn:num><akn:heading>Screening and treatment for maternal mental health and substance use disorders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–13a. Screening and treatment for maternal mental health and substance use disorders(a) GrantsThe Secretary shall make grants to States, Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations (as such terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25) to establish, improve, or maintain programs for screening, assessment, and treatment services, including culturally and linguistically appropriate services, as appropriate, for women who are postpartum, pregnant, or have given birth within the preceding 12 months, for maternal mental health and substance use disorders.


(b) ApplicationTo seek a grant under this section, an entity listed in subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, any such application shall include explanations of—(1) how a program, or programs, will increase the percentage of women screened and treated, as appropriate, for maternal mental health and substance use disorders in 1 or more communities; and

(2) how a program, or programs, if expanded, would increase access to screening and treatment services for maternal mental health and substance use disorders.


(c) PriorityIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall, as appropriate, give priority to entities listed in subsection (a) that—(1) are proposing to create, improve, or enhance screening, prevention, and treatment services for maternal mental health and substance use disorders in primary care settings;

(2) are currently partnered with, or will partner with, one or more community-based organizations to address maternal mental health and substance use disorders;

(3) are located in, or provide services under this section in, an area with disproportionately high rates of maternal mental health or substance use disorders or other related disparities; and

(4) operate in a health professional shortage area designated under section 254e of this title, including maternity car</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants The Secretary shall make grants to States, Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations (as such terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25) to establish, improve, or maintain programs for screening, assessment, and treatment services, including culturally and linguistically appropriate services, as appropriate, for women who are postpartum, pregnant, or have given birth within the preceding 12 months, for maternal mental health and substance use disorders.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application To seek a grant under this section, an entity listed in subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, any such application shall include explanations of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall, as appropriate, give priority to entities listed in subsection (a) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds The activities eligible for funding through a grant under subsection (a)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to grantees and entities listed in subsection (a) for carrying out activities pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dissemination of best practices The Secretary, based on evaluation of the activities funded pursuant to this section, shall identify and disseminate evidence-based or evidence-informed practices for screening, assessment, treatment, and referral to treatment services for maternal mental health and substance use disorders, including culturally and linguistically appropriate services, for women during pregnancy and 12 months following pregnancy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Matching requirement The Federal share of the cost of the activities for which a grant is made to an entity under subsection (a) shall not exceed 90 percent of the total cost of such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_13a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $24,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>