<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b"><akn:num>247b</akn:num><akn:heading>Project grants for preventive health services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b. Project grants for preventive health services(a) Grant authorityThe Secretary may make grants to States, and in consultation with State health authorities, to political subdivisions of States and to other public entities to assist them in meeting the costs of establishing and maintaining preventive health service programs.


(b) ApplicationNo grant may be made under section (a) 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a)”. unless an application therefor has been submitted to, and approved by, the Secretary. Such an application shall be in such form and be submitted in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall provide—(1) a complete description of the type and extent of the program for which the applicant is seeking a grant under subsection (a);

(2) with respect to each such program (A) the amount of Federal, State, and other funds obligated by the applicant in its latest annual accounting period for the provision of such program, (B) a description of the services provided by the applicant in such program in such period, (C) the amount of Federal funds needed by the applicant to continue providing such services in such program, and (D) if the applicant proposes changes in the provision of the services in such program, the priorities of such proposed changes, reasons for such changes, and the amount of Federal funds needed by the applicant to make such changes;

(3) assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the program which will be provided with funds under a grant under subsection (a) will be provided in a manner consistent with the State health plan in effect under section 300m–3(c) 22 See References in Text note below. of this title and in those cases where the applicant is a State, that such program will be provided, where appropriate, in a manner consistent with any plans in effect under an application approved under section 247 2 of this title;

(4) assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that the applicant wil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant authority The Secretary may make grants to States, and in consultation with State health authorities, to political subdivisions of States and to other public entities to assist them in meeting the costs of establishing and maintaining preventive health service programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application No grant may be made under section (a) 11 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (a)”. unless an application therefor has been submitted to, and approved by, the Secretary. Such an application shall be in such form and be submitted in such manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall provide—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval; annual project review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval; annual project review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grant; payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of grant; payment The amount of a grant under subsection (a) shall be determined by the Secretary. Payments under such grants may be made in advance on the basis of estimates or by the way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of underpayments or overpayments, and in such installments and on such terms and conditions as the Secretary finds necessary to carry out the purposes of such grants.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reduction The Secretary, at the request of a recipient of a grant under subsection (a), may reduce the amount of such grant by— when the furnishing of such supplies or equipment or the detail of such an officer or employee is for the convenience of and at the request of such grant recipient and for the purpose of carrying out a program with respect to which the grant under subsection (a) is made. The amount by which any such grant is so reduced shall be available for payment by the Secretary of the costs incurred in furnishing the supplies or equipment, or in detailing the personnel, on which the reduction of such grant is based, and such amount shall be deemed as part of the grant and shall be deemed to have been paid to the grant recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recordkeeping; audit authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recordkeeping; audit authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant funds; mandatory treatment pro­hibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Use of grant funds; mandatory treatment pro­hibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports The Secretary shall include, as part of the report required by section 300u–4 of this title, a report on the extent of the problems presented by the diseases and conditions referred to in subsection (j); on the amount of funds obligated under grants under subsection (a) in the preceding fiscal year for each of the programs listed in subsection (j); and on the effectiveness of the activities assisted under grants under subsection (a) in controlling such diseases and conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Technical assistance The Secretary may provide technical assistance to States, State health authorities, and other public entities in connection with the operation of their preventive health service programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>