<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–18" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–18/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–18/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_18"><akn:num>247b–18</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveillance and research regarding muscular dystrophy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–18. Surveillance and research regarding muscular dystrophy(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants and cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private entities (including health departments of States and political subdivisions of States, and including universities and other educational entities) for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on Duchenne and other forms of muscular dystrophy. In making such awards, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance in lieu of cash.


(b) National muscular dystrophy epidemiology programThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants to public or nonprofit private entities (including health departments of States and political subdivisions of States, and including universities and other educational entities) for the purpose of carrying out epidemiological activities regarding Duchenne and other forms of muscular dystrophies, including collecting and analyzing information on the number, incidence, correlates, and symptoms of cases. In carrying out the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall provide for a national surveillance program and, to the extent possible, ensure that data be representative of all affected populations and shared in a timely manner. In making awards under this subsection, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance in lieu of cash.


(c) Coordination with centers of excellenceThe Secretary shall ensure that epidemiological information under subsections (a) and (b) is made available to centers of excellence supported under section 283g(b) of this title by the Director of the National Institutes of Health.


(d) DataIn carrying out this section, the Secretary may ensure that any data on patients that is collected as part of the Muscular Dystrophy STARnet (under a grant under this section) is regularly updated to reflect change</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants and cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private entities (including health departments of States and political subdivisions of States, and including universities and other educational entities) for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on Duchenne and other forms of muscular dystrophy. In making such awards, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance in lieu of cash.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National muscular dystrophy epidemiology program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National muscular dystrophy epidemiology program The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may award grants to public or nonprofit private entities (including health departments of States and political subdivisions of States, and including universities and other educational entities) for the purpose of carrying out epidemiological activities regarding Duchenne and other forms of muscular dystrophies, including collecting and analyzing information on the number, incidence, correlates, and symptoms of cases. In carrying out the preceding sentence, the Secretary shall provide for a national surveillance program and, to the extent possible, ensure that data be representative of all affected populations and shared in a timely manner. In making awards under this subsection, the Secretary may provide direct technical assistance in lieu of cash.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with centers of excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with centers of excellence The Secretary shall ensure that epidemiological information under subsections (a) and (b) is made available to centers of excellence supported under section 283g(b) of this title by the Director of the National Institutes of Health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data In carrying out this section, the Secretary may ensure that any data on patients that is collected as part of the Muscular Dystrophy STARnet (under a grant under this section) is regularly updated to reflect changes in patient condition over time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports and study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports and study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_18_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>