<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_3"><akn:num>247b–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Education, technology assessment, and epidemiology regarding lead poisoning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–3. Education, technology assessment, and epidemiology regarding lead poisoning(a) Prevention(1) Public educationThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall carry out a program to educate health professionals and paraprofessionals and the general public on the prevention of lead poisoning in infants and children. In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall make available information concerning the health effects of low-level lead toxicity, the causes of lead poisoning, and the primary and secondary preventive measures that may be taken to prevent such poisoning.


(2) Interagency Task Force(A) Not later than 6 months after October 27, 1992, the Secretary shall establish a council to be known as the Interagency Task Force on the Prevention of Lead Poisoning (in this paragraph referred to as the “Task Force”). The Task Force shall coordinate the efforts of Federal agencies to prevent lead poisoning.

(B) The Task Force shall be composed of—(i) the Secretary, who shall serve as the chair of the Task Force;

(ii) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development;

(iii) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency; and

(iv) senior staff of each of the officials specified in clauses (i) through (iii), as selected by the officials respectively.


(C) The Task Force shall—(i) review, evaluate, and coordinate current strategies and plans formulated by the officials serving as members of the Task Force, including—(I) the plan of the Secretary of Health and Human Services entitled “Strategic Plan for the Elimination of Lead Poisoning”, dated February 21, 1991;

(II) the plan of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development entitled “Comprehensive and Workable Plan for the Abatement of Lead-Based Paint in Privately Owned Housing”, dated December 7, 1990; and

(III) the strategy of the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled “Strategy for Reducing Lead Exposures”, dated February </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prevention</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technology assessment and epidemiology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Technology assessment and epidemiology The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall, directly or through grants or contracts—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>