<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–4a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–4a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–4a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_4a"><akn:num>247b–4a</akn:num><akn:heading>Early detection, diagnosis, and interventions for newborns and infants with hearing loss</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–4a. Early detection, diagnosis, and interventions for newborns and infants with hearing loss(a) DefinitionsFor the purposes of this section only, the following terms in this section are defined as follows:(1) Hearing screeningNewborn and infant hearing screening consists of objective physiologic procedures to detect possible hearing loss and to identify newborns and infants who, after rescreening, require further audiologic and medical evaluations.


(2) Audiologic evaluationAudiologic evaluation consists of procedures to assess the status of the auditory system; to establish the site of the auditory disorder; the type and degree of hearing loss, and the potential effects of hearing loss on communication; and to identify appropriate treatment and referral options. Referral options should include linkage to State IDEA part C coordinating agencies or other appropriate agencies, medical evaluation, hearing aid/sensory aid assessment, audiologic rehabilitation treatment, national and local consumer, self-help, parent, and education organizations, and other family-centered services.


(3) Medical evaluationMedical evaluation by a physician consists of key components including history, examination, and medical decision making focused on symptomatic and related body systems for the purpose of diagnosing the etiology of hearing loss and related physical conditions, and for identifying appropriate treatment and referral options.


(4) Medical interventionMedical intervention is the process by which a physician provides medical diagnosis and direction for medical and/or surgical treatment options of hearing loss and/or related medical disorder associated with hearing loss.


(5) Audiologic rehabilitationAudiologic rehabilitation (intervention) consists of procedures, techniques, and technologies to facilitate the receptive and expressive communication abilities of a child with hearing loss.


(6) Early interventionEarly intervention (e.g., nonmedical) means providing a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For the purposes of this section only, the following terms in this section are defined as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of this section are to clarify the authority within the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.] to authorize statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems, technical assistance, a national applied research program, and interagency and private sector collaboration for policy development, in order to assist the States in making progress toward the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems Under the existing authority of the Public Health Service Act [42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.], the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make awards of grants or cooperative agreements to develop statewide newborn and infant hearing screening, evaluation and intervention programs and systems for the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance, data management, and applied research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance, data management, and applied research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination and collaboration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to preempt any State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_4a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>