<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_1"><akn:num>247b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Screenings, referrals, and education regarding lead poisoning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–1. Screenings, referrals, and education regarding lead poisoning(a) Authority for grants(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States and political subdivisions of States for the initiation and expansion of community programs designed—(A) to provide, for infants and children—(i) screening for elevated blood lead levels;

(ii) referral for treatment of such levels; and

(iii) referral for environmental intervention associated with such levels; and


(B) to provide education about childhood lead poisoning.


(2) Authority regarding certain entitiesWith respect to a geographic area with a need for activities authorized in paragraph (1), in any case in which neither the State nor the political subdivision in which such area is located has applied for a grant under paragraph (1), the Secretary may make a grant under such paragraph to any grantee under section 254b, 254b, or 256a of this title 11 See References in Text notes below. for carrying out such activities in the area.


(3) Provision of all services and activities through each granteeIn making grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure that each of the activities described in such paragraph is provided through each grantee under such paragraph. The Secretary may authorize such a grantee to provide the services and activities directly, or through arrangements with other providers.



(b) Status as medicaid provider(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the Secretary may not make a grant under subsection (a) unless, in the case of any service described in such subsection that is made available pursuant to the State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] for the State involved—(A) the applicant for the grant will provide the service directly, and the applicant has entered into a participation agreement under the State plan and is qualified to</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority for grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Status as medicaid provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Status as medicaid provider</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority in making grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority in making grants In making grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to applications for programs that will serve areas with a high incidence of elevated blood lead levels in infants and children.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant application No grant may be made under subsection (a), unless an application therefor has been submitted to, and approved by, the Secretary. Such an application shall be in such form and shall be submitted in such manner as the Secretary shall prescribe and shall include each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to services and activities under other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Relationship to services and activities under other programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Method and amount of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Method and amount of payment The Secretary shall determine the amount of a grant made under subsection (a). Payments under such grants may be made in advance on the basis of estimates or by way of reimbursement, with necessary adjustments on account of underpayments or overpayments, and in such installments and on such terms and conditions as the Secretary finds necessary to carry out the purposes of such grants. Not more than 10 percent of any grant may be obligated for administrative costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplies, equipment, and employee detail</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Supplies, equipment, and employee detail The Secretary, at the request of a recipient of a grant under subsection (a), may reduce the amount of such grant by— when the furnishing of such supplies or equipment or the detail of such an officer or employee is for the convenience of and at the request of such grant recipient and for the purpose of carrying out a program with respect to which the grant under subsection (a) is made. The amount by which any such grant is so reduced shall be available for payment by the Secretary of the costs incurred in furnishing the supplies or equipment, or in detailing the personnel, on which the reduction of such grant is based, and such amount shall be deemed as part of the grant and shall be deemed to have been paid to the grant recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Records Each recipient of a grant under subsection (a) shall keep such records as the Secretary shall prescribe, including records which fully disclose the amount and disposition by such recipient of the proceeds of such grant, the total cost of the undertaking in connection with which such grant was made, and the amount of that portion of the cost of the undertaking supplied by other sources, and such other records as will facilitate an effective audit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit and examination of records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Audit and examination of records The Secretary and the Comptroller General of the United States, or any of their duly authorized representatives, shall have access for the purpose of audit and examination to any books, documents, papers, and records of the recipient of a grant under subsection (a), that are pertinent to such grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Annual report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>