<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_21"><akn:num>247b–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Mosquito-borne diseases; coordination grants to States; assessment and control grants to political s</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–21. Mosquito-borne diseases; coordination grants to States; assessment and control grants to political subdivisions(a) Coordination grants to States; assessment grants to political subdivisions(1) In generalWith respect to mosquito control programs to prevent and control mosquito-borne diseases (referred to in this section as “control programs”), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States for the purpose of—(A) coordinating control programs in the State involved; and

(B) assisting such State in making grants to political subdivisions of the State to conduct assessments to determine the immediate needs in such subdivisions for control programs, including programs to address emerging infectious mosquito-borne diseases, and to develop, on the basis of such assessments, plans for carrying out control programs in the subdivisions or improving existing control programs.


(2) Preference in making grantsIn making grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall give preference to States that have one or more political subdivisions with an incidence, prevalence, or high risk of mosquito-borne disease, or a population of infected mosquitoes, that is substantial relative to political subdivisions in other States.


(3) Certain requirementsA grant may be made under paragraph (1) only if—(A) the State involved has developed, or agrees to develop, a plan for coordinating control programs in the State, and the plan takes into account any assessments or plans described in subsection (b)(3) that have been conducted or developed, respectively, by political subdivisions in the State;

(B) in developing such plan, the State consulted or will consult (as the case may be under subparagraph (A)) with political subdivisions in the State that are carrying out or planning to carry out control programs;

(C) the State agrees to monitor control programs in the State in order to ensure that the programs are car</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination grants to States; assessment grants to political subdivisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordination grants to States; assessment grants to political subdivisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention and control grants to political subdivisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prevention and control grants to political subdivisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications for grants A grant may be made under subsection (a) or (b) only if an application for the grant is submitted to the Secretary and the application is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance Amounts appropriated under subsection (f) may be used by the Secretary to provide training and technical assistance with respect to the planning, development, and operation of assessments and plans under subsection (a) and control programs under subsection (b). The Secretary may provide such technical assistance directly or through awards of grants or contracts to public and private entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of political subdivision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definition of political subdivision In this section, the term “political subdivision” means the local political jurisdiction immediately below the level of State government, including counties, parishes, and boroughs. If State law recognizes an entity of general government that functions in lieu of, and is not within, a county, parish, or borough, the Secretary may recognize an area under the jurisdiction of such other entities of general government as a political subdivision for purposes of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_21_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>