<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–19" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–19/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–19/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_19"><akn:num>247b–19</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–19. Information and education(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the “Secretary”) shall establish and implement a program to provide information and education on muscular dystrophy to health professionals and the general public, including information and education on advances in the diagnosis and treatment of muscular dystrophy and training and continuing education through programs for scientists, physicians, medical students, and other health professionals who provide care for patients with muscular dystrophy.


(b) StipendsThe Secretary may use amounts made available under this section provides 11 So in original. Probably should be “to provide”. stipends for health professionals who are enrolled in training programs under this section.


(c) RequirementsIn carrying out this section, the Secretary may—(1) partner with leaders in the muscular dystrophy patient community;

(2) cooperate with professional organizations and the patient community in the development and issuance of care considerations for pediatric and adult patients, including acute care considerations, for Duchenne-Becker muscular dystrophy, and various other forms of muscular dystrophy, and in periodic review and updates, as appropriate;

(3) in developing and updating care considerations under paragraph (2), incorporate strategies specifically responding to the findings of the national transitions survey of minority, young adult, and adult communities of muscular dystrophy patients; and

(4) widely disseminate the Duchenne-Becker muscular dystrophy and various other forms of muscular dystrophy care considerations as broadly as possible, including through partnership opportunities with the muscular dystrophy patient community.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 107–84, § 5, Dec. 18, 2001, 115 Stat. 828; Pub. L. 110–361, § 4, Oct. 8, 2008,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_19_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the “Secretary”) shall establish and implement a program to provide information and education on muscular dystrophy to health professionals and the general public, including information and education on advances in the diagnosis and treatment of muscular dystrophy and training and continuing education through programs for scientists, physicians, medical students, and other health professionals who provide care for patients with muscular dystrophy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_19_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stipends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Stipends The Secretary may use amounts made available under this section provides 11 So in original. Probably should be “to provide”. stipends for health professionals who are enrolled in training programs under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_19_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements In carrying out this section, the Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_19_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>