<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_6"><akn:num>247b–6</akn:num><akn:heading>National strategy for combating and eliminating tuberculosis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–6. National strategy for combating and eliminating tuberculosis(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States, political subdivisions, and other public entities for preventive health service programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis.


(b) Research and development; demonstration projects; education and trainingWith respect to the prevention, treatment, control, and elimination of tuberculosis, the Secretary may, directly or through grants to public or nonprofit private entities, carry out the following:(1) Research, with priority given to research and development concerning latent tuberculosis infection, strains of tuberculosis resistant to drugs, and research concerning cases of tuberculosis that affect certain populations at risk for tuberculosis.

(2) Research and development and related activities to develop new tools for the elimination of tuberculosis, including drugs, diagnostics, vaccines, and public health interventions, such as directly observed therapy and non-pharmaceutical intervention, and methods to enhance detection and response to outbreaks of tuberculosis, including multidrug resistant tuberculosis. The Secretary is encouraged to give priority to programmatically relevant research so that new tools can be utilized in public health practice.

(3) Demonstration projects for—(A) the development of regional capabilities to prevent, control, and eliminate tuberculosis and prevent multidrug resistant and extensively drug resistant strains of tuberculosis;

(B) the intensification of efforts to reduce health disparities in the incidence of tuberculosis;

(C) the intensification of efforts to control tuberculosis along the United States-Mexico border and among United States-Mexico binational populations, including through expansion of the scope and number of programs that—(i) detect and treat binational cases of tuberculosis; and

(ii) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States, political subdivisions, and other public entities for preventive health service programs for the prevention, control, and elimination of tuberculosis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and development; demonstration projects; education and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research and development; demonstration projects; education and training With respect to the prevention, treatment, control, and elimination of tuberculosis, the Secretary may, directly or through grants to public or nonprofit private entities, carry out the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation with providers of primary health services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation with providers of primary health services The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) or (b) only if the applicant for the grant agrees that, in carrying out activities under the grant, the applicant will cooperate with public and nonprofit private providers of primary health services or substance abuse services, including entities receiving assistance under section 254b, 254b, or 256a of this title 11 See References in Text notes below. or under subchapter III–A or XVII.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application for grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplies and services in lieu of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Supplies and services in lieu of grant funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Advisory Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Tuberculosis Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Federal Tuberculosis Task Force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>