<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–9a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–9a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247b–9a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247b_9a"><akn:num>247b–9a</akn:num><akn:heading>Better diabetes care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247b–9a. Better diabetes care(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Catalyst to Better Diabetes Care Act of 2009”.


(b) National diabetes report card(1) In generalThe Secretary, in collaboration with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this section as the “Director”), shall prepare on a biennial basis a national diabetes report card (referred to in this section as a “Report Card”) and, to the extent possible, for each State.11 So in original.


(2) Contents(A) In generalEach Report Card shall include aggregate health outcomes related to individuals diagnosed with diabetes and prediabetes including—(i) preventative care practices and quality of care;

(ii) risk factors; and

(iii) outcomes.


(B) Updated reportsEach Report Card that is prepared after the initial Report Card shall include trend analysis for the Nation and, to the extent possible, for each State, for the purpose of—(i) tracking progress in meeting established national goals and objectives for improving diabetes care, costs, and prevalence (including Healthy People 2010); and

(ii) informing policy and program development.



(3) AvailabilityThe Secretary, in collaboration with the Director, shall make each Report Card publicly available, including by posting the Report Card on the Internet.



(c) Improvement of vital statistics collection(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in collaboration with appropriate agencies and States, shall—(A) promote the education and training of physicians on the importance of birth and death certificate data and how to properly complete these documents, including the collection of such data for diabetes and other chronic diseases;

(B) encourage State adoption of the latest standard revisions of birth and death certificates; and

(C) work with States to re-engineer their vital statistics systems in order to provide cost-effective, timely, and </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_9a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Catalyst to Better Diabetes Care Act of 2009”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_9a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National diabetes report card</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National diabetes report card</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_9a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvement of vital statistics collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Improvement of vital statistics collection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_9a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study on appropriate level of diabetes medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Study on appropriate level of diabetes medical education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247b_9a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>