<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247c–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247c–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247c–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247c_1"><akn:num>247c–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Infertility and sexually transmitted diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247c–1. Infertility and sexually transmitted diseases(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and other public or nonprofit private entities for the purpose of carrying out the activities described in subsection (c) regarding any treatable sexually transmitted disease that can cause infertility in women if treatment is not received for the disease.


(b) Authority regarding individual diseasesWith respect to diseases described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall, in making a grant under such subsection, specify the particular disease or diseases with respect to which the grant is to be made. The Secretary may not make the grant unless the applicant involved agrees to carry out this section only with respect to the disease or diseases so specified.


(c) Authorized activitiesWith respect to any sexually transmitted disease described in subsection (a), the activities referred to in such subsection are—(1) screening women for the disease and for secondary conditions resulting from the disease, subject to compliance with criteria issued under subsection (f);

(2) providing treatment to women for the disease;

(3) providing counseling to women on the prevention and control of the disease (including, in the case of a woman with the disease, counseling on the benefits of locating and providing such counseling to any individual from whom the woman may have contracted the disease and any individual whom the woman may have exposed to the disease);

(4) providing follow-up services;

(5) referrals for necessary medical services for women screened pursuant to paragraph (1), including referrals for evaluation and treatment with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome and other sexually transmitted diseases;

(6) in the case of any woman receiving services pursuant to any of paragraphs (1) through (5), providing to the partner of the woman th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and other public or nonprofit private entities for the purpose of carrying out the activities described in subsection (c) regarding any treatable sexually transmitted disease that can cause infertility in women if treatment is not received for the disease.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority regarding individual diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority regarding individual diseases With respect to diseases described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall, in making a grant under such subsection, specify the particular disease or diseases with respect to which the grant is to be made. The Secretary may not make the grant unless the applicant involved agrees to carry out this section only with respect to the disease or diseases so specified.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized activities With respect to any sexually transmitted disease described in subsection (a), the activities referred to in such subsection are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of availability of all services through each grantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement of availability of all services through each grantee The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that each activity authorized in subsection (c) will be available through the applicant. With respect to compliance with such agreement, the applicant may expend the grant to carry out any of the activities directly, and may expend the grant to enter into agreements with other public or nonprofit private entities under which the entities carry out the activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required providers regarding certain services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Required providers regarding certain services The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that, in expending the grant to carry out activities authorized in subsection (c), the services described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of such subsection will be provided only through entities that are State or local health departments, grantees under section 254b, 254b, 256a, or 300 of this title,11 See References in Text notes below. or are other public or nonprofit private entities that provide health services to a significant number of low-income women.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality assurance regarding screening for diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Quality assurance regarding screening for diseases For purposes of this section, the Secretary shall establish criteria for ensuring the quality of screening procedures for diseases described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Confidentiality The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees, subject to applicable law, to maintain the confidentiality of information on individuals with respect to activities carried out under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on imposition of fees for services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitation on imposition of fees for services The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that, if a charge is imposed for the provision of services or activities under the grant, such charge—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on certain expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitations on certain expenditures The Secretary may make a grant under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that not less than 80 percent of the grant will be expended for the purpose of carrying out paragraphs (1) through (7) of subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247c_1_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reports to Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>