<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–4b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–4b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–4b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_4b"><akn:num>247d–4b</akn:num><akn:heading>Children’s Preparedness Unit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–4b. Children’s Preparedness Unit(a) Enhancing emergency preparedness for childrenThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this subsection as the “Director”), shall maintain an internal team of experts, to be known as the Children’s Preparedness Unit (referred to in this subsection as the “Unit”), to work collaboratively to provide guidance on the considerations for, and the specific needs of, children before, during, and after public health emergencies. The Unit shall inform the Director regarding emergency preparedness and response efforts pertaining to children at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.


(b) ExpertiseThe team described in subsection (a) shall include one or more pediatricians, which may be a developmental-behavioral pediatrician, and may also include behavioral scientists, child psychologists, epidemiologists, biostatisticians, health communications staff, and individuals with other areas of expertise, as the Secretary determines appropriate.


(c) DutiesThe team described in subsection (a) may—(1) assist State, local, Tribal, and territorial emergency planning and response activities related to children, which may include developing, identifying, and sharing best practices;

(2) provide technical assistance, training, and consultation to Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial public health officials to improve preparedness and response capabilities with respect to the needs of children, including providing such technical assistance, training, and consultation to eligible entities in order to support the achievement of measurable evidence-based benchmarks and objective standards applicable to sections 247d–3a and 247d–3b of this title;

(3) improve the utilization of methods to incorporate the needs of children in planning for and responding to a public health emergency, including public awareness of such methods;

(4) coordinate with, and improve, public-p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_4b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enhancing emergency preparedness for children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Enhancing emergency preparedness for children The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (referred to in this subsection as the “Director”), shall maintain an internal team of experts, to be known as the Children’s Preparedness Unit (referred to in this subsection as the “Unit”), to work collaboratively to provide guidance on the considerations for, and the specific needs of, children before, during, and after public health emergencies. The Unit shall inform the Director regarding emergency preparedness and response efforts pertaining to children at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_4b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expertise</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Expertise The team described in subsection (a) shall include one or more pediatricians, which may be a developmental-behavioral pediatrician, and may also include behavioral scientists, child psychologists, epidemiologists, biostatisticians, health communications staff, and individuals with other areas of expertise, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_4b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The team described in subsection (a) may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>