<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_11"><akn:num>247d–11</akn:num><akn:heading>State All Payer Claims Databases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–11. State All Payer Claims Databases(a) In generalThe Secretary shall make one-time grants to eligible States for the purposes described in subsection (b).


(b) UsesA State may use a grant received under subsection (a) for one of the following purposes:(1) To establish a State All Payer Claims Database.

(2) To improve an 11 So in original. existing State All Payer Claims Databases.1


(c) EligibilityTo be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary specifies, including, with respect to a State All Payer Claims Database, at least specifics on how the State will ensure uniform data collection and the privacy and security of such data.


(d) Grant period and amountGrants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 3-years,22 So in original. Probably should be “3 years,”. and in an amount of $2,500,000, of which $1,000,000 shall be made available to the State for each of the first 2 years of the grant period, and $500,000 shall be made available to the State for the third year of the grant period.


(e) Authorized users(1) ApplicationAn entity desiring authorization for access to a State All Payer Claims Database that has received a grant under this section shall submit to the State All Payer Claims Database an application for such access, which shall include—(A) in the case of an entity requesting access for research purposes—(i) a description of the uses and methodologies for evaluating health system performance using such data; and

(ii) documentation of approval of the research by an institutional review board, if applicable for a particular plan of research; or


(B) in the case of an entity such as an employer, health insurance issuer, third-party administrator, or health care provider, requesting access for the purpose of quality improvement or cost-containment, a description of the intended uses for such data.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall make one-time grants to eligible States for the purposes described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses A State may use a grant received under subsection (a) for one of the following purposes:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility To be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (a), a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary specifies, including, with respect to a State All Payer Claims Database, at least specifics on how the State will ensure uniform data collection and the privacy and security of such data.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant period and amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant period and amount Grants awarded under this section shall be for a period of 3-years,22 So in original. Probably should be “3 years,”. and in an amount of $2,500,000, of which $1,000,000 shall be made available to the State for each of the first 2 years of the grant period, and $500,000 shall be made available to the State for the third year of the grant period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized users</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorized users</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expanded access</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_11_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023, and $25,000,000 for fiscal year 2024, to remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>