<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_7f"><akn:num>247d–7f</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–7f. Collaboration and coordination(a) Limited antitrust exemption(1) Meetings and consultations to discuss security countermeasures, qualified countermeasures, or qualified pandemic or epidemic product development(A) Authority to conduct meetings and consultationsThe Secretary, in coordination with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security, may conduct meetings and consultations with persons engaged in the development of a security countermeasure (as defined in section 247d–6b of this title), a qualified countermeasure (as defined in section 247d–6a of this title), or a qualified pandemic or epidemic product (as defined in section 247d–6d of this title) for the purpose of the development, manufacture, distribution, purchase, or storage of a countermeasure or product. The Secretary may convene such meeting or consultation at the request of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Attorney General, the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission (referred to in this section as the “Chairman”), or any interested person, or upon initiation by the Secretary. The Secretary shall give prior notice of any such meeting or consultation, and the topics to be discussed, to the Attorney General, the Chairman, and the Secretary of Homeland Security.


(B) Meeting and consultation conditionsA meeting or consultation conducted under subparagraph (A) shall—(i) be chaired or, in the case of a consultation, facilitated by the Secretary;

(ii) be open to persons involved in the development, manufacture, distribution, purchase, or storage of a countermeasure or product, as determined by the Secretary;

(iii) be open to the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Chairman;

(iv) be limited to discussions involving covered activities; and

(v) be conducted in such manner as to ensure that no national security, confidential commercial, or proprietary information is disclosed outside the meeting or consultation.


(C) LimitationThe Secretary may no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limited antitrust exemption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limited antitrust exemption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sunset The applicability of this section shall expire after January 30, 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>