<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_6d"><akn:num>247d–6d</akn:num><akn:heading>Targeted liability protections for pandemic and epidemic products and security countermeasures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–6d. Targeted liability protections for pandemic and epidemic products and security countermeasures(a) Liability protections(1) In generalSubject to the other provisions of this section, a covered person shall be immune from suit and liability under Federal and State law with respect to all claims for loss caused by, arising out of, relating to, or resulting from the administration to or the use by an individual of a covered countermeasure if a declaration under subsection (b) has been issued with respect to such countermeasure.


(2) Scope of claims for loss(A) LossFor purposes of this section, the term “loss” means any type of loss, including—(i) death;

(ii) physical, mental, or emotional injury, illness, disability, or condition;

(iii) fear of physical, mental, or emotional injury, illness, disability, or condition, including any need for medical monitoring; and

(iv) loss of or damage to property, including business interruption loss.


Each of clauses (i) through (iv) applies without regard to the date of the occurrence, presentation, or discovery of the loss described in the clause.

(B) ScopeThe immunity under paragraph (1) applies to any claim for loss that has a causal relationship with the administration to or use by an individual of a covered countermeasure, including a causal relationship with the design, development, clinical testing or investigation, manufacture, labeling, distribution, formulation, packaging, marketing, promotion, sale, purchase, donation, dispensing, prescribing, administration, licensing, or use of such countermeasure.



(3) Certain conditionsSubject to the other provisions of this section, immunity under paragraph (1) with respect to a covered countermeasure applies only if—(A) the countermeasure was administered or used during the effective period of the declaration that was issued under subsection (b) with respect to the countermeasure;

(B) the countermeasure was administered or used for the category or categories of di</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Liability protections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Declaration by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of willful misconduct</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definition of willful misconduct</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception to immunity of covered persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception to immunity of covered persons</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for suit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procedures for suit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions by and against the United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Actions by and against the United States Nothing in this section shall be construed to abrogate or limit any right, remedy, or authority that the United States or any agency thereof may possess under any other provision of law or to waive sovereign immunity or to abrogate or limit any defense or protection available to the United States or its agencies, instrumentalities, officers, or employees under any other law, including any provision of chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to tort claims procedure).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Severability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Severability If any provision of this section, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this section and the application of such remainder to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction concerning National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction concerning National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program Nothing in this section, or any amendment made by the Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness Act, shall be construed to affect the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program under subchapter XIX of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>