<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_9"><akn:num>247d–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Dental education for parents of newborns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–9. Dental education for parents of newborns
The Secretary shall develop and implement, through entities that fund or provide perinatal care services to targeted low-income children under a State child health plan under title XXI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.], a program to deliver oral health educational materials that inform new parents about risks for, and prevention of, early childhood caries and the need for a dental visit within their newborn’s first year of life.
(Pub. L. 111–3, title V, § 501(c), Feb. 4, 2009, 123 Stat. 87.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Social Security Act, referred to in text, is act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, 49 Stat. 620. Title XXI of the Act is classified generally to subchapter XXI (§ 1397aa et seq.) of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 1305 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Children’s Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Apr. 1, 2009, and applicable to child health assistance and medical assistance provided on or after that date, with certain exceptions, see section 3 of Pub. L. 111–3, set out as a note under section 1396 of this title.


Definition of “Secretary”
“Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, see section 1(c)(3) of Pub. L. 111–3, set out as a note under section 1396 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>