<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_7g"><akn:num>247d–7g</akn:num><akn:heading>National Biodefense Science Board and working groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–7g. National Biodefense Science Board and working groups(a) In general(1) Establishment and functionThe Secretary shall establish the National Biodefense Science Board (referred to in this section as the “Board”) to provide expert advice and guidance to the Secretary on scientific, technical and other matters of special interest to the Department of Health and Human Services regarding current and future chemical, biological, nuclear, and radiological agents, whether naturally occurring, accidental, or deliberate.


(2) MembershipThe membership of the Board shall be comprised of individuals who represent the Nation’s preeminent scientific, public health, and medical experts, as follows—(A) such Federal officials as the Secretary may determine are necessary to support the functions of the Board;

(B) four individuals representing the pharmaceutical, biotechnology, and device industries;

(C) four individuals representing academia; and

(D) five other members as determined appropriate by the Secretary, of whom—(i) one such member shall be a practicing healthcare professional;

(ii) one such member shall be an individual from an organization representing healthcare consumers;

(iii) one such member shall be an individual with pediatric subject matter expertise; and

(iv) one such member shall be a State, tribal, territorial, or local public health official.



Nothing in this paragraph shall preclude a member of the Board from satisfying two or more of the requirements described in subparagraph (D).

(3) Term of appointmentA member of the Board described in subparagraph (B), (C), or (D) of paragraph (2) shall serve for a term of 3 years, except that the Secretary may adjust the terms of the initial Board appointees in order to provide for a staggered term of appointment for all members.


(4) Consecutive appointments; maximum termsA member may be appointed to serve not more than 3 terms on the Board and may serve not more than 2 consecutive terms.


(5) DutiesThe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other working groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other working groups The Secretary may establish a working group of experts, or may use an existing working group or advisory committee, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions Any term that is defined in section 247d–7e of this title and that is used in this section shall have the same meaning in this section as such term is given in section 247d–7e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 to carry out this section for fiscal year 2007 and each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>