<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–7e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_7e"><akn:num>247d–7e</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–7e. Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BARDAThe term “BARDA” means the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority.


(2) FundThe term “Fund” means the Biodefense Medical Countermeasure Development Fund established under subsection (d).


(3) Other transactionsThe term “other transactions” means transactions, other than procurement contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements.


(4) Qualified countermeasureThe term “qualified countermeasure” has the meaning given such term in section 247d–6a of this title.


(5) Qualified pandemic or epidemic productThe term “qualified pandemic or epidemic product” has the meaning given the term in section 247d–6d of this title.


(6) Advanced research and development(A) In generalThe term “advanced research and development” means, with respect to a product that is or may become a qualified countermeasure or a qualified pandemic or epidemic product, activities that predominantly—(i) are conducted after basic research and preclinical development of the product; and

(ii) are related to manufacturing the product on a commercial scale and in a form that satisfies the regulatory requirements under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] or under section 262 of this title.


(B) Activities includedThe term under subparagraph (A) includes—(i) testing of the product to determine whether the product may be approved, cleared, or licensed under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] or under section 262 of this title for a use that is or may be the basis for such product becoming a qualified countermeasure or qualified pandemic or epidemic product, or to help obtain such approval, clearance, or license;

(ii) design and development of tests or models, including animal models, for such testing;

(iii) activities to facilitate manufacture of the product on a commercial scale with consistently high quality, as well as to im</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Strategic plan for countermeasure research, development, and procurement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Strategic plan for countermeasure research, development, and procurement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of certain provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inapplicability of certain provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_7e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Independent evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>