<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–3b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–3b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–3b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_3b"><akn:num>247d–3b</akn:num><akn:heading>Partnerships for State and regional hospital preparedness to improve surge capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–3b. Partnerships for State and regional hospital preparedness to improve surge capacity(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall award competitive grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to enable such entities to improve surge capacity and enhance community and hospital preparedness for, and response to, public health emergencies in accordance with subsection (c), including, as appropriate, capacity and preparedness to address the needs of children and other at-risk individuals.


(b) EligibilityTo be eligible for an award under subsection (a), an entity shall—(1)(A) be a coalition that includes—(i) one or more hospitals, at least one of which shall be a designated trauma center, consistent with section 300d–13(c) of this title;

(ii) one or more other local health care facilities, including clinics, health centers, community health centers, primary care facilities, mental health centers, mobile medical assets, or nursing homes;

(iii)(I) one or more political subdivisions;

(II) one or more States; or

(III) one or more States and one or more political subdivisions; and


(iv) one or more emergency medical service organizations or emergency management organizations; and


(B) prepare, in consultation with the Chief Executive Officer and the lead health officials of the State, District, or territory in which the hospital and health care facilities described in subparagraph (A) are located, and submit to the Secretary, an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require; or


(2)(A) be an entity described in section 247d–3a(b)(1) of this title; and

(B) submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including the information or assurances required under section 247d–3a(b)(2) of this title and an assurance that the State will adhere to any applicable guidelines esta</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall award competitive grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to enable such entities to improve surge capacity and enhance community and hospital preparedness for, and response to, public health emergencies in accordance with subsection (c), including, as appropriate, capacity and preparedness to address the needs of children and other at-risk individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility To be eligible for an award under subsection (a), an entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds An award under subsection (a) shall be expended for activities to achieve the preparedness goals described under paragraphs (1), (3), (4), (5), and (6) of section 300hh–1(b) of this title with respect to all-hazards, including chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear threats.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preferences</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consistency of planned activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consistency of planned activities The Secretary may not award a cooperative agreement to an eligible entity described in subsection (b)(1) unless the application submitted by the entity is coordinated and consistent with an applicable State All-Hazards Public Health Emergency Preparedness and Response Plan and relevant local plans, as determined by the Secretary in consultation with relevant State health officials.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on awards A political subdivision shall not participate in more than one coalition described in subsection (b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maintenance of funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance and accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Performance and accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_3b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>