<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/247d–6e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_247d_6e"><akn:num>247d–6e</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered countermeasure process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 247d–6e. Covered countermeasure process(a) Establishment of FundUpon the issuance by the Secretary of a declaration under section 247d–6d(b) of this title, there is hereby established in the Treasury an emergency fund designated as the “Covered Countermeasure Process Fund” for purposes of providing timely, uniform, and adequate compensation to eligible individuals for covered injuries directly caused by the administration or use of a covered countermeasure pursuant to such declaration, which Fund shall consist of such amounts designated as emergency appropriations under section 402 of H. Con. Res. 95 of the 109th Congress, this emergency designation shall remain in effect through October 1, 2006.


(b) Payment of compensation(1) In generalIf the Secretary issues a declaration under 247d–6d(b) of this title, the Secretary shall, after amounts have by law been provided for the Fund under subsection (a), provide compensation to an eligible individual for a covered injury directly caused by the administration or use of a covered countermeasure pursuant to such declaration.


(2) Elements of compensationThe compensation that shall be provided pursuant to paragraph (1) shall have the same elements, and be in the same amount, as is prescribed by sections 239c, 239d, and 239e of this title in the case of certain individuals injured as a result of administration of certain countermeasures against smallpox, except that section 239e(a)(2)(B) of this title shall not apply.


(3) Rule of constructionNeither reasonable and necessary medical benefits nor lifetime total benefits for lost employment income due to permanent and total disability shall be limited by section 239e of this title.


(4) Determination of eligibility and compensationExcept as provided in this section, the procedures for determining, and for reviewing a determination of, whether an individual is an eligible individual, whether such individual has sustained a covered injury, whether compensation may be avail</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Fund Upon the issuance by the Secretary of a declaration under section 247d–6d(b) of this title, there is hereby established in the Treasury an emergency fund designated as the “Covered Countermeasure Process Fund” for purposes of providing timely, uniform, and adequate compensation to eligible individuals for covered injuries directly caused by the administration or use of a covered countermeasure pursuant to such declaration, which Fund shall consist of such amounts designated as emergency appropriations under section 402 of H. Con. Res. 95 of the 109th Congress, this emergency designation shall remain in effect through October 1, 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payment of compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Voluntary program The Secretary shall ensure that a State, local, or Department of Health and Human Services plan to administer or use a covered countermeasure is consistent with any declaration under 247d–6d of this title and any applicable guidelines of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and that potential participants are educated with respect to contraindications, the voluntary nature of the program, and the availability of potential benefits and compensation under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exhaustion; exclusivity; election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exhaustion; exclusivity; election</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_247d_6e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section, the following terms shall have the following meanings:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>