<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/249" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/249/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/249/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_249"><akn:num>249</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical care and treatment of quarantined and detained persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 249. Medical care and treatment of quarantined and detained persons(a) Persons entitled to treatmentAny person when detained in accordance with quarantine laws, or, at the request of the Immigration and Naturalization Service, any person detained by that Service, may be treated and cared for by the Public Health Service.


(b) Temporary treatment in emergency casesPersons not entitled to treatment and care at institutions, hospitals, and stations of the Service may, in accordance with regulations of the Surgeon General, be admitted thereto for temporary treatment and care in case of emergency.


(c) Authorization for outside treatmentPersons whose care and treatment is authorized by subsection (a) may, in accordance with regulations, receive such care and treatment at the expense of the Service from public or private medical or hospital facilities other than those of the Service, when authorized by the officer in charge of the station at which the application is made.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 322, 58 Stat. 696; June 25, 1948, ch. 654, § 3, 62 Stat. 1018; Aug. 8, 1956, ch. 1036, § 3, 70 Stat. 1120; Pub. L. 88–424, Aug. 13, 1964, 78 Stat. 398; Pub. L. 90–174, § 10(c), Dec. 5, 1967, 81 Stat. 541; Pub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 986(a), (b)(1), (2), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 603.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1981—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 97–35, § 986(a), (b)(2), redesignated subsec. (c) as (a). Former subsec. (a), which related to persons entitled to medical, etc., treatment and hospitalization, was struck out.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 97–35, § 986(a), (b)(2), redesignated subsec. (d) as (b). Former subsec. (b), which related to treatment for seamen on foreign-flag vessels, was struck out.
Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 97–35, § 986(b)(1), (2), redesignated subsec. (e) as (c), substituted “subsection (a)” for “subsection (c)”, and struck out “entitled to care and treatment under subsection (a) of this section and persons” after “Persons”. Former subsec. (c) redesignated (a).
Subs</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_249_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Persons entitled to treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Persons entitled to treatment Any person when detained in accordance with quarantine laws, or, at the request of the Immigration and Naturalization Service, any person detained by that Service, may be treated and cared for by the Public Health Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_249_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary treatment in emergency cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Temporary treatment in emergency cases Persons not entitled to treatment and care at institutions, hospitals, and stations of the Service may, in accordance with regulations of the Surgeon General, be admitted thereto for temporary treatment and care in case of emergency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_249_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for outside treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization for outside treatment Persons whose care and treatment is authorized by subsection (a) may, in accordance with regulations, receive such care and treatment at the expense of the Service from public or private medical or hospital facilities other than those of the Service, when authorized by the officer in charge of the station at which the application is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>