<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254b_1"><akn:num>254b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>State grants to health care providers who provide services to a high percentage of medically underse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254b–1. State grants to health care providers who provide services to a high percentage of medically underserved populations or other special populations(a) In generalA State may award grants to health care providers who treat a high percentage, as determined by such State, of medically underserved populations or other special populations in such State.


(b) Source of fundsA grant program established by a State under subsection (a) may not be established within a department, agency, or other entity of such State that administers the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.), and no Federal or State funds allocated to such Medicaid program, the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.), or the TRICARE program under chapter 55 of title 10 may be used to award grants or to pay administrative costs associated with a grant program established under subsection (a).


(Pub. L. 111–148, title V, § 5606, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title X, § 10501(k), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 999.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Social Security Act, referred to in subsec. (b), is act Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, 49 Stat. 620. Titles XVIII and XIX of the Act are classified generally to subchapters XVIII (§ 1395 et seq.) and XIX (§ 1396 et seq.), respectively, of chapter 7 of this title. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see section 1305 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A State may award grants to health care providers who treat a high percentage, as determined by such State, of medically underserved populations or other special populations in such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Source of funds A grant program established by a State under subsection (a) may not be established within a department, agency, or other entity of such State that administers the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.), and no Federal or State funds allocated to such Medicaid program, the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.), or the TRICARE program under chapter 55 of title 10 may be used to award grants or to pay administrative costs associated with a grant program established under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>