<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254c"><akn:num>254c</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural health care services outreach, rural health network development, and small health care provide</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254c. Rural health care services outreach, rural health network development, and small health care provider quality improvement grant programs(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide grants for expanded delivery of health care services in rural areas, for the planning and implementation of integrated health care networks in rural areas, and for the planning and implementation of small health care provider quality improvement activities.


(b) Definitions(1) DirectorThe term “Director” means the Director specified in subsection (d).


(2) Federally qualified health center; rural health clinicThe terms “Federally qualified health center” and “rural health clinic” have the meanings given the terms in section 1395x(aa) of this title.


(3) Health professional shortage areaThe term “health professional shortage area” means a health professional shortage area designated under section 254e of this title.


(4) Medically underserved communityThe term “medically underserved community” has the meaning given the term in section 295p(6) of this title.


(5) Medically underserved populationThe term “medically underserved population” has the meaning given the term in section 254b(b)(3) of this title.



(c) ProgramThe Secretary shall establish, under section 241 of this title, a small health care provider quality improvement grant program.


(d) Administration(1) ProgramsThe rural health care services outreach, rural health network development, and small health care provider quality improvement grant programs established under section 241 of this title shall be administered by the Director of the Office of Rural Health Policy of the Health Resources and Services Administration, in consultation with State offices of rural health or other appropriate State government entities.


(2) Grants(A) In generalIn carrying out the programs described in paragraph (1), the Director may award grants under subsections (e), (f), and (g) to expand access to, coordinate, and improve </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide grants for expanded delivery of health care services in rural areas, for the planning and implementation of integrated health care networks in rural areas, and for the planning and implementation of small health care provider quality improvement activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program The Secretary shall establish, under section 241 of this title, a small health care provider quality improvement grant program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural health care services outreach grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rural health care services outreach grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rural health network development grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rural health network development grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small health care provider quality improvement grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Small health care provider quality improvement grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>General requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) General requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report Not later than 4 years after March 27, 2020, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report on the activities and outcomes of the grant programs under subsections (e), (f), and (g), including the impact of projects funded under such programs on the health status of rural residents with chronic conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $79,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>