<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254c–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254c_16"><akn:num>254c–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health services delivered via telehealth</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254c–16. Mental health services delivered via telehealth(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means a public or nonprofit private telehealth provider network that offers services that include mental health services provided by qualified mental health providers.


(2) Qualified mental health professionalsThe term “qualified mental health professionals” refers to providers of mental health services reimbursed under the medicare program carried out under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.) who have additional training in the treatment of mental illness in children and adolescents or who have additional training in the treatment of mental illness in the elderly.


(3) Special populationsThe term “special populations” refers to the following 2 distinct groups:(A) Children and adolescents in mental health underserved rural areas or in mental health underserved urban areas.

(B) Elderly individuals located in long-term care facilities in mental health underserved rural or urban areas.


(4) TelehealthThe term “telehealth” means the use of electronic information and telecommunications technologies to support long distance clinical health care, patient and professional health-related education, public health, and health administration.



(b) Program authorized(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office for the Advancement of Telehealth of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants to eligible entities to establish demonstration projects for the provision of mental health services to special populations as delivered remotely by qualified mental health professionals using telehealth and for the provision of education regarding mental illness as delivered remotely by qualified mental health professionals using telehealth.


(2) Populations servedThe Secretary shall award the grants under paragraph (1) in a manner that distributes the grants so as to serve e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program authorized</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Equitable distribution In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall ensure, to the greatest extent possible, that such grants are equitably distributed among geographical regions of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application An entity that desires a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be reasonable.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report Not later than 4 years after October 26, 2002, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that shall evaluate activities funded with grants under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254c_16_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2002 and such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2003 through 2006.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>