<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254d"><akn:num>254d</akn:num><akn:heading>National Health Service Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254d. National Health Service Corps(a) Establishment; composition; purpose; definitions(1) For the purpose of eliminating health manpower shortages in health professional shortage areas, there is established, within the Service, the National Health Service Corps, which shall consist of—(A) such officers of the Regular and Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Service as the Secretary may designate,

(B) such civilian employees of the United States as the Secretary may appoint, and

(C) such other individuals who are not employees of the United States.


(2) The Corps shall be utilized by the Secretary to provide primary health services in health professional shortage areas.

(3) For purposes of this subpart and subpart III:(A) The term “Corps” means the National Health Service Corps.

(B) The term “Corps member” means each of the officers, employees, and individuals of which the Corps consists pursuant to paragraph (1).

(C) The term “health professional shortage area” has the meaning given such term in section 254e(a) of this title.

(D) The term “primary health services” means health services regarding family medicine, internal medicine, pediatrics, obstetrics and gynecology, dentistry, or mental health, that are provided by physicians or other health professionals.

(E)(i) The term “behavioral and mental health professionals” means health service psychologists, licensed clinical social workers, licensed professional counselors, marriage and family therapists, psychiatric nurse specialists, and psychiatrists.

(ii) The term “graduate program of behavioral and mental health” means a program that trains behavioral and mental health professionals.




(b) Recruitment and fellowship programs(1) The Secretary may conduct at schools of medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, and, as appropriate, nursing and other schools of the health professions, including schools at which graduate programs of behavioral and mental health are offered, and at entit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; composition; purpose; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; composition; purpose; definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment and fellowship programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recruitment and fellowship programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Travel and moving expenses; persons entitled; reimbursement; limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Travel and moving expenses; persons entitled; reimbursement; limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monthly pay adjustments of members directly engaged in delivery of health services in health professional shortage area; “monthly pay” defined; monthly pay adjustment of member with service obligation incurred under Scholarship Program or Loan Repayment Program; personnel system applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monthly pay adjustments of members directly engaged in delivery of health services in health professional shortage area; “monthly pay” defined; monthly pay adjustment of member with service obligation incurred under Scholarship Program or Loan Repayment Program; personnel system applicable</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment ceiling of Department not affected by Corps members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employment ceiling of Department not affected by Corps members Corps members assigned under section 254f of this title to provide health services in health professional shortage areas shall not be counted against any employment ceiling affecting the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of personnel provisions inapplicable to members whose service obligation incurred under Scholarship Program or Loan Repayment Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Assignment of personnel provisions inapplicable to members whose service obligation incurred under Scholarship Program or Loan Repayment Program Sections 215 and 217 of this title shall not apply to members of the National Health Service Corps during their period of obligated service under the Scholarship Program or the Loan Repayment Program, except when such members are Commissioned Corps officers who entered into a contract with 33 So in original. The word “the” probably should appear. Secretary under section 254l or 254l–1 of this title after December 31, 2006 and when the Secretary determines that exercising the authority provided under section 215 or 217 of this title with respect to any such officer to 44 So in original. would not cause unreasonable disruption to health care services provided in the community in which such officer is providing health care services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conversion from Corps member to commissioned officer; retirement credits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Conversion from Corps member to commissioned officer; retirement credits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective administration of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Effective administration of program The Secretary shall ensure that adequate staff is provided to the Service with respect to effectively administering the program for the Corps.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects; waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Demonstration projects; waivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254d_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions For the purposes of this subpart and subpart III:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>