<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254e"><akn:num>254e</akn:num><akn:heading>Health professional shortage areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254e. Health professional shortage areas(a) Designation by Secretary; removal from areas designated; “medical facility” defined(1) For purposes of this subpart the term “health professional shortage area” means (A) an area in an urban or rural area (which need not conform to the geographic boundaries of a political subdivision and which is a rational area for the delivery of health services) which the Secretary determines has a health manpower shortage and which is not reasonably accessible to an adequately served area, (B) a population group which the Secretary determines has such a shortage, or (C) a public or nonprofit private medical facility or other public facility which the Secretary determines has such a shortage. All Federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics, as defined in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)), that meet the requirements of section 254g of this title shall be automatically designated as having such a shortage. The Secretary shall not remove an area from the areas determined to be health professional shortage areas under subparagraph (A) of the preceding sentence until the Secretary has afforded interested persons and groups in such area an opportunity to provide data and information in support of the designation as a health professional shortage area or a population group described in subparagraph (B) of such sentence or a facility described in subparagraph (C) of such sentence, and has made a determination on the basis of the data and information submitted by such persons and groups and other data and information available to the Secretary.

(2) For purposes of this subsection, the term “medical facility” means a facility for the delivery of health services and includes—(A) a hospital, State mental hospital, public health center, outpatient medical facility, rehabilitation facility, facility for long-term care, community mental health center, migrant health center, facility operated by a city</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation by Secretary; removal from areas designated; “medical facility” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation by Secretary; removal from areas designated; “medical facility” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for designation of health professional shortage areas; promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria for designation of health professional shortage areas; promulgation of regulations The Secretary shall establish by regulation criteria for the designation of areas, population groups, medical facilities, and other public facilities, in the States, as health professional shortage areas. In establishing such criteria, the Secretary shall take into consideration the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in determination of designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Considerations in determination of designation In determining whether to make a designation, the Secretary shall take into consideration the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation; publication of descriptive lists</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designation; publication of descriptive lists</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of proposed designation of areas and facilities; time for comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Notice of proposed designation of areas and facilities; time for comment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of designation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notice of designation The Secretary shall give written notice of the designation of a health professional shortage area, not later than 60 days from the date of such designation, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Recommendations to Secretary Any person may recommend to the Secretary the designation of an area, population group, medical facility, or other public facility as a health professional shortage area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public information programs in designated areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Public information programs in designated areas The Secretary may conduct such information programs in areas, among population groups, and in medical facilities and other public facilities designated under this section as health professional shortage areas as may be necessary to inform public and nonprofit private entities which are located or have a demonstrated interest in such areas of the assistance available under this subchapter by virtue of the designation of such areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Dissemination The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration shall disseminate information concerning the designation criteria described in subsection (b) to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254e_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Regulations and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>