<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254m"><akn:num>254m</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligated service under contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254m. Obligated service under contract(a) Service in full-time clinical practiceExcept as provided in section 254n of this title, each individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254l or 254l–1 of this title shall provide service in the full-time clinical practice of such individual’s profession as a member of the Corps for the period of obligated service provided in such contract. The Secretary may treat teaching as clinical practice for up to 20 percent of such period of obligated service. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, with respect to a member of the Corps participating in the teaching health centers graduate medical education program under section 256h of this title, for the purpose of calculating time spent in full-time clinical practice under this section, up to 50 percent of time spent teaching by such member may be counted toward his or her service obligation.


(b) Notice to individual; information for informed decision; eligibility; notice to Secretary; qualification and appointment as commissioned officer; appointment as civilian member; designation of non-United States employee as member; deferment of obligated service(1) If an individual is required under subsection (a) to provide service as specified in section 254l(f)(1)(B)(v) or 254l–1(f)(1)(B)(iv) of this title (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as “obligated service”), the Secretary shall, not later than ninety days before the date described in paragraph (5), determine if the individual shall provide such service—(A) as a member of the Corps who is a commissioned officer in the Regular or Reserve Corps 11 See Change of Name note below. of the Service or who is a civilian employee of the United States, or

(B) as a member of the Corps who is not such an officer or employee,


and shall notify such individual of such determination.

(2) If the Secretary determines that an individual shall provide obligated service as a member of the Corps wh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service in full-time clinical practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Service in full-time clinical practice Except as provided in section 254n of this title, each individual who has entered into a written contract with the Secretary under section 254l or 254l–1 of this title shall provide service in the full-time clinical practice of such individual’s profession as a member of the Corps for the period of obligated service provided in such contract. The Secretary may treat teaching as clinical practice for up to 20 percent of such period of obligated service. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, with respect to a member of the Corps participating in the teaching health centers graduate medical education program under section 256h of this title, for the purpose of calculating time spent in full-time clinical practice under this section, up to 50 percent of time spent teaching by such member may be counted toward his or her service obligation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to individual; information for informed decision; eligibility; notice to Secretary; qualification and appointment as commissioned officer; appointment as civilian member; designation of non-United States employee as member; deferment of obligated service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice to individual; information for informed decision; eligibility; notice to Secretary; qualification and appointment as commissioned officer; appointment as civilian member; designation of non-United States employee as member; deferment of obligated service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Obligated service period; commencement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Obligated service period; commencement An individual shall be considered to have begun serving a period of obligated service— whichever is earlier.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assignment of personnel The Secretary shall assign individuals performing obligated service in accordance with a written contract under the Scholarship Program to health professional shortage areas in accordance with sections 254d through 254h and sections 254j and 254k of this title. If the Secretary determines that there is no need in a health professional shortage area (designated under section 254e of this title) for a member of the profession in which an individual is obligated to provide service under a written contract and if such individual is an officer in the Service or a civilian employee of the United States, the Secretary may detail such individual to serve his period of obligated service as a full-time member of such profession in such unit of the Department as the Secretary may determine.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>