<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254t"><akn:num>254t</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254t. Demonstration project(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary shall establish a demonstration project to provide for the participation of individuals who are chiropractic doctors or pharmacists in the Loan Repayment Program described in section 254l–1 of this title.


(b) ProcedureAn individual that receives assistance under this section with regard to the program described in section 254l–1 of this title shall comply with all rules and requirements described in such section (other than subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 254l–1(b)(1) of this title) in order to receive assistance under this section.


(c) Limitations(1) In generalThe demonstration project described in this section shall provide for the participation of individuals who shall provide services in rural and urban areas.


(2) Availability of other health professionalsThe Secretary may not assign an individual receiving assistance under this section to provide obligated service at a site unless—(A) the Secretary has assigned a physician (as defined in section 1395x(r) of this title) or other health professional licensed to prescribe drugs to provide obligated service at such site under section 254m or 254n of this title; and

(B) such physician or other health professional will provide obligated service at such site concurrently with the individual receiving assistance under this section.


(3) Rules of construction(A) Supervision of individualsNothing in this section shall be construed to require or imply that a physician or other health professional licensed to prescribe drugs must supervise an individual receiving assistance under the demonstration project under this section, with respect to such project.


(B) Licensure of health professionalsNothing in this section shall be construed to supersede State law regarding licensure of health professionals.




(d) DesignationsThe demonstration project described in this section, and any providers who are selected to participate in such project, shall n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary shall establish a demonstration project to provide for the participation of individuals who are chiropractic doctors or pharmacists in the Loan Repayment Program described in section 254l–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure An individual that receives assistance under this section with regard to the program described in section 254l–1 of this title shall comply with all rules and requirements described in such section (other than subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 254l–1(b)(1) of this title) in order to receive assistance under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Designations The demonstration project described in this section, and any providers who are selected to participate in such project, shall not be considered by the Secretary in the designation of a health professional shortage area under section 254e of this title during fiscal years 2002 through 2004.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction This section shall not be construed to require any State to participate in the project described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254t_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>