<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254u" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254u/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/254u/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_254u"><akn:num>254u</akn:num><akn:heading>Public health departments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 254u. Public health departments(a) In generalTo the extent that funds are appropriated under subsection (e), the Secretary shall establish a demonstration project to provide for the participation of individuals who are eligible for the Loan Repayment Program described in section 254l–1 of this title and who agree to complete their service obligation in a State health department that provides a significant amount of service to health professional shortage areas or areas at risk of a public health emergency, as determined by the Secretary, or in a local or tribal health department that serves a health professional shortage area or an area at risk of a public health emergency.


(b) ProcedureTo be eligible to receive assistance under subsection (a), with respect to the program described in section 254l–1 of this title, an individual shall—(1) comply with all rules and requirements described in such section (other than section 254l–1(f)(1)(B)(iv) of this title); and

(2) agree to serve for a time period equal to 2 years, or such longer period as the individual may agree to, in a State, local, or tribal health department, described in subsection (a).


(c) DesignationsThe demonstration project described in subsection (a), and any healthcare providers who are selected to participate in such project, shall not be considered by the Secretary in the designation of health professional shortage areas under section 254e of this title during fiscal years 2007 through 2010.


(d) ReportNot later than 3 years after December 19, 2006, the Secretary shall submit a report to the relevant committees of Congress that evaluates the participation of individuals in the demonstration project under subsection (a), the impact of such participation on State, local, and tribal health departments, and the benefit and feasibility of permanently allowing such placements in the Loan Repayment Program.


(e) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254u_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general To the extent that funds are appropriated under subsection (e), the Secretary shall establish a demonstration project to provide for the participation of individuals who are eligible for the Loan Repayment Program described in section 254l–1 of this title and who agree to complete their service obligation in a State health department that provides a significant amount of service to health professional shortage areas or areas at risk of a public health emergency, as determined by the Secretary, or in a local or tribal health department that serves a health professional shortage area or an area at risk of a public health emergency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254u_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure To be eligible to receive assistance under subsection (a), with respect to the program described in section 254l–1 of this title, an individual shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254u_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designations The demonstration project described in subsection (a), and any healthcare providers who are selected to participate in such project, shall not be considered by the Secretary in the designation of health professional shortage areas under section 254e of this title during fiscal years 2007 through 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254u_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 3 years after December 19, 2006, the Secretary shall submit a report to the relevant committees of Congress that evaluates the participation of individuals in the demonstration project under subsection (a), the impact of such participation on State, local, and tribal health departments, and the benefit and feasibility of permanently allowing such placements in the Loan Repayment Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_254u_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2007 through 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>