<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_256b"><akn:num>256b</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on prices of drugs purchased by covered entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 256b. Limitation on prices of drugs purchased by covered entities(a) Requirements for agreement with Secretary(1) In generalThe Secretary shall enter into an agreement with each manufacturer of covered outpatient drugs under which the amount required to be paid (taking into account any rebate or discount, as provided by the Secretary) to the manufacturer for covered outpatient drugs (other than drugs described in paragraph (3)) purchased by a covered entity on or after the first day of the first month that begins after November 4, 1992, does not exceed an amount equal to the average manufacturer price for the drug under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] in the preceding calendar quarter, reduced by the rebate percentage described in paragraph (2). Each such agreement shall require that the manufacturer furnish the Secretary with reports, on a quarterly basis, of the price for each covered outpatient drug subject to the agreement that, according to the manufacturer, represents the maximum price that covered entities may permissibly be required to pay for the drug (referred to in this section as the “ceiling price”), and shall require that the manufacturer offer each covered entity covered outpatient drugs for purchase at or below the applicable ceiling price if such drug is made available to any other purchaser at any price.


(2) “Rebate percentage” defined(A) In generalFor a covered outpatient drug purchased in a calendar quarter, the “rebate percentage” is the amount (expressed as a percentage) equal to—(i) the average total rebate required under section 1927(c) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(c)] with respect to the drug (for a unit of the dosage form and strength involved) during the preceding calendar quarter; divided by

(ii) the average manufacturer price for such a unit of the drug during such quarter.


(B) Over the counter drugs(i) In generalFor purposes of subparagraph (A), in the case of over the counter drugs,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for agreement with Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements for agreement with Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 111–152, title II, § 2302(2), Mar. 30, 2010, 124 Stat. 1083</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improvements in program integrity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Improvements in program integrity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of orphan drugs for certain covered entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of orphan drugs for certain covered entities For covered entities described in subparagraph (M) (other than a children’s hospital described in subparagraph (M)), (N), or (O) of subsection (a)(4), the term “covered outpatient drug” shall not include a drug designated by the Secretary under section 360bb of title 21 for a rare disease or condition.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>