<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_256e"><akn:num>256e</akn:num><akn:heading>Program of payments to children’s hospitals that operate graduate medical education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 256e. Program of payments to children’s hospitals that operate graduate medical education programs(a) PaymentsThe Secretary shall make two payments under this section to each children’s hospital for each of fiscal years 2000 through 2005, each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011, each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018, and each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, one for the direct expenses and the other for indirect expenses associated with operating approved graduate medical residency training programs. The Secretary shall promulgate regulations pursuant to the rulemaking requirements of title 5 which shall govern payments made under this subpart.


(b) Amount of payments(1) In generalSubject to paragraphs (2) and (3), the amounts payable under this section to a children’s hospital for an approved graduate medical residency training program for a fiscal year are each of the following amounts:(A) Direct expense amountThe amount determined under subsection (c) for direct expenses associated with operating approved graduate medical residency training programs.


(B) Indirect expense amountThe amount determined under subsection (d) for indirect expenses associated with the treatment of more severely ill patients and the additional costs relating to teaching residents in such programs.



(2) Capped amount(A) In generalThe total of the payments made to children’s hospitals under paragraph (1)(A) or paragraph (1)(B) in a fiscal year shall not exceed the funds appropriated under paragraph (1) or (2), respectively, of subsection (f) for such payments for that fiscal year.


(B) Pro rata reductions of payments for direct expensesIf the Secretary determines that the amount of funds appropriated under subsection (f)(1) for a fiscal year is insufficient to provide the total amount of payments otherwise due for such periods under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall reduce the amounts so payable on a pro rata basis to reflect such shortfall.



(3) Annual reporting required(A)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments The Secretary shall make two payments under this section to each children’s hospital for each of fiscal years 2000 through 2005, each of fiscal years 2007 through 2011, each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018, and each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023, one for the direct expenses and the other for indirect expenses associated with operating approved graduate medical residency training programs. The Secretary shall promulgate regulations pursuant to the rulemaking requirements of title 5 which shall govern payments made under this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment for direct graduate medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of payment for direct graduate medical education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment for indirect medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of payment for indirect medical education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Making of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Making of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256e_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>