<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_256h"><akn:num>256h</akn:num><akn:heading>Program of payments to teaching health centers that operate graduate medical education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 256h. Program of payments to teaching health centers that operate graduate medical education programs(a) Payments(1) In generalSubject to subsection (h)(2), the Secretary shall make payments under this section for direct expenses and indirect expenses to qualified teaching health centers that are listed as sponsoring institutions by the relevant accrediting body for, as appropriate—(A) maintenance of filled positions at existing approved graduate medical residency training programs;

(B) expansion of existing approved graduate medical residency training programs; and

(C) establishment of new approved graduate medical residency training programs.


(2) Per resident amountIn making payments under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the cost of training residents at teaching health centers and the implications of the per resident amount on approved graduate medical residency training programs at teaching health centers.


(3) PriorityIn making payments under paragraph (1)(C), the Secretary shall give priority to qualified teaching health centers that—(A) serve a health professional shortage area with a designation in effect under section 254e of this title or a medically underserved community (as defined in section 295p of this title); or

(B) are located in a rural area (as defined in section 1395ww(d)(2)(D) of this title).



(b) Amount of payments(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (2), the amounts payable under this section to qualified teaching health centers for an approved graduate medical residency training program for a fiscal year are each of the following amounts:(A) Direct expense amountThe amount determined under subsection (c) for direct expenses associated with sponsoring approved graduate medical residency training programs.


(B) Indirect expense amountThe amount determined under subsection (d) for indirect expenses associated with the additional costs relating to teaching residents in such programs.



(2) Capped amount(A) In generalThe tota</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment for direct graduate medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of payment for direct graduate medical education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of payment for indirect medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of payment for indirect medical education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification regarding relationship to other payments for graduate medical education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Clarification regarding relationship to other payments for graduate medical education Payments under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reconciliation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reconciliation The Secretary shall determine any changes to the number of residents reported by a teaching health center in the application of the teaching health center for the current fiscal year to determine the final amount payable to the teaching health center for the current fiscal year for both direct expense and indirect expense amounts. Based on such determination, the Secretary shall recoup any overpayments made to pay any balance due to the extent possible. The final amount so determined shall be considered a final intermediary determination for the purposes of section 1395oo of this title and shall be subject to administrative and judicial review under that section in the same manner as the amount of payment under section 1395ww(d) 22 See References in Text note below. of this title is subject to review under such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reporting required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Annual reporting required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations The Secretary shall promulgate regulations to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256h_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>