<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/256i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_256i"><akn:num>256i</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based collaborative care network program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 256i. Community-based collaborative care network program(a) In generalThe Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to support community-based collaborative care networks that meet the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) Community-based collaborative care networks(1) DescriptionA community-based collaborative care network (referred to in this section as a “network”) shall be a consortium of health care providers with a joint governance structure (including providers within a single entity) that provides comprehensive coordinated and integrated health care services (as defined by the Secretary) for low-income populations.


(2) Required inclusionA network shall include the following providers (unless such provider does not exist within the community, declines or refuses to participate, or places unreasonable conditions on their participation):(A) A hospital that meets the criteria in section 1396r–4(b)(1) of this title; and

(B) All Federally qualified health centers (as defined in section 1395x(aa) of this title 11 So in original. A closing parenthesis probably should appear. located in the community.


(3) PriorityIn awarding grants, the Secretary shall give priority to networks that include—(A) the capability to provide the broadest range of services to low-income individuals;

(B) the broadest range of providers that currently serve a high volume of low-income individuals; and

(C) a county or municipal department of health.



(c) Application(1) ApplicationA network described in subsection (b) shall submit an application to the Secretary.


(2) RenewalIn subsequent years, based on the performance of grantees, the Secretary may provide renewal grants to prior year grant recipients.



(d) Use of funds(1) Use by granteesGrant funds may be used for the following activities:(A) Assist low-income individuals to—(i) access and appropriately use health services;

(ii) enroll in health coverage programs; and

(iii) obtain a regular primary care provider or a m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to support community-based collaborative care networks that meet the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based collaborative care networks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Community-based collaborative care networks</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256i_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_256i_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>