<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/262" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/262/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/262/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_262"><akn:num>262</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulation of biological products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 262. Regulation of biological products(a) Biologics license(1) No person shall introduce or deliver for introduction into interstate commerce any biological product unless—(A) a biologics license under this subsection or subsection (k) is in effect for the biological product; and

(B) each package of the biological product is plainly marked with—(i) the proper name of the biological product contained in the package;

(ii) the name, address, and applicable license number of the manufacturer of the biological product; and

(iii) the expiration date of the biological product.



(2)(A) The Secretary shall establish, by regulation, requirements for the approval, suspension, and revocation of biologics licenses.

(B) Pediatric studies.—A person that submits an application for a license under this paragraph shall submit to the Secretary as part of the application any assessments required under section 505B of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 355c].

(C) The Secretary shall approve a biologics license application—(i) on the basis of a demonstration that—(I) the biological product that is the subject of the application is safe, pure, and potent; and

(II) the facility in which the biological product is manufactured, processed, packed, or held meets standards designed to assure that the biological product continues to be safe, pure, and potent; and


(ii) if the applicant (or other appropriate person) consents to the inspection of the facility that is the subject of the application, in accordance with subsection (c).


(D) Postmarket studies and clinical trials; labeling; risk evaluation and mitigation strategy.—A person that submits an application for a license under this paragraph is subject to sections 505(o), 505(p), and 505–1 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 355(o), (p), 355–1].

(E)(i) The Secretary may rely upon qualified data summaries to support the approval of a supplemental application, with respect to a qualified indicat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biologics license</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Biologics license</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Falsely labeling or marking package or container; altering label or mark</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Falsely labeling or marking package or container; altering label or mark No person shall falsely label or mark any package or container of any biological product or alter any label or mark on the package or container of the biological product so as to falsify the label or mark.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspection of establishment for propagation and preparation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Inspection of establishment for propagation and preparation Any officer, agent, or employee of the Department of Health and Human Services, authorized by the Secretary for the purpose, may during all reasonable hours enter and inspect any establishment for the propagation or manufacture and preparation of any biological product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recall of product presenting imminent hazard; violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recall of product presenting imminent hazard; violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interference with officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interference with officers No person shall interfere with any officer, agent, or employee of the Service in the performance of any duty imposed upon him by this section or by regulations made by authority thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for offenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Penalties for offenses Any person who shall violate, or aid or abet in violating, any of the provisions of this section shall be punished upon conviction by a fine not exceeding $500 or by imprisonment not exceeding one year, or by both such fine and imprisonment, in the discretion of the court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction with other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Construction with other laws Nothing contained in this chapter shall be construed as in any way affecting, modifying, repealing, or superseding the provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exportation of partially processed biological products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exportation of partially processed biological products A partially processed biological product which— shall be subject to no restriction on the export of the product under this chapter or the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] if the product is manufactured, processed, packaged, and held in conformity with current good manufacturing practice requirements or meets international manufacturing standards as certified by an international standards organization recognized by the Secretary and meets the requirements of section 801(e)(1) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (21 U.S.C. 381(e)).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Biological product” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) “Biological product” defined In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_262_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Application of Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.], including the requirements under sections 505(o), 505(p), and 505–1 of such Act [21 U.S.C. 355(o), (p), 355–1], applies to a biological product subject to regulation under this section, except that a product for which a license has been approved under subsection (a) shall not be required to have an approved application under section 505 of such Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>