<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/263a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/263a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/263a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_263a"><akn:num>263a</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of laboratories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 263a. Certification of laboratories(a) “Laboratory” or “clinical laboratory” definedAs used in this section, the term “laboratory” or “clinical laboratory” means a facility for the biological, microbiological, serological, chemical, immuno-hematological, hematological, biophysical, cytological, pathological, or other examination of materials derived from the human body for the purpose of providing information for the diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of any disease or impairment of, or the assessment of the health of, human beings.


(b) Certificate requirementNo person may solicit or accept materials derived from the human body for laboratory examination or other procedure unless there is in effect for the laboratory a certificate issued by the Secretary under this section applicable to the category of examinations or procedures which includes such examination or procedure.


(c) Issuance and renewal of certificates(1) In generalThe Secretary may issue or renew a certificate for a laboratory only if the laboratory meets the requirements of subsection (d).


(2) TermA certificate issued under this section shall be valid for a period of 2 years or such shorter period as the Secretary may establish.



(d) Requirements for certificates(1) In generalA laboratory may be issued a certificate or have its certificate renewed if—(A) the laboratory submits (or if the laboratory is accredited under subsection (e), the accreditation body which accredited the laboratory submits), an application—(i) in such form and manner as the Secretary shall prescribe,

(ii) that describes the characteristics of the laboratory examinations and other procedures performed by the laboratory including—(I) the number and types of laboratory examinations and other procedures performed,

(II) the methodologies for laboratory examinations and other procedures employed, and

(III) the qualifications (educational background, training, and experience) of the personnel directing and supervising the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Laboratory” or “clinical laboratory” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Laboratory” or “clinical laboratory” defined As used in this section, the term “laboratory” or “clinical laboratory” means a facility for the biological, microbiological, serological, chemical, immuno-hematological, hematological, biophysical, cytological, pathological, or other examination of materials derived from the human body for the purpose of providing information for the diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of any disease or impairment of, or the assessment of the health of, human beings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certificate requirement No person may solicit or accept materials derived from the human body for laboratory examination or other procedure unless there is in effect for the laboratory a certificate issued by the Secretary under this section applicable to the category of examinations or procedures which includes such examination or procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance and renewal of certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Issuance and renewal of certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for certificates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements for certificates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accreditation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accreditation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Inspections</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermediate sanctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Intermediate sanctions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension, revocation, and limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Suspension, revocation, and limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_263a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Injunctions Whenever the Secretary has reason to believe that continuation of any activity by a laboratory would constitute a significant hazard to the public health the Secretary may bring suit in the district court of the United States for the district in which such laboratory is situated to enjoin continuation of such activity. Upon proper showing, a temporary injunction or restraining order against continuation of such activity pending issuance of a final order under this subsection shall be granted without bond by such court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>