<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/271" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/271/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/271/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_271"><akn:num>271</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for violation of quarantine laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 271. Penalties for violation of quarantine laws(a) Penalties for persons violating quarantine lawsAny person who violates any regulation prescribed under sections 264 to 266 of this title, or any provision of section 269 of this title or any regulation prescribed thereunder, or who enters or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the quarantine officer in charge, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.


(b) Penalties for vessels violating quarantine lawsAny vessel which violates section 269 of this title, or any regulations thereunder or under section 267 of this title, or which enters within or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of the quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the officer in charge, shall forfeit to the United States not more than $5,000, the amount to be determined by the court, which shall be a lien on such vessel, to be recovered by proceedings in the proper district court of the United States. In all such proceedings the United States attorney shall appear on behalf of the United States; and all such proceedings shall be conducted in accordance with the rules and laws governing cases of seizure of vessels for violation of the revenue laws of the United States.


(c) Remittance or mitigation of forfeituresWith the approval of the Secretary, the Surgeon General may, upon application therefor, remit or mitigate any forfeiture provided for under subsection (b) of this section, and he shall have authority to ascertain the facts upon all such applications.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 368, 58 Stat. 706; June 25, 1948, ch. 646, § 1, 62 Stat. 909; 1953 Reorg. Plan No. 1, §§ 5, 8, eff. Apr. 11, 1953, 18 F.R. 2053, 67 Stat. 631.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries

Change of Name
“Secretary of Heal</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for persons violating quarantine laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Penalties for persons violating quarantine laws Any person who violates any regulation prescribed under sections 264 to 266 of this title, or any provision of section 269 of this title or any regulation prescribed thereunder, or who enters or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the quarantine officer in charge, shall be punished by a fine of not more than $1,000 or by imprisonment for not more than one year, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for vessels violating quarantine laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties for vessels violating quarantine laws Any vessel which violates section 269 of this title, or any regulations thereunder or under section 267 of this title, or which enters within or departs from the limits of any quarantine station, ground, or anchorage in disregard of the quarantine rules and regulations or without permission of the officer in charge, shall forfeit to the United States not more than $5,000, the amount to be determined by the court, which shall be a lien on such vessel, to be recovered by proceedings in the proper district court of the United States. In all such proceedings the United States attorney shall appear on behalf of the United States; and all such proceedings shall be conducted in accordance with the rules and laws governing cases of seizure of vessels for violation of the revenue laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_271_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remittance or mitigation of forfeitures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Remittance or mitigation of forfeitures With the approval of the Secretary, the Surgeon General may, upon application therefor, remit or mitigate any forfeiture provided for under subsection (b) of this section, and he shall have authority to ascertain the facts upon all such applications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>