<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274e"><akn:num>274e</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of organ purchases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274e. Prohibition of organ purchases(a) ProhibitionIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly acquire, receive, or otherwise transfer any human organ for valuable consideration for use in human transplantation if the transfer affects interstate commerce. The preceding sentence does not apply with respect to human organ paired donation.


(b) PenaltiesAny person who violates subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $50,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of subsection (a):(1) The term “human organ” means the human (including fetal) kidney, liver, heart, lung, pancreas, bone marrow, cornea, eye, bone, and skin or any subpart thereof and any other human organ (or any subpart thereof, including that derived from a fetus) specified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services by regulation.

(2) The term “valuable consideration” does not include the reasonable payments associated with the removal, transportation, implantation, processing, preservation, quality control, and storage of a human organ or the expenses of travel, housing, and lost wages incurred by the donor of a human organ in connection with the donation of the organ.

(3) The term “interstate commerce” has the meaning prescribed for it by section 321(b) of title 21.

(4) The term “human organ paired donation” means the donation and receipt of human organs under the following circumstances:(A) An individual (referred to in this paragraph as the “first donor”) desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the “first patient”), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a donor for such patient.

(B) A second individual (referred to in this paragraph as the “second donor”) desires to make a living donation of a human organ specifically to a second particular patient (referred to in this paragraph as the “second patient”), but such donor is biologically incompatible as a don</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly acquire, receive, or otherwise transfer any human organ for valuable consideration for use in human transplantation if the transfer affects interstate commerce. The preceding sentence does not apply with respect to human organ paired donation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Penalties Any person who violates subsection (a) shall be fined not more than $50,000 or imprisoned not more than five years, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of subsection (a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>