<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274i" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274i/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274i/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274i"><akn:num>274i</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility requirements for Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274i. Eligibility requirements for Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal(a) In generalSubject to the provisions of this section and the availability of funds under this part, any organ donor, or the family of any organ donor, shall be eligible for a Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal (hereafter in this part referred to as a “medal”).


(b) DocumentationThe Secretary of Health and Human Services shall direct the entity operating the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network to—(1) establish an application procedure requiring the relevant organ procurement organization through which an individual or family of the individual made an organ donation, to submit to such entity documentation supporting the eligibility of the individual or the family, respectively, to receive a medal;

(2) determine through the documentation provided and, if necessary, independent investigation whether the individual or family, respectively, is eligible to receive such a medal; and

(3) arrange for the presentation to the relevant organ procurement organization all medals struck pursuant to section 274i–2 of this title to individuals or families that are determined to be eligible to receive medals.


(c) Limitation(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), only 1 medal may be presented to a family under subsection (b). Such medal shall be presented to the donating family member, or in the case of a deceased donor, the family member who signed the consent form authorizing, or who otherwise authorized, the donation of the organ involved.


(2) ExceptionIn the case of a family in which more than 1 member is an organ donor, a medal may be presented for each such organ donor.



(Pub. L. 110–413, § 2, Oct. 14, 2008, 122 Stat. 4338.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274i_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to the provisions of this section and the availability of funds under this part, any organ donor, or the family of any organ donor, shall be eligible for a Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal (hereafter in this part referred to as a “medal”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274i_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Documentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Documentation The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall direct the entity operating the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274i_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>