<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/274l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_274l"><akn:num>274l</akn:num><akn:heading>Stem cell therapeutic outcomes database</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 274l. Stem cell therapeutic outcomes database(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall by contract establish and maintain a scientific database of information relating to patients who have been recipients of a stem cell therapeutics product (including bone marrow, cord blood, or other such product) from a donor.


(b) InformationThe outcomes database shall include information in a standardized electronic format with respect to patients described in subsection (a), diagnosis, transplant procedures, results, long-term follow-up, and such other information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, to conduct an ongoing evaluation of the scientific and clinical status of transplantation involving recipients of a stem cell therapeutics product from a donor.


(c) Annual report on patient outcomesThe Secretary shall require the entity awarded a contract under this section to submit to the Secretary an annual report concerning patient outcomes with respect to each transplant center, based on data collected and maintained by the entity pursuant to this section.


(d) Publicly available dataThe outcomes database shall make relevant scientific information not containing individually identifiable information available to the public in the form of summaries and data sets to encourage medical research and to provide information to transplant programs, physicians, patients, entities awarded a contract under section 274k of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. donor registries, and cord blood banks.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 379A, as added Pub. L. 105–196, § 3, July 16, 1998, 112 Stat. 635; amended Pub. L. 109–129, § 3(b), Dec. 20, 2005, 119 Stat. 2561.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 274l, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 379A, as added Pub. L. 101–616, title I, § 101(a)(2), Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 3282, related to study by General Accounting Office, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 105–196, §§ 3, 7, July 16, 199</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall by contract establish and maintain a scientific database of information relating to patients who have been recipients of a stem cell therapeutics product (including bone marrow, cord blood, or other such product) from a donor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information The outcomes database shall include information in a standardized electronic format with respect to patients described in subsection (a), diagnosis, transplant procedures, results, long-term follow-up, and such other information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, to conduct an ongoing evaluation of the scientific and clinical status of transplantation involving recipients of a stem cell therapeutics product from a donor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274l_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report on patient outcomes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report on patient outcomes The Secretary shall require the entity awarded a contract under this section to submit to the Secretary an annual report concerning patient outcomes with respect to each transplant center, based on data collected and maintained by the entity pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_274l_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publicly available data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publicly available data The outcomes database shall make relevant scientific information not containing individually identifiable information available to the public in the form of summaries and data sets to encourage medical research and to provide information to transplant programs, physicians, patients, entities awarded a contract under section 274k of this title 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. donor registries, and cord blood banks.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>