<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280c_3"><akn:num>280c–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements to States and public health departments for Alzheimer’s disease and related d</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280c–3. Cooperative agreements to States and public health departments for Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias(a) In generalThe Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the heads of other agencies, as appropriate, shall award cooperative agreements to health departments of States, political subdivisions of States, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations, to address Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, including by reducing cognitive decline, helping meet the needs of caregivers, and addressing unique aspects of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias to support the development and implementation of evidence-based interventions with respect to—(1) educating and informing the public, based on evidence-based public health research and data, about Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;

(2) supporting early detection and diagnosis;

(3) reducing the risk of potentially avoidable hospitalizations for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;

(4) reducing the risk of cognitive decline and cognitive impairment associated with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;

(5) improving support to meet the needs of caregivers of individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias;

(6) supporting care planning and management for individuals with Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.11 So in original. The period probably should be “; and”.

(7) supporting other relevant activities identified by the Secretary or the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, as appropriate 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(b) PreferenceIn awarding cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that focus on addressing health disparities, including populations and geographic areas that have the highest prevalence of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.


(c) EligibilityTo be eligible to r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the heads of other agencies, as appropriate, shall award cooperative agreements to health departments of States, political subdivisions of States, and Indian tribes and tribal organizations, to address Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias, including by reducing cognitive decline, helping meet the needs of caregivers, and addressing unique aspects of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias to support the development and implementation of evidence-based interventions with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preference In awarding cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall give preference to applications that focus on addressing health disparities, including populations and geographic areas that have the highest prevalence of Alzheimer’s disease and related dementias.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility To be eligible to receive a cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity (pursuant to subsection (a)) shall prepare and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching requirement Each health department that is awarded a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to 30 percent of the amount provided under such agreement (which may be provided in cash or in-kind) to carry out the activities supported by the cooperative agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver authority The Secretary may waive all or part of the matching requirement described in subsection (d) for any fiscal year for a health department of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe and tribal organization (including those located in a rural area or frontier area), if the Secretary determines that applying such matching requirement would result in serious hardship or an inability to carry out the purposes of the cooperative agreement awarded to such health department of a State, political subdivision of a State, or Indian tribe and tribal organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Non-duplication of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Non-duplication of effort The Secretary shall ensure that activities under any cooperative agreement awarded under this subpart do not unnecessarily duplicate efforts of other agencies and offices within the Department of Health and Human Services related to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to items and services under other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Relationship to items and services under other programs A State may not make payments from a cooperative agreement under subsection (a) for any item or service to the extent that payment has been made, or can reasonably be expected to be made, with respect to such item or service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>