<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280c_6"><akn:num>280c–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Projects to improve maternal, infant, and child health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280c–6. Projects to improve maternal, infant, and child health(a) In general(1) Establishment of programThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make grants to eligible entities to pay the Federal share of the cost of providing the services specified in subsection (b) to families in which a member is—(A) a pregnant woman at risk of delivering an infant with a health or developmental complication; or

(B) a child less than 3 years of age—(i) who is experiencing or is at risk of a health or developmental complication, or of child abuse or neglect; or

(ii) who has been prenatally exposed to maternal substance abuse.



(2) Minimum period of awards; administrative consultations(A) The Secretary shall award grants under paragraph (1) for periods of at least three years.

(B) The Administrator of the Administration for Children, Youth, and Families and the Director of the National Commission to Prevent Infant Mortality shall be consulted regarding the promulgation of program guidelines and funding priorities under this section.


(3) Requirement of status as medicaid provider(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary may make a grant under paragraph (1) only if, in the case of any service under such paragraph that is covered in the State plan approved under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] for the State involved—(i) the entity involved will provide the service directly, and the entity has entered into a participation agreement under the State plan and is qualified to receive payments under such plan; or

(ii) the entity will enter into an agreement with an organization under which the organization will provide the service, and the organization has entered into such a participation agreement and is qualified to receive such payments.


(B)(i) In the case of an organization making an agreement under subparagraph (A)(ii) regarding the provision of services under paragraph (1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Home visiting services for eligible families</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Home visiting services for eligible families With respect to an eligible family, each of the following services shall, directly or through arrangement with other public or nonprofit private entities, be available (as applicable to the family member involved) in each project operated with a grant under subsection (a):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in making grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Considerations in making grants In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall take into consideration—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal share With respect to the costs of carrying out a project under subsection (a), a grant under such subsection for the project may not exceed 90 percent of such costs. To be eligible to receive such a grant, an applicant must provide assurances that the applicant will obtain at least 10 percent of such costs from non-Federal funds (and such contributions to such costs may be in cash or in-kind, including facilities and personnel).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding at-risk births</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction regarding at-risk births For purposes of subsection (a)(1), a pregnant woman shall be considered to be at risk of delivering an infant with a health or developmental complication if during the pregnancy the woman—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delivery of services and case management</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Delivery of services and case management</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Outreach Each grantee under subsection (a) shall provide outreach and casefinding services to inform eligible families of the availability of home visiting services from the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Confidentiality In accordance with applicable State law, an entity receiving a grant under subsection (a) shall maintain confidentiality with respect to services provided to families under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain assurances The Secretary may award a grant under subsection (a) only if the entity involved provides assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_6_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Secretary of certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Submission to Secretary of certain information The Secretary may award a grant under subsection (a) only if the entity involved submits to the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>