<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280c–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280c_2"><akn:num>280c–2</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280c–2. General provisions(a) Limitation on administrative expensesThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless the State agrees that not more than 10 percent of the grant will be expended for administrative expenses with respect to the grant.


(b) Description of intended use of grantThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless—(1) the State submits to the Secretary a description of the purposes for which the State intends to expend the grant; and

(2) such description provides information relating to the programs and activities to be supported and services to be provided, including—(A) the number of individuals who will receive services pursuant to section 280c(a) of this title and the average costs of providing such services to each such individual; and

(B) a description of the manner in which such programs and activities will be coordinated with any similar programs and activities of public and private entities.



(c) Requirement of applicationThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless the State has submitted to the Secretary an application for the grant. The application shall—(1) contain the description of intended expenditures required in subsection (b);

(2) with respect to carrying out the purpose for which the grant is to be made, provide assurances of compliance satisfactory to the Secretary; and

(3) otherwise be in such form, be made in such manner, and contain such information and agreements as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this subpart.


(d) Evaluations and report by SecretaryThe Secretary shall—(1) provide for an evaluation of each demonstration project for which a grant is made under section 280c(a) of this title; and

(2) not later than 6 months after the completion of such evaluations, submit to the Congress a report describing the findings made as a result of the evaluations.


(e) Autho</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on administrative expenses The Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless the State agrees that not more than 10 percent of the grant will be expended for administrative expenses with respect to the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of intended use of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Description of intended use of grant The Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirement of application The Secretary may not make a grant under section 280c(a) of this title to a State unless the State has submitted to the Secretary an application for the grant. The application shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations and report by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluations and report by Secretary The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280c_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorizations of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this subpart, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 1988 through 1990, $7,500,000 for fiscal year 1991, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1992 and 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>