<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280e_3a"><akn:num>280e–3a</akn:num><akn:heading>National childhood cancer registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280e–3a. National childhood cancer registry(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make awards to State cancer registries to enhance and expand infrastructure to collect information to better understand the epidemiology of cancer in children, adolescents, and young adults. Such registries may be updated to include each occurrence of such cancers within a period of time designated by the Secretary.


(b) ActivitiesThe grants described in subsection (a) may be used for—(1) identifying, recruiting, and training potential sources for reporting childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases;

(2) developing practices to ensure early inclusion of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases in State cancer registries through the use of electronic reporting;

(3) collecting and submitting deidentified data to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for inclusion in a national database that includes information on childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancers; and

(4) improving State cancer registries and the database described in paragraph (3), as appropriate, including to support the early inclusion of childhood, adolescent, and young adult cancer cases.


(c) CoordinationTo encourage the greatest possible efficiency and effectiveness of federally supported efforts with respect to the activities described in this section, the Secretary shall ensure the appropriate coordination of programs supported under this section with other federally supported cancer registry programs and the activities under section 285a–11(a) of this title, as appropriate.


(d) Informed consent and privacy requirements and coordination with existing programsThe activities described in this section shall be subject to section 552a of title 5, the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, applicable Federal and State informed consent reg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make awards to State cancer registries to enhance and expand infrastructure to collect information to better understand the epidemiology of cancer in children, adolescents, and young adults. Such registries may be updated to include each occurrence of such cancers within a period of time designated by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities The grants described in subsection (a) may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination To encourage the greatest possible efficiency and effectiveness of federally supported efforts with respect to the activities described in this section, the Secretary shall ensure the appropriate coordination of programs supported under this section with other federally supported cancer registry programs and the activities under section 285a–11(a) of this title, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informed consent and privacy requirements and coordination with existing programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Informed consent and privacy requirements and coordination with existing programs The activities described in this section shall be subject to section 552a of title 5, the regulations promulgated under section 264(c) of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, applicable Federal and State informed consent regulations, any other applicable Federal and State laws relating to the privacy of patient information, and section 280e(d)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>