<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–11" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–11/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–11/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280e_11"><akn:num>280e–11</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment and duties of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280e–11. Establishment and duties of Foundation(a) In generalThere shall be established in accordance with this section a nonprofit private corporation to be known as the National Foundation for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this part referred to as the “Foundation”). The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government, and officers, employees, and members of the board of the Foundation shall not be officers or employees of the Federal Government.


(b) Purpose of FoundationThe purpose of the Foundation shall be to support and carry out activities for the prevention and control of diseases, disorders, injuries, and disabilities, and for promotion of public health.


(c) Endowment fund(1) In generalIn carrying out subsection (b), the Foundation shall establish a fund for providing endowments for positions that are associated with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and dedicated to the purpose described in such subsection. Subject to subsection (f)(1)(B), the fund shall consist of such donations as may be provided by non-Federal entities and such non-Federal assets of the Foundation (including earnings of the Foundation and the fund) as the Foundation may elect to transfer to the fund.


(2) Authorized expenditures of fundThe provision of endowments under paragraph (1) shall be the exclusive function of the fund established under such paragraph. Such endowments may be expended only for the compensation of individuals holding the positions, for staff, equipment, quarters, travel, and other expenditures that are appropriate in supporting the positions, and for recruiting individuals to hold the positions endowed by the fund.



(d) Certain activities of FoundationIn carrying out subsection (b), the Foundation may provide for the following with respect to the purpose described in such subsection:(1) Programs of fellowships for State and local public health officials to work and study in association with th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There shall be established in accordance with this section a nonprofit private corporation to be known as the National Foundation for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (in this part referred to as the “Foundation”). The Foundation shall not be an agency or instrumentality of the Federal Government, and officers, employees, and members of the board of the Foundation shall not be officers or employees of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose of Foundation The purpose of the Foundation shall be to support and carry out activities for the prevention and control of diseases, disorders, injuries, and disabilities, and for promotion of public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Endowment fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Endowment fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain activities of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain activities of Foundation In carrying out subsection (b), the Foundation may provide for the following with respect to the purpose described in such subsection:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General structure of Foundation; nonprofit status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General structure of Foundation; nonprofit status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Board of directors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Board of directors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain responsibilities of executive director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain responsibilities of executive director In carrying out subsection (e)(2), the Director shall carry out the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) General provisions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Federal funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_11_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Committee for establishment of Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Committee for establishment of Foundation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>