<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280e–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280e_3"><akn:num>280e–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Study in certain States to determine factors contributing to elevated breast cancer mortality rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280e–3. Study in certain States to determine factors contributing to elevated breast cancer mortality rates(a) In generalSubject to subsections (c) and (d), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Cancer Institute, shall conduct a study for the purpose of determining the factors contributing to the fact that breast cancer mortality rates in the States specified in subsection (b) are elevated compared to rates in other States.


(b) Relevant StatesThe States referred to in subsection (a) are Connecticut, Delaware, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Rhode Island, Vermont, and the District of Columbia.


(c) Cooperation of StateThe Secretary may conduct the study required in subsection (a) in a State only if the State agrees to cooperate with the Secretary in the conduct of the study, including providing information from any registry operated by the State pursuant to section 280e(a) of this title.


(d) Planning, commencement, and durationThe Secretary shall, during each of the fiscal years 1993 and 1994, develop a plan for conducting the study required in subsection (a). The study shall be initiated by the Secretary not later than fiscal year 1994, and the collection of data under the study may continue through fiscal year 1998.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title III, § 399E, formerly § 399K, as added Pub. L. 102–515, § 3, Oct. 24, 1992, 106 Stat. 3376; renumbered § 399E and amended Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title V, § 502(2)(A), (C), Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1115; Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 104(b)(2)(A), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3693.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 109–482 struck out heading and text of subsec. (e). Text read as follows: “Not later than September 30, 1999, the Secretary shall complete the study required in subsection (a) of this section and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsections (c) and (d), the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Cancer Institute, shall conduct a study for the purpose of determining the factors contributing to the fact that breast cancer mortality rates in the States specified in subsection (b) are elevated compared to rates in other States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relevant States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relevant States The States referred to in subsection (a) are Connecticut, Delaware, Maryland, Massachusetts, New Hampshire, New Jersey, New York, Rhode Island, Vermont, and the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cooperation of State The Secretary may conduct the study required in subsection (a) in a State only if the State agrees to cooperate with the Secretary in the conduct of the study, including providing information from any registry operated by the State pursuant to section 280e(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280e_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning, commencement, and duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Planning, commencement, and duration The Secretary shall, during each of the fiscal years 1993 and 1994, develop a plan for conducting the study required in subsection (a). The study shall be initiated by the Secretary not later than fiscal year 1994, and the collection of data under the study may continue through fiscal year 1998.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>