<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_4c"><akn:num>280g–4c</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding access to forensics for victims of interpersonal violence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–4c. Expanding access to forensics for victims of interpersonal violence(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Community health aide; community health practitionerThe terms “community health aide” and “community health practitioner” have the meanings given such terms for purposes of section 1616l of title 25.


(2) Health care providerThe term “health care provider” has the meaning given such term by the Secretary, and includes registered nurses, nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, clinical nurse specialists, physician assistants, and physicians.


(3) Indian tribe; Tribal organizationThe terms “Indian Tribe” and “Tribal organization” shall have the meanings given such terms in section 5304 of title 25.


(4) Institution of higher educationThe term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 1001 of title 20.


(5) Interpersonal violenceThe term “interpersonal violence” means any form of violence that is emotional and trauma-inducing for victims, families of victims, perpetrators, and communities.


(6) Native Hawaiian organizationThe term “Native Hawaiian organization” has the meaning given such term in section 11711 of this title.


(7) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.


(8) Trauma-informed careThe term “trauma-informed care” means care received by trauma survivors that is culturally competent in accordance with professional standards of practice and accounting for patients’ experiences and preferences in order to eliminate or mitigate triggers that may cause re-traumatization of the patient.


(9) Urban Indian organizationThe term “Urban Indian organization” has the meaning given such term in section 1603 of title 25.



(b) Demonstration grants for comprehensive forensic training(1) Establishment of programThe Secretary shall establish a demonstration program to award grants to eligible entities for the clinical training of health care providers to provide generalist forensic serv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration grants for comprehensive forensic training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Demonstration grants for comprehensive forensic training</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance grants and learning collectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance grants and learning collectives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National report Not later than 1 year after March 15, 2022, and annually thereafter, the Office for Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Indian Health Service, the Office on Women’s Health of the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice shall jointly submit to the Secretary a report on the need for, throughout the States, Indian Tribes, and territories—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>