<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–7a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–7a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–7a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_7a"><akn:num>280g–7a</akn:num><akn:heading>Surveillance of neurological diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–7a. Surveillance of neurological diseases(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with other agencies as the Secretary determines, shall, as appropriate—(1) enhance and expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of neurological diseases; and

(2) incorporate information obtained through such activities into an integrated surveillance system, which may consist of or include a registry, to be known as the National Neurological Conditions Surveillance System.


(b) ResearchThe Secretary shall ensure that the National Neurological Conditions Surveillance System is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on neurological diseases.


(c) ContentIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary—(1) shall provide for the collection and storage of information on the incidence and prevalence of neurological diseases in the United States;

(2) to the extent practicable, shall provide for the collection and storage of other available information on neurological diseases, including information related to persons living with neurological diseases who choose to participate, such as—(A) demographics, such as age, race, ethnicity, sex, geographic location, family history, and other information, as appropriate;

(B) risk factors that may be associated with neurological diseases, such as genetic and environmental risk factors and other information, as appropriate; and

(C) diagnosis and progression markers;


(3) may provide for the collection and storage of information relevant to analysis on neurological diseases, such as information concerning—(A) the natural history of the diseases;

(B) the prevention of the diseases;

(C) the detection, management, and treatment approaches for the diseases; and

(D) the development of outcomes measures;


(4) may address issues identified during the consultation process under subsection (d); and

(5) initially may address a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in coordination with other agencies as the Secretary determines, shall, as appropriate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Research The Secretary shall ensure that the National Neurological Conditions Surveillance System is designed in a manner that facilitates further research on neurological diseases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Content In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with individuals with appropriate expertise, which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grants The Secretary may award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, public or private nonprofit entities to carry out activities under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other Federal, State, and local agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coordination with other Federal, State, and local agencies Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public access</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Public access Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary shall ensure that information and analysis in the National Neurological Conditions Surveillance System are available, as appropriate, to the public, including researchers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Privacy The Secretary shall ensure that information and analysis in the National Neurological Conditions Surveillance System are made available only to the extent permitted by applicable Federal and State law, and in a manner that protects personal privacy, to the extent required by applicable Federal and State privacy law, at a minimum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_7a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Definition In this section, the term “national voluntary health association” means a national nonprofit organization with chapters, other affiliated organizations, or networks in States throughout the United States with experience serving the population of individuals with neurological disease and have demonstrated experience in neurological disease research, care, and patient services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>