<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g"><akn:num>280g</akn:num><akn:heading>Children’s asthma treatment grants program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g. Children’s asthma treatment grants program(a) Authority to make grants(1) In generalIn addition to any other payments made under this chapter or title V of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 701 et seq.], the Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to carry out the following purposes:(A) To provide access to quality medical care for children who live in areas that have a high prevalence of asthma and who lack access to medical care.

(B) To provide on-site education to parents, children, health care providers, and medical teams to recognize the signs and symptoms of asthma, and to train them in the use of medications to treat asthma and prevent its exacerbations.

(C) To decrease preventable trips to the emergency room by making medication available to individuals who have not previously had access to treatment or education in the management of asthma.

(D) To provide other services, such as smoking cessation programs, home modification, and other direct and support services that ameliorate conditions that exacerbate or induce asthma.


(2) 11 So in original. Two pars. (2) have been enacted. Certain projectsIn making grants under paragraph (1), the Secretary may make grants designed to develop and expand the following projects:(A) Projects to provide comprehensive asthma services to children in accordance with the guidelines of the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program (through the National Heart, Lung and Blood Institute), including access to care and treatment for asthma in a community-based setting.

(B) Projects to fully equip mobile health care clinics that provide preventive asthma care including diagnosis, physical examinations, pharmacological therapy, skin testing, peak flow meter testing, and other asthma-related health care services.

(C) Projects to conduct validated asthma management education programs for patients with asthma and their families, including patient education regarding asthma management, family education on as</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to make grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority to make grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other children’s programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination with other children’s programs An eligible entity shall identify in the plan submitted as part of an application for a grant under this section how the entity will coordinate operations and activities under the grant with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Evaluation An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an evaluation of the operations and activities carried out under the grant that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference for States that allow students to self-administer medication to treat asthma and anaphylaxis</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preference for States that allow students to self-administer medication to treat asthma and anaphylaxis</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2001 through 2005.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>