<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_16"><akn:num>280g–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Food Safety Integrated Centers of Excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–16. Food Safety Integrated Centers of Excellence(a) In generalNot later than 1 year after January 4, 2011, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in consultation with the working group described in subsection (b)(2), shall designate 5 Integrated Food Safety Centers of Excellence (referred to in this section as the “Centers of Excellence”) to serve as resources for Federal, State, and local public health professionals to respond to foodborne illness outbreaks. The Centers of Excellence shall be headquartered at selected State health departments.


(b) Selection of Centers of Excellence(1) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to be designated as a Center of Excellence under subsection (a), an entity shall—(A) be a State health department;

(B) partner with 1 or more institutions of higher education that have demonstrated knowledge, expertise, and meaningful experience with regional or national food production, processing, and distribution, as well as leadership in the laboratory, epidemiological, and environmental detection and investigation of foodborne illness; and

(C) provide to the Secretary such information, at such time, and in such manner, as the Secretary may require.


(2) Working groupNot later than 180 days after January 4, 2011, the Secretary shall establish a diverse working group of experts and stakeholders from Federal, State, and local food safety and health agencies, the food industry, including food retailers and food manufacturers, consumer organizations, and academia to make recommendations to the Secretary regarding designations of the Centers of Excellence.


(3) Additional Centers of ExcellenceThe Secretary may designate eligible entities to be regional Food Safety Centers of Excellence, in addition to the 5 Centers designated under subsection (a).



(c) ActivitiesUnder the leadership of the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, each Center of Excellence shall be</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 1 year after January 4, 2011, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and in consultation with the working group described in subsection (b)(2), shall designate 5 Integrated Food Safety Centers of Excellence (referred to in this section as the “Centers of Excellence”) to serve as resources for Federal, State, and local public health professionals to respond to foodborne illness outbreaks. The Centers of Excellence shall be headquartered at selected State health departments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection of Centers of Excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Selection of Centers of Excellence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities Under the leadership of the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, each Center of Excellence shall be based out of a selected State health department, which shall provide assistance to other regional, State, and local departments of health through activities that include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to Congress Not later than 2 years after January 4, 2011, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_16_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>No duplication of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) No duplication of effort In carrying out activities of the Centers of Excellence or other programs under this section, the Secretary shall not duplicate other Federal foodborne illness response efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>