<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_12"><akn:num>280g–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary Care Extension Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–12. Primary Care Extension Program(a) Establishment, purpose and definition(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, shall establish a Primary Care Extension Program.


(2) PurposeThe Primary Care Extension Program shall provide support and assistance to primary care providers to educate providers about preventive medicine, health promotion, chronic disease management, mental and behavioral health services (including substance abuse prevention and treatment services), and evidence-based and evidence-informed therapies and techniques, in order to enable providers to incorporate such matters into their practice and to improve community health by working with community-based health connectors (referred to in this section as “Health Extension Agents”).


(3) DefinitionsIn this section:(A) Health Extension AgentThe term “Health Extension Agent” means any local, community-based health worker who facilitates and provides assistance to primary care practices by implementing quality improvement or system redesign, incorporating the principles of the patient-centered medical home to provide high-quality, effective, efficient, and safe primary care and to provide guidance to patients in culturally and linguistically appropriate ways, and linking practices to diverse health system resources.


(B) Primary care providerThe term “primary care provider” means a clinician who provides integrated, accessible health care services and who is accountable for addressing a large majority of personal health care needs, including providing preventive and health promotion services for men, women, and children of all ages, developing a sustained partnership with patients, and practicing in the context of family and community, as recognized by a State licensing or regulatory authority, unless otherwise specified in this section.




(b) Grants to establish State Hubs and local Primary Care Extension Agencies(1) GrantsThe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment, purpose and definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment, purpose and definition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to establish State Hubs and local Primary Care Extension Agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grants to establish State Hubs and local Primary Care Extension Agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State and local activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal program administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal program administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements on the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements on the Secretary In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with the heads of other Federal agencies with demonstrated experience and expertise in health care and preventive medicine, such as the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the National Institutes of Health, the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology, the Indian Health Service, the Agricultural Cooperative Extension Service of the Department of Agriculture, and other entities, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_12_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations To awards grants as provided in subsection (d), there are authorized to be appropriated $120,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2011 and 2012, and such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section for each of fiscal years 2013 through 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>