<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_5"><akn:num>280g–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Public and health care provider education and support services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–5. Public and health care provider education and support services(a) In generalThe Secretary, directly or through the awarding of grants to public or private nonprofit entities, may conduct activities, which may include demonstration projects for the purpose of improving the provision of information on prematurity to health professionals and other health care providers and the public and improving the treatment and outcomes mothers 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “for”. of infants born preterm, and infants born preterm, as appropriate.


(b) ActivitiesActivities to be carried out under subsection (a) may include the establishment of—(1) programs, including those to test and evaluate strategies, which, in collaboration with States, localities, tribes, and community organizations, support the provision of information and education to health professionals, other health care providers, and the public concerning—(A) the core risk factors for preterm labor and delivery;

(B) evidence-based strategies to prevent preterm birth and associated outcomes;

(C) medically indicated deliveries before full term, and the risks of non-medically indicated deliveries before full term;

(D) the importance of preconception and prenatal care, including—(i) smoking cessation;

(ii) weight maintenance and good nutrition, including folic acid intake;

(iii) the screening for and the treatment of infections;

(iv) screening for and treatment of substance use disorders;

(v) screening for and treatment of maternal depression;

(vi) maternal immunization; and

(vii) stress management;


(E) treatments and outcomes for premature infants, including late preterm infants; and

(F) the informational needs of families during the stay of an infant in a neonatal intensive care unit.


(2) programs to increase the availability, awareness, and use of pregnancy and post-term information services that provide evidence-based, clinical information through counselors, community outrea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, directly or through the awarding of grants to public or private nonprofit entities, may conduct activities, which may include demonstration projects for the purpose of improving the provision of information on prematurity to health professionals and other health care providers and the public and improving the treatment and outcomes mothers 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “for”. of infants born preterm, and infants born preterm, as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities Activities to be carried out under subsection (a) may include the establishment of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $1,900,000 for each of fiscal years 2014 through 2018.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>