<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280g–4b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280g_4b"><akn:num>280g–4b</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanding access to unified care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280g–4b. Expanding access to unified care(a) Establishment of programThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a program (referred to in this section as the “program”) to award grants to eligible entities for the clinical training of sexual assault forensic examiners (including registered nurses, nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, clinical nurse specialists, physician assistants, and physicians) to administer medical forensic examinations and treatments to survivors of sexual assault.


(b) PurposeThe purpose of the program is to enable each grant recipient to expand access to medical forensic examination services by providing new providers with the clinical training necessary to establish and maintain competency in such services and to test the provisions of such services at new facilities in expanded health care settings.


(c) GrantsUnder the program, the Secretary shall award 3-year grants to eligible entities that meet the requirements established by the Secretary.


(d) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—(1) be—(A) a safety net clinic acting in partnership with a high-volume emergency services provider or a hospital currently providing sexual assault medical forensic examinations performed by sexual assault forensic examiners, that will use grant funds to—(i) assign rural health care service providers to the high-volume hospitals for clinical practicum hours to qualify such providers as sexual assault forensic examiners; or

(ii) assign practitioners at high-volume hospitals to rural health care services providers to instruct, oversee, and approve clinical practicum hours in the community to be served;


(B) an organization described in section 501(c)(3) of title 26 and exempt from taxation under 501(a) of such title, that provides legal training and technical assistance to Tribal communities and to organizations and agencies serving Indian</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall establish a program (referred to in this section as the “program”) to award grants to eligible entities for the clinical training of sexual assault forensic examiners (including registered nurses, nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, clinical nurse specialists, physician assistants, and physicians) to administer medical forensic examinations and treatments to survivors of sexual assault.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The purpose of the program is to enable each grant recipient to expand access to medical forensic examination services by providing new providers with the clinical training necessary to establish and maintain competency in such services and to test the provisions of such services at new facilities in expanded health care settings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants Under the program, the Secretary shall award 3-year grants to eligible entities that meet the requirements established by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible entities To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Grant amount Each grant awarded under this section shall be in an amount not to exceed $400,000 per year. A grant recipient may carry over funds from one fiscal year to the next without obtaining approval from the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280g_4b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>