<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280h–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280h–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280h–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280h_5"><akn:num>280h–5</akn:num><akn:heading>School-based health centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280h–5. School-based health centers(a) Definitions; establishment of criteriaIn this section:(1) Comprehensive primary health servicesThe term “comprehensive primary health services” means the core services offered by school-based health centers, which shall include the following:(A) PhysicalComprehensive health assessments, diagnosis, and treatment of minor, acute, and chronic medical conditions, and referrals to, and follow-up for, specialty care and oral and vision health services.


(B) Mental healthMental health and substance use disorder assessments, crisis intervention, counseling, treatment, and referral to a continuum of services including emergency psychiatric care, community support programs, inpatient care, and outpatient programs.



(2) Medically underserved children and adolescents(A) In generalThe term “medically underserved children and adolescents” means a population of children and adolescents who are residents of an area designated as a medically underserved area or a health professional shortage area by the Secretary.


(B) CriteriaThe Secretary shall prescribe criteria for determining the specific shortages of personal health services for medically underserved children and adolescents under subparagraph (A) that shall—(i) take into account any comments received by the Secretary from the chief executive officer of a State and local officials in a State; and

(ii) include factors indicative of the health status of such children and adolescents of an area, including the ability of the residents of such area to pay for health services, the accessibility of such services, the availability of health professionals to such children and adolescents, and other factors as determined appropriate by the Secretary.



(3) School-based health centerThe term “school-based health center” means a health clinic that—(A) meets the definition of a school-based health center under section 1397jj(c)(9)(A) of this title and is administered by a sponsoring facility (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions; establishment of criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions; establishment of criteria In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to award grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to award grants The Secretary shall award grants for the costs of the operation of school-based health centers (referred to in this section as “SBHCs”) that meet the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferences and consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preferences and consideration In reviewing applications:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Waiver of requirements The Secretary may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Matching requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Supplement, not supplant Grant funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal or State funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Evaluation The Secretary shall develop and implement a plan for evaluating SBHCs and monitoring quality performance under the awards made under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280h_5_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Age appropriate services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Age appropriate services An eligible entity receiving funds under this section shall only provide age appropriate services through a 1 SBHC funded under this section to an individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>