<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280i–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280i–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280i–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280i_2"><akn:num>280i–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280i–2. Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee” (in this section referred to as the “Committee”), to coordinate all efforts within the Department of Health and Human Services concerning autism spectrum disorder.


(b) ResponsibilitiesIn carrying out its duties under this section, the Committee shall, on a regular basis—(1) monitor autism spectrum disorder research, and to the extent practicable services and support activities, across all relevant Federal departments and agencies, including coordination of Federal activities with respect to autism spectrum disorder;

(2) summarize of 11 So in original. The word “of” probably should not appear. advances in autism spectrum disorder research related to causes, prevention, treatment, early screening, diagnosis or rule out, interventions, including school and community-based interventions, and access to services and supports for individuals with autism spectrum disorder across the lifespan of such individuals;

(3) make recommendations to the Secretary regarding any appropriate changes to such activities, including with 22 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “recommendations”. respect to the strategic plan developed under paragraph (5);

(4) make recommendations to the Secretary regarding public participation in decisions relating to autism spectrum disorder, and the process by which public feedback can be better integrated into such decisions;

(5) develop a strategic plan for the conduct of, and support for, autism spectrum disorder research, as described in section 284g(a)(1) of this title, which shall include—(A) proposed budgetary requirements; and

(B) recommendations to ensure that autism spectrum disorder research, and services and support activities to the extent practicable, of the Department of Health and Human Services and of other Federal departments and agencies are not unn</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish a committee, to be known as the “Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee” (in this section referred to as the “Committee”), to coordinate all efforts within the Department of Health and Human Services concerning autism spectrum disorder.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibilities In carrying out its duties under this section, the Committee shall, on a regular basis—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative support; terms of service; other provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Administrative support; terms of service; other provisions The following provisions shall apply with respect to the Committee:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subcommittees; establishment and membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Subcommittees; establishment and membership In carrying out its functions, the Committee may establish subcommittees and convene workshops and conferences. Such subcommittees shall be composed of Committee members and may hold such meetings as are necessary to enable the subcommittees to carry out their duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280i_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sunset This section shall not apply after September 30, 2029, and the Committee shall be terminated on such date.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>