<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280k–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280k–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280k–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280k_3"><akn:num>280k–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Updating national oral healthcare surveillance activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280k–3. Updating national oral healthcare surveillance activities(1) PRAMS(A) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall carry out activities to update and improve the Pregnancy Risk Assessment Monitoring System (referred to in this section as “PRAMS”) as it relates to oral healthcare.


(B) State reports and mandatory measurements(i) In generalNot later than 5 years after March 23, 2010, and every 5 years thereafter, a State shall submit to the Secretary a report concerning activities conducted within the State under PRAMS.


(ii) MeasurementsThe oral healthcare measurements developed by the Secretary for use under PRAMS shall be mandatory with respect to States for purposes of the State reports under clause (i).



(C) FundingThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this paragraph, such sums as may be necessary.



(2) National Health and Nutrition Examination SurveyThe Secretary shall develop oral healthcare components that shall include tooth-level surveillance for inclusion in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Such components shall be updated by the Secretary at least every 6 years. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “tooth-level surveillance” means a clinical examination where an examiner looks at each dental surface, on each tooth in the mouth and as expanded by the Division of Oral Health of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.


(3) Medical Expenditures Panel SurveyThe Secretary shall ensure that the Medical Expenditures Panel Survey by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality includes the verification of dental utilization, expenditure, and coverage findings through conduct of a look-back analysis.


(4) National Oral Health Surveillance System(A) AppropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated, such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2014 to increase the participation of States in the National Oral Healt</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280k_3_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>PRAMS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) PRAMS</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280k_3_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey The Secretary shall develop oral healthcare components that shall include tooth-level surveillance for inclusion in the National Health and Nutrition Examination Survey. Such components shall be updated by the Secretary at least every 6 years. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “tooth-level surveillance” means a clinical examination where an examiner looks at each dental surface, on each tooth in the mouth and as expanded by the Division of Oral Health of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280k_3_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical Expenditures Panel Survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Medical Expenditures Panel Survey The Secretary shall ensure that the Medical Expenditures Panel Survey by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality includes the verification of dental utilization, expenditure, and coverage findings through conduct of a look-back analysis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280k_3_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Oral Health Surveillance System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) National Oral Health Surveillance System</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>