<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280m"><akn:num>280m</akn:num><akn:heading>Young women’s breast health awareness and support of young women diagnosed with breast cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280m. Young women’s breast health awareness and support of young women diagnosed with breast cancer(a) Public education campaign(1) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall conduct a national evidence-based education campaign to increase awareness of young women’s knowledge regarding—(A) breast health in young women of all racial, ethnic, and cultural backgrounds;

(B) breast awareness and good breast health habits;

(C) the occurrence of breast cancer and the general and specific risk factors in women who may be at high risk for breast cancer based on familial, racial, ethnic, and cultural backgrounds such as Ashkenazi Jewish populations;

(D) evidence-based information that would encourage young women and their health care professional to increase early detection of breast cancers; and

(E) the availability of health information and other resources for young women diagnosed with breast cancer.


(2) Evidence-based, age appropriate messagesThe campaign shall provide evidence-based, age-appropriate messages and materials as developed by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Advisory Committee established under paragraph (4).


(3) Media campaignIn conducting the education campaign under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall award grants to entities to establish national multimedia campaigns oriented to young women that may include advertising through television, radio, print media, billboards, posters, all forms of existing and especially emerging social networking media, other Internet media, and any other medium determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(4) Advisory committee(A) EstablishmentNot later than 60 days after March 23, 2010, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish an advisory committee to assist in creating and conducting the education campaigns under paragraph (1) and subsection (b)(1).


(B) Member</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public education campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Public education campaign</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care professional education campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health care professional education campaign The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and in consultation with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall conduct an education campaign among physicians and other health care professionals to increase awareness—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention research activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prevention research activities The Secretary, acting through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for young women diagnosed with breast cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Support for young women diagnosed with breast cancer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No duplication of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No duplication of effort In conducting an education campaign or other program under subsections (a), (b), (c), or (d), the Secretary shall avoid duplicating other existing Federal breast cancer education efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measurement; reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Measurement; reporting The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition In this section, the term “young women” means women 15 to 44 years of age.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280m_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations To carry out subsections (a), (b), (c)(1), and (d), there are authorized to be appropriated $9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>