<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/280n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_280n"><akn:num>280n</akn:num><akn:heading>National Parkinson’s Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 280n. National Parkinson’s Project(a) Definition of Parkinson’sIn this section, the term “Parkinson’s” means—(1) Parkinson’s disease; and

(2) all other neurodegenerative Parkinsonisms, including multiple system atrophy, corticobasal degeneration, progressive supranuclear palsy, and Parkinson’s-related dementia.


(b) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall carry out a national project, to be known as the National Parkinson’s Project (referred to in this section as the “Project”), to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s.


(c) Activities carried out through ProjectIn carrying out the Project, the Secretary shall—(1) create, maintain, and periodically update an integrated national plan to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s, ameliorate symptoms, and slow or stop progression;

(2) carry out the annual assessment under subsection (d);

(3) provide information, including—(A) an estimate of the level of current Federal investment in preventing, diagnosing, treating, and curing Parkinson’s, ameliorating symptoms, and slowing or stopping progression; and

(B) if applicable, an estimate of the investment necessary to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s, ameliorate symptoms, and slow or stop progression;


(4) coordinate research and services across all Federal agencies related to Parkinson’s;

(5) encourage the development of safe and effective treatments, strategies, and other approaches to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s, ameliorate symptoms, and slow or stop progression;

(6) improve the—(A) early diagnosis of Parkinson’s; and

(B) coordination of the care and treatment of individuals with Parkinson’s;


(7) review the impact of Parkinson’s on the physical, mental, and social health of individuals living with Parkinson’s and their caregivers and families;

(8) coordinate with international bodies, to the extent possible, to integrate and inform the mission to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s, ameliorate symptoms, an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of Parkinson’s</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of Parkinson’s In this section, the term “Parkinson’s” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment The Secretary shall carry out a national project, to be known as the National Parkinson’s Project (referred to in this section as the “Project”), to prevent, diagnose, treat, and cure Parkinson’s.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities carried out through Project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Activities carried out through Project In carrying out the Project, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual assessment Not later than 24 months after July 2, 2024, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall carry out an assessment of the Nation’s progress in preparing for, and responding to, the escalating burden of Parkinson’s, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Advisory Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Information sharing Each Federal department and agency that has information relating to Parkinson’s shall share such information with the Secretary consistent with the statutory obligations of such department or agency regarding disclosure of information, as necessary to enable the Secretary to complete a report under subsection (e)(4).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_280n_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sunset</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sunset The section shall cease to be effective at the end of calendar year 2035.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>