<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_282"><akn:num>282</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of National Institutes of Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 282. Director of National Institutes of Health(a) AppointmentThe National Institutes of Health shall be headed by the Director of NIH who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director of NIH shall perform functions as provided under subsection (b) and as the Secretary may otherwise prescribe.


(b) Duties and authorityIn carrying out the purposes of section 241 of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH—(1) shall carry out this subchapter, including being responsible for the overall direction of the National Institutes of Health and for the establishment and implementation of general policies respecting the management and operation of programs and activities within the National Institutes of Health;

(2) shall coordinate and oversee the operation of the national research institutes, national centers, and administrative entities within the National Institutes of Health;

(3) shall, in consultation with the heads of the national research institutes and national centers, be responsible for program coordination across the national research institutes and national centers, including conducting priority-setting reviews, to ensure that the research portfolio of the National Institutes of Health is balanced and free of unnecessary duplication, and takes advantage of collaborative, cross-cutting research;

(4) shall assemble accurate data to be used to assess research priorities, including—(A) information to better evaluate scientific opportunity, public health burdens, and progress in reducing health disparities; and

(B) data on study populations of clinical research, funded by or conducted at each national research institute and national center, which—(i) specifies the inclusion of—(I) women;

(II) members of minority groups;

(III) relevant age categories, including pediatric subgroups; and

(IV) other demographic variables as the Director of the National Institutes of Health determines appropri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment The National Institutes of Health shall be headed by the Director of NIH who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. The Director of NIH shall perform functions as provided under subsection (b) and as the Secretary may otherwise prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties and authority In carrying out the purposes of section 241 of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH— Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the duration of a peer review group appointed under paragraph (16). The members of such a group shall be individuals who by virtue of their training or experience are eminently qualified to perform the review functions of such group. Not more than one-fourth of the members of any such group shall be officers or employees of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of substances and organisms for research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Availability of substances and organisms for research The Director of NIH may make available to individuals and entities, for biomedical and behavioral research, substances and living organisms. Such substances and organisms shall be made available under such terms and conditions (including payment for them) as the Secretary determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services of experts or consultants; number; payment of expenses, conditions, recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Services of experts or consultants; number; payment of expenses, conditions, recovery</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of research information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dissemination of research information The Director of NIH shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Associate Director for Prevention; functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Associate Director for Prevention; functions There shall be in the National Institutes of Health an Associate Director for Prevention. The Director of NIH shall delegate to the Associate Director for Prevention the functions of the Director relating to the promotion of the disease prevention research programs of the national research institutes and the coordination of such programs among the national research institutes and between the national research institutes and other public and private entities, including elementary, secondary, and post-secondary schools. The Associate Director shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferred</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transferred</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased participation of women and disadvantaged individuals in biomedical and behavioral research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Increased participation of women and disadvantaged individuals in biomedical and behavioral research The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH and the Directors of the agencies of the National Institutes of Health, shall, in conducting and supporting programs for research, research training, recruitment, and other activities, provide for an increase in the number of women and individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds (including racial and ethnic minorities) in the fields of biomedical and behavioral research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data bank of information on clinical trials for drugs for serious or life-threatening diseases and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Data bank of information on clinical trials for drugs for serious or life-threatening diseases and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expanded clinical trial registry data bank</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Expanded clinical trial registry data bank</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>