<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/282a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_282a"><akn:num>282a</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 282a. Authorization of appropriations(a) In general(1) This subchapterFor purposes of carrying out this subchapter, there are authorized to be appropriated—(A) $30,331,309,000 for fiscal year 2007;

(B) $32,831,309,000 for fiscal year 2008;

(C) such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2009;

(D) $34,851,000,000 for fiscal year 2018;

(E) $35,585,871,000 for fiscal year 2019; and

(F) $36,472,442,775 for fiscal year 2020.


(2) Funding for pediatric research initiativeFor the purpose of carrying out section 282(b)(7)(B)(ii) of this title, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives, out of the Pediatric Research Initiative Fund described in section 9008 of title 26, and in addition to amounts otherwise made available under paragraph (1) of this subsection, $12,600,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028.



(b) Office of the DirectorOf the amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, there are authorized to be appropriated for programs and activities under this subchapter carried out through the Office of the Director of NIH such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2009.


(c) Trans-NIH research(1) Common Fund(A) AccountFor the purpose of allocations under section 282(b)(7)(B)(i) of this title (relating to research identified by the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives), there is established an account to be known as the Common Fund.


(B) Reservation(i) In generalOf the total amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) for fiscal year 2007 or any subsequent fiscal year, the Director of NIH shall reserve an amount for the Common Fund, subject to any applicable provisions in appropriations Acts.


(ii) Minimum amountFor each fiscal year, the percentage constituted by the amount reserved under clause (i) relative to the total amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) for such year may no</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Office of the Director Of the amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year, there are authorized to be appropriated for programs and activities under this subchapter carried out through the Office of the Director of NIH such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2009.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trans-NIH research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Trans-NIH research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer authority Of the total amount appropriated under subsection (a)(1) for a fiscal year, the Director of NIH may (in addition to the reservation under subsection (c)(1) for such year) transfer not more than 1 percent for programs or activities that are authorized in this subchapter and identified by the Director to receive funds pursuant to this subsection. In making such transfers, the Director may not decrease any appropriation account under subsection (a)(1) by more than 1 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_282a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction This section may not be construed as affecting the authorities of the Director of NIH under section 281 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>