<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_283d"><akn:num>283d</akn:num><akn:heading>Children’s Vaccine Initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 283d. Children’s Vaccine Initiative
The Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Vaccine Program under subchapter XIX and acting through the Directors of the National Institute for Allergy and Infectious Diseases, the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, the National Institute for Aging, and other public and private programs, shall carry out activities, which shall be consistent with the global Children’s Vaccine Initiative, to develop affordable new and improved vaccines to be used in the United States and in the developing world that will increase the efficacy and efficiency of the prevention of infectious diseases. In carrying out such activities, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, develop and make available vaccines that require fewer contacts to deliver, that can be given early in life, that provide long lasting protection, that obviate refrigeration, needles and syringes, and that protect against a larger number of diseases.
(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 404B, as added Pub. L. 103–43, title II, § 204, June 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 146; amended Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 103(b)(3), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3687; Pub. L. 110–154, § 1(b)(2), Dec. 21, 2007, 121 Stat. 1827; Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title II, § 2042(d), Dec. 13, 2016, 130 Stat. 1073.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2016—Pub. L. 114–255 struck out subsec. (a) designation and heading “Development of New Vaccines” and subsec. (b). Prior to amendment, text of subsec. (b) read as follows: “In the report required in section 300aa–4 of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Vaccine Program under subchapter XIX, shall include information with respect to activities and the progress made in implementing the provisions of this section and achieving its goals.”
2007—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 110–154 substituted “Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development” for “National Ins</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>