<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_283e"><akn:num>283e</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for use of animals in research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 283e. Plan for use of animals in research(a) PreparationThe Director of NIH, after consultation with the committee established under subsection (e), shall prepare a plan—(1) for the National Institutes of Health to conduct or support research into—(A) methods of biomedical research and experimentation that do not require the use of animals;

(B) methods of such research and experimentation that reduce the number of animals used in such research;

(C) methods of such research and experimentation that produce less pain and distress in such animals; and

(D) methods of such research and experimentation that involve the use of marine life (other than marine mammals);


(2) for establishing the validity and reliability of the methods described in paragraph (1);

(3) for encouraging the acceptance by the scientific community of such methods that have been found to be valid and reliable; and

(4) for training scientists in the use of such methods that have been found to be valid and reliable.


(b) Submission to Congressional committeesNot later than October 1, 1993, the Director of NIH shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, the plan required in subsection (a) and shall begin implementation of the plan.


(c) Periodic review and revisionThe Director of NIH shall periodically review, and as appropriate, make revisions in the plan required under subsection (a). A description of any revision made in the plan shall be included in the first biennial report under section 283 of this title that is submitted after the revision is made.


(d) Dissemination of informationThe Director of NIH shall take such actions as may be appropriate to convey to scientists and others who use animals in biomedical or behavioral research or experimentation information respecting the methods found to be valid and reliable under subsection (a)(2).


(e) Interagency Coordinating Committee </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation The Director of NIH, after consultation with the committee established under subsection (e), shall prepare a plan—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Submission to Congressional committees Not later than October 1, 1993, the Director of NIH shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, the plan required in subsection (a) and shall begin implementation of the plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review and revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Periodic review and revision The Director of NIH shall periodically review, and as appropriate, make revisions in the plan required under subsection (a). A description of any revision made in the plan shall be included in the first biennial report under section 283 of this title that is submitted after the revision is made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dissemination of information The Director of NIH shall take such actions as may be appropriate to convey to scientists and others who use animals in biomedical or behavioral research or experimentation information respecting the methods found to be valid and reliable under subsection (a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Coordinating Committee on the Use of Animals in Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interagency Coordinating Committee on the Use of Animals in Research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>