<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_283g"><akn:num>283g</akn:num><akn:heading>Muscular dystrophy; initiative through Director of National Institutes of Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 283g. Muscular dystrophy; initiative through Director of National Institutes of Health(a) Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities(1) In generalThe Director of NIH, in coordination with the Directors of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases, the Eunice Kennedy Shriver National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, and the other national research institutes as appropriate, shall expand and intensify programs of such Institutes with respect to research and related activities concerning various forms of muscular dystrophy, including Duchenne, Becker, congenital muscular dystrophy, limb-girdle muscular dystrophy, myotonic, facioscapulohumeral muscular dystrophy (referred to in this section as “FSHD”) and other forms of muscular dystrophy.


(2) CoordinationThe Directors referred to in paragraph (1) shall jointly coordinate the programs referred to in such paragraph and consult with the Muscular Dystrophy Interagency Coordinating Committee established under section 6 of the MD–CARE Act.11 See References in Text note below.


(3) Allocations by Director of NIHThe Director of NIH shall allocate the amounts appropriated to carry out this section for each fiscal year among the national research institutes referred to in paragraph (1).



(b) Centers of excellence(1) In generalThe Director of NIH shall award grants and contracts under subsection (a)(1) to public or nonprofit private entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, improving, and providing basic operating support for centers of excellence regarding research on various forms of muscular dystrophy. Such centers of excellence shall be known as the “Paul D. Wellstone Muscular Dystrophy Cooperative Research Centers”.


(2) ResearchEach center under paragraph (1) shall supplement but not replace the establishment of a comprehe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expansion, intensification, and coordination of activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers of excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Centers of excellence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilitation of research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Facilitation of research The Director of NIH shall provide for a program under subsection (a)(1) under which samples of tissues and genetic materials that are of use in research on muscular dystrophy are donated, collected, preserved, and made available for such research. The program shall be carried out in accordance with accepted scientific and medical standards for the donation, collection, and preservation of such samples.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan for HHS activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plan for HHS activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public input</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public input The Secretary shall, under subsection (a)(1), provide for a means through which the public can obtain information on the existing and planned programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services with respect to various forms of muscular dystrophy and through which the Secretary can receive comments from the public regarding such programs and activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Clinical research The Coordinating Committee may evaluate the potential need to enhance the clinical research infrastructure required to test emerging therapies for the various forms of muscular dystrophy by prioritizing the achievement of the goals related to this topic in the plan under subsection (e)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>