<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/283k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_283k"><akn:num>283k</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomedical and behavioral research facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 283k. Biomedical and behavioral research facilities(a) Modernization and construction of facilities(1) In generalThe Director of NIH, acting through the Office of the Director of NIH or the Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, may make grants or contracts to public and nonprofit private entities to expand, remodel, renovate, or alter existing research facilities or construct new research facilities, subject to the provisions of this section.


(2) Construction and cost of constructionFor purposes of this section, the terms “construction” and “cost of construction” include the construction of new buildings and the expansion, renovation, remodeling, and alteration of existing buildings, including architects’ fees, but do not include the cost of acquisition of land or off-site improvements.



(b) Scientific and technical review boards for merit-based review of proposals(1) In general: approval as precondition to grants(A) EstablishmentThere is established a Scientific and Technical Review Board on Biomedical and Behavioral Research Facilities (referred to in this section as the “Board”).


(B) RequirementThe Director of NIH, acting through the Office of the Director of NIH, may approve an application for a grant under subsection (a) only if the Board has under paragraph (2) recommended the application for approval.



(2) Duties(A) AdviceThe Board shall provide advice to the Director of NIH and the Council of Councils established under section 282(l) of this title (in this section referred to as the “Council”) in carrying out this section.


(B) Determination of meritIn carrying out subparagraph (A), the Board shall make a determination of the merit of each application submitted for a grant under subsection (a), after consideration of the requirements established in subsection (c), and shall report the results of the determination to the Director of NIH and the Council. Such determinations shall be conducted in a manner consistent w</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Modernization and construction of facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Modernization and construction of facilities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific and technical review boards for merit-based review of proposals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scientific and technical review boards for merit-based review of proposals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement of application The Director of NIH, acting through the Office of the Director of NIH or the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, may make a grant under subsection (a) only if an application for the grant is submitted to the Director and the application is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Director determines to be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grant; payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amount of grant; payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recapture of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Recapture of payments If, not later than 20 years after the completion of construction for which a grant has been awarded under subsection (a)— the United States shall be entitled to recover from the applicant or other owner of the facility the amount bearing the same ratio to the current value (as determined by an agreement between the parties or by action brought in the United States District Court for the district in which such facility is situated) of the facility as the amount of the Federal participation bore to the cost of the construction of such facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_283k_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Guidelines Not later than 6 months after June 10, 1993, the Director of NIH, acting through the Office of the Director of NIH, after consultation with the Council, shall issue guidelines with respect to grants under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>