<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284"><akn:num>284</akn:num><akn:heading>Directors of national research institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284. Directors of national research institutes(a) Appointment(1) In generalThe Director of the National Cancer Institute shall be appointed by the President, and the Directors of the other national research institutes and national centers shall be appointed by the Secretary, acting through the Director of National Institutes of Health. Each Director of a national research institute or national center shall report directly to the Director of National Institutes of Health.


(2) Appointment(A) TermA Director of a national research institute or national center who is appointed by the Secretary, acting through the Director of National Institutes of Health, shall be appointed for 5 years.


(B) ReappointmentAt the end of the term of a Director of a national research institute or national center, the Director may be reappointed in accordance with standards applicable to the relevant appointment mechanism. There shall be no limit on the number of terms that a Director may serve.


(C) VacanciesIf the office of a Director of a national research institute or national center becomes vacant before the end of such Director’s term, the Director appointed to fill the vacancy shall be appointed for a 5-year term starting on the date of such appointment.


(D) Current directorsEach Director of a national research institute or national center who is serving on December 13, 2016, shall be deemed to be appointed for a 5-year term under this subsection beginning on such date.


(E) Rule of constructionNothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary or the Director of National Institutes of Health to terminate the appointment of a director referred to in subparagraph (A) before the expiration of such director’s 5-year term.


(F) Nature of appointmentAppointments and reappointments under this subsection shall be made on the basis of ability and experience as it relates to the mission of the National Institutes of Health and its components, includi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and authority; grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties and authority; grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other public and private entities; cooperation with other national research institutes; appointment of additional peer review groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination with other public and private entities; cooperation with other national research institutes; appointment of additional peer review groups In carrying out subsection (b), each Director of a national research institute— Chapter 10 of title 5 shall not apply to the duration of a peer review group appointed under paragraph (3).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>