<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284k"><akn:num>284k</akn:num><akn:heading>Clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284k. Clinical research(a) In generalThe Director of National Institutes of Health shall undertake activities to support and expand the involvement of the National Institutes of Health in clinical research.


(b) RequirementsIn carrying out subsection (a), the Director of National Institutes of Health shall—(1) consider the recommendations of the Division of Research Grants Clinical Research Study Group and other recommendations for enhancing clinical research; and

(2) establish intramural and extramural clinical research fellowship programs directed specifically at medical and dental students and a continuing education clinical research training program at the National Institutes of Health.


(c) Support for the diverse needs of clinical researchThe Director of National Institutes of Health, in cooperation with the Directors of the Institutes, Centers, and Divisions of the National Institutes of Health, shall support and expand the resources available for the diverse needs of the clinical research community, including inpatient, outpatient, and critical care clinical research.


(d) Peer reviewThe Director of National Institutes of Health shall establish peer review mechanisms to evaluate applications for the awards and fellowships provided for in subsection (b)(2) and section 284l of this title. Such review mechanisms shall include individuals who are exceptionally qualified to appraise the merits of potential clinical research training and research grant proposals.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 409G, formerly § 409C, as added Pub. L. 106–505, title II, § 203, Nov. 13, 2000, 114 Stat. 2326; renumbered § 409G, Pub. L. 107–109, § 3(1), Jan. 4, 2002, 115 Stat. 1408.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 284l of this title, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “section 409D”, and was translated as meaning section 409D of act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, as added by section 204(b) of Pub. L. 106–505. Such section 409D was renumbered section 409H </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of National Institutes of Health shall undertake activities to support and expand the involvement of the National Institutes of Health in clinical research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements In carrying out subsection (a), the Director of National Institutes of Health shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for the diverse needs of clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support for the diverse needs of clinical research The Director of National Institutes of Health, in cooperation with the Directors of the Institutes, Centers, and Divisions of the National Institutes of Health, shall support and expand the resources available for the diverse needs of the clinical research community, including inpatient, outpatient, and critical care clinical research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Peer review The Director of National Institutes of Health shall establish peer review mechanisms to evaluate applications for the awards and fellowships provided for in subsection (b)(2) and section 284l of this title. Such review mechanisms shall include individuals who are exceptionally qualified to appraise the merits of potential clinical research training and research grant proposals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>