<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284m" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284m/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284m/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284m"><akn:num>284m</akn:num><akn:heading>Program for pediatric studies of drugs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284m. Program for pediatric studies of drugs(a) List of priority issues in pediatric therapeutics(1) In generalNot later than one year after September 27, 2007, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health and in consultation with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and experts in pediatric research, shall develop and publish a priority list of needs in pediatric therapeutics, including drugs, biological products, or indications that require study. The list shall be revised every three years.


(2) Consideration of available informationIn developing and prioritizing the list under paragraph (1), the Secretary—(A) shall consider—(i) therapeutic gaps in pediatrics that may include developmental pharmacology, pharmacogenetic determinants of drug response, metabolism of drugs and biologics in children, and pediatric clinical trials;

(ii) particular pediatric diseases, disorders or conditions where more complete knowledge and testing of therapeutics, including drugs and biologics, and identification of biomarkers for such diseases, disorders, or conditions, may be beneficial in pediatric populations; and

(iii) the adequacy of necessary infrastructure to conduct pediatric pharmacological research, including research networks and trained pediatric investigators; and


(B) may consider the availability of qualified countermeasures (as defined in section 247d–6a of this title), security countermeasures (as defined in section 247d–6b of this title), and qualified pandemic or epidemic products (as defined in section 247d–6d of this title) to address the needs of pediatric populations, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, consistent with the purposes of this section.



(b) Pediatric studies and researchThe Secretary, acting through the National Institutes of Health, shall award funds to entities that have the expertise to conduct pediatric clinical trials or other research (including qualified univers</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284m_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of priority issues in pediatric therapeutics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) List of priority issues in pediatric therapeutics</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284m_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pediatric studies and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Pediatric studies and research The Secretary, acting through the National Institutes of Health, shall award funds to entities that have the expertise to conduct pediatric clinical trials or other research (including qualified universities, hospitals, laboratories, contract research organizations, practice groups, federally funded programs such as pediatric pharmacology research units, other public or private institutions, or individuals) to enable the entities to conduct the drug studies or other research on the issues described in paragraphs (1) and (2)(A) of subsection (a). The Secretary may use contracts, grants, or other appropriate funding mechanisms to award funds under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284m_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Process for proposed pediatric study requests and labeling changes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Process for proposed pediatric study requests and labeling changes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284m_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>