<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284n"><akn:num>284n</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284n. Certain demonstration projects(a) Bridging the sciences(1) In generalFrom amounts to be appropriated under section 282a(b) of this title, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of NIH, (in this subsection referred to as the “Secretary”) in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Secretary of Energy, and other agency heads when necessary, may allocate funds for the national research institutes and national centers to make grants for the purpose of improving the public health through demonstration projects for biomedical research at the interface between the biological, behavioral, and social sciences and the physical, chemical, mathematical, and computational sciences.


(2) Goals, priorities, and methods; interagency collaborationThe Secretary shall establish goals, priorities, and methods of evaluation for research under paragraph (1), and shall provide for interagency collaboration with respect to such research. In developing such goals, priorities, and methods, the Secretary shall ensure that—(A) the research reflects the vision of innovation and higher risk with long-term payoffs; and

(B) the research includes a wide spectrum of projects, funded at various levels, with varying timeframes.


(3) Peer reviewA grant may be made under paragraph (1) only if the application for the grant has undergone technical and scientific peer review under section 289a of this title and has been reviewed by the advisory council under section 282(k) of this title or has been reviewed by an advisory council composed of representatives from appropriate scientific disciplines who can fully evaluate the applicant.



(b) High-risk, high-reward research(1) In generalFrom amounts to be appropriated under section 282a(b) of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, may allocate funds for the national research institutes and national centers to make awards of grants or contracts or to engage in ot</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bridging the sciences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Bridging the sciences</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>High-risk, high-reward research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) High-risk, high-reward research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress Not later than the end of fiscal year 2009, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall conduct an evaluation of the activities under this section and submit a report to the Congress on the results of such evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions For purposes of this section, the terms “Director of NIH”, “national research institute”, and “national center” have the meanings given such terms in section 281 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>