<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284q"><akn:num>284q</akn:num><akn:heading>Pain research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284q. Pain research(a) Research initiatives(1) In generalThe Director of NIH is encouraged to continue and expand, through the Pain Consortium, an aggressive program of basic and clinical research on the causes of and potential treatments for pain.


(2) Annual recommendationsNot less than annually, the Pain Consortium, in consultation with the Division of Program Coordination, Planning, and Strategic Initiatives, shall develop and submit to the Director of NIH recommendations on appropriate pain research initiatives that could be undertaken with funds reserved under section 282a(c)(1) of this title for the Common Fund or otherwise available for such initiatives.


(3) DefinitionIn this subsection, the term “Pain Consortium” means the Pain Consortium of the National Institutes of Health or a similar trans-National Institutes of Health coordinating entity designated by the Secretary for purposes of this subsection.



(b) Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee(1) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish not later than 1 year after March 23, 2010, and as necessary maintain a committee, to be known as the Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee (in this section referred to as the “Committee”), to coordinate all efforts within the Department of Health and Human Services and other Federal agencies that relate to pain research.


(2) Membership(A) In generalThe Committee shall be composed of the following voting members:(i) Not more than 7 voting Federal representatives appoint 11 So in original. Probably should be “appointed”. by the Secretary from agencies that conduct pain care research and treatment.

(ii) 12 additional voting members appointed under subparagraph (B).


(B) Additional membersThe Committee shall include additional voting members appointed by the Secretary as follows:(i) 6 non-Federal members shall be appointed from among scientists, physicians, and other health professionals.

(ii) 6 members shall be appointed from members of the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research initiatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interagency Pain Research Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>