<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/284r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_284r"><akn:num>284r</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 284r. Basic research(1) Developing policiesNot later than 2 years after December 13, 2016, the Director of the National Institutes of Health (referred to in this section as the “Director of the National Institutes of Health”), taking into consideration the recommendations developed under section 2039,11 See References in Text note below. shall develop policies for projects of basic research funded by National Institutes of Health to assess—(A) relevant biological variables including sex, as appropriate; and

(B) how differences between male and female cells, tissues, or animals may be examined and analyzed.


(2) Revising policiesThe Director of the National Institutes of Health may update or revise the policies developed under paragraph (1) as appropriate.


(3) Consultation and outreachIn developing, updating, or revising the policies under this section, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—(A) consult with—(i) the Office of Research on Women’s Health;

(ii) the Office of Laboratory Animal Welfare; and

(iii) appropriate members of the scientific and academic communities; and


(B) conduct outreach to solicit feedback from members of the scientific and academic communities on the influence of sex as a variable in basic research, including feedback on when it is appropriate for projects of basic research involving cells, tissues, or animals to include both male and female cells, tissues, or animals.


(4) Additional requirementsThe Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—(A) ensure that projects of basic research funded by the National Institutes of Health are conducted in accordance with the policies developed, updated, or revised under this section, as applicable; and

(B) encourage that the results of such research, when published or reported, be disaggregated as appropriate with respect to the analysis of any sex differences.


(Pub. L. 114–255, div. A, title II, § 2038(g), Dec. 13, 2016, 130 Stat. 1066.)

Editorial Notes

Refer</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284r_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Developing policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Developing policies Not later than 2 years after December 13, 2016, the Director of the National Institutes of Health (referred to in this section as the “Director of the National Institutes of Health”), taking into consideration the recommendations developed under section 2039,11 See References in Text note below. shall develop policies for projects of basic research funded by National Institutes of Health to assess—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284r_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revising policies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Revising policies The Director of the National Institutes of Health may update or revise the policies developed under paragraph (1) as appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284r_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Consultation and outreach In developing, updating, or revising the policies under this section, the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_284r_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Additional requirements The Director of the National Institutes of Health shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>