<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285a_2"><akn:num>285a–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Special authorities of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285a–2. Special authorities of Director(a) Information and education program(1) The Director of the Institute shall establish an information and education program to collect, identify, analyze, and disseminate on a timely basis, through publications and other appropriate means, to cancer patients and their families, physicians and other health professionals, and the general public, information on cancer research, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment (including information respecting nutrition programs for cancer patients and the relationship between nutrition and cancer). The Director of the Institute may take such action as may be necessary to insure that all channels for the dissemination and exchange of scientific knowledge and information are maintained between the Institute and the public and between the Institute and other scientific, medical, and biomedical disciplines and organizations nationally and internationally.

(2) In carrying out paragraph (1), the Director of the Institute shall—(A) provide public and patient information and education programs, providing information that will help individuals take personal steps to reduce their risk of cancer, to make them aware of early detection techniques and to motivate appropriate utilization of those techniques, to help individuals deal with cancer if it strikes, and to provide information to improve long-term survival;

(B) continue and expand programs to provide physicians and the public with state-of-the-art information on the treatment of particular forms of cancers, and to identify those clinical trials that might benefit patients while advancing knowledge of cancer treatment;

(C) assess the incorporation of state-of-the-art cancer treatments into clinical practice and the extent to which cancer patients receive such treatments and include the results of such assessments in the biennial reports required under section 284b 11 See References in Text note below. of this title;

(D) maintain and operate th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information and education program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Information and education program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Cancer Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) National Cancer Program The Director of the Institute in carrying out the National Cancer Program— Except as otherwise provided, experts and consultants whose services are obtained under paragraph (5) shall be paid or reimbursed, in accordance with title 5 for their travel to and from their place of service and for other expenses associated with their assignment. Such expenses shall not be allowed in connection with the assignment of an expert or consultant whose services are obtained under paragraph (5) unless the expert or consultant has agreed in writing to complete the entire period of the assignment or one year of the assignment, whichever is shorter, unless separated or reassigned for reasons which are beyond the control of the expert or consultant and which are acceptable to the Director of the Institute. If the expert or consultant violates the agreement, the money spent by the United States for such expenses is recoverable from the expert or consultant as a debt due the Un</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pre-clinical models to evaluate promising pediatric cancer therapies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pre-clinical models to evaluate promising pediatric cancer therapies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>