<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285a_13"><akn:num>285a–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific framework for recalcitrant cancers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285a–13. Scientific framework for recalcitrant cancers(a) Development of scientific framework(1) In generalFor each recalcitrant cancer identified under subsection (b), the Director of the Institute shall develop (in accordance with subsection (c)) a scientific framework for the conduct or support of research on such cancer.


(2) ContentsThe scientific framework with respect to a recalcitrant cancer shall include the following:(A) Current status(i) Review of literatureA summary of findings from the current literature in the areas of—(I) the prevention, diagnosis, and treatment of such cancer;

(II) the fundamental biologic processes that regulate such cancer (including similarities and differences of such processes from the biological processes that regulate other cancers); and

(III) the epidemiology of such cancer.


(ii) Scientific advancesThe identification of relevant emerging scientific areas and promising scientific advances in basic, translational, and clinical science relating to the areas described in subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i).


(iii) ResearchersA description of the availability of qualified individuals to conduct scientific research in the areas described in clause (i).


(iv) Coordinated research initiativesThe identification of the types of initiatives and partnerships for the coordination of intramural and extramural research of the Institute in the areas described in clause (i) with research of the relevant national research institutes, Federal agencies, and non-Federal public and private entities in such areas.


(v) Research resourcesThe identification of public and private resources, such as patient registries and tissue banks, that are available to facilitate research relating to each of the areas described in clause (i).



(B) Identification of research questionsThe identification of research questions relating to basic, translational, and clinical science in the areas described in subclauses (I) and (II) of subparagraph (A)(i) t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of scientific framework</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development of scientific framework</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of recalcitrant cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of recalcitrant cancer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Working groups</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Working groups For each recalcitrant cancer identified under subsection (b), the Director of the Institute shall convene a working group comprised of representatives of appropriate Federal agencies and other non-Federal entities to provide expertise on, and assist in developing, a scientific framework under subsection (a). The Director of the Institute (or the Director’s designee) shall participate in the meetings of each such working group.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations for exception funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recommendations for exception funding The Director of the Institute shall consider each relevant scientific framework developed under subsection (a) when making recommendations for exception funding for grant applications.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_13_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definition In this section, the term “recalcitrant cancer” means a cancer for which the five-year relative survival rate is below 50 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>