<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285a_7"><akn:num>285a–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Prostate cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285a–7. Prostate cancer(a) Expansion and coordination of activitiesThe Director of the Institute, in consultation with the National Cancer Advisory Board, shall expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of the Institute with respect to research on prostate cancer.


(b) Coordination with other institutesThe Director of the Institute shall coordinate the activities of the Director under subsection (a) with similar activities conducted by other national research institutes and agencies of the National Institutes of Health to the extent that such Institutes 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. and agencies have responsibilities that are related to prostate cancer.


(c) Programs(1) In generalIn carrying out subsection (a), the Director of the Institute shall conduct or support research to expand the understanding of the cause of, and to find a cure for, prostate cancer. Activities under such subsection shall provide for an expansion and intensification of the conduct and support of—(A) basic research concerning the etiology and causes of prostate cancer;

(B) clinical research and related activities concerning the causes, prevention, detection and treatment of prostate cancer;

(C) prevention and control and early detection programs with respect to prostate cancer in accordance with section 285a–1 of this title, particularly as it relates to intensifying research on the role of prostate specific antigen for the screening and early detection of prostate cancer;

(D) an Inter-Institute Task Force, under the direction of the Director of the Institute, to provide coordination between relevant National Institutes of Health components of research efforts on prostate cancer;

(E) control programs with respect to prostate cancer in accordance with section 285a–1 of this title;

(F) information and education programs with respect to prostate cancer in accordance with section 285a–2 of this title; and

(G) research and demonstration centers with respec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion and coordination of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expansion and coordination of activities The Director of the Institute, in consultation with the National Cancer Advisory Board, shall expand, intensify, and coordinate the activities of the Institute with respect to research on prostate cancer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination with other institutes The Director of the Institute shall coordinate the activities of the Director under subsection (a) with similar activities conducted by other national research institutes and agencies of the National Institutes of Health to the extent that such Institutes 11 So in original. Probably should not be capitalized. and agencies have responsibilities that are related to prostate cancer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>