<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285a_9"><akn:num>285a–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for education, prevention, and early detection of radiogenic cancers and diseases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285a–9. Grants for education, prevention, and early detection of radiogenic cancers and diseases(a) DefinitionIn this section the term “entity” means any—(1) National Cancer Institute-designated cancer center;

(2) Department of Veterans Affairs hospital or medical center;

(3) Federally Qualified Health Center, community health center, or hospital;

(4) agency of any State or local government, including any State department of health; or

(5) nonprofit organization.


(b) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration in consultation with the Director of the National Institutes of Health and the Director of the Indian Health Service, may make competitive grants to any entity for the purpose of carrying out programs to—(1) screen individuals described under section 4(a)(1)(A)(i) or 5(a)(1)(A) of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act (42 U.S.C. 2210 note) for cancer as a preventative health measure;

(2) provide appropriate referrals for medical treatment of individuals screened under paragraph (1) and to ensure, to the extent practicable, the provision of appropriate follow-up services;

(3) develop and disseminate public information and education programs for the detection, prevention, and treatment of radiogenic cancers and diseases; and

(4) facilitate putative applicants in the documentation of claims as described in section 5(a) of the Radiation Exposure Compensation Act (42 U.S.C. 2210 note).


(c) Indian Health ServiceThe programs under subsection (a) shall include programs provided through the Indian Health Service or through tribal contracts, compacts, grants, or cooperative agreements with the Indian Health Service and which are determined appropriate to raising the health status of Indians.


(d) Grant and contract authorityEntities receiving a grant under subsection (b) may expend the grant to carry out the purpose described in such subsection.


(e) Health coverage unaffectedNothing in t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition In this section the term “entity” means any—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration in consultation with the Director of the National Institutes of Health and the Director of the Indian Health Service, may make competitive grants to any entity for the purpose of carrying out programs to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian Health Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Indian Health Service The programs under subsection (a) shall include programs provided through the Indian Health Service or through tribal contracts, compacts, grants, or cooperative agreements with the Indian Health Service and which are determined appropriate to raising the health status of Indians.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant and contract authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Grant and contract authority Entities receiving a grant under subsection (b) may expend the grant to carry out the purpose described in such subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health coverage unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Health coverage unaffected Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect any coverage obligation of a governmental or private health plan or program relating to an individual referred to under subsection (b)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>