<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–10" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–10/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285a–10/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285a_10"><akn:num>285a–10</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, information, and education with respect to blood cancer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285a–10. Research, information, and education with respect to blood cancer(a) Joe Moakley Research Excellence Program(1) In generalThe Director of NIH shall expand, intensify, and coordinate programs for the conduct and support of research with respect to blood cancer, and particularly with respect to leukemia, lymphoma, and multiple myeloma.


(2) AdministrationThe Director of NIH shall carry out this subsection through the Director of the National Cancer Institute and in collaboration with any other agencies that the Director determines to be appropriate.



(b) Geraldine Ferraro Cancer Education Program(1) In generalThe Secretary shall direct the appropriate agency within the Department of Health and Human Services, in collaboration with the Director of NIH, to establish and carry out a program to provide information and education for patients and the general public with respect to blood cancer, and particularly with respect to the treatment of leukemia, lymphoma, and multiple myeloma.


(2) AdministrationThe Agency determined by the Secretary under paragraph (1) shall carry out this subsection in collaboration with private health organizations that have national education and patient assistance programs on blood-related cancers.



(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 417D, as added Pub. L. 107–172, § 3, May 14, 2002, 116 Stat. 541; amended Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 103(b)(17), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3688; Pub. L. 115–180, title II, § 204(a), June 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 1390.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Pub. L. 115–180 made technical correction to directory language of Pub. L. 107–172, § 3, which enacted this section.
2007—Subsec. (a)(3). Pub. L. 109–482, § 103(b)(17)(A), struck out heading and text of par. (3). Text read as follows: “For the purpose of carrying out this subsection, there is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2002 and each subsequent fiscal year. Such authorizations of appropriations are in addition</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_10_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joe Moakley Research Excellence Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Joe Moakley Research Excellence Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285a_10_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geraldine Ferraro Cancer Education Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Geraldine Ferraro Cancer Education Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>