<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285d–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285d–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285d–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285d_8"><akn:num>285d–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Juvenile arthritis and related conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285d–8. Juvenile arthritis and related conditions(a) Expansion and coordination of activitiesThe Director of the Institute, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, shall expand and intensify the programs of such Institutes with respect to research and related activities concerning juvenile arthritis and related conditions.


(b) CoordinationThe Directors referred to in subsection (a) shall jointly coordinate the programs referred to in such subsection and consult with the Arthritis and Musculoskeletal Diseases Interagency Coordinating Committee.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 442A, as added Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title III, § 301(a), Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1111; amended Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 103(b)(23), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3688.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 109–482 struck out heading and text of subsec. (c). Text read as follows: “For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2001 through 2005.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2007 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 109–482 applicable only with respect to amounts appropriated for fiscal year 2007 or subsequent fiscal years, see section 109 of Pub. L. 109–482, set out as a note under section 281 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285d_8_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expansion and coordination of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Expansion and coordination of activities The Director of the Institute, in coordination with the Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases, shall expand and intensify the programs of such Institutes with respect to research and related activities concerning juvenile arthritis and related conditions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285d_8_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination The Directors referred to in subsection (a) shall jointly coordinate the programs referred to in such subsection and consult with the Arthritis and Musculoskeletal Diseases Interagency Coordinating Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>