<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285e–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285e–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285e–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285e_2"><akn:num>285e–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Alzheimer’s Disease centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285e–2. Alzheimer’s Disease centers(a) Cooperative agreements and grants for establishing and supporting(1) The Director of the Institute may enter into cooperative agreements with and make grants to public or private nonprofit entities (including university medical centers) to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, or strengthening, and providing basic operating support (including staffing) for centers for basic and clinical research (including multidisciplinary research) into, training in, and demonstration of advanced diagnostic, prevention, and treatment methods for Alzheimer’s disease.

(2) A cooperative agreement or grant under paragraph (1) shall be entered into in accordance with policies established by the Director of NIH and after consultation with the Institute’s advisory council.


(b) Use of Federal payments under cooperative agreement or grant(1) Federal payments made under a cooperative agreement or grant under subsection (a) may, with respect to Alzheimer’s disease, be used for—(A) diagnostic examinations, patient assessments, patient care costs, and other costs necessary for conducting research;

(B) training, including training for allied health professionals;

(C) diagnostic and treatment clinics designed to meet the special needs of minority and rural populations and other underserved populations;

(D) activities to educate the public; and

(E) the dissemination of information.


(2) For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “training” does not include research training for which Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards may be provided under section 288 of this title.


(c) Support period; additional periodsSupport of a center under subsection (a) may be for a period of not to exceed five years. Such period may be extended by the Director for additional periods of not more than five years each if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285e_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements and grants for establishing and supporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperative agreements and grants for establishing and supporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285e_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of Federal payments under cooperative agreement or grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of Federal payments under cooperative agreement or grant</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285e_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support period; additional periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support period; additional periods Support of a center under subsection (a) may be for a period of not to exceed five years. Such period may be extended by the Director for additional periods of not more than five years each if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director and if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>