<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285f–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285f–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285f–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285f_5"><akn:num>285f–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Research centers for pathogens of pandemic concern</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285f–5. Research centers for pathogens of pandemic concern(a) In generalThe Director of the Institute, in collaboration, as appropriate, with the directors of applicable institutes, centers, and divisions of the National Institutes of Health, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and the Director of the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority, shall establish or continue a multidisciplinary research program to advance the discovery and preclinical development of medical products for priority virus families and other viral pathogens with a significant potential to cause a pandemic, through support for research centers.


(b) Uses of fundsThe Director of the Institute shall award funding through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or private entities to provide support for research centers described in subsection (a) for the purpose of—(1) conducting basic research through preclinical development of new medical products or technologies, including platform technologies, to address pathogens of pandemic concern;

(2) identifying potential targets for therapeutic candidates, including antivirals, to treat such pathogens;

(3) identifying existing medical products with the potential to address such pathogens, including candidates that could be used in outpatient settings; and

(4) carrying out or supporting other research related to medical products to address such pathogens, as determined appropriate by the Director.


(c) CoordinationThe Director of the Institute shall, as appropriate, provide for the coordination of activities among the centers described in subsection (a), including through—(1) facilitating the exchange of information and regular communication among the centers, as appropriate; and

(2) requiring the periodic preparation and submission to the Director of reports on the activities of each center.


(d) PriorityIn awarding funding through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under subsection (a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of the Institute, in collaboration, as appropriate, with the directors of applicable institutes, centers, and divisions of the National Institutes of Health, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, and the Director of the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority, shall establish or continue a multidisciplinary research program to advance the discovery and preclinical development of medical products for priority virus families and other viral pathogens with a significant potential to cause a pandemic, through support for research centers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses of funds The Director of the Institute shall award funding through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or private entities to provide support for research centers described in subsection (a) for the purpose of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination The Director of the Institute shall, as appropriate, provide for the coordination of activities among the centers described in subsection (a), including through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority In awarding funding through grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements under subsection (a), the Director of the Institute shall, as appropriate, give priority to applicants with existing frameworks and partnerships, as applicable, to support the advancement of such research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Collaboration The Director of the Institute shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285f_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement, not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Supplement, not supplant Any support received by a center described in subsection (a) under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other public or private support for activities authorized to be supported.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>