<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285g–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285g–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285g–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285g_4"><akn:num>285g–4</akn:num><akn:heading>National Center for Medical Rehabilitation Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285g–4. National Center for Medical Rehabilitation Research(a) Establishment of CenterThere shall be in the Institute an agency to be known as the National Center for Medical Rehabilitation Research (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Director of the Institute shall appoint a qualified individual to serve as Director of the Center. The Director of the Center shall report directly to the Director of the Institute.


(b) PurposeThe general purpose of the Center is the conduct, support, and coordination of research and research training (including research on the development of orthotic and prosthetic devices), the dissemination of health information, and other programs with respect to the rehabilitation of individuals with physical disabilities resulting from diseases or disorders of the neurological, musculoskeletal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, or any other physiological system (hereafter in this section referred to as “medical rehabilitation”).


(c) Authority of Director(1) In carrying out the purpose described in subsection (b), the Director of the Center may—(A) provide for clinical trials regarding medical rehabilitation;

(B) provide for research regarding model systems of medical rehabilitation;

(C) coordinate the activities within the Center with similar activities of other agencies of the Federal Government, including the other agencies of the National Institutes of Health, and with similar activities of other public entities and of private entities;

(D) support multidisciplinary medical rehabilitation research conducted or supported by more than one such agency;

(E) in consultation with the advisory council for the Institute and with the approval of the Director of NIH—(i) establish technical and scientific peer review groups in addition to those appointed under section 282(b)(16) of this title; and

(ii) appoint the members of peer review groups established under subparagraph (A); and


(F) support medical rehabilitation resear</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of Center There shall be in the Institute an agency to be known as the National Center for Medical Rehabilitation Research (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Director of the Institute shall appoint a qualified individual to serve as Director of the Center. The Director of the Center shall report directly to the Director of the Institute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The general purpose of the Center is the conduct, support, and coordination of research and research training (including research on the development of orthotic and prosthetic devices), the dissemination of health information, and other programs with respect to the rehabilitation of individuals with physical disabilities resulting from diseases or disorders of the neurological, musculoskeletal, cardiovascular, pulmonary, or any other physiological system (hereafter in this section referred to as “medical rehabilitation”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority of Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Research Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical Rehabilitation Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Medical Rehabilitation Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Advisory Board on Medical Rehabilitation Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) National Advisory Board on Medical Rehabilitation Research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and coordination of medical rehabilitation research programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review and coordination of medical rehabilitation research programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285g_4_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Medical rehabilitation research” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) “Medical rehabilitation research” defined For purposes of this section, the term “medical rehabilitation research” means the science of mechanisms and interventions that prevent, improve, restore, or replace lost, underdeveloped, or deteriorating function.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>