<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285m–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285m–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285m–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285m_3"><akn:num>285m–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Multipurpose deafness and other communication disorders center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285m–3. Multipurpose deafness and other communication disorders center(a) Development, modernization and operation; “modernization” definedThe Director of the Institute shall, after consultation with the advisory council for the Institute, provide for the development, modernization, and operation (including care required for research) of new and existing centers for studies of disorders of hearing and other communication processes. For purposes of this section, the term “modernization” means the alteration, remodeling, improvement, expansion, and repair of existing buildings and the provision of equipment for such buildings to the extent necessary to make them suitable for use as centers described in the preceding sentence.


(b) Use of facilities; qualificationsEach center assisted under this section shall—(1) use the facilities of a single institution or a consortium of cooperating institutions; and

(2) meet such qualifications as may be prescribed by the Secretary.


(c) Requisite programsEach center assisted under this section shall, at least, conduct—(1) basic and clinical research into the cause 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. diagnosis, early detection, prevention, control and treatment of disorders of hearing and other communication processes and complications resulting from such disorders, including research into rehabilitative aids, implantable biomaterials, auditory speech processors, speech production devices, and other otolaryngologic procedures;

(2) training programs for physicians, scientists, and other health and allied health professionals;

(3) information and continuing education programs for physicians and other health and allied health professionals who will provide care for patients with disorders of hearing or other communication processes; and

(4) programs for the dissemination to the general public of information—(A) on the importance of early detection of disorders of hearing and other communication processes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development, modernization and operation; “modernization” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development, modernization and operation; “modernization” defined The Director of the Institute shall, after consultation with the advisory council for the Institute, provide for the development, modernization, and operation (including care required for research) of new and existing centers for studies of disorders of hearing and other communication processes. For purposes of this section, the term “modernization” means the alteration, remodeling, improvement, expansion, and repair of existing buildings and the provision of equipment for such buildings to the extent necessary to make them suitable for use as centers described in the preceding sentence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of facilities; qualifications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of facilities; qualifications Each center assisted under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisite programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requisite programs Each center assisted under this section shall, at least, conduct—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Stipends</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Stipends A center may use funds provided under subsection (a) to provide stipends for health professionals enrolled in training programs described in subsection (c)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Discretionary programs Each center assisted under this section may conduct programs—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable geographical distribution; needs of elderly and children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Equitable geographical distribution; needs of elderly and children The Director of the Institute shall, to the extent practicable, provide for an equitable geographical distribution of centers assisted under this section. The Director shall give appropriate consideration to the need for centers especially suited to meeting the needs of the elderly, and of children (particularly with respect to their education and training), affected by disorders of hearing or other communication processes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285m_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of support; recommended extensions of peer review group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Period of support; recommended extensions of peer review group Support of a center under this section may be for a period not to exceed seven years. Such period may be extended by the Director of the Institute for one or more additional periods of not more than five years if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director, with the advice of the Institute’s advisory council, if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>