<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285p–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285p–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285p–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285p_2"><akn:num>285p–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Rural Mental Health Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285p–2. Office of Rural Mental Health Research(a) In generalThere is established within the Institute an office to be known as the Office of Rural Mental Health Research (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director, who shall be appointed by the Director of such Institute from among individuals experienced or knowledgeable in the provision of mental health services in rural areas. The Secretary shall carry out the authorities established in this section acting through the Director of the Office.


(b) Coordination of activitiesThe Director of the Office, in consultation with the Director of the Institute and with the Director of the Office of Rural Health Policy, shall—(1) coordinate the research activities of the Department of Health and Human Services as such activities relate to the mental health of residents of rural areas; and

(2) coordinate the activities of the Office with similar activities of public and nonprofit private entities.


(c) Research, demonstrations, evaluations, and disseminationThe Director of the Office may, with respect to the mental health of adults and children residing in rural areas—(1) conduct research on conditions that are unique to the residents of rural areas, or more serious or prevalent in such residents;

(2) conduct research on improving the delivery of services in such areas; and

(3) disseminate information to appropriate public and nonprofit private entities.


(d) Authority regarding grants and contractsThe Director of the Office may carry out the authorities established in subsection (c) directly and through grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts with public or nonprofit private entities.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 464T, as added Pub. L. 102–321, title I, § 124(b), July 10, 1992, 106 Stat. 365; amended Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 104(b)(1)(L), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3693.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Subsec. (e). Pub. L. 109–482 struck out headin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285p_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established within the Institute an office to be known as the Office of Rural Mental Health Research (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director, who shall be appointed by the Director of such Institute from among individuals experienced or knowledgeable in the provision of mental health services in rural areas. The Secretary shall carry out the authorities established in this section acting through the Director of the Office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285p_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination of activities The Director of the Office, in consultation with the Director of the Institute and with the Director of the Office of Rural Health Policy, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285p_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, demonstrations, evaluations, and dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Research, demonstrations, evaluations, and dissemination The Director of the Office may, with respect to the mental health of adults and children residing in rural areas—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285p_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority regarding grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authority regarding grants and contracts The Director of the Office may carry out the authorities established in subsection (c) directly and through grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts with public or nonprofit private entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>