<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285q–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285q–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285q–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285q_2"><akn:num>285q–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285q–2. Advisory council(a) Appointment; functions and duties; acceptance of conditional gifts; subcommittees(1) The Secretary shall appoint an advisory council for the Institute which shall advise, assist, consult with, and make recommendations to the Secretary and the Director of the Institute on matters related to the activities carried out by and through the Institute and the policies respecting such activities.

(2) The advisory council for the Institute may recommend to the Secretary acceptance, in accordance with section 238 of this title, of conditional gifts for study, investigations, and research and for the acquisition of grounds or construction, equipping, or maintenance of facilities for the Institute.

(3) The advisory council for the Institute—(A)(i) may make recommendations to the Director of the Institute respecting research conducted at the Institute,

(ii) may review applications for grants and cooperative agreements for research or training and recommend for approval applications for projects which show promise of making valuable contributions to human knowledge, and

(iii) may review any grant, contract, or cooperative agreement proposed to be made or entered into by the Institute;


(B) may collect, by correspondence or by personal investigation, information as to studies which are being carried on in the United States or any other country as to the diseases, disorders, or other aspects of human health with respect to which the Institute is concerned and with the approval of the Director of the Institute make available such information through appropriate publications for the benefit of public and private health entities and health professions personnel and scientists and for the information of the general public; and

(C) may appoint subcommittees and convene workshops and conferences.



(b) Membership; ex officio members; compensation(1) The advisory council shall consist of ex officio members and not more than eighteen members appointed b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment; functions and duties; acceptance of conditional gifts; subcommittees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment; functions and duties; acceptance of conditional gifts; subcommittees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership; ex officio members; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership; ex officio members; compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of office; vacancy; reappointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Term of office; vacancy; reappointment The term of office of an appointed member of the advisory council is four years, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of such term and the Secretary shall make appointments to an advisory council in such a manner as to ensure that the terms of the members do not all expire in the same year. A member may serve after the expiration of the member’s term until a successor has taken office. A member who has been appointed for a term of four years may not be reappointed to an advisory council before two years from the date of expiration of such term of office. If a vacancy occurs in the advisory council among the appointed members, the Secretary shall make an appointment to fill the vacancy within 90 days from the date the vacancy occurs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairman; selection; term of office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chairman; selection; term of office The chairman of the advisory council shall be selected by the Secretary from among the appointed members, except that the Secretary may select the Director of the Institute to be the chairman of the advisory council. The term of office of the chairman shall be two years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings The advisory council shall meet at the call of the chairman or upon the request of the Director of the Institute, but at least three times each fiscal year. The location of the meetings of the advisory council is subject to the approval of the Director of the Institute.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive secretary; staff; orientation and training for new members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Executive secretary; staff; orientation and training for new members The Director of the Institute shall designate a member of the staff of the Institute to serve as the executive secretary of the advisory council. The Director of the Institute shall make available to the advisory council such staff, information, and other assistance as it may require to carry out its functions. The Director of the Institute shall provide orientation and training for new members of the advisory council to provide them with such information and training as may be appropriate for their effective participation in the functions of the advisory council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285q_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Material for inclusion in biennial report; additional reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Material for inclusion in biennial report; additional reports The advisory council may prepare, for inclusion in the triennial report made under section 283 of this title (1) comments respecting the activities of the advisory council in the fiscal years respecting which the report is prepared, (2) comments on the progress of the Institute in meeting its objectives, and (3) recommendations respecting the future directions and program and policy emphasis of the Institute. The advisory council may prepare such additional reports as it may determine appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>