<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285t_1"><akn:num>285t–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers of excellence for research education and training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285t–1. Centers of excellence for research education and training(a) In generalThe Director of the Institute shall make awards of grants or contracts to designated biomedical and behavioral research institutions under paragraph (1) of subsection (c), or to consortia under paragraph (2) of such subsection, for the purpose of assisting the institutions in supporting programs of excellence in biomedical and behavioral research training for individuals who are members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations.


(b) Required use of fundsAn award may be made under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that the grant will be expended—(1) to train members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations as professionals in the area of biomedical or behavioral research or both; or

(2) to expand, remodel, renovate, or alter existing research facilities or construct new research facilities for the purpose of conducting minority health disparities research and other health disparities research.


(c) Centers of excellence(1) In generalFor purposes of this section, a designated biomedical and behavioral research institution is a biomedical and behavioral research institution that—(A) has a significant number of members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations enrolled as students in the institution (including individuals accepted for enrollment in the institution);

(B) has been effective in assisting such students of the institution to complete the program of education or training and receive the degree involved;

(C) has made significant efforts to recruit minority students to enroll in and graduate from the institution, which may include providing means-tested scholarships and other financial assistance as appropriate; and

(D) has made significant recruitment efforts to increase the number of minority or other members of health disparity populations ser</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director of the Institute shall make awards of grants or contracts to designated biomedical and behavioral research institutions under paragraph (1) of subsection (c), or to consortia under paragraph (2) of such subsection, for the purpose of assisting the institutions in supporting programs of excellence in biomedical and behavioral research training for individuals who are members of minority health disparity populations or other health disparity populations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Required use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Required use of funds An award may be made under subsection (a) only if the applicant involved agrees that the grant will be expended—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers of excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Centers of excellence</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duration of grant The period during which payments are made under a grant under subsection (a) may not exceed 5 years. Such payments shall be subject to annual approval by the Director of the Institute and to the availability of appropriations for the fiscal year involved to make the payments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Maintenance of effort</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain expenditures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Certain expenditures The Director of the Institute may authorize a designated biomedical and behavioral research institution to expend a portion of an award under subsection (a) for research endowments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>