<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/285t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_285t"><akn:num>285t</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose of Institute</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 285t. Purpose of Institute(a) In generalThe general purpose of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities (in this subpart referred to as the “Institute”) is the conduct and support of research, training, dissemination of information, and other programs with respect to minority health conditions and other populations with health disparities.


(b) PrioritiesThe Director of the Institute shall in expending amounts appropriated under this subpart give priority to conducting and supporting minority health disparities research.


(c) Minority health disparities researchFor purposes of this subpart:(1) The term “minority health disparities research” means basic, clinical, and behavioral research on minority health conditions (as defined in paragraph (2)), including research to prevent, diagnose, and treat such conditions.

(2) The term “minority health conditions”, with respect to individuals who are members of minority groups, means all diseases, disorders, and conditions (including with respect to mental health and substance abuse)—(A) unique to, more serious, or more prevalent in such individuals;

(B) for which the factors of medical risk or types of medical intervention may be different for such individuals, or for which it is unknown whether such factors or types are different for such individuals; or

(C) with respect to which there has been insufficient research involving such individuals as subjects or insufficient data on such individuals.


(3) The term “minority group” has the meaning given the term “racial and ethnic minority group” in section 300u–6 of this title.

(4) The terms “minority” and “minorities” refer to individuals from a minority group.


(d) Health disparity populationsFor purposes of this subpart:(1) A population is a health disparity population if, as determined by the Director of the Institute after consultation with the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, there is a significant disparity in t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The general purpose of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities (in this subpart referred to as the “Institute”) is the conduct and support of research, training, dissemination of information, and other programs with respect to minority health conditions and other populations with health disparities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priorities The Director of the Institute shall in expending amounts appropriated under this subpart give priority to conducting and supporting minority health disparities research.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minority health disparities research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Minority health disparities research For purposes of this subpart:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health disparity populations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Health disparity populations For purposes of this subpart:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of activities The Director of the Institute shall act as the primary Federal official with responsibility for coordinating all minority health disparities research and other health disparities research conducted or supported by the National Institutes of Health, and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaborative comprehensive plan and budget</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Collaborative comprehensive plan and budget</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Participation in clinical research The Director of the Institute shall work with the Director of NIH and the directors of the agencies of the National Institutes of Health to carry out the provisions of section 289a–2 of this title that relate to minority groups.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research endowments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Research endowments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Certain activities In carrying out subsection (a), the Director of the Institute—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_285t_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Advisory council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>