<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/286b–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/286b–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/286b–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_286b_6"><akn:num>286b–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts for establishment of regional medical libraries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 286b–6. Grants and contracts for establishment of regional medical libraries(a) Existing public or private nonprofit medical librariesThe Secretary, with the advice of the Board, shall make grants to and enter into contracts with existing public or private nonprofit medical libraries so as to enable each of them to serve as the regional medical library for the geographical area in which it is located.


(b) Uses for grants and contractsThe uses for which grants and contracts under this section may be employed include the—(1) acquisition of books, journals, and other similar materials;

(2) cataloging, binding, and other procedures for processing library resource materials for use by those who are served by the library;

(3) acquisition of duplicating devices and other equipment to facilitate the use of the resources of the library by those who are served by it;

(4) acquisition of mechanisms and employment of personnel for the speedy transmission of materials from the regional library to local libraries in the geographic area served by the regional library; and

(5) planning for services and activities under this section.


(c) Conditions(1) Grants and contracts under this section shall only be made to or entered into with medical libraries which agree—(A) to modify and increase their library resources, and to supplement the resources of cooperating libraries in the region, so as to be able to provide adequate supportive services to all libraries in the region as well as to individual users of library services; and

(B) to provide free loan services to qualified users and make available photoduplicated or facsimile copies of biomedical materials which qualified requesters may retain.


(2) The Secretary, in awarding grants and contracts under this section, shall give priority to medical libraries having the greatest potential of fulfilling the needs for regional medical libraries. In determining the priority to be assigned to any medical library, the Secretary sha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_286b_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Existing public or private nonprofit medical libraries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Existing public or private nonprofit medical libraries The Secretary, with the advice of the Board, shall make grants to and enter into contracts with existing public or private nonprofit medical libraries so as to enable each of them to serve as the regional medical library for the geographical area in which it is located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_286b_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses for grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Uses for grants and contracts The uses for which grants and contracts under this section may be employed include the—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_286b_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_286b_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basic resources materials; limitation on grant or contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Basic resources materials; limitation on grant or contract Grants and contracts under this section for basic resource materials to a library may not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>