<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_287"><akn:num>287</akn:num><akn:heading>National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 287. National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences(a) PurposeThe purpose of the National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences (in this subpart referred to as the “Center”) is to advance translational sciences, including by—(1) coordinating and developing resources that leverage basic research in support of translational science; and

(2) developing partnerships and working cooperatively to foster synergy in ways that do not create duplication, redundancy, and competition with industry activities.


(b) Clinical trial activities(1) In generalThe Center may develop and provide infrastructure and resources for all phases of clinical trials research. Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Center may support clinical trials only through the end of phase IIB.


(2) ExceptionThe Center may support clinical trial activities through the end of phase III for a treatment for a rare disease or condition (as defined in section 360bb of title 21) so long as—(A) the Center gives public notice for a period of at least 120 days of the Center’s intention to support the clinical trial activities in phase III;

(B) no public or private organization provides credible written intent to the Center that the organization has timely plans to further the clinical trial activities or conduct clinical trials of a similar nature beyond phase IIB; and

(C) the Center ensures that support of the clinical trial activities in phase III will not increase the Federal Government’s liability beyond the award value of the Center’s support.



(c) Biennial reportThe Center shall publish a report on a biennial basis that, with respect to all research supported by the Center, includes a complete list of—(1) the molecules being studied;

(2) clinical trial activities being conducted;

(3) the methods and tools in development;

(4) ongoing partnerships, including—(A) the rationale for each partnership;

(B) the status of each partnership;

(C) the funding provided by the Center to other enti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of the National Center for Advancing Translational Sciences (in this subpart referred to as the “Center”) is to advance translational sciences, including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clinical trial activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Clinical trial activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biennial report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Biennial report The Center shall publish a report on a biennial basis that, with respect to all research supported by the Center, includes a complete list of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Inclusion of list The first biennial report submitted under this section after December 13, 2016, shall include a complete list of all of the methods and tools, if any, which have been developed by research supported by the Center.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret, or other privileged or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5 or section 1905 of title 18.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>