<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287a–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287a–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287a–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_287a_2"><akn:num>287a–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Rare disease regional centers of excellence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 287a–2. Rare disease regional centers of excellence(a) Cooperative agreements and grants(1) In generalThe Director of the Office of Rare Diseases (in this section referred to as the “Director”), in collaboration with the directors of the other relevant institutes and centers of the National Institutes of Health, may enter into cooperative agreements with and make grants to public or private nonprofit entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, or strengthening, and providing basic operating support for regional centers of excellence for clinical research into, training in, and demonstration of diagnostic, prevention, control, and treatment methods for rare diseases.


(2) PoliciesA cooperative agreement or grant under paragraph (1) shall be entered into in accordance with policies established by the Director of NIH.



(b) Coordination with other institutesThe Director shall coordinate the activities under this section with similar activities conducted by other national research institutes, centers and agencies of the National Institutes of Health and by the Food and Drug Administration to the extent that such institutes, centers and agencies have responsibilities that are related to rare diseases.


(c) Uses for Federal payments under cooperative agreements or grantsFederal payments made under a cooperative agreement or grant under subsection (a) may be used for—(1) staffing, administrative, and other basic operating costs, including such patient care costs as are required for research;

(2) clinical training, including training for allied health professionals, continuing education for health professionals and allied health professions personnel, and information programs for the public with respect to rare diseases; and

(3) clinical research and demonstration programs.


(d) Period of support; additional periodsSupport of a center under subsection (a) may be for a period of not to exceed 5 years. Such period may be extended by the Director</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287a_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperative agreements and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cooperative agreements and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287a_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination with other institutes The Director shall coordinate the activities under this section with similar activities conducted by other national research institutes, centers and agencies of the National Institutes of Health and by the Food and Drug Administration to the extent that such institutes, centers and agencies have responsibilities that are related to rare diseases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287a_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses for Federal payments under cooperative agreements or grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uses for Federal payments under cooperative agreements or grants Federal payments made under a cooperative agreement or grant under subsection (a) may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287a_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of support; additional periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Period of support; additional periods Support of a center under subsection (a) may be for a period of not to exceed 5 years. Such period may be extended by the Director for additional periods of not more than 5 years if the operations of such center have been reviewed by an appropriate technical and scientific peer review group established by the Director and if such group has recommended to the Director that such period should be extended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>