<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/287d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_287d"><akn:num>287d</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Research on Women’s Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 287d. Office of Research on Women’s Health(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Office of the Director of NIH an office to be known as the Office of Research on Women’s Health (in this part referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director, who shall be appointed by the Director of NIH and who shall report directly to the Director.


(b) PurposeThe Director of the Office shall—(1) identify projects of research on women’s health that should be conducted or supported by the national research institutes;

(2) identify multidisciplinary research relating to research on women’s health that should be so conducted or supported;

(3) carry out paragraphs (1) and (2) with respect to the aging process in women, with priority given to menopause;

(4) promote coordination and collaboration among entities conducting research identified under any of paragraphs (1) through (3);

(5) encourage the conduct of such research by entities receiving funds from the national research institutes;

(6) recommend an agenda for conducting and supporting such research;

(7) promote the sufficient allocation of the resources of the national research institutes for conducting and supporting such research;

(8) assist in the administration of section 289a–2 of this title with respect to the inclusion of women as subjects in clinical research; and

(9) prepare the report required in section 287d–2 of this title.


(c) Coordinating Committee(1) In carrying out subsection (b), the Director of the Office shall establish a committee to be known as the Coordinating Committee on Research on Women’s Health (in this subsection referred to as the “Coordinating Committee”).

(2) The Coordinating Committee shall be composed of the Directors of the national research institutes (or the senior-level staff designees of the Directors).

(3) The Director of the Office shall serve as the chair of the Coordinating Committee.

(4) With respect to research on women’s health, the Coordi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Office of the Director of NIH an office to be known as the Office of Research on Women’s Health (in this part referred to as the “Office”). The Office shall be headed by a director, who shall be appointed by the Director of NIH and who shall report directly to the Director.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose The Director of the Office shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordinating Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordinating Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Advisory Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation of women among researchers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Representation of women among researchers The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Personnel and in collaboration with the Director of the Office, shall determine the extent to which women are represented among senior physicians and scientists of the national research institutes and among physicians and scientists conducting research with funds provided by such institutes, and as appropriate, carry out activities to increase the extent of such representation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_287d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>