<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288"><akn:num>288</akn:num><akn:heading>Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288. Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards(a) Biomedical and behavioral research and research training; programs and institutions included; restriction; special consideration(1) The Secretary shall—(A) provide Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards for—(i) biomedical and behavioral research at the National Institutes of Health in matters relating to the cause, diagnosis, prevention, and treatment of the diseases or other health problems to which the activities of the National Institutes of Health and Administration 11 So in original. Reference to Administration probably should not appear. are directed;

(ii) training at the National Institutes of Health and at the Administration 1 of individuals to undertake such research;

(iii) biomedical and behavioral research and health services research (including research in primary medical care) at public and nonprofit private entities; and

(iv) pre-doctoral and post-doctoral training at public and private institutions of individuals to undertake biomedical and behavioral research;


(B) make grants to public and nonprofit private institutions to enable such institutions to make Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards for research (and training to undertake biomedical and behavioral research) in the matters described in subparagraph (A)(i) to individuals selected by such institutions; and

(C) provide contracts for scholarships and loan repayments in accordance with sections 288–4 and 288–5 22 See References in Text note below. of this title, subject to providing not more than an aggregate 50 such contracts during the fiscal years 1994 through 1996.


A reference in this subsection to the National Institutes of Health shall be considered to include the institutes, agencies, divisions, and bureaus included in the National Institutes of Health or under the Administration,1 as the case may be.

(2) Ruth L. Kirschstein National Research Service Awards may not be used to support reside</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biomedical and behavioral research and research training; programs and institutions included; restriction; special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Biomedical and behavioral research and research training; programs and institutions included; restriction; special consideration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prerequisites for Award; review and approval by appropriate advisory councils; Award period; uses for Award; payments to non-Federal public or nonprofit private institutions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prerequisites for Award; review and approval by appropriate advisory councils; Award period; uses for Award; payments to non-Federal public or nonprofit private institutions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health research or teaching; service period; recovery upon noncompliance with service requirement, formula; cancellation or waiver of obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Health research or teaching; service period; recovery upon noncompliance with service requirement, formula; cancellation or waiver of obligation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>