<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/288–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_288_4"><akn:num>288–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Undergraduate scholarship program regarding professions needed by National Research Institutes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 288–4. Undergraduate scholarship program regarding professions needed by National Research Institutes(a) Establishment of program(1) In generalSubject to section 288(a)(1)(C) of this title, the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, may carry out a program of entering into contracts with individuals described in paragraph (2) under which—(A) the Director of NIH agrees to provide to the individuals scholarships for pursuing, as undergraduates at accredited institutions of higher education, academic programs appropriate for careers in professions needed by the National Institutes of Health; and

(B) the individuals agree to serve as employees of the National Institutes of Health, for the period described in subsection (c), in positions that are needed by the National Institutes of Health and for which the individuals are qualified.


(2) Individuals from disadvantaged backgroundsThe individuals referred to in paragraph (1) are individuals who—(A) are enrolled or accepted for enrollment as full-time undergraduates at accredited institutions of higher education; and

(B) are from disadvantaged backgrounds.



(b) Facilitation of interest of students in careers at National Institutes of HealthIn providing employment to individuals pursuant to contracts under subsection (a)(1), the Director of NIH shall carry out activities to facilitate the interest of the individuals in pursuing careers as employees of the National Institutes of Health.


(c) Period of obligated service(1) Duration of serviceFor purposes of subparagraph (B) of subsection (a)(1), the period of service for which an individual is obligated to serve as an employee of the National Institutes of Health is, subject to paragraph (2)(A), 12 months for each academic year for which the scholarship under such subsection is provided.


(2) Schedule for service(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), the Director of NIH may not provide a scholarship under subsection (a) unless the individual applying for the schola</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilitation of interest of students in careers at National Institutes of Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facilitation of interest of students in careers at National Institutes of Health In providing employment to individuals pursuant to contracts under subsection (a)(1), the Director of NIH shall carry out activities to facilitate the interest of the individuals in pursuing careers as employees of the National Institutes of Health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Period of obligated service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Period of obligated service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions regarding scholarship</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provisions regarding scholarship</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties for breach of scholarship contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Penalties for breach of scholarship contract The provisions of section 254o of this title shall apply to the program established in subsection (a) to the same extent and in the same manner as such provisions apply to the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program established in section 254l–1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirement of application The Director of NIH may not provide a scholarship under subsection (a) unless an application for the scholarship is submitted to the Director and the application is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Director determines to be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_288_4_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Availability of authorization of appropriations Amounts appropriated for a fiscal year for scholarships under this section shall remain available until the expiration of the second fiscal year beginning after the fiscal year for which the amounts were appropriated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>