<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289a_2"><akn:num>289a–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of women and minorities in clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289a–2. Inclusion of women and minorities in clinical research(a) Requirement of inclusion(1) In generalIn conducting or supporting clinical research for purposes of this subchapter, the Director of NIH shall, subject to subsection (b), ensure that—(A) women are included as subjects in each project of such research; and

(B) members of minority groups are included as subjects in such research.


(2) Outreach regarding participation as subjectsThe Director of NIH, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Research on Women’s Health and the Director of the Office of Research on Minority Health, shall conduct or support outreach programs for the recruitment of women and members of minority groups as subjects in projects of clinical research.


(3) Strategic planning(A) In generalThe directors of the national institutes and national centers shall consult at least once annually with the Director of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities and the Director of the Office of Research on Women’s Health regarding objectives of the national institutes and national centers to ensure that future activities by such institutes and centers take into account women and minorities and are focused on reducing health disparities.


(B) Strategic plansAny strategic plan issued by a national institute or national center shall include details on the objectives described in subparagraph (A).




(b) Inapplicability of requirementThe requirement established in subsection (a) regarding women and members of minority groups shall not apply to a project of clinical research if the inclusion, as subjects in the project, of women and members of minority groups, respectively—(1) is inappropriate with respect to the health of the subjects;

(2) is inappropriate with respect to the purpose of the research; or

(3) is inappropriate under such other circumstances as the Director of NIH may designate.


(c) Design of clinical trials(1) In generalIn the case of any clin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of inclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of inclusion</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Inapplicability of requirement The requirement established in subsection (a) regarding women and members of minority groups shall not apply to a project of clinical research if the inclusion, as subjects in the project, of women and members of minority groups, respectively—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Design of clinical trials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Design of clinical trials</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date certain for guidelines; applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Date certain for guidelines; applicability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by advisory councils</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports by advisory councils</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>