<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289a"><akn:num>289a</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289a. Peer review requirements(a) Applications for biomedical and behavioral research grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts; regulations(1) The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall by regulation require appropriate technical and scientific peer review of—(A) applications made for grants and cooperative agreements under this chapter for biomedical and behavioral research; and

(B) applications made for biomedical and behavioral research and development contracts to be administered through the National Institutes of Health.


(2) Regulations promulgated under paragraph (1) shall require that the review of applications made for grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements required by the regulations be conducted—(A) to the extent practical, in a manner consistent with the system for technical and scientific peer review applicable on November 20, 1985, to grants under this chapter for biomedical and behavioral research, and

(B) to the extent practical, by technical and scientific peer review groups performing such review on or before November 20, 1985,


and shall authorize such review to be conducted by groups appointed under sections 282(b)(16) and 284(c)(3) of this title.


(b) Periodic review of research at National Institutes of HealthThe Director of NIH shall establish procedures for periodic technical and scientific peer review of research at the National Institutes of Health. Such procedures shall require that—(1) the reviewing entity be provided a written description of the research to be reviewed, and

(2) the reviewing entity provide the advisory council of the national research institute involved with such description and the results of the review by the entity,


and shall authorize such review to be conducted by groups appointed under sections 282(b)(6) 11 See References in Text note below. and 284(c)(3) of this title.

(c) Compliance with requirements for inclusion of women and minorities in clinical research(1) In technical an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications for biomedical and behavioral research grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applications for biomedical and behavioral research grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts; regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic review of research at National Institutes of Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Periodic review of research at National Institutes of Health The Director of NIH shall establish procedures for periodic technical and scientific peer review of research at the National Institutes of Health. Such procedures shall require that— and shall authorize such review to be conducted by groups appointed under sections 282(b)(6) 11 See References in Text note below. and 284(c)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with requirements for inclusion of women and minorities in clinical research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Compliance with requirements for inclusion of women and minorities in clinical research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>