<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289b–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289b–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289b–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289b_1"><akn:num>289b–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection against financial conflicts of interest in certain projects of research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289b–1. Protection against financial conflicts of interest in certain projects of research(a) Issuance of regulationsThe Secretary shall by regulation define the specific circumstances that constitute the existence of a financial interest in a project on the part of an entity or individual that will, or may be reasonably expected to, create a bias in favor of obtaining results in such project that are consistent with such financial interest. Such definition shall apply uniformly to each entity or individual conducting a research project under this chapter. In the case of any entity or individual receiving assistance from the Secretary for a project of research described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall by regulation establish standards for responding to, including managing, reducing, or eliminating, the existence of such a financial interest. The entity may adopt individualized procedures for implementing the standards.


(b) Relevant projectsA project of research referred to in subsection (a) is a project of clinical research whose purpose is to evaluate the safety or effectiveness of a drug, medical device, or treatment and for which such entity is receiving assistance from the Secretary.


(c) Identifying and reporting to SecretaryThe Secretary shall by regulation require that each entity described in subsection (a) that applies for assistance under this chapter for any project described in subsection (b) submit in or with its application for such assistance—(1) assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that such entity has established and has in effect an administrative process under subsection (a) to identify financial interests (as defined under subsection (a)) that exist regarding the project; and

(2) an agreement that the entity will report to the Secretary such interests identified by the entity and how any such interests identified by the entity will be managed or eliminated in order that the project in question will be protected from bias that may</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Issuance of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Issuance of regulations The Secretary shall by regulation define the specific circumstances that constitute the existence of a financial interest in a project on the part of an entity or individual that will, or may be reasonably expected to, create a bias in favor of obtaining results in such project that are consistent with such financial interest. Such definition shall apply uniformly to each entity or individual conducting a research project under this chapter. In the case of any entity or individual receiving assistance from the Secretary for a project of research described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall by regulation establish standards for responding to, including managing, reducing, or eliminating, the existence of such a financial interest. The entity may adopt individualized procedures for implementing the standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relevant projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Relevant projects A project of research referred to in subsection (a) is a project of clinical research whose purpose is to evaluate the safety or effectiveness of a drug, medical device, or treatment and for which such entity is receiving assistance from the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identifying and reporting to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identifying and reporting to Secretary The Secretary shall by regulation require that each entity described in subsection (a) that applies for assistance under this chapter for any project described in subsection (b) submit in or with its application for such assistance—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Monitoring of process The Secretary shall monitor the establishment and conduct of the administrative process established by an entity pursuant to subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Response In any case in which the Secretary determines that an entity has failed to comply with subsection (c) regarding a project of research described in subsection (b), the Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289b_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>