<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289d"><akn:num>289d</akn:num><akn:heading>Animals in research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289d. Animals in research(a) Establishment of guidelinesThe Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall establish guidelines for the following:(1) The proper care of animals to be used in biomedical and behavioral research.

(2) The proper treatment of animals while being used in such research. Guidelines under this paragraph shall require—(A) the appropriate use of tranquilizers, analgesics, anesthetics, paralytics, and euthanasia for animals in such research; and

(B) appropriate pre-surgical and post-surgical veterinary medical and nursing care for animals in such research.


Such guidelines shall not be construed to prescribe methods of research.

(3) The organization and operation of animal care committees in accordance with subsection (b).


(b) Animal care committees; establishment; membership; functions(1) Guidelines of the Secretary under subsection (a)(3) shall require animal care committees at each entity which conducts biomedical and behavioral research with funds provided under this chapter (including the National Institutes of Health and the national research institutes) to assure compliance with the guidelines established under subsection (a).

(2) Each animal care committee shall be appointed by the chief executive officer of the entity for which the committee is established, shall be composed of not fewer than three members, and shall include at least one individual who has no association with such entity and at least one doctor of veterinary medicine.

(3) Each animal care committee of a research entity shall—(A) review the care and treatment of animals in all animal study areas and facilities of the research entity at least semi-annually to evaluate compliance with applicable guidelines established under subsection (a) for appropriate animal care and treatment;

(B) keep appropriate records of reviews conducted under subparagraph (A); and

(C) for each review conducted under subparagraph (A), file with the Director of NIH at least annua</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of guidelines The Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, shall establish guidelines for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Animal care committees; establishment; membership; functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Animal care committees; establishment; membership; functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assurances required in application or contract proposal; reasons for use of animals; notice and comment requirements for promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assurances required in application or contract proposal; reasons for use of animals; notice and comment requirements for promulgation of regulations The Director of NIH shall require each applicant for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement involving research on animals which is administered by the National Institutes of Health or any national research institute to include in its application or contract proposal, submitted after the expiration of the twelve-month period beginning on November 20, 1985— Notwithstanding subsection (a)(2) of section 553 of title 5, regulations under this subsection shall be promulgated in accordance with the notice and comment requirements of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to meet guidelines; suspension or revocation of grant or contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Failure to meet guidelines; suspension or revocation of grant or contract If the Director of NIH determines that— the Director of NIH shall suspend or revoke such grant or contract under such conditions as the Director determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of trade secrets or privileged or confidential information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure of trade secrets or privileged or confidential information No guideline or regulation promulgated under subsection (a) or (c) may require a research entity to disclose publicly trade secrets or commercial or financial information which is privileged or confidential.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>