<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289g_1"><akn:num>289g–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Research on transplantation of fetal tissue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289g–1. Research on transplantation of fetal tissue(a) Establishment of program(1) In generalThe Secretary may conduct or support research on the transplantation of human fetal tissue for therapeutic purposes.


(2) Source of tissueHuman fetal tissue may be used in research carried out under paragraph (1) regardless of whether the tissue is obtained pursuant to a spontaneous or induced abortion or pursuant to a stillbirth.



(b) Informed consent of donor(1) In generalIn research carried out under subsection (a), human fetal tissue may be used only if the woman providing the tissue makes a statement, made in writing and signed by the woman, declaring that—(A) the woman donates the fetal tissue for use in research described in subsection (a);

(B) the donation is made without any restriction regarding the identity of individuals who may be the recipients of transplantations of the tissue; and

(C) the woman has not been informed of the identity of any such individuals.


(2) Additional statementIn research carried out under subsection (a), human fetal tissue may be used only if the attending physician with respect to obtaining the tissue from the woman involved makes a statement, made in writing and signed by the physician, declaring that—(A) in the case of tissue obtained pursuant to an induced abortion—(i) the consent of the woman for the abortion was obtained prior to requesting or obtaining consent for a donation of the tissue for use in such research;

(ii) no alteration of the timing, method, or procedures used to terminate the pregnancy was made solely for the purposes of obtaining the tissue; and

(iii) the abortion was performed in accordance with applicable State law;


(B) the tissue has been donated by the woman in accordance with paragraph (1); and

(C) full disclosure has been provided to the woman with regard to—(i) such physician’s interest, if any, in the research to be conducted with the tissue; and

(ii) any known medical risks to the woman or ri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informed consent of donor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Informed consent of donor</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Informed consent of researcher and donee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Informed consent of researcher and donee In research carried out under subsection (a), human fetal tissue may be used only if the individual with the principal responsibility for conducting the research involved makes a statement, made in writing and signed by the individual, declaring that the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of statements for audit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of statements for audit</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of State and local law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Applicability of State and local law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Report The Secretary shall annually submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, a report describing the activities carried out under this section during the preceding fiscal year, including a description of whether and to what extent research under subsection (a) has been conducted in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Human fetal tissue” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) “Human fetal tissue” defined For purposes of this section, the term “human fetal tissue” means tissue or cells obtained from a dead human embryo or fetus after a spontaneous or induced abortion, or after a stillbirth.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>