<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289g_2"><akn:num>289g–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions regarding human fetal tissue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289g–2. Prohibitions regarding human fetal tissue(a) Purchase of tissueIt shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly acquire, receive, or otherwise transfer any human fetal tissue for valuable consideration if the transfer affects interstate commerce.


(b) Solicitation or acceptance of tissue as directed donation for use in transplantationIt shall be unlawful for any person to solicit or knowingly acquire, receive, or accept a donation of human fetal tissue for the purpose of transplantation of such tissue into another person if the donation affects interstate commerce, the tissue will be or is obtained pursuant to an induced abortion, and—(1) the donation will be or is made pursuant to a promise to the donating individual that the donated tissue will be transplanted into a recipient specified by such individual;

(2) the donated tissue will be transplanted into a relative of the donating individual; or

(3) the person who solicits or knowingly acquires, receives, or accepts the donation has provided valuable consideration for the costs associated with such abortion.


(c) Solicitation or acceptance of tissue from fetuses gestated for research purposesIt shall be unlawful for any person or entity involved or engaged in interstate commerce to—(1) solicit or knowingly acquire, receive, or accept a donation of human fetal tissue knowing that a human pregnancy was deliberately initiated to provide such tissue; or

(2) knowingly acquire, receive, or accept tissue or cells obtained from a human embryo or fetus that was gestated in the uterus of a nonhuman animal.


(d) Criminal penalties for violations(1) In generalAny person who violates subsection (a), (b), or (c) shall be fined in accordance with title 18, subject to paragraph (2), or imprisoned for not more than 10 years, or both.


(2) Penalties applicable to persons receiving considerationWith respect to the imposition of a fine under paragraph (1), if the person involved violates subsection (a) or (b)(3), a f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of tissue</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purchase of tissue It shall be unlawful for any person to knowingly acquire, receive, or otherwise transfer any human fetal tissue for valuable consideration if the transfer affects interstate commerce.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation or acceptance of tissue as directed donation for use in transplantation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Solicitation or acceptance of tissue as directed donation for use in transplantation It shall be unlawful for any person to solicit or knowingly acquire, receive, or accept a donation of human fetal tissue for the purpose of transplantation of such tissue into another person if the donation affects interstate commerce, the tissue will be or is obtained pursuant to an induced abortion, and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation or acceptance of tissue from fetuses gestated for research purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Solicitation or acceptance of tissue from fetuses gestated for research purposes It shall be unlawful for any person or entity involved or engaged in interstate commerce to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties for violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criminal penalties for violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>