<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/289g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_289g"><akn:num>289g</akn:num><akn:heading>Fetal research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 289g. Fetal research(a) Conduct or support by Secretary; restrictionsThe Secretary may not conduct or support any research or experimentation, in the United States or in any other country, on a nonviable living human fetus ex utero or a living human fetus ex utero for whom viability has not been ascertained unless the research or experimentation—(1) may enhance the well-being or meet the health needs of the fetus or enhance the probability of its survival to viability; or

(2) will pose no added risk of suffering, injury, or death to the fetus and the purpose of the research or experimentation is the development of important biomedical knowledge which cannot be obtained by other means.


(b) Risk standard for fetuses intended to be aborted and fetuses intended to be carried to term to be sameIn administering the regulations for the protection of human research subjects which—(1) apply to research conducted or supported by the Secretary;

(2) involve living human fetuses in utero; and

(3) are published in section 46.208 of part 46 of title 45 of the Code of Federal Regulations;


or any successor to such regulations, the Secretary shall require that the risk standard (published in section 46.102(g) of such part 46 or any successor to such regulations) be the same for fetuses which are intended to be aborted and fetuses which are intended to be carried to term.

(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title IV, § 498, as added Pub. L. 99–158, § 2, Nov. 20, 1985, 99 Stat. 877; amended Pub. L. 100–607, title I, §§ 156, 157(b), Nov. 4, 1988, 102 Stat. 3059; Pub. L. 103–43, title I, § 121(b)(1), June 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 133.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1993—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 103–43 struck out subsec. (c) which directed Biomedical Ethics Advisory Committee to conduct a study of the nature, advisability, and biomedical and ethical implications of exercising any waiver of the risk standard published in section 46.102(g) of part 46 of title 45 of the Code of Federal Regulations and to </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conduct or support by Secretary; restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conduct or support by Secretary; restrictions The Secretary may not conduct or support any research or experimentation, in the United States or in any other country, on a nonviable living human fetus ex utero or a living human fetus ex utero for whom viability has not been ascertained unless the research or experimentation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_289g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk standard for fetuses intended to be aborted and fetuses intended to be carried to term to be same</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Risk standard for fetuses intended to be aborted and fetuses intended to be carried to term to be same In administering the regulations for the protection of human research subjects which— or any successor to such regulations, the Secretary shall require that the risk standard (published in section 46.102(g) of such part 46 or any successor to such regulations) be the same for fetuses which are intended to be aborted and fetuses which are intended to be carried to term.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>