<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290aa–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290aa–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290aa–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290aa_16"><akn:num>290aa–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of performance of Department of Health and Human Services programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290aa–16. Evaluation of performance of Department of Health and Human Services programs(1) Evaluations(A) In generalNot later than 5 years after July 22, 2016, except as otherwise provided in this section,11 See References in Text note below. the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall complete an evaluation of any program administered by the Secretary included in this Act (or an amendment made by this Act, excluding sections 703 through 707), including any grant administered by the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration under section 1536 of title 21, that provides grants for the primary purpose of providing assistance in addressing problems pertaining to opioid abuse based upon the outcomes and metrics identified under paragraph (2).


(B) PublicationWith respect to each evaluation completed under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall, not later than 90 days after the date on which such evaluation is completed, publish the results of such evaluation and issue a report on such evaluation to the appropriate committees. Such report shall also be published along with the data used to make such evaluation.



(2) Metrics and outcomes(A) In generalNot later than 180 days after July 22, 2016, the Secretary shall identify—(i) outcomes that are to be achieved by activities funded by the programs described in paragraph (1)(A); and

(ii) the metrics by which the achievement of such outcomes shall be determined.


(B) PublicationThe Secretary shall, not later than 30 days after completion of the requirement under subparagraph (A), publish the outcomes and metrics identified under such subparagraph.



(3) Metrics data collectionThe Secretary shall require grantees under the programs described in paragraph (1)(A) to collect, and annually report to the Secretary, data based upon the metrics identified under paragraph (2)(A).


(4) Independent evaluationFor purposes of paragraph (1), </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290aa_16_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290aa_16_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Metrics and outcomes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Metrics and outcomes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290aa_16_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Metrics data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Metrics data collection The Secretary shall require grantees under the programs described in paragraph (1)(A) to collect, and annually report to the Secretary, data based upon the metrics identified under paragraph (2)(A).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290aa_16_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Independent evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Independent evaluation For purposes of paragraph (1), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290aa_16_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Exception If a program described in paragraph (1)(A) is subject to an evaluation similar to the evaluation required under such paragraph pursuant to another provision of Federal law, the Secretary may opt not to conduct an evaluation under such paragraph with respect to such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>