<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–37" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–37/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–37/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_37"><akn:num>290bb–37</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health crisis response partnership pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–37. Mental health crisis response partnership pilot program(a) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary will award competitive grants to States, localities, territories, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations to establish new, or enhance existing, mobile crisis response teams that divert the response for mental health and substance use disorder crises from law enforcement to mobile crisis teams, as described in subsection (b).


(b) Mobile crisis teams describedA mobile crisis team, for purposes of this section, is a team of individuals—(1) that is available to respond to individuals in mental health and substance use disorder crises and provide immediate stabilization, referrals to community-based mental health and substance use disorder services and supports, and triage to a higher level of care if medically necessary;

(2) which may include licensed counselors, clinical social workers, physicians, paramedics, crisis workers, peer support specialists, or other qualified individuals; and

(3) which may provide support to divert mental health and substance use disorder crisis calls from the 9–1–1 system to the 9–8–8 system.


(c) PriorityIn awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize applications which account for the specific needs of the communities to be served, including children and families, veterans, rural and underserved populations, and other groups at increased risk of death from suicide or overdose.


(d) Report(1) Initial reportNot later than September 30, 2024, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on steps taken by States, localities, territories, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations prior to December 29, 2022, to strengthen the partnerships among mental health providers, substance use disorder treatment providers, primary care physicians, mental health and substance use disorder crisis teams, paramedics, law enforcement officers, and other first responders.


(2) Pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_37_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall establish a pilot program under which the Secretary will award competitive grants to States, localities, territories, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations to establish new, or enhance existing, mobile crisis response teams that divert the response for mental health and substance use disorder crises from law enforcement to mobile crisis teams, as described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_37_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mobile crisis teams described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mobile crisis teams described A mobile crisis team, for purposes of this section, is a team of individuals—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_37_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priority In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize applications which account for the specific needs of the communities to be served, including children and families, veterans, rural and underserved populations, and other groups at increased risk of death from suicide or overdose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_37_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_37_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>