<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_36d"><akn:num>290bb–36d</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment Referral Routing Service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–36d. Treatment Referral Routing Service(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall maintain the National Treatment Referral Routing Service (referred to in this section as the “Routing Service”) to assist individuals and families in locating mental and substance use disorders treatment providers.


(b) Activities of the SecretaryTo maintain the Routing Service, the activities of the Assistant Secretary shall include administering—(1) a nationwide, telephone number providing year-round access to information that is updated on a regular basis regarding local behavioral health providers and community-based organizations in a manner that is confidential, without requiring individuals to identify themselves, is in languages that include at least English and Spanish, and is at no cost to the individual using the Routing Service; and

(2) an Internet website to provide a searchable, online treatment services locator of behavioral health treatment providers and community-based organizations, which shall include information on the name, location, contact information, and basic services provided by such providers and organizations.


(c) Removing practitioner contact informationIn the event that the Internet website described in subsection (b)(2) contains information on any practitioner who prescribes narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V of section 812 of title 21 for the purpose of maintenance or detoxification treatment, the Assistant Secretary—(1) shall provide an opportunity to such practitioner to have the contact information of the practitioner removed from the website at the request of the practitioner; and

(2) may evaluate other methods to periodically update the information displayed on such website.


(d) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the Assistant Secretary from using any unobligated amounts otherwise made available to the Administration to maintain the Routing Service.


(July </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall maintain the National Treatment Referral Routing Service (referred to in this section as the “Routing Service”) to assist individuals and families in locating mental and substance use disorders treatment providers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities of the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities of the Secretary To maintain the Routing Service, the activities of the Assistant Secretary shall include administering—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Removing practitioner contact information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Removing practitioner contact information In the event that the Internet website described in subsection (b)(2) contains information on any practitioner who prescribes narcotic drugs in schedule III, IV, or V of section 812 of title 21 for the purpose of maintenance or detoxification treatment, the Assistant Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent the Assistant Secretary from using any unobligated amounts otherwise made available to the Administration to maintain the Routing Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>