<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_36"><akn:num>290bb–36</akn:num><akn:heading>Youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–36. Youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to—(1) develop and implement State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies in schools, educational institutions, juvenile justice systems, substance use disorder programs, mental health programs, foster care systems, pediatric health programs, and other child and youth support organizations;

(2) support public organizations and private nonprofit organizations actively involved in State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies and in the development and continuation of State-sponsored statewide youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies;

(3) provide grants to institutions of higher education to coordinate the implementation of State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies;

(4) collect and analyze data on State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention services that can be used to monitor the effectiveness of such services and for research, technical assistance, and policy development; and

(5) assist eligible entities, through State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, in achieving targets for youth suicide reductions under title V of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 701 et seq.].


(b) Eligible entity(1) DefinitionIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(A) a State;

(B) a public organization or private nonprofit organization designated by a State or Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5304]) to develop or direct the State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and preven</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entity</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Preference In providing assistance under a grant or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall give preference to public organizations, private nonprofit organizations, political subdivisions, institutions of higher education, and Tribal organizations actively involved with the State-sponsored statewide or Tribal youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategy that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement for suicide prevention activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirement for suicide prevention activities Not less than 85 percent of grant funds received under this section shall be used to provide suicide prevention activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination and collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination and collaboration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction; religious and moral accommodation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction; religious and moral accommodation Nothing in this section shall be construed to require suicide assessment, early intervention, or treatment services for youth whose parents or legal guardians object based on the parents’ or legal guardians’ religious beliefs or moral objections.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Evaluations and report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction; student medication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rule of construction; student medication Nothing in this section or section 290bb–36a of this title shall be construed to allow school personnel to require that a student obtain any medication as a condition of attending school or receiving services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition Funds appropriated to carry out this section, section 290bb–34 of this title, section 290bb–36a of this title, or section 290bb–36b of this title shall not be used to pay for or refer for abortion.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Parental consent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Parental consent States and entities receiving funding under this section and section 290bb–36a of this title shall obtain prior written, informed consent from the child’s parent or legal guardian for assessment services, school-sponsored programs, and treatment involving medication related to youth suicide conducted in elementary and secondary schools. The requirement of the preceding sentence does not apply in the following cases:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>