<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_21"><akn:num>290bb–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Center for Substance Abuse Prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–21. Center for Substance Abuse Prevention(a) Establishment; DirectorThere is established in the Administration a Center for Substance Abuse Prevention (hereafter referred to in this part as the “Prevention Center”). The Prevention Center shall be headed by a Director appointed by the Secretary from individuals with extensive experience or academic qualifications in the prevention of drug or alcohol abuse.


(b) Duties of DirectorThe Director of the Prevention Center shall—(1) sponsor regional workshops on the prevention of drug and alcohol abuse through the reduction of risk and the promotion of resiliency;

(2) coordinate the findings of research sponsored by agencies of the Service on the prevention of drug and alcohol abuse;

(3) collaborate with the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, the Director of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, and States to promote the study of substance abuse prevention and the dissemination and implementation of research findings that will improve the delivery and effectiveness of substance abuse prevention activities;

(4) develop effective drug and alcohol abuse prevention literature (including educational information on the effects of drugs abused by individuals, including drugs that are emerging as abused drugs);

(5) in cooperation with the Secretary of Education, assure the widespread dissemination of prevention materials among States, political subdivisions, and school systems;

(6) support clinical training programs for health professionals who provide substance use and misuse prevention and treatment services and other health professionals involved in illicit drug use education and prevention;

(7) in cooperation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, develop and disseminate educational materials to increase awareness for individuals at greatest risk for substance use disorders to prevent the transmission of communicable diseases, such as HIV, hepatitis, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; Director There is established in the Administration a Center for Substance Abuse Prevention (hereafter referred to in this part as the “Prevention Center”). The Prevention Center shall be headed by a Director appointed by the Secretary from individuals with extensive experience or academic qualifications in the prevention of drug or alcohol abuse.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of Director The Director of the Prevention Center shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants, contracts and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants, contracts and cooperative agreements The Director may make grants and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements in carrying out subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National data base</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National data base The Director of the Prevention Center shall establish a national data base providing information on programs for the prevention of substance abuse. The data base shall contain information appropriate for use by public entities and information appropriate for use by nonprofit private entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>