<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–38" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–38/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–38/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_38"><akn:num>290bb–38</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for jail diversion programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–38. Grants for jail diversion programs(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary shall make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations (as the terms “Indian tribes” and “tribal organizations” are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5304]), acting directly or through agreements with other public or nonprofit entities, or a health facility or program operated by or in accordance with a contract or grant with the Indian Health Service, to develop and implement programs to divert individuals with a mental illness from the criminal justice system to community-based services.


(b) Administration(1) ConsultationThe Secretary shall consult with the Attorney General and any other appropriate officials in carrying out this section.


(2) Regulatory authorityThe Secretary shall issue regulations and guidelines necessary to carry out this section, including methodologies and outcome measures for evaluating programs carried out by States, political subdivisions of States, Indian Tribes, and Tribal organizations receiving grants under subsection (a).



(c) Applications(1) In generalTo receive a grant under subsection (a), the chief executive of a State, chief executive of a subdivision of a State, an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization, a health facility or program described in subsection (a), or a public or nonprofit entity referred to in subsection (a) shall prepare and submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary shall reasonably require.


(2) ContentSuch application shall—(A) contain an assurance that—(i) community-based mental health services will be available for the individuals who are diverted from the criminal justice system, and that such services are based on evidence-based practices, reflect current research findings, include case management, assertive community treatment, medication </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary shall make grants to States, political subdivisions of States, and Indian Tribes and Tribal organizations (as the terms “Indian tribes” and “tribal organizations” are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5304]), acting directly or through agreements with other public or nonprofit entities, or a health facility or program operated by or in accordance with a contract or grant with the Indian Health Service, to develop and implement programs to divert individuals with a mental illness from the criminal justice system to community-based services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consideration regarding veterans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special consideration regarding veterans In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall, as appropriate, give special consideration to entities proposing to use grant funding to support jail diversion services for veterans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Use of funds A State, political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization that receives a grant under subsection (a) may use funds received under such grant to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geographic distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Geographic distribution The Secretary shall ensure that such grants awarded under subsection (a) are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States and between urban and rural populations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Training and technical assistance Training and technical assistance may be provided by the Secretary to assist a State, political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization receiving a grant under subsection (a) in establishing and operating a diversion program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Evaluations The programs described in subsection (a) shall be evaluated not less than one time in every 12-month period using the methodology and outcome measures identified in the grant application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_38_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $14,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>