<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_25b"><akn:num>290bb–25b</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs to reduce underage drinking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–25b. Programs to reduce underage drinking(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “alcohol beverage industry” means the brewers, vintners, distillers, importers, distributors, and retail or online outlets that sell or serve beer, wine, and distilled spirits.

(2) The term “school-based prevention” means programs, which are institutionalized, and run by staff members or school-designated persons or organizations in any grade of school, kindergarten through 12th grade.

(3) The term “youth” means persons under the age of 21.


(b) Sense of CongressIt is the sense of the Congress that:(1) A multi-faceted effort is needed to more successfully address the problem of underage drinking in the United States. A coordinated approach to prevention, intervention, treatment, enforcement, and research is key to making progress. This chapter recognizes the need for a focused national effort, and addresses particulars of the Federal portion of that effort, as well as Federal support for State activities.

(2) The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall continue to conduct research and collect data on the short and long-range impact of alcohol use and abuse upon adolescent brain development and other organ systems.

(3) States and communities, including colleges and universities, are encouraged to adopt comprehensive prevention approaches, including—(A) evidence-based screening, programs and curricula;

(B) brief intervention strategies;

(C) consistent policy enforcement; and

(D) environmental changes that limit underage access to alcohol.


(4) Public health groups, consumer groups, and the alcohol beverage industry should continue and expand evidence-based efforts to prevent and reduce underage drinking.

(5) The entertainment industries have a powerful impact on youth, and they should use rating systems and marketing codes to reduce the likelihood that underage audiences will be exposed to movies, recordings, or television programs with unsuitable a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sense of Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sense of Congress It is the sense of the Congress that:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency coordinating committee; annual report on State underage drinking prevention and enforcement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interagency coordinating committee; annual report on State underage drinking prevention and enforcement activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National media campaign to prevent underage drinking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National media campaign to prevent underage drinking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community-based coalition enhancement grants to prevent underage drinking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Community-based coalition enhancement grants to prevent underage drinking</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to organizations representing pediatric providers and other related health professionals to reduce underage drinking through screening and brief interventions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Grants to organizations representing pediatric providers and other related health professionals to reduce underage drinking through screening and brief interventions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection and research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Data collection and research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>