<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_36c"><akn:num>290bb–36c</akn:num><akn:heading>National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–36c. National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall maintain the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program (referred to in this section as the “program”), authorized under section 290bb–32 of this title and in effect prior to December 13, 2016.


(b) ActivitiesIn maintaining the program, the activities of the Secretary shall include—(1) supporting and coordinating a network of crisis centers across the United States for providing suicide prevention and mental health crisis intervention services, including appropriate follow-up services, to individuals seeking help at any time, day or night;

(2) maintaining a suicide prevention hotline to link callers to local emergency, mental health, and social services resources;

(3) consulting with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that veterans calling the suicide prevention hotline have access to a specialized veterans’ suicide prevention hotline;

(4) improving awareness of the program for suicide prevention and mental health crisis intervention services, including by conducting an awareness initiative and ongoing outreach to the public;

(5) improving the collection and analysis of demographic information, in a manner that protects personal privacy, consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy laws, in order to understand disparities in access to the program among individuals who are seeking help; and

(6) taking such steps as may be necessary to ensure the suicide prevention hotline is protected from cybersecurity incidents and eliminates known cybersecurity vulnerabilities.


(c) Plan(1) In generalFor purposes of supporting the crisis centers under subsection (b)(1) and maintaining the suicide prevention hotline under subsection (b)(2), the Secretary shall develop and implement a plan to ensure the provision of high-quality services.


(2) ContentsThe plan required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:(A) Program e</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary, shall maintain the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program (referred to in this section as the “program”), authorized under section 290bb–32 of this title and in effect prior to December 13, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities In maintaining the program, the activities of the Secretary shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improving epidemiological data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Improving epidemiological data The Secretary shall, as appropriate, formalize and strengthen agreements between the Suicide Prevention Lifeline program and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with respect to the secure sharing of de-identified epidemiological data. Such agreements shall include appropriate privacy and security protections that meet the requirements of applicable Federal law, at a minimum.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data to assist State and local suicide prevention activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Data to assist State and local suicide prevention activities The Secretary shall ensure that the aggregated information collected and any applicable analyses conducted under subsection (b)(5), including from local call centers, as applicable, are made available in a usable format to State and local agencies in order to inform suicide prevention activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cybersecurity reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Cybersecurity reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $101,621,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>