<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb"><akn:num>290bb</akn:num><akn:heading>Center for Substance Abuse Treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb. Center for Substance Abuse Treatment(a) EstablishmentThere is established in the Administration a Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Center shall be headed by a Director (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) appointed by the Secretary from among individuals with extensive experience or academic qualifications in the treatment of substance use disorders or in the evaluation of substance use disorder treatment systems.


(b) DutiesThe Director of the Center shall—(1) administer the substance use disorder treatment block grant program authorized in section 300x–21 of this title;

(2) ensure that emphasis is placed on children and adolescents in the development of treatment programs;

(3) collaborate with the Attorney General to develop programs to provide substance use disorder treatment services to individuals who have had contact with the Justice system, especially adolescents;

(4) collaborate with the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Prevention in order to provide outreach services to identify individuals in need of treatment services, with emphasis on the provision of such services to pregnant and postpartum women and their infants and to individuals who illicitly use drugs intravenously;

(5) collaborate with the Director of the National Institute on Drug Abuse, with the Director of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, and with the States to promote the study, dissemination, and implementation of research findings that will improve the delivery and effectiveness of treatment services;

(6) collaborate with the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to promote the increased integration into the mainstream of the health care system of the United States of programs for providing treatment services;

(7) evaluate plans submitted by the States pursuant t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established in the Administration a Center for Substance Abuse Treatment (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Center”). The Center shall be headed by a Director (hereafter in this section referred to as the “Director”) appointed by the Secretary from among individuals with extensive experience or academic qualifications in the treatment of substance use disorders or in the evaluation of substance use disorder treatment systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties The Director of the Center shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants and contracts In carrying out the duties established in subsection (b), the Director may make grants to and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements with public and nonprofit private entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>