<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–7a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–7a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–7a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_7a"><akn:num>290bb–7a</akn:num><akn:heading>Youth prevention and recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–7a. Youth prevention and recovery(a) Omitted

(b) Resource centerThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”, except as otherwise provided), in consultation with the Secretary of Education and other heads of agencies, including the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, as appropriate, shall establish a resource center to provide technical support to recipients of grants under subsection (c).


(c) Youth prevention and recovery initiative(1) In generalThe Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall administer a program to provide support for communities to support the prevention of, treatment of, and recovery from, substance use disorders for children, adolescents, and young adults.


(2) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(i) a local educational agency, or a consortium of local educational agencies, that is seeking to establish or expand substance use prevention or recovery support services at one or more secondary schools;

(ii) a State educational agency;

(iii) an institution of higher education (or consortia of such institutions), which may include a recovery program at an institution of higher education;

(iv) a local board or one-stop operator;

(v) a nonprofit organization with appropriate expertise in providing services or programs for children, adolescents, or young adults, excluding a school;

(vi) a State, political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization; or

(vii) a high school or dormitory serving high school students that receives funding from the Bureau of Indian Education.


(B) Foster careThe term “foster care” has the meaning given such term in section 1355.20(a) of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).


(C) High schoolThe term “high school” has the meaning given such term in secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_7a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_7a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Resource center The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”, except as otherwise provided), in consultation with the Secretary of Education and other heads of agencies, including the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, as appropriate, shall establish a resource center to provide technical support to recipients of grants under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_7a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Youth prevention and recovery initiative</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Youth prevention and recovery initiative</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>