<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–36b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_36b"><akn:num>290bb–36b</akn:num><akn:heading>Mental health and substance use disorder services for students in higher education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–36b. Mental health and substance use disorder services for students in higher education(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services and in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may award grants on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education to enhance services for students with mental health or substance use disorders that can lead to school failure, such as depression, substance use disorders, and suicide attempts, prevent mental and substance use disorders, reduce stigma, and improve the identification and treatment for students at risk, so that students will successfully complete their studies.


(b) Use of fundsThe Secretary may not make a grant to an institution of higher education under this section unless the institution agrees to use the grant only for one or more of the following:(1) Educating students, families, faculty, and staff to increase awareness of mental health and substance use disorders and promote resiliency.

(2) The operation of hotlines.

(3) Preparing informational material.

(4) Providing outreach services to notify students about available mental health and substance use disorder resources and services.

(5) Administering voluntary mental health and substance use disorder screenings and assessments.

(6) Supporting the training of students, faculty, and staff to recognize and respond effectively and appropriately to students experiencing mental health and substance use disorders.

(7) Creating a network infrastructure to link institutions of higher education with health care providers who treat mental health and substance use disorders.

(8) Providing mental health and substance use. 11 So in original. disorders prevention and treatment services to students, which may include recovery support services and programming and early intervention, treatment, and management, including through the use of telehealth services.

(9) Conducting research through a counselin</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services and in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may award grants on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education to enhance services for students with mental health or substance use disorders that can lead to school failure, such as depression, substance use disorders, and suicide attempts, prevent mental and substance use disorders, reduce stigma, and improve the identification and treatment for students at risk, so that students will successfully complete their studies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds The Secretary may not make a grant to an institution of higher education under this section unless the institution agrees to use the grant only for one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible grant recipients Any institution of higher education receiving a grant under this section may carry out activities under the grant through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an institution of higher education shall prepare and submit an application to the Secretary at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, the application shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirement of matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports For each fiscal year that grants are awarded under this section, the Secretary shall conduct a study on the results of the grants and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on such results that includes the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definition In this section, the term “institution of higher education” has the meaning given such term in section 1001 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Technical assistance The Secretary may provide technical assistance to grantees in carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_36b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $7,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>