<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–25f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_25f"><akn:num>290bb–25f</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention and education programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–25f. Prevention and education programs(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the “Secretary”) shall award grants to public and nonprofit private entities to enable such entities to carry out science-based education programs in elementary and secondary schools to highlight the harmful effects of anabolic steroids.


(b) Eligibility(1) ApplicationTo be eligible for grants under subsection (a), an entity shall prepare and submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(2) PreferenceIn awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give preference to applicants that intend to use grant funds to carry out programs based on—(A) the Athletes Training and Learning to Avoid Steroids program;

(B) The Athletes Targeting Healthy Exercise and Nutrition Alternatives program; and

(C) other programs determined to be effective by the National Institute on Drug Abuse.



(c) Use of fundsAmounts received under a grant under subsection (a) shall be used for education programs that will directly communicate with teachers, principals, coaches, as well as elementary and secondary school children concerning the harmful effects of anabolic steroids.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2010.


(Pub. L. 108–358, § 4, Oct. 22, 2004, 118 Stat. 1664.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a), means Pub. L. 108–358, October 22, 2004, 92 Stat. 1661, known as the Anabolic Steroid Control Act of 2004. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2004 Amendment note set out under section 801 of Title 21, Food and Drugs, and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Anabolic Steroid Control Act of 2004, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which compri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the “Secretary”) shall award grants to public and nonprofit private entities to enable such entities to carry out science-based education programs in elementary and secondary schools to highlight the harmful effects of anabolic steroids.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds Amounts received under a grant under subsection (a) shall be used for education programs that will directly communicate with teachers, principals, coaches, as well as elementary and secondary school children concerning the harmful effects of anabolic steroids.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_25f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2005 through 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>