<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–44" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–44/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–44/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_44"><akn:num>290bb–44</akn:num><akn:heading>Assertive community treatment grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–44. Assertive community treatment grant program(a) In generalThe Assistant Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities—(1) to establish assertive community treatment programs for adults with a serious mental illness; or

(2) to maintain or expand such programs.


(b) Eligible entitiesTo be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a State, political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25), mental health system, health care facility, or any other entity the Assistant Secretary deems appropriate.


(c) Special considerationIn selecting among applicants for a grant under this section, the Assistant Secretary may give special consideration to the potential of the applicant’s program to reduce hospitalization, homelessness, and involvement with the criminal justice system while improving the health and social outcomes of the patient.


(d) Additional activitiesThe Assistant Secretary shall—(1) not later than the end of fiscal year 2026, submit a report to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives on the grant program under this section, including an evaluation of—(A) any cost savings and public health outcomes such as mortality, suicide, substance use disorders, hospitalization, and use of services;

(B) rates of involvement with the criminal justice system of patients;

(C) rates of homelessness among patients; and

(D) patient and family satisfaction with program participation; and


(2) provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance to grant recipients under this section to help such recipients to establish, maintain, or expand their assertive community treatment programs.


(e) Authorization of appropriations(1) In generalTo carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $9,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_44_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Assistant Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_44_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be a State, political subdivision of a State, Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25), mental health system, health care facility, or any other entity the Assistant Secretary deems appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_44_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special consideration In selecting among applicants for a grant under this section, the Assistant Secretary may give special consideration to the potential of the applicant’s program to reduce hospitalization, homelessness, and involvement with the criminal justice system while improving the health and social outcomes of the patient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_44_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Additional activities The Assistant Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_44_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>