<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–39" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–39/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290bb–39/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290bb_39"><akn:num>290bb–39</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer-supported mental health services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290bb–39. Peer-supported mental health services(a) Grants authorizedThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to develop, expand, and enhance access to mental health peer-delivered services.


(b) Use of fundsGrants awarded under subsection (a) shall be used to develop, expand, and enhance national, statewide, or community-focused programs, including virtual peer-support services and technology-related capabilities, including by—(1) carrying out workforce development, recruitment, and retention activities, to train, recruit, and retain peer-support providers;

(2) building connections between mental health treatment programs, including between community organizations and peer-support networks, including virtual peer-support networks, and with other mental health support services;

(3) reducing stigma associated with mental health disorders;

(4) expanding and improving virtual peer mental health support services, including through the adoption of technologies and capabilities to expand access to virtual peer mental health support services, such as by acquiring equipment and software necessary to efficiently run virtual peer-support services; and

(5) conducting research on issues relating to mental illness and the impact peer-support has on resiliency, including identifying—(A) the signs of mental illness;

(B) the resources available to individuals with mental illness and to their families; and

(C) the resources available to help support individuals living with mental illness.



(c) Special considerationIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give special consideration to the unique needs of rural areas.


(d) DefinitionIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(1) a consumer-run nonprofit organization that—(A) is principally governed by people living with a mental health condition; and

(B) mobilizes resources within and outside of</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_39_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants authorized The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants to eligible entities to enable such entities to develop, expand, and enhance access to mental health peer-delivered services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_39_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds Grants awarded under subsection (a) shall be used to develop, expand, and enhance national, statewide, or community-focused programs, including virtual peer-support services and technology-related capabilities, including by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_39_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special consideration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Special consideration In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give special consideration to the unique needs of rural areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_39_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition In this section, the term “eligible entity” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290bb_39_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $13,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>