<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290dd_3"><akn:num>290dd–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for reducing overdose deaths</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290dd–3. Grants for reducing overdose deaths(a) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to expand access to drugs or devices approved, cleared, or otherwise legally marketed under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.] for emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose.


(2) Eligible entityFor purposes of this section, the term “eligible entity” means a State, Territory, locality, or Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25).


(3) SubgrantsFor the purposes for which a grant is awarded under this section, the eligible entity receiving the grant may award subgrants to a Federally qualified health center (as defined in section 1395x(aa) of this title), an opioid treatment program (as defined in section 8.2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations)), any practitioner dispensing narcotic drugs for the purpose of maintenance or detoxification treatment, or any nonprofit organization that the Secretary deems appropriate, which may include Urban Indian organizations (as defined in section 1603 of title 25).


(4) PrescribingFor purposes of this section, the term “prescribing” means, with respect to a drug or device approved, cleared, or otherwise legally marketed under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act for emergency treatment of known or suspected opioid overdose, the practice of prescribing such drug or device—(A) in conjunction with an opioid prescription for patients at an elevated risk of overdose, including patients prescribed both an opioid and a benzodiazepine;

(B) in conjunction with an opioid agonist approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act [21 U.S.C. 355] for the treatment of opioid use disorder;

(C) to the caregiver or a close relative of patients at an elevated risk of overdose from opioids; or

(D) in other circumstances in which a provider identifies a patient i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary, in such form and manner as specified by the Secretary, an application that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use amounts under the grant for any of the following activities, but may use not more than 20 percent of the grant funds for activities described in paragraphs (3) and (4):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Improving access to overdose treatment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Improving access to overdose treatment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations by recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Evaluations by recipients As a condition of receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall, for each year for which the grant is received, submit to the Secretary an evaluation of activities funded by the grant which contains such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports by the Secretary Not later than 5 years after the date on which the first grant under this section is awarded, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report aggregating the information received from the grant recipients for such year under subsection (e) and evaluating the outcomes achieved by the programs funded by grants awarded under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $5,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>