<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290dd_4"><akn:num>290dd–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Program to support coordination and continuation of care for drug overdose patients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290dd–4. Program to support coordination and continuation of care for drug overdose patients(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall identify or facilitate the development of best practices for—(1) emergency treatment of known or suspected drug overdose;

(2) the use of recovery coaches, as appropriate, to encourage individuals who experience a non-fatal overdose to seek treatment for substance use disorder and to support coordination and continuation of care;

(3) coordination and continuation of care and treatment, including, as appropriate, through referrals, of individuals after a drug overdose; and

(4) the provision or prescribing of overdose reversal medication, as appropriate.


(b) Grant establishment and participation(1) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to support implementation of voluntary programs for care and treatment of individuals after a drug overdose, as appropriate, which may include implementation of the best practices described in subsection (a).


(2) Eligible entityIn this section, the term “eligible entity” means—(A) a State substance abuse agency;

(B) an Indian Tribe or tribal organization; or

(C) an entity that offers treatment or other services for individuals in response to, or following, drug overdoses or a drug overdose, such as an emergency department, in consultation with a State substance abuse agency.


(3) ApplicationAn eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, that includes—(A) evidence that such eligible entity carries out, or is capable of contracting and coordinating with other community entities to carry out, the activities described in paragraph (4);

(B) evidence that such eligible entity will work with a recovery community organization to recruit, train, hire, mentor, and supervis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall identify or facilitate the development of best practices for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant establishment and participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant establishment and participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reporting Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Privacy The requirements of this section, including with respect to data reporting and program oversight, shall be subject to all applicable Federal and State privacy laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_4_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>