<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–2a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–2a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290dd–2a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290dd_2a"><akn:num>290dd–2a</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting access to information on evidence-based programs and practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290dd–2a. Promoting access to information on evidence-based programs and practices(a) In generalThe Assistant Secretary shall, as appropriate, improve access to reliable and valid information on evidence-based programs and practices, including information on the strength of evidence associated with such programs and practices, related to mental and substance use disorders for States, local communities, nonprofit entities, and other stakeholders, by posting on the Internet website of the Administration information on evidence-based programs and practices that have been reviewed by the Assistant Secretary in accordance with the requirements of this section.


(b) Applications(1) Application periodIn carrying out subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary may establish a period for the submission of applications for evidence-based programs and practices to be posted publicly in accordance with subsection (a).


(2) NoticeIn establishing the application period under paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall provide for the public notice of such application period in the Federal Register. Such notice may solicit applications for evidence-based programs and practices to address gaps in information identified by the Assistant Secretary, the National Mental Health and Substance Use Policy Laboratory established under section 290aa–0 of this title, or the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation, including pursuant to the evaluation and recommendations under section 6021 of the Helping Families in Mental Health Crisis Reform Act of 2016 or priorities identified in the strategic plan under section 290aa(l) of this title.



(c) RequirementsThe Assistant Secretary may establish minimum requirements for the applications submitted under subsection (b), including applications related to the submission of research and evaluation.


(d) Review and rating(1) In generalThe Assistant Secretary shall review applications prior to public posting in accordance with subsection (a)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_2a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Assistant Secretary shall, as appropriate, improve access to reliable and valid information on evidence-based programs and practices, including information on the strength of evidence associated with such programs and practices, related to mental and substance use disorders for States, local communities, nonprofit entities, and other stakeholders, by posting on the Internet website of the Administration information on evidence-based programs and practices that have been reviewed by the Assistant Secretary in accordance with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_2a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Applications</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_2a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements The Assistant Secretary may establish minimum requirements for the applications submitted under subsection (b), including applications related to the submission of research and evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290dd_2a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review and rating</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Review and rating</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>