<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290ee_7"><akn:num>290ee–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive opioid recovery centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290ee–7. Comprehensive opioid recovery centers(a) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to establish or operate a comprehensive opioid recovery center (referred to in this section as a “Center”). A Center may be a single entity or an integrated delivery network.


(b) Grant period(1) In generalA grant awarded under subsection (a) shall be for a period of not less than 3 years and not more than 5 years.


(2) RenewalA grant awarded under subsection (a) may be renewed, on a competitive basis, for additional periods of time, as determined by the Secretary. In determining whether to renew a grant under this paragraph, the Secretary shall consider the data submitted under subsection (h).



(c) Minimum number of CentersThe Secretary shall allocate the amounts made available under subsection (j) such that not fewer than 10 grants may be awarded. Not more than one grant shall be made to entities in a single State for any one period.


(d) Application(1) Eligible entityAn entity is eligible for a grant under this section if the entity offers treatment and other services for individuals with a substance use disorder.


(2) Submission of applicationIn order to be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances, including relevant documentation, as the Secretary may require. Such application shall include—(A) evidence that such entity carries out, or has the demonstrated capability to carry out, through referral or contractual arrangements, the activities described in subsection (g); and

(B) such other information as the Secretary may require.



(e) PriorityIn awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities—(1) located in a State with an age-adjusted rate of drug overdose deaths that is above the national overdose mortality rate, as determined by the Direc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to establish or operate a comprehensive opioid recovery center (referred to in this section as a “Center”). A Center may be a single entity or an integrated delivery network.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant period</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum number of Centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Minimum number of Centers The Secretary shall allocate the amounts made available under subsection (j) such that not fewer than 10 grants may be awarded. Not more than one grant shall be made to entities in a single State for any one period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Preference In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary may give preference to eligible entities utilizing technology-enabled collaborative learning and capacity building models, including such models as defined in section 2 of the Expanding Capacity for Health Outcomes Act (Public Law 114–270; 130 Stat. 1395), to conduct the activities described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Center activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Center activities Each Center shall, at a minimum, carry out the following activities directly, through referral, or through contractual arrangements, which may include carrying out such activities through technology-enabled collaborative learning and capacity building models described in subsection (f):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data reporting and program oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Data reporting and program oversight</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Privacy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Privacy The provisions of this section, including with respect to data reporting and program oversight, shall be subject to all applicable Federal and State privacy laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_7_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030 for purposes of carrying out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>