<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–5a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–5a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ee–5a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290ee_5a"><akn:num>290ee–5a</akn:num><akn:heading>Sobriety treatment and recovery teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290ee–5a. Sobriety treatment and recovery teams(a) In generalThe Secretary may make grants to States, units of local government, or tribal governments to establish or expand Sobriety Treatment And Recovery Team (referred to in this section as “START”) or other similar programs to determine the effectiveness of pairing social workers or mentors with families that are struggling with a substance use disorder and child abuse or neglect in order to help provide peer support, intensive treatment, and child welfare services to such families.


(b) Allowable usesA grant awarded under this section may be used for one or more of the following activities:(1) Training eligible staff, including social workers, social services coordinators, child welfare specialists, substance use disorder treatment professionals, and mentors.

(2) Expanding access to substance use disorder treatment services and drug testing.

(3) Enhancing data sharing with law enforcement agencies, child welfare agencies, substance use disorder treatment providers, judges, and court personnel.

(4) Program evaluation and technical assistance.


(c) Program requirementsA State, unit of local government, or tribal government receiving a grant under this section shall—(1) serve only families for which—(A) there is an open record with the child welfare agency; and

(B) substance use disorder was a reason for the record or finding described in paragraph (1); 11 So in original. Probably should be “subparagraph (A)”. and


(2) coordinate any grants awarded under this section with any grant awarded under section 629g(f) of this title focused on improving outcomes for children affected by substance abuse.


(d) Technical assistanceThe Secretary may reserve not more than 5 percent of funds provided under this section to provide technical assistance on the establishment or expansion of programs funded under this section from the National Center on Substance Abuse and Child Welfare.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title V, §</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_5a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make grants to States, units of local government, or tribal governments to establish or expand Sobriety Treatment And Recovery Team (referred to in this section as “START”) or other similar programs to determine the effectiveness of pairing social workers or mentors with families that are struggling with a substance use disorder and child abuse or neglect in order to help provide peer support, intensive treatment, and child welfare services to such families.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_5a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allowable uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allowable uses A grant awarded under this section may be used for one or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_5a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program requirements A State, unit of local government, or tribal government receiving a grant under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ee_5a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance The Secretary may reserve not more than 5 percent of funds provided under this section to provide technical assistance on the establishment or expansion of programs funded under this section from the National Center on Substance Abuse and Child Welfare.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>