<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ii–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ii–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290ii–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290ii_2"><akn:num>290ii–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations and enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290ii–2. Regulations and enforcement(a) TrainingNot later than 1 year after October 17, 2000, the Secretary, after consultation with appropriate State and local protection and advocacy organizations, physicians, facilities, and other health care professionals and patients, shall promulgate regulations that require facilities to which the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 11 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 10801 et seq.) applies, to meet the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) RequirementsThe regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall require that—(1) facilities described in subsection (a) ensure that there is an adequate number of qualified professional and supportive staff to evaluate patients, formulate written individualized, comprehensive treatment plans, and to provide active treatment measures;

(2) appropriate training be provided for the staff of such facilities in the use of restraints and any alternatives to the use of restraints; and

(3) such facilities provide complete and accurate notification of deaths, as required under section 290ii–1(a) of this title.


(c) EnforcementA facility to which this part applies that fails to comply with any requirement of this part, including a failure to provide appropriate training, shall not be eligible for participation in any program supported in whole or in part by funds appropriated to any Federal department or agency.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title V, § 593, as added Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3207, Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1196.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986, referred to in subsec. (a), was Pub. L. 99–319, May 23, 1986, 100 Stat. 478. Pub. L. 99–319 was renamed the Protection and Advocacy for Individuals with Mental Illness Act by Pub. L. 106–310, div. B, title XXXII, § 3206(a), Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1193, and is classified generally to chapter 114 (§ 10801 et seq.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ii_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Training Not later than 1 year after October 17, 2000, the Secretary, after consultation with appropriate State and local protection and advocacy organizations, physicians, facilities, and other health care professionals and patients, shall promulgate regulations that require facilities to which the Protection and Advocacy for Mentally Ill Individuals Act of 1986 11 See References in Text note below. (42 U.S.C. 10801 et seq.) applies, to meet the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ii_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements The regulations promulgated under subsection (a) shall require that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290ii_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement A facility to which this part applies that fails to comply with any requirement of this part, including a failure to provide appropriate training, shall not be eligible for participation in any program supported in whole or in part by funds appropriated to any Federal department or agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>