<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290jj" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290jj/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290jj/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290jj"><akn:num>290jj</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement relating to the rights of residents of certain non-medical, community-based facilities f</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290jj. Requirement relating to the rights of residents of certain non-medical, community-based facilities for children and youth(a) Protection of rights(1) In generalA public or private non-medical, community-based facility for children and youth (as defined in regulations to be promulgated by the Secretary) that receives support in any form from any program supported in whole or in part with funds appropriated under this chapter shall protect and promote the rights of each resident of the facility, including the right to be free from physical or mental abuse, corporal punishment, and any restraints or involuntary seclusions imposed for purposes of discipline or convenience.


(2) NonapplicabilityNotwithstanding this part, a facility that provides inpatient psychiatric treatment services for individuals under the age of 21, as authorized and defined in subsections (a)(16) and (h) of section 1905 of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396d], shall comply with the requirements of part H.


(3) Applicability of Medicaid provisionsA non-medical, community-based facility for children and youth funded under the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] shall continue to meet all existing requirements for participation in such program that are not affected by this part.



(b) Requirements(1) In generalPhysical restraints and seclusion may only be imposed on a resident of a facility described in subsection (a) if—(A) the restraints or seclusion are imposed only in emergency circumstances and only to ensure the immediate physical safety of the resident, a staff member, or others and less restrictive interventions have been determined to be ineffective; and

(B) the restraints or seclusion are imposed only by an individual trained and certified, by a State-recognized body (as defined in regulation promulgated by the Secretary) and pursuant to a process determined appropriate by the State and approved by the Secretary, in the preve</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290jj_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Protection of rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290jj_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290jj_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rule of construction</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290jj_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>