<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290kk–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290kk–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/290kk–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_290kk_1"><akn:num>290kk–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious organizations as program participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 290kk–1. Religious organizations as program participants(a) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a religious organization, on the same basis as any other nonprofit private provider—(1) may receive financial assistance under a designated program; and

(2) may be a provider of services under a designated program.


(b) Religious organizationsThe purpose of this section is to allow religious organizations to be program participants on the same basis as any other nonprofit private provider without impairing the religious character of such organizations, and without diminishing the religious freedom of program beneficiaries.


(c) Nondiscrimination against religious organizations(1) Eligibility as program participantsReligious organizations are eligible to be program participants on the same basis as any other nonprofit private organization as long as the programs are implemented consistent with the Establishment Clause and Free Exercise Clause of the First Amendment to the United States Constitution. Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to restrict the ability of the Federal Government, or a State or local government receiving funds under such programs, to apply to religious organizations the same eligibility conditions in designated programs as are applied to any other nonprofit private organization.


(2) NondiscriminationNeither the Federal Government nor a State or local government receiving funds under designated programs shall discriminate against an organization that is or applies to be a program participant on the basis that the organization has a religious character.



(d) Religious character and freedom(1) Religious organizationsExcept as provided in this section, any religious organization that is a program participant shall retain its independence from Federal, State, and local government, including such organization’s control over the definition, development, practice, and expression of its religious beliefs.


(2) Additional safeg</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a religious organization, on the same basis as any other nonprofit private provider—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Religious organizations The purpose of this section is to allow religious organizations to be program participants on the same basis as any other nonprofit private provider without impairing the religious character of such organizations, and without diminishing the religious freedom of program beneficiaries.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination against religious organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nondiscrimination against religious organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious character and freedom</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Religious character and freedom</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Employment practices Nothing in this section shall be construed to modify or affect the provisions of any other Federal or State law or regulation that relates to discrimination in employment. A religious organization’s exemption provided under section 2000e–1 of this title regarding employment practices shall not be affected by its participation in, or receipt of funds from, a designated program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of program beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rights of program beneficiaries</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Fiscal accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_290kk_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compliance With respect to compliance with this section by an agency, a religious organization may obtain judicial review of agency action in accordance with chapter 7 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>