<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_291d"><akn:num>291d</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 291d. State plans(a) Submission; requirementsAny State desiring to participate in this part may submit a State plan. Such plan must—(1) designate a single State agency as the sole agency for the administration of the plan, or designate such agency as the sole agency for supervising the administration of the plan;

(2) contain satisfactory evidence that the State agency designated in accordance with paragraph (1) of this subsection will have authority to carry out such plan in conformity with this part;

(3) provide for the designation of a State advisory council which shall include (A) representatives of nongovernmental organizations or groups, and of public agencies, concerned with the operation, construction, or utilization of hospital or other facilities for diagnosis, prevention, or treatment of illness or disease, or for provision of rehabilitation services, and representatives particularly concerned with education or training of health professions personnel, and (B) an equal number of representatives of consumers familiar with the need for the services provided by such facilities, to consult with the State agency in carrying out the plan, and provide, if such council does not include any representatives of nongovernmental organizations or groups, or State agencies, concerned with rehabilitation, for consultation with organizations, groups, and State agencies so concerned;

(4) set forth, in accordance with criteria established in regulations prescribed under section 291c of this title and on the basis of a statewide inventory of existing facilities, a survey of need, and (except to the extent provided by or pursuant to such regulations) community, area, or regional plans—(A) the number of general hospital beds and long-term care beds, and the number and types of hospital facilities and facilities for long-term care, needed to provide adequate facilities for inpatient care of people residing in the State, and a plan for the distribution of such beds and facil</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission; requirements Any State desiring to participate in this part may submit a State plan. Such plan must—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by Surgeon General; hearing after disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Approval by Surgeon General; hearing after disapproval The Surgeon General shall approve any State plan and any modification thereof which complies with the provisions of subsection (a). If any such plan or modification thereof shall have been disapproved by the Surgeon General for failure to comply with subsection (a), the Federal Hospital Council shall, upon request of the State agency, afford it an opportunity for hearing. If such Council determines that the plan or modification complies with the provisions of such subsection, the Surgeon General shall thereupon approve such plan or modification.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>