<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_291j_3"><akn:num>291j–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 291j–3. Applications and conditions(a) Contents of applicationsFor each project for which a guarantee of a loan to a nonprofit private agency or a direct loan to a public agency is sought under this part, there shall be submitted to the Secretary, through the State agency designated in accordance with section 291d of this title, an application by such private nonprofit agency or by such public agency. If two or more private nonprofit agencies, or two or more public agencies, join in the project, the application may be filed by one or more such agencies. Such application shall (1) set forth all of the descriptions, plans, specifications, assurances, and information which are required by the third sentence of section 291e(a) of this title (other than clause (6) thereof) with respect to applications submitted under that section, (2) contain such other information as the Secretary may require to carry out the purposes of this part, and (3) include a certification by the State agency of the total cost of the project and the amount of the loan for which a guarantee is sought under this part, or the amount of the direct loan sought under this part, as the case may be.


(b) Conditions for approvalThe Secretary may approve such application only if—(1) there remains sufficient balance in the allotment determined for such State pursuant to section 291j–2 of this title to cover the amount of the loan for which a guarantee is sought, or the amount of the direct loan sought (as the case may be), in such application,

(2) he makes each of the findings which are required by clauses (1) through (4) of section 291e(b) of this title for the approval of applications for projects thereunder (except that, in the case of the finding required under such clause (4) of entitlement of a project to a priority established under section 291c(a) of this title; such finding shall be made without regard to the provisions of clauses (1) and (3) of such section),

(3) he finds that there is compli</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contents of applications For each project for which a guarantee of a loan to a nonprofit private agency or a direct loan to a public agency is sought under this part, there shall be submitted to the Secretary, through the State agency designated in accordance with section 291d of this title, an application by such private nonprofit agency or by such public agency. If two or more private nonprofit agencies, or two or more public agencies, join in the project, the application may be filed by one or more such agencies. Such application shall (1) set forth all of the descriptions, plans, specifications, assurances, and information which are required by the third sentence of section 291e(a) of this title (other than clause (6) thereof) with respect to applications submitted under that section, (2) contain such other information as the Secretary may require to carry out the purposes of this part, and (3) include a certification by the State agency of the total cost of the project and the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions for approval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conditions for approval The Secretary may approve such application only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Hearing No application under this section shall be disapproved until the Secretary has afforded the State agency an opportunity for a hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of approved applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amendment of approved applications Amendment of an approved application shall be subject to approval in the same manner as an original application.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery rights; terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Recovery rights; terms and conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incontestable guarantee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Incontestable guarantee Any guarantee of a loan to a nonprofit private agency made by the Secretary pursuant to this part shall be incontestable in the hands of an applicant on whose behalf such guarantee is made, and as to any person who makes or contracts to make a loan to such applicant in reliance thereon, except for fraud or misrepresentation on the part of such applicant or such other person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>