<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/291j–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_291j_7"><akn:num>291j–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Loans to public facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 291j–7. Loans to public facilities(a) Interest rates; security; equitable geographical distribution(1) Any loan made by the Secretary to a public agency under this part for the modernization or construction of a public hospital or other health facility shall require such public agency to pay interest thereon at a rate comparable to the current rate of interest prevailing with respect to loans, to nonprofit private agencies, which are guaranteed under this part, for the modernization or construction of similar facilities in the same or similar areas, minus 3 per centum per annum.

(2)(A) No loan to a public agency shall be made under this part unless—(i) the Secretary is reasonably satisfied that such agency will be able to make payments of principal and interest thereon when due, and

(ii) such agency provides the Secretary with reasonable assurances that there will be available to such agency such additional funds as may be necessary to complete the project with respect to which such loan is requested.


(B) Any loan to a public agency shall have such security, have such maturity date, be repayable in such installments, and be subject to such other terms and conditions (including provision for recovery in case of default) as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out the purposes of this part while adequately protecting the financial interests of the United States.


(3) In making loans to public agencies under this part, the Secretary shall give due regard to achieving an equitable geographical distribution of such loans.


(b) Sale(1) The Secretary shall from time to time, but with due regard to the financial interests of the United States, sell loans referred to in subsection (a)(1) either on the private market or to the Federal National Mortgage Association in accordance with section 1717 of title 12.

(2) Any loan so sold shall be sold for an amount which is equal (or approximately equal) to the amount of the unpaid principal of such loan as of th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest rates; security; equitable geographical distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interest rates; security; equitable geographical distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Sale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Right of recovery; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Right of recovery; waiver The Secretary may, for good cause, waive any right of recovery which he has against a public agency by reason of the failure of such agency to make payments of principal and interest on a loan made to such agency under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interest and interest subsidies as gross income under Internal Revenue Code</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interest and interest subsidies as gross income under Internal Revenue Code After any loan to a public agency under this part has been sold and guaranteed, interest paid on such loan and any interest subsidy paid by the Secretary with respect to such loan which is received by the purchaser thereof (or his successor in interest) shall be included in gross income for the purposes of chapter 1 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales proceeds; deposit and use</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sales proceeds; deposit and use Amounts received by the Secretary as proceeds from the sale of loans under this section shall be deposited in the loan fund established by section 291j–6 of this title, and shall be available to the Secretary for the making of further loans under this part in accordance with the provisions of subsection (a)(2) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_291j_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, for deposit in the loan fund established by section 291j–6 of this title, $30,000,000 to provide initial capital for the making of direct loans by the Secretary to public agencies for the modernization or construction of facilities referred to in subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>