<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_292d"><akn:num>292d</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of borrowers and terms of insured loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 292d. Eligibility of borrowers and terms of insured loans(a) In generalA loan by an eligible lender shall be insurable by the Secretary under the provisions of this subpart only if—(1) made to—(A) a student who—(i)(I) has been accepted for enrollment at an eligible institution, or (II) in the case of a student attending an eligible institution, is in good standing at that institution, as determined by the institution;


(ii) is or will be a full-time student at the eligible institution;

(iii) has agreed that all funds received under such loan shall be used solely for tuition, other reasonable educational expenses, including fees, books, and laboratory expenses, and reasonable living expenses, incurred by such students; and

(iv) in the case of a pharmacy student, has satisfactorily completed three years of training; or


(B) an individual who—(i) has previously had a loan insured under this subpart when the individual was a full-time student at an eligible institution;

(ii) is in a period during which, pursuant to paragraph (2), the principal amount of such previous loan need not be paid; and

(iii) has agreed that all funds received under the proposed loan shall be used solely for repayment of interest due on previous loans made under this subpart;



(2) evidenced by a note or other written agreement which—(A) is made without security and without endorsement, except that if the borrower is a minor and such note or other written agreement executed by him would not, under the applicable law, create a binding obligation, an endorsement may be required;

(B) provides for repayment of the principal amount of the loan in installments over a period of not less than 10 years (unless sooner repaid) nor more than 25 years beginning not earlier than 9 months nor later than 12 months after the date of—(i) the date on which—(I) the borrower ceases to be a participant in an accredited internship or residency program of not more than four years in duration;

(II) the borrowe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A loan by an eligible lender shall be insurable by the Secretary under the provisions of this subpart only if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on rate of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on rate of interest The rate of interest prescribed and defined by the Secretary for the purpose of subsection (a)(2)(D) may not exceed the average of the bond equivalent rates of the 91-day Treasury bills auctioned for the previous quarter plus 3 percentage points, rounded to the next higher one-eighth of 1 percent.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum annual payment by borrower</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Minimum annual payment by borrower The total of the payments by a borrower during any year or any repayment period with respect to the aggregate amount of all loans to that borrower which are insured under this subpart shall not be less than the annual interest on the outstanding principal, except as provided in subsection (a)(2)(C), unless the borrower, in the written agreement described in subsection (a)(2), agrees to make payments during any year or any repayment period in a lesser amount.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of certain laws on rate or amount of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of certain laws on rate or amount of interest No provision of any law of the United States (other than subsections (a)(2)(D) and (b)) or of any State that limits the rate or amount of interest payable on loans shall apply to a loan insured under this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination regarding forbearance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Determination regarding forbearance Any period of time granted to a borrower under this subpart in the form of forbearance on the loan shall not be included in the 25-year total loan repayment period under subsection (a)(2)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan repayment schedule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Loan repayment schedule Lenders and holders under this subpart shall offer borrowers graduated loan repayment schedules that, during the first 5 years of loan repayment, are based on the borrower’s debt-to-income ratio.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding determination of need of students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rule of construction regarding determination of need of students With respect to any determination of the financial need of a student for a loan covered by Federal loan insurance under this subpart, this subpart may not be construed to limit the authority of any school to make such allowances for students with special circumstances as the school determines appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292d_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>