<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_292e"><akn:num>292e</akn:num><akn:heading>Certificate of loan insurance; effective date of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 292e. Certificate of loan insurance; effective date of insurance(a) In general(1) Authority for issuance of certificateIf, upon application by an eligible lender, made upon such form, containing such information, and supported by such evidence as the Secretary may require, and otherwise in conformity with this section, the Secretary finds that the applicant has made a loan to an eligible borrower which is insurable under the provisions of this subpart, he may issue to the applicant a certificate of insurance covering the loan and setting forth the amount and terms of the insurance.


(2) Effective date of insuranceInsurance evidenced by a certificate of insurance pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall become effective upon the date of issuance of the certificate, except that the Secretary is authorized, in accordance with regulations, to issue commitments with respect to proposed loans, or with respect to lines (or proposed lines) of credit, submitted by eligible lenders, and in that event, upon compliance with subsection (a)(1) by the lender, the certificate of insurance may be issued effective as of the date when any loan, or any payment by the lender pursuant to a line of credit, to be covered by such insurance is made to a student described in section 292d(a)(1) of this title. Such insurance shall cease to be effective upon 60 days’ default by the lender in the payment of any installment of the premiums payable pursuant to section 292g of this title.


(3) Certain agreements for lendersAn application submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(1) shall contain—(A) an agreement by the applicant to pay, in accordance with regulations, the premiums fixed by the Secretary pursuant to section 292g of this title; and

(B) an agreement by the applicant that if the loan is covered by insurance the applicant will submit such supplementary reports and statements during the effective period of the loan agreement, upon such forms, at such times, and containing such information as t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority regarding comprehensive insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority regarding comprehensive insurance coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of insurance rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assignment of insurance rights The rights of an eligible lender arising under insurance evidenced by a certificate of insurance issued to it under this section may be assigned by such lender, subject to regulation by the Secretary, only to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of refinancing or consolidation of obligations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect of refinancing or consolidation of obligations The consolidation of the obligations of two or more federally insured loans obtained by a borrower in any fiscal year into a single obligation evidenced by a single instrument of indebtedness or the refinancing of a single loan shall not affect the insurance by the United States. If the loans thus consolidated are covered by separate certificates of insurance issued under subsection (a), the Secretary may upon surrender of the original certificates issue a new certificate of insurance in accordance with that subsection upon the consolidated obligation. If the loans thus consolidated are covered by a single comprehensive certificate issued under subsection (b), the Secretary may amend that certificate accordingly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction regarding consolidation of debts and refinancing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rule of construction regarding consolidation of debts and refinancing Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the lender and the borrower, by mutual agreement, from consolidating all of the borrower’s loans insured under this subpart into a single instrument (or, if the borrower obtained only 1 loan insured under this subpart, refinancing the loan 1 time) under the terms applicable to an insured loan made at the same time as the consolidation. The lender or loan holder should provide full information to the borrower concerning the advantages and disadvantages of loan consolidation or refinancing. Nothing in this section shall be construed to preclude the consolidation of the borrower’s loans insured under this subpart under section 1078–3 of title 20. Any loans insured pursuant to this subpart that are consolidated under section 1078–3 of title 20 shall not be eligible for special allowance payments under section 1087–1 of title 20.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>