<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_292r"><akn:num>292r</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 292r. Loan provisions(a) Amount of loan(1) In generalLoans from a student loan fund (established under an agreement with a school under section 292q of this title) may not, subject to paragraph (2), exceed for any student for a school year (or its equivalent) the cost of attendance (including tuition, other reasonable educational expenses, and reasonable living costs) for that year at the educational institution attended by the student (as determined by such educational institution).


(2) Third and fourth years of medical schoolFor purposes of paragraph (1), the amount of the loan may, in the case of the third or fourth year of a student at a school of medicine or osteopathic medicine, be increased to the extent necessary to pay the balances of loans that, from sources other than the student loan fund under section 292q of this title, were made to the individual for attendance at the school. The authority to make such an increase is subject to the school and the student agreeing that such amount (as increased) will be expended to pay such balances.



(b) Terms and conditionsSubject to section 292s of this title, any such loans shall be made on such terms and conditions as the school may determine, but may be made only to a student who is in need of the amount thereof to pursue a full-time course of study at the school leading to a degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of dentistry or an equivalent degree, doctor of osteopathy, bachelor of science in pharmacy or an equivalent degree, doctor of pharmacy or an equivalent degree, doctor of podiatric medicine or an equivalent degree, doctor of optometry or an equivalent degree, or doctor of veterinary medicine or an equivalent degree.


(c) Repayment; exclusions from repayment periodSuch loans shall be repayable in equal or graduated periodic installments (with the right of the borrower to accelerate repayment) over the period of not less than 10 years nor more than 25 years, at the discretion of the institution, whic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of loan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of loan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions Subject to section 292s of this title, any such loans shall be made on such terms and conditions as the school may determine, but may be made only to a student who is in need of the amount thereof to pursue a full-time course of study at the school leading to a degree of doctor of medicine, doctor of dentistry or an equivalent degree, doctor of osteopathy, bachelor of science in pharmacy or an equivalent degree, doctor of pharmacy or an equivalent degree, doctor of podiatric medicine or an equivalent degree, doctor of optometry or an equivalent degree, or doctor of veterinary medicine or an equivalent degree.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment; exclusions from repayment period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repayment; exclusions from repayment period Such loans shall be repayable in equal or graduated periodic installments (with the right of the borrower to accelerate repayment) over the period of not less than 10 years nor more than 25 years, at the discretion of the institution, which begins one year after the student ceases to pursue a full-time course of study at a school of medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, pharmacy, podiatry, optometry, or veterinary medicine, excluding from such period—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation of liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cancellation of liability The liability to repay the unpaid balance of such a loan and accrued interest thereon shall be canceled upon the death of the borrower, or if the Secretary determines that he has become permanently, and totally disabled.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate of interest</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rate of interest Such loans shall bear interest, on the unpaid balance of the loan, computed only for periods for which the loan is repayable, at the rate of 5 percent per year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Security or endorsement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Security or endorsement Loans shall be made under this subpart without security or endorsement, except that if the borrower is a minor and the note or other evidence of obligation executed by him would not, under the applicable law, create a binding obligation, either security or endorsement may be required.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transferring and assigning loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transferring and assigning loans No note or other evidence of a loan made under this subpart may be transferred or assigned by the school making the loan except that, if the borrowers transfer to another school participating in the program under this subpart, such note or other evidence of a loan may be transferred to such other school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge with respect to insurance for certain cancellations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Charge with respect to insurance for certain cancellations Subject to regulations of the Secretary, a school may assess a charge with respect to loans made this subpart 11 So in original. Probably should be “under this subpart”. to cover the costs of insuring against cancellation of liability under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Charge with respect to late payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Charge with respect to late payments Subject to regulations of the Secretary, and in accordance with this section, a school shall assess a charge with respect to a loan made under this subpart for failure of the borrower to pay all or any part of an installment when it is due and, in the case of a borrower who is entitled to deferment of the loan under subsection (c), for any failure to file timely and satisfactory evidence of such entitlement. No such charge may be made if the payment of such installment or the filing of such evidence is made within 60 days after the date on which such installment or filing is due. The amount of any such charge may not exceed an amount equal to 6 percent of the amount of such installment. The school may elect to add the amount of any such charge to the principal amount of the loan as of the first day after the day on which such installment or evidence was due, or to make the amount of the charge payable to the school not later than the due date of</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292r_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of schools regarding rate of payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authority of schools regarding rate of payment A school may provide, in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, that during the repayment period of a loan from a loan fund established pursuant to an agreement under this subpart payments of principal and interest by the borrower with respect to all the outstanding loans made to him from loan funds so established shall be at a rate equal to not less than $40 per month.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>