<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292y" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292y/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/292y/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_292y"><akn:num>292y</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 292y. General provisions(a) Date certain for applicationsThe Secretary shall from time to time set dates by which schools must file applications for Federal capital contributions.


(b) Contingent reduction in allotmentsIf the total of the amounts requested for any fiscal year in such applications exceeds the amounts appropriated under this section for that fiscal year, the allotment to the loan fund of each such school shall be reduced to whichever of the following is the smaller: (A) the amount requested in its application; or (B) an amount which bears the same ratio to the amounts appropriated as the number of students estimated by the Secretary to be enrolled in such school during such fiscal year bears to the estimated total number of students in all such schools during such year. Amounts remaining after allotment under the preceding sentence shall be reallotted in accordance with clause (B) of such sentence among schools whose applications requested more than the amounts so allotted to their loan funds, but with such adjustments as may be necessary to prevent the total allotted to any such school’s loan fund from exceeding the total so requested by it.


(c) Allotment of excess fundsFunds available in any fiscal year for payment to schools under this subpart which are in excess of the amount appropriated pursuant to this section for that year shall be allotted among schools in such manner as the Secretary determines will best carry out the purposes of this subpart.


(d) Payment of installments to schoolsAllotments to a loan fund of a school shall be paid to it from time to time in such installments as the Secretary determines will not result in unnecessary accumulations in the loan fund at such school.


(e) Disposition of funds returned to Secretary(1) Expenditure for Federal capital contributionsSubject to section 292s(b)(5) of this title, any amounts from student loan funds under section 292q of this title that are returned to the Secretary by health pro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Date certain for applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Date certain for applications The Secretary shall from time to time set dates by which schools must file applications for Federal capital contributions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingent reduction in allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contingent reduction in allotments If the total of the amounts requested for any fiscal year in such applications exceeds the amounts appropriated under this section for that fiscal year, the allotment to the loan fund of each such school shall be reduced to whichever of the following is the smaller: (A) the amount requested in its application; or (B) an amount which bears the same ratio to the amounts appropriated as the number of students estimated by the Secretary to be enrolled in such school during such fiscal year bears to the estimated total number of students in all such schools during such year. Amounts remaining after allotment under the preceding sentence shall be reallotted in accordance with clause (B) of such sentence among schools whose applications requested more than the amounts so allotted to their loan funds, but with such adjustments as may be necessary to prevent the total allotted to any such school’s loan fund from exceeding the total so requested by it.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of excess funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allotment of excess funds Funds available in any fiscal year for payment to schools under this subpart which are in excess of the amount appropriated pursuant to this section for that year shall be allotted among schools in such manner as the Secretary determines will best carry out the purposes of this subpart.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of installments to schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payment of installments to schools Allotments to a loan fund of a school shall be paid to it from time to time in such installments as the Secretary determines will not result in unnecessary accumulations in the loan fund at such school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disposition of funds returned to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disposition of funds returned to Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_292y_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding for certain medical schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding for certain medical schools</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>