<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_293a"><akn:num>293a</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarships for disadvantaged students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 293a. Scholarships for disadvantaged students(a) In generalThe Secretary may make a grant to an eligible entity (as defined in subsection (d)(1)) under this section for the awarding of scholarships by schools to any full-time student who is an eligible individual as defined in subsection (d). Such scholarships may be expended only for tuition expenses, other reasonable educational expenses, and reasonable living expenses incurred in the attendance of such school.


(b) Preference in providing scholarshipsThe Secretary may not make a grant to an entity under subsection (a) unless the health professions and nursing schools involved agree that, in providing scholarships pursuant to the grant, the schools will give preference to students for whom the costs of attending the schools would constitute a severe financial hardship and, notwithstanding other provisions of this section, to former recipients of scholarships under sections 293 and 293d(d)(2)(B) of this title (as such sections existed on the day before November 13, 1998).


(c) Amount of awardIn awarding grants to eligible entities that are health professions and nursing schools, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities based on the proportion of graduating students going into primary care, the proportion of underrepresented minority students, and the proportion of graduates working in medically underserved communities.


(d) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entitiesThe term “eligible entities” means an entity that—(A) is a school of medicine, osteopathic medicine, dentistry, nursing (as defined in section 296 of this title), pharmacy, podiatric medicine, optometry, veterinary medicine, public health, chiropractic, or allied health, a school offering a graduate program in behavioral and mental health practice, or an entity providing programs for the training of physician assistants; and

(B) is carrying out a program for recruiting and retaining students from disadvantaged backgrounds, inclu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make a grant to an eligible entity (as defined in subsection (d)(1)) under this section for the awarding of scholarships by schools to any full-time student who is an eligible individual as defined in subsection (d). Such scholarships may be expended only for tuition expenses, other reasonable educational expenses, and reasonable living expenses incurred in the attendance of such school.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference in providing scholarships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preference in providing scholarships The Secretary may not make a grant to an entity under subsection (a) unless the health professions and nursing schools involved agree that, in providing scholarships pursuant to the grant, the schools will give preference to students for whom the costs of attending the schools would constitute a severe financial hardship and, notwithstanding other provisions of this section, to former recipients of scholarships under sections 293 and 293d(d)(2)(B) of this title (as such sections existed on the day before November 13, 1998).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of award In awarding grants to eligible entities that are health professions and nursing schools, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities based on the proportion of graduating students going into primary care, the proportion of underrepresented minority students, and the proportion of graduates working in medically underserved communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>