<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_293c"><akn:num>293c</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational assistance in the health professions regarding individuals from disadvantaged background</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 293c. Educational assistance in the health professions regarding individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds(a) In general(1) Authority for grantsFor the purpose of assisting individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, as determined in accordance with criteria prescribed by the Secretary, to undertake education to enter a health profession, the Secretary may make grants to and enter into contracts with schools of medicine, osteopathic medicine, public health, dentistry, veterinary medicine, optometry, pharmacy, allied health, chiropractic, and podiatric medicine, public and nonprofit private schools that offer graduate programs in behavioral and mental health, programs for the training of physician assistants, and other public or private nonprofit health or educational entities to assist in meeting the costs described in paragraph (2).


(2) Authorized expendituresA grant or contract under paragraph (1) may be used by the entity to meet the cost of—(A) identifying, recruiting, and selecting individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds, as so determined, for education and training in a health profession;

(B) facilitating the entry of such individuals into such a school;

(C) providing counseling, mentoring, or other services designed to assist such individuals to complete successfully their education at such a school;

(D) providing, for a period prior to the entry of such individuals into the regular course of education of such a school, preliminary education and health research training designed to assist them to complete successfully such regular course of education at such a school, or referring such individuals to institutions providing such preliminary education;

(E) publicizing existing sources of financial aid available to students in the education program of such a school or who are undertaking training necessary to qualify them to enroll in such a program;

(F) paying such scholarships as the Secretary may determine for such individuals for any period of h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements for awards In making awards to eligible entities under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall give preference to approved applications for programs that involve a comprehensive approach by several public or nonprofit private health or educational entities to establish, enhance and expand educational programs that will result in the development of a competitive applicant pool of individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds who desire to pursue health professions careers. In considering awards for such a comprehensive partnership approach, the following shall apply with respect to the entity involved:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable allocation of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equitable allocation of financial assistance The Secretary, to the extent practicable, shall ensure that services and activities under subsection (a) are adequately allocated among the various racial and ethnic populations who are from disadvantaged backgrounds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matching requirements The Secretary may require that an entity that applies for a grant or contract under subsection (a), provide non-Federal matching funds, as appropriate, to ensure the institutional commitment of the entity to the projects funded under the grant or contract. As determined by the Secretary, such non-Federal matching funds may be provided directly or through donations from public or private entities and may be in cash or in-kind, fairly evaluated, including plant, equipment, or services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>