<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293k–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293k–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/293k–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_293k_2"><akn:num>293k–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Training in general, pediatric, and public health dentistry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 293k–2. Training in general, pediatric, and public health dentistry(a) Support and development of dental training programs(1) In generalThe Secretary may make grants to, or enter into contracts with, a school of dentistry, public or nonprofit private hospital, or a public or private nonprofit entity which the Secretary has determined is capable of carrying out such grant or contract—(A) to plan, develop, and operate, or participate in, an approved professional training program in the field of general dentistry, pediatric dentistry, or public health dentistry for dental students, residents, practicing dentists, dental hygienists, or other approved primary care dental trainees, that emphasizes training for general, pediatric, or public health dentistry;

(B) to provide financial assistance to dental students, residents, practicing dentists, and dental hygiene students who are in need thereof, who are participants in any such program, and who plan to work in the practice of general, pediatric, public heath dentistry, or dental hygiene;

(C) to plan, develop, and operate a program for the training of oral health care providers who plan to teach in general, pediatric, public health dentistry, or dental hygiene;

(D) to provide financial assistance in the form of traineeships and fellowships to dentists who plan to teach or are teaching in general, pediatric, or public health dentistry;

(E) to meet the costs of projects to establish, maintain, or improve dental faculty development programs in primary care (which may be departments, divisions or other units);

(F) to meet the costs of projects to establish, maintain, or improve predoctoral and postdoctoral training in primary care programs;

(G) to create a loan repayment program for faculty in dental programs; and

(H) to provide technical assistance to pediatric training programs in developing and implementing instruction regarding the oral health status, dental care needs, and risk-based clinical disease management o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support and development of dental training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Support and development of dental training programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entity For purposes of this subsection, entities eligible for such grants or contracts in general, pediatric, or public health dentistry shall include entities that have programs in dental or dental hygiene schools, or approved residency or advanced education programs in the practice of general, pediatric, or public health dentistry. Eligible entities may partner with schools of public health to permit the education of dental students, residents, and dental hygiene students for a master’s year in public health at a school of public health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities in making awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priorities in making awards With respect to training provided for under this section, the Secretary shall give priority in awarding grants or contracts to the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duration of award The period during which payments are made to an entity from an award of a grant or contract under subsection (a) shall be 5 years. The provision of such payments shall be subject to annual approval by the Secretary and subject to the availability of appropriations for the fiscal year involved to make the payments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorizations of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorizations of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out subsections (a) and (b), there is authorized to be appropriated $28,531,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_293k_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Carryover funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Carryover funds An entity that receives an award under this section may carry over funds from 1 fiscal year to another without obtaining approval from the Secretary. In no case may any funds be carried over pursuant to the preceding sentence for more than 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>