<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294a"><akn:num>294a</akn:num><akn:heading>Area health education centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294a. Area health education centers(a) Establishment of awardsThe Secretary shall make the following 2 types of awards in accordance with this section:(1) Infrastructure development awardThe Secretary shall make awards to eligible entities to enable such entities to initiate health care workforce educational programs or to continue to carry out comparable programs that are operating at the time the award is made by planning, developing, operating, and evaluating an area health education center program.


(2) Point of service maintenance and enhancement awardThe Secretary shall make awards to eligible entities to maintain and improve the effectiveness and capabilities of an existing area health education center program, and make other modifications to the program that are appropriate due to changes in demographics, needs of the populations served, or other similar issues affecting the area health education center program. For the purposes of this section, the term “Program” refers to the area health education center program.



(b) Eligible entities; application(1) Eligible entities(A) Infrastructure developmentFor purposes of subsection (a)(1), the term “eligible entity” means a school of medicine or osteopathic medicine, an incorporated consortium of such schools, or the parent institutions of such a school. With respect to a State in which no area health education center program is in operation, the Secretary may award a grant or contract under subsection (a)(1) to a school of nursing.


(B) Point of service maintenance and enhancementFor purposes of subsection (a)(2), the term “eligible entity” means an entity that has received funds under this section, is operating an area health education center program, including an area health education center or centers, and has a center or centers that are no longer eligible to receive financial assistance under subsection (a)(1).



(2) ApplicationAn eligible entity desiring to receive an award under this section shall s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of awards The Secretary shall make the following 2 types of awards in accordance with this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities; application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities; application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching funds With respect to the costs of operating a program through a grant under this section, to be eligible for financial assistance under this section, an entity shall make available (directly or through contributions from State, county or municipal governments, or the private sector) recurring non-Federal contributions in cash or in kind, toward such costs in an amount that is equal to not less than 50 percent of such costs. At least 25 percent of the total required non-Federal contributions shall be in cash. An entity may apply to the Secretary for a waiver of not more than 75 percent of the matching fund amount required by the entity for each of the first 3 years the entity is funded through a grant under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation Not less than 75 percent of the total amount provided to an area health education center program under subsection (a)(1) or (a)(2) shall be allocated to the area health education centers participating in the program under this section. To provide needed flexibility to newly funded area health education center programs, the Secretary may waive the requirement in the sentence for the first 2 years of a new area health education center program funded under subsection (a)(1).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Award</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Award An award to an entity under this section shall be not less than $250,000 annually per area health education center included in the program involved. If amounts appropriated to carry out this section are not sufficient to comply with the preceding sentence, the Secretary may reduce the per center amount provided for in such sentence as necessary, provided the distribution established in subsection (j)(2) is maintained.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Project terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inapplicability of provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Inapplicability of provision Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, section 295j(a) of this title shall not apply to an area health education center funded under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>