<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294o" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294o/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294o/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294o"><akn:num>294o</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council on Graduate Medical Education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294o. Advisory Council on Graduate Medical Education(a) Establishment; dutiesThere is established the Council on Graduate Medical Education (in this section referred to as the “Council”). The Council shall—(1) make recommendations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), and to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, with respect to—(A) the supply and distribution of physicians in the United States;

(B) current and future shortages or excesses of physicians in medical and surgical specialties and subspecialties;

(C) issues relating to foreign medical school graduates;

(D) appropriate Federal policies with respect to the matters specified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), including policies concerning changes in the financing of undergraduate and graduate medical education programs and changes in the types of medical education training in graduate medical education programs;

(E) appropriate efforts to be carried out by hospitals, schools of medicine, schools of osteopathic medicine, and accrediting bodies with respect to the matters specified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C), including efforts for changes in undergraduate and graduate medical education programs; and

(F) deficiencies in, and needs for improvements in, existing data bases concerning the supply and distribution of, and postgraduate training programs for, physicians in the United States and steps that should be taken to eliminate those deficiencies;


(2) encourage entities providing graduate medical education to conduct activities to voluntarily achieve the recommendations of the Council under paragraph (1)(E);

(3) develop, publish, and implement performance measures for programs under this subchapter, except for programs under part C or D;

(4) develop and publish guidelines for longitudinal evaluations (as described in section 294n(</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; duties There is established the Council on Graduate Medical Education (in this section referred to as the “Council”). The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition The Council shall be composed of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of appointed members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Terms of appointed members</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Chair The Council shall elect one of its members as Chairman of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quorum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Quorum Nine members of the Council shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Vacancies Any vacancy in the Council shall not affect its power to function.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation Each member of the Council who is not otherwise employed by the United States Government shall receive compensation at a rate equal to the daily rate prescribed for GS–18 under the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5 for each day, including traveltime,11 So in original. Probably should be “travel time,”. such member is engaged in the actual performance of duties as a member of the Council. A member of the Council who is an officer or employee of the United States Government shall serve without additional compensation. All members of the Council shall be reimbursed for travel, subsistence, and other necessary expenses incurred by them in the performance of their duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain authorities and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Certain authorities and duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports Not later than September 30, 2023, and not less than every 5 years thereafter, the Council shall submit to the Secretary, and to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, a report on the recommendations described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294o_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Funding Amounts otherwise appropriated under this subchapter may be utilized by the Secretary to support the activities of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>