<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294p"><akn:num>294p</akn:num><akn:heading>Training for health care providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294p. Training for health care providers(a) Grant programThe Secretary shall establish a program to award grants to accredited schools of allopathic medicine, osteopathic medicine, and nursing, and other health professional training programs for the training of health care professionals to improve the provision of prenatal care, labor care, birthing, and postpartum care for racial and ethnic minority populations, including with respect to perceptions and biases that may affect the approach to, and provision of, care.


(b) EligibilityTo be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity described in such subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(c) Reporting requirements(1) Periodic grantee reportsEach entity awarded a grant under this section shall periodically submit to the Secretary a report on the status of activities conducted using the grant, including a description of the impact of such training on patient outcomes, as applicable.


(2) Report to CongressNot later than September 30, 2026, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the activities conducted using grants under subsection (a) and any best practices identified and disseminated under subsection (d).



(d) Best practicesThe Secretary may identify and disseminate best practices for the training described in subsection (a).


(e) Authorization of appropriationsTo carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VII, § 763, as added Pub. L. 117–103, div. P, title I, § 132, Mar. 15, 2022, 136 Stat. 795.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 294p, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VII, § 763, as added Pub. L. 106–310, div. A, title III, § 301(b), Oct. 17, 2000, 114 Stat. 1111, related to pediatric rheumatologists, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 117–103, div. P, title I, § 13</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grant program The Secretary shall establish a program to award grants to accredited schools of allopathic medicine, osteopathic medicine, and nursing, and other health professional training programs for the training of health care professionals to improve the provision of prenatal care, labor care, birthing, and postpartum care for racial and ethnic minority populations, including with respect to perceptions and biases that may affect the approach to, and provision of, care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility To be eligible for a grant under subsection (a), an entity described in such subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294p_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294p_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Best practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Best practices The Secretary may identify and disseminate best practices for the training described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294p_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>