<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294q" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294q/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294q/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294q"><akn:num>294q</akn:num><akn:heading>National Health Care Workforce Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294q. National Health Care Workforce Commission(a) PurposeIt is the purpose of this section to establish a National Health Care Workforce Commission that—(1) serves as a national resource for Congress, the President, States, and localities;

(2) communicates and coordinates with the Departments of Health and Human Services, Labor, Veterans Affairs, Homeland Security, and Education on related activities administered by one or more of such Departments;

(3) develops and commissions evaluations of education and training activities to determine whether the demand for health care workers is being met;

(4) identifies barriers to improved coordination at the Federal, State, and local levels and recommend ways to address such barriers; and

(5) encourages innovations to address population needs, constant changes in technology, and other environmental factors.


(b) EstablishmentThere is hereby established the National Health Care Workforce Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).


(c) Membership(1) Number and appointmentThe Commission shall be composed of 15 members to be appointed by the Comptroller General, without regard to section 1004 of title 5.


(2) Qualifications(A) In generalThe membership of the Commission shall include individuals—(i) with national recognition for their expertise in health care labor market analysis, including health care workforce analysis; health care finance and economics; health care facility management; health care plans and integrated delivery systems; health care workforce education and training; health care philanthropy; providers of health care services; and other related fields; and

(ii) who will provide a combination of professional perspectives, broad geographic representation, and a balance between urban, suburban, rural, and frontier representatives.


(B) Inclusion(i) In generalThe membership of the Commission shall include no less than one representative of—(I) the health care workforce and health profes</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose It is the purpose of this section to establish a National Health Care Workforce Commission that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment There is hereby established the National Health Care Workforce Commission (in this section referred to as the “Commission”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with Federal, State, and local agencies, Congress, and other organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultation with Federal, State, and local agencies, Congress, and other organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director and staff; experts and consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Director and staff; experts and consultants Subject to such review as the Comptroller General of the United States determines to be necessary to ensure the efficient administration of the Commission, the Commission may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Powers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294q_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>