<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294r" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294r/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294r/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294r"><akn:num>294r</akn:num><akn:heading>State health care workforce development grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294r. State health care workforce development grants(a) EstablishmentThere is established a competitive health care workforce development grant program (referred to in this section as the “program”) for the purpose of enabling State partnerships to complete comprehensive planning and to carry out activities leading to coherent and comprehensive health care workforce development strategies at the State and local levels.


(b) Fiscal and administrative agentThe Health Resources and Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Administration”) shall be the fiscal and administrative agent for the grants awarded under this section. The Administration is authorized to carry out the program, in consultation with the National Health Care Workforce Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”), which shall review reports on the development, implementation, and evaluation activities of the grant program, including—(1) administering the grants;

(2) providing technical assistance to grantees; and

(3) reporting performance information to the Commission.


(c) Planning grants(1) Amount and durationA planning grant shall be awarded under this subsection for a period of not more than one year and the maximum award may not be more than $150,000.


(2) EligibilityTo be eligible to receive a planning grant, an entity shall be an eligible partnership. An eligible partnership shall be a State workforce investment board, if it includes or modifies the members to include at least one representative from each of the following: health care employer, labor organization, a public 2-year institution of higher education, a public 4-year institution of higher education, the recognized State federation of labor, the State public secondary education agency, the State P–16 or P–20 Council if such a council exists, and a philanthropic organization that is actively engaged in providing learning, mentoring, and work oppo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294r_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a competitive health care workforce development grant program (referred to in this section as the “program”) for the purpose of enabling State partnerships to complete comprehensive planning and to carry out activities leading to coherent and comprehensive health care workforce development strategies at the State and local levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294r_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal and administrative agent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fiscal and administrative agent The Health Resources and Services Administration of the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Administration”) shall be the fiscal and administrative agent for the grants awarded under this section. The Administration is authorized to carry out the program, in consultation with the National Health Care Workforce Commission (referred to in this section as the “Commission”), which shall review reports on the development, implementation, and evaluation activities of the grant program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294r_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Planning grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Planning grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294r_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Implementation grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294r_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization for appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>