<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/294t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_294t"><akn:num>294t</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs to promote mental health among the health professional workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 294t. Programs to promote mental health among the health professional workforce(a) Programs to promote mental health among health care professionals(1) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants or contracts to health care entities, including entities that provide health care services, such as hospitals, community health centers, and rural health clinics, or to medical professional associations, to establish or enhance evidence-based or evidence-informed programs dedicated to improving mental health and resiliency for health care professionals.


(2) Use of fundsAn eligible entity receiving a grant or contract under this subsection shall use funds received through the grant or contract to implement a new program or enhance an existing program to promote mental health among health care professionals, which may include—(A) improving awareness among health care professionals about risk factors for, and signs of, suicide and mental health or substance use disorders, in accordance with evidence-based or evidence-informed practices;

(B) establishing new, or enhancing existing, evidence-based or evidence-informed programs for preventing suicide and improving mental health and resiliency among health care professionals;

(C) establishing new, or enhancing existing, peer-support programs among health care professionals; or

(D) providing mental health care, follow-up services and care, or referral for such services and care, as appropriate.


(3) PriorityIn awarding grants and contracts under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities in health professional shortage areas or rural areas.



(b) Training grantsThe Secretary may establish a program to award grants to health professions schools, academic health centers, State or local governments, Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations, or other appropriate public or private nonprofit entities (or consortia of entities, including entities promoting multidisciplinary approaches) to support the trai</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs to promote mental health among health care professionals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Programs to promote mental health among health care professionals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Training grants The Secretary may establish a program to award grants to health professions schools, academic health centers, State or local governments, Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations, or other appropriate public or private nonprofit entities (or consortia of entities, including entities promoting multidisciplinary approaches) to support the training of health care students, residents, or health care professionals in evidence-based or evidence-informed strategies to address mental and substance use disorders and improve mental health and resiliency among health care professionals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grant terms A grant or contract awarded under subsection (a) or (b) shall be for a period of 3 years.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application submission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application submission An entity seeking a grant or contract under subsection (a) or (b) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reporting An entity awarded a grant or contract under subsection (a) or (b) shall periodically submit to the Secretary a report evaluating the activities supported by the grant or contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_294t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations To carry out this section and section 5 of the Dr. Lorna Breen Health Care Provider Protection Act, there are authorized to be appropriated $35,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2024.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>