<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295f_3"><akn:num>295f–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Fellowship training in applied public health epidemiology, public health laboratory science, public </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295f–3. Fellowship training in applied public health epidemiology, public health laboratory science, public health informatics, and expansion of the Epidemic Intelligence Service(a) In generalThe Secretary may carry out activities to address documented workforce shortages in State and local health departments in the critical areas of applied public health epidemiology and public health laboratory science and informatics and may expand the Epidemic Intelligence Service.


(b) Specific usesIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide for the expansion of existing fellowship programs operated through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in a manner that is designed to alleviate shortages of the type described in subsection (a).


(c) Other programsThe Secretary may provide for the expansion of other applied epidemiology training programs that meet objectives similar to the objectives of the programs described in subsection (b).


(d) Work obligationParticipation in fellowship training programs under this section shall be deemed to be service for purposes of satisfying work obligations stipulated in contracts under section 254q–1(j) of this title.


(e) General supportAmounts may be used from grants awarded under this section to expand the Public Health Informatics Fellowship Program at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to better support all public health systems at all levels of government.


(f) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $39,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2013, of which—(1) $5,000,000 shall be made available in each such fiscal year for epidemiology fellowship training program activities under subsections (b) and (c);

(2) $5,000,000 shall be made available in each such fiscal year for laboratory fellowship training programs under subsection (b);

(3) $5,000,000 shall be made available in each such fiscal year for the Public Health Informatics </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may carry out activities to address documented workforce shortages in State and local health departments in the critical areas of applied public health epidemiology and public health laboratory science and informatics and may expand the Epidemic Intelligence Service.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specific uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specific uses In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall provide for the expansion of existing fellowship programs operated through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in a manner that is designed to alleviate shortages of the type described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other programs The Secretary may provide for the expansion of other applied epidemiology training programs that meet objectives similar to the objectives of the programs described in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Work obligation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Work obligation Participation in fellowship training programs under this section shall be deemed to be service for purposes of satisfying work obligations stipulated in contracts under section 254q–1(j) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>General support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) General support Amounts may be used from grants awarded under this section to expand the Public Health Informatics Fellowship Program at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to better support all public health systems at all levels of government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $39,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2013, of which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>