<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295f–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295f_2"><akn:num>295f–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Training for mid-career public and allied health professionals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295f–2. Training for mid-career public and allied health professionals(a) In generalThe Secretary may make grants to, or enter into contracts with, any eligible entity to award scholarships to eligible individuals to enroll in degree or professional training programs for the purpose of enabling mid-career professionals in the public health and allied health workforce to receive additional training in the field of public health and allied health.


(b) Eligibility(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” indicates an accredited educational institution that offers a course of study, certificate program, or professional training program in public or allied health or a related discipline, as determined by the Secretary 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.


(2) Eligible individualsThe term “eligible individuals” includes those individuals employed in public and allied health positions at the Federal, State, tribal, or local level who are interested in retaining or upgrading their education.



(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2010 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015. Fifty percent of appropriated funds shall be allotted to public health mid-career professionals and 50 percent shall be allotted to allied health mid-career professionals.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VII, § 777, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title V, § 5206(b), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 612.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 295f–2, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VII, § 772, formerly § 775, as added Nov. 18, 1971, Pub. L. 92–157, title I, § 104(a), 85 Stat. 448; renumbered § 772 and amended Oct. 12, 1976, Pub. L. 94–484, title V, § 503(a), 90 Stat. 2300; Dec. 19, 1977, Pub. L. 95–215, §§ 1(b), 8(c), 91 Stat. 1504, 1507; Nov. 9, 1978, Pub. L. 95–623, § 12(j), 92 Stat. 3457; Oct. 22, 1985, Pub. L. 99–129, title II, § 211(c), 99 S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make grants to, or enter into contracts with, any eligible entity to award scholarships to eligible individuals to enroll in degree or professional training programs for the purpose of enabling mid-career professionals in the public health and allied health workforce to receive additional training in the field of public health and allied health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295f_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $60,000,000 for fiscal year 2010 and such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2011 through 2015. Fifty percent of appropriated funds shall be allotted to public health mid-career professionals and 50 percent shall be allotted to allied health mid-career professionals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>