<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295h"><akn:num>295h</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan repayment program for substance use disorder treatment workforce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295h. Loan repayment program for substance use disorder treatment workforce(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall carry out a program under which—(1) the Secretary enters into agreements with individuals to make payments in accordance with subsection (b) on the principal of and interest on any eligible loan; and

(2) the individuals each agree to the requirements of service in substance use disorder treatment employment, as described in subsection (d).


(b) PaymentsFor each year of obligated service by an individual pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make a payment to such individual as follows:(1) Service in a shortage areaThe Secretary shall pay—(A) for each year of obligated service by an individual pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a), ⅙ of the principal of and interest on each eligible loan of the individual which is outstanding on the date the individual began service pursuant to the agreement; and

(B) for completion of the sixth and final year of such service, the remainder of such principal and interest.


(2) Maximum amountThe total amount of payments under this section to any individual shall not exceed $250,000.



(c) Eligible loansThe loans eligible for repayment under this section are each of the following:(1) Any loan for education or training for a substance use disorder treatment employment.

(2) Any loan under part E of subchapter VI (relating to nursing student loans).

(3) Any Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan, or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan (as such terms are used in section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 [20 U.S.C. 1087e]).

(4) Any Federal Perkins Loan under part E of title I 11 So in original. Probably should be “part E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965”. of the Higher Education Act of 1965.

(5) Any other Federal loan as dete</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall carry out a program under which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Payments For each year of obligated service by an individual pursuant to an agreement under subsection (a), the Secretary shall make a payment to such individual as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible loans The loans eligible for repayment under this section are each of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Requirements of service Any individual receiving payments under this program as required by an agreement under subsection (a) shall agree to an annual commitment to full-time employment, with no more than 1 year passing between any 2 years of covered employment, in substance use disorder treatment employment in the United States in—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ineligibility for double benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Ineligibility for double benefits No borrower may, for the same service, receive a reduction of loan obligations or a loan repayment under both—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Breach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional criteria The Secretary—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report to Congress Not later than 5 years after October 24, 2018, and every other year thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definition In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295h_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $40,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2030.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>