<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295n–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295n–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295n–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295n_2"><akn:num>295n–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295n–2. Use of funds(a) In generalAmounts provided under a grant or contract awarded under this subchapter may be used for training program development and support, faculty development, model demonstrations, trainee support including tuition, books, program fees and reasonable living expenses during the period of training, technical assistance, workforce analysis, dissemination of information, and exploring new policy directions, as appropriate to meet recognized health workforce objectives, in accordance with this subchapter.


(b) Maintenance of effortWith respect to activities for which a grant awarded under this subchapter is to be expended, the entity shall agree to maintain expenditures of non-Federal amounts for such activities at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the entity for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the entity receives such a grant.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VII, § 797, as added Pub. L. 105–392, title I, § 106(a)(2)(F), Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3557.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295n_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Amounts provided under a grant or contract awarded under this subchapter may be used for training program development and support, faculty development, model demonstrations, trainee support including tuition, books, program fees and reasonable living expenses during the period of training, technical assistance, workforce analysis, dissemination of information, and exploring new policy directions, as appropriate to meet recognized health workforce objectives, in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295n_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance of effort With respect to activities for which a grant awarded under this subchapter is to be expended, the entity shall agree to maintain expenditures of non-Federal amounts for such activities at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the entity for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the entity receives such a grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>