<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295o–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295o–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/295o–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_295o_1"><akn:num>295o–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Generally applicable provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 295o–1. Generally applicable provisions(a) Awarding of grants and contractsThe Secretary shall ensure that grants and contracts under this subchapter are awarded on a competitive basis, as appropriate, to carry out innovative demonstration projects or provide for strategic workforce supplementation activities as needed to meet health workforce goals and in accordance with this subchapter. Contracts may be entered into under this subchapter with public or private entities as may be necessary.


(b) Eligible entitiesUnless specifically required otherwise in this subchapter, the Secretary shall accept applications for grants or contracts under this subchapter from health professions schools, academic health centers, State or local governments, or other appropriate public or private nonprofit entities for funding and participation in health professions and nursing training activities. The Secretary may accept applications from for-profit private entities if determined appropriate by the Secretary.


(c) Information requirements(1) In generalRecipients of grants and contracts under this subchapter shall meet information requirements as specified by the Secretary.


(2) Data collectionThe Secretary shall establish procedures to ensure that, with respect to any data collection required under this subchapter, such data is collected in a manner that takes into account age, sex, race, and ethnicity.


(3) Use of fundsThe Secretary shall establish procedures to permit the use of amounts appropriated under this subchapter to be used for data collection purposes.


(4) EvaluationsThe Secretary shall establish procedures to ensure the annual evaluation of programs and projects operated by recipients of grants or contracts under this subchapter. Such procedures shall ensure that continued funding for such programs and projects will be conditioned upon a demonstration that satisfactory progress has been made by the program or project in meeting the objectives of the program or pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awarding of grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Awarding of grants and contracts The Secretary shall ensure that grants and contracts under this subchapter are awarded on a competitive basis, as appropriate, to carry out innovative demonstration projects or provide for strategic workforce supplementation activities as needed to meet health workforce goals and in accordance with this subchapter. Contracts may be entered into under this subchapter with public or private entities as may be necessary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entities Unless specifically required otherwise in this subchapter, the Secretary shall accept applications for grants or contracts under this subchapter from health professions schools, academic health centers, State or local governments, or other appropriate public or private nonprofit entities for funding and participation in health professions and nursing training activities. The Secretary may accept applications from for-profit private entities if determined appropriate by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Training programs Training programs conducted with amounts received under this subchapter shall meet applicable accreditation and quality standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Duration of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review regarding certain programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Peer review regarding certain programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference or priority considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Preference or priority considerations In considering a preference or priority for funding which is based on outcome measures for an eligible entity under this subchapter, the Secretary may also consider the future ability of the eligible entity to meet the outcome preference or priority through improvements in the eligible entity’s program design.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Analytic activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Analytic activities The Secretary shall ensure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_295o_1_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Osteopathic Schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Osteopathic Schools For purposes of this subchapter, any reference to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>