<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_296"><akn:num>296</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 296. Definitions
As used in this subchapter:(1) Eligible entitiesThe term “eligible entities” means schools of nursing, nursing centers, academic health centers, State or local governments, and other public or private nonprofit entities determined appropriate by the Secretary that submit to the Secretary an application in accordance with section 296a of this title.


(2) School of nursingThe term “school of nursing” means an accredited (as defined in paragraph 6) collegiate, associate degree, or diploma school of nursing in a State where graduates are—(A) authorized to sit for the National Council Licensure EXamination-Registered Nurse (NCLEX–RN); or

(B) licensed registered nurses who will receive a graduate or equivalent degree or training to become an advanced education nurse as defined by section 296j(b) of this title.


(3) Collegiate school of nursingThe term “collegiate school of nursing” means a department, division, or other administrative unit in a college or university which provides primarily or exclusively a program of education in professional nursing and related subjects leading to the degree of bachelor of arts, bachelor of science, bachelor of nursing, or to an equivalent degree, or to a graduate degree in nursing, or to an equivalent degree, and including advanced training related to such program of education provided by such school, but only if such program, or such unit, college or university is accredited.


(4) Associate degree school of nursingThe term “associate degree school of nursing” means a department, division, or other administrative unit in a junior college, community college, college, or university which provides primarily or exclusively a two-year program of education in professional nursing and allied subjects leading to an associate degree in nursing or to an equivalent degree, but only if such program, or such unit, college, or university is accredited.


(5) Diploma school of nursingThe term “diploma school of nursing” means a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Eligible entities The term “eligible entities” means schools of nursing, nursing centers, academic health centers, State or local governments, and other public or private nonprofit entities determined appropriate by the Secretary that submit to the Secretary an application in accordance with section 296a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>School of nursing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) School of nursing The term “school of nursing” means an accredited (as defined in paragraph 6) collegiate, associate degree, or diploma school of nursing in a State where graduates are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collegiate school of nursing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Collegiate school of nursing The term “collegiate school of nursing” means a department, division, or other administrative unit in a college or university which provides primarily or exclusively a program of education in professional nursing and related subjects leading to the degree of bachelor of arts, bachelor of science, bachelor of nursing, or to an equivalent degree, or to a graduate degree in nursing, or to an equivalent degree, and including advanced training related to such program of education provided by such school, but only if such program, or such unit, college or university is accredited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Associate degree school of nursing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Associate degree school of nursing The term “associate degree school of nursing” means a department, division, or other administrative unit in a junior college, community college, college, or university which provides primarily or exclusively a two-year program of education in professional nursing and allied subjects leading to an associate degree in nursing or to an equivalent degree, but only if such program, or such unit, college, or university is accredited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Diploma school of nursing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Diploma school of nursing The term “diploma school of nursing” means a school affiliated with a hospital or university, or an independent school, which provides primarily or exclusively a program of education in professional nursing and allied subjects leading to a diploma or to equivalent indicia that such program has been satisfactorily completed, but only if such program, or such affiliated school or such hospital or university or such independent school is accredited.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accredited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Accredited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonprofit</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Nonprofit The term “nonprofit” as applied to any school, agency, organization, or institution means one which is a corporation or association, or is owned and operated by one or more corporations or associations, no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) State The term “State” means a State, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, or the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ambulatory surgical center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Ambulatory surgical center The term “ambulatory surgical center” has the meaning applicable to such term under title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally qualified health center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Federally qualified health center The term “Federally qualified health center” has the meaning given such term under section 1861(aa)(4) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395x(aa)(4)].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>