<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_296b"><akn:num>296b</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 296b. Use of funds(a) In generalAmounts provided under a grant or contract awarded under this subchapter may be used for training program development and support, faculty development, model demonstrations, trainee support including tuition, books, program fees and reasonable living expenses during the period of training, technical assistance, workforce analysis, and dissemination of information, as appropriate to meet recognized nursing objectives, in accordance with this subchapter.


(b) Maintenance of effortWith respect to activities for which a grant awarded under this subchapter is to be expended, the entity shall agree to maintain expenditures of non-Federal amounts for such activities at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the entity for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the entity receives such a grant. Such Federal funds are intended to supplement, not supplant, existing non-Federal expenditures for such activities.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VIII, § 803, as added Pub. L. 105–392, title I, § 123(4), Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3564; amended Pub. L. 116–136, div. A, title III, § 3404(a)(3), Mar. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 392.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 296b, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VIII, § 803, as added Sept. 4, 1964, Pub. L. 88–581, § 2, 78 Stat. 911; amended Aug. 16, 1968, Pub. L. 90–490, title II, § 202, 82 Stat. 780; Nov. 18, 1971, Pub. L. 92–158, §§ 2(b), 13, 85 Stat. 465, 480; July 29, 1975, Pub. L. 94–63, title IX, § 941(b), 89 Stat. 364, set forth provisions relating to amount of construction grant, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 99–92, §§ 9(a)(1), 10(a), Aug. 16, 1985, 99 Stat. 400, 402, effective Oct. 1, 1985.

Amendments2020—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 116–136 inserted at end “Such Federal funds are intended to supplement, not supplant, existing non-Federal expenditures for such activities.”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Amounts provided under a grant or contract awarded under this subchapter may be used for training program development and support, faculty development, model demonstrations, trainee support including tuition, books, program fees and reasonable living expenses during the period of training, technical assistance, workforce analysis, and dissemination of information, as appropriate to meet recognized nursing objectives, in accordance with this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Maintenance of effort With respect to activities for which a grant awarded under this subchapter is to be expended, the entity shall agree to maintain expenditures of non-Federal amounts for such activities at a level that is not less than the level of such expenditures maintained by the entity for the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year for which the entity receives such a grant. Such Federal funds are intended to supplement, not supplant, existing non-Federal expenditures for such activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>