<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296e–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296e–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296e–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_296e_1"><akn:num>296e–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for health professions education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 296e–1. Grants for health professions education(a) Cultural competency, prevention, and public health and individuals with disability grantsThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may make awards of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the development, evaluation, and dissemination of research, demonstration projects, and model curricula for cultural competency, prevention, public health proficiency, reducing health disparities, and aptitude for working with individuals with disabilities training for use in health professions schools and continuing education programs, and for other purposes determined as appropriate by the Secretary. Grants under this section shall be the same as provided in section 293e of this title.


(b) CollaborationIn carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall collaborate with the entities described in section 293e(b) of this title. The Secretary shall coordinate with curricula and research and demonstration projects developed under such section 293e.


(c) DisseminationModel curricula developed under this section shall be disseminated and evaluated in the same manner as model curricula developed under section 293e of this title, as described in subsection (c) of such section.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsThere are to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2015.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VIII, § 807, as added Pub. L. 106–525, title IV, § 401(b)(2), Nov. 22, 2000, 114 Stat. 2508; amended Pub. L. 111–148, title V, § 5307(b), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 628.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 807 of act July 1, 1944, was renumbered section 808 by Pub. L. 106–525 and is classified to section 296f of this title.
Another prior section 807 of act July 1, 1944, was renumbered section 811 and classified to section 296f of this title prior to repeal by P</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296e_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cultural competency, prevention, and public health and individuals with disability grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cultural competency, prevention, and public health and individuals with disability grants The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, may make awards of grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the development, evaluation, and dissemination of research, demonstration projects, and model curricula for cultural competency, prevention, public health proficiency, reducing health disparities, and aptitude for working with individuals with disabilities training for use in health professions schools and continuing education programs, and for other purposes determined as appropriate by the Secretary. Grants under this section shall be the same as provided in section 293e of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296e_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collaboration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Collaboration In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall collaborate with the entities described in section 293e(b) of this title. The Secretary shall coordinate with curricula and research and demonstration projects developed under such section 293e.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296e_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination Model curricula developed under this section shall be disseminated and evaluated in the same manner as model curricula developed under section 293e of this title, as described in subsection (c) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296e_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations There are to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2010 through 2015.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>