<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/296j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_296j"><akn:num>296j</akn:num><akn:heading>Advanced education nursing grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 296j. Advanced education nursing grants(a) In generalThe Secretary may award grants to and enter into contracts with eligible entities to meet the costs of—(1) projects that support the enhancement of advanced nursing education and practice; and

(2) traineeships for individuals in advanced nursing education programs.


(b) Definition of advanced education nursesFor purposes of this section, the term “advanced education nurses” means individuals trained in advanced degree programs including individuals in combined R.N./graduate degree programs, post-nursing master’s certificate programs, or, in the case of nurse midwives, in certificate programs in existence on the date that is one day prior to November 13, 1998, to serve as nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists, nurse midwives, nurse anesthetists, nurse educators, nurse administrators, clinical nurse leaders, or public health nurses, or in other nurse specialties determined by the Secretary to require advanced education.


(c) Authorized nurse practitionerNurse practitioner programs eligible for support under this section are educational programs for registered nurses (irrespective of the type of school of nursing in which the nurses received their training) that—(1) meet guidelines prescribed by the Secretary; and

(2) have as their objective the education of nurses who will upon completion of their studies in such programs, be qualified to effectively provide primary health care, including primary health care in homes and in ambulatory care facilities, long-term care facilities, acute care, and other health care settings.


(d) Authorized nurse-midwifery programsMidwifery programs that are eligible for support under this section are educational programs that—(1) have as their objective the education of midwives; and

(2) are accredited by the American College of Nurse-Midwives Accreditation Commission for Midwifery Education.


(e) Authorized nurse anesthesia programsNurse anesthesia programs eligible</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may award grants to and enter into contracts with eligible entities to meet the costs of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of advanced education nurses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definition of advanced education nurses For purposes of this section, the term “advanced education nurses” means individuals trained in advanced degree programs including individuals in combined R.N./graduate degree programs, post-nursing master’s certificate programs, or, in the case of nurse midwives, in certificate programs in existence on the date that is one day prior to November 13, 1998, to serve as nurse practitioners, clinical nurse specialists, nurse midwives, nurse anesthetists, nurse educators, nurse administrators, clinical nurse leaders, or public health nurses, or in other nurse specialties determined by the Secretary to require advanced education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized nurse practitioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorized nurse practitioner Nurse practitioner programs eligible for support under this section are educational programs for registered nurses (irrespective of the type of school of nursing in which the nurses received their training) that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized nurse-midwifery programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorized nurse-midwifery programs Midwifery programs that are eligible for support under this section are educational programs that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized nurse anesthesia programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorized nurse anesthesia programs Nurse anesthesia programs eligible for support under this section are education programs that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorized clinical nurse specialist programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorized clinical nurse specialist programs Clinical nurse specialist programs eligible for support under this section are education programs that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other authorized educational programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Other authorized educational programs The Secretary shall prescribe guidelines as appropriate for other advanced nurse education programs eligible for support under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_296j_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Traineeships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Traineeships</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>