<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_297b"><akn:num>297b</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 297b. Loan provisions(a) Maximum amount per individual per year; preference to first year studentsThe total of the loans for any academic year (or its equivalent, as determined under regulations of the Secretary) made by schools of nursing from loan funds established pursuant to agreements under this part may not exceed $3,300 in the case of any student, except that for the final two academic years of the program involved, such total may not exceed $5,200. The aggregate of the loans for all years from such funds may not exceed $17,000 in the case of any student during fiscal years 2010 and 2011. After fiscal year 2011, such amounts shall be adjusted to provide for a cost-of-attendance increase for the yearly loan rate and the aggregate of the loans. In the granting of such loans, a school shall give preference to licensed practical nurses, to persons with exceptional financial need, and to persons who enter as first-year students after enactment of this subchapter.


(b) Terms and conditionsLoans from any such student loan fund by any school shall be made on such terms and conditions as the school may determine; subject, however, to such conditions, limitations, and requirements as the Secretary may prescribe (by regulation or in the agreement with the school) with a view to preventing impairment of the capital of such fund to the maximum extent practicable in the light of the objective of enabling the student to complete his course of study; and except that—(1) such a loan may be made only to a student who (A) is in need of the amount of the loan to pursue a full-time or half-time course of study at the school leading to a baccalaureate or associate degree in nursing or an equivalent degree, or a diploma in nursing, or a graduate degree in nursing, (B) is capable, in the opinion of the school, of maintaining good standing in such course of study, and (C) with respect to any student enrolling in the school after June 30, 2000, is of financial need (as defined in r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum amount per individual per year; preference to first year students</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Maximum amount per individual per year; preference to first year students The total of the loans for any academic year (or its equivalent, as determined under regulations of the Secretary) made by schools of nursing from loan funds established pursuant to agreements under this part may not exceed $3,300 in the case of any student, except that for the final two academic years of the program involved, such total may not exceed $5,200. The aggregate of the loans for all years from such funds may not exceed $17,000 in the case of any student during fiscal years 2010 and 2011. After fiscal year 2011, such amounts shall be adjusted to provide for a cost-of-attendance increase for the yearly loan rate and the aggregate of the loans. In the granting of such loans, a school shall give preference to licensed practical nurses, to persons with exceptional financial need, and to persons who enter as first-year students after enactment of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Terms and conditions Loans from any such student loan fund by any school shall be made on such terms and conditions as the school may determine; subject, however, to such conditions, limitations, and requirements as the Secretary may prescribe (by regulation or in the agreement with the school) with a view to preventing impairment of the capital of such fund to the maximum extent practicable in the light of the objective of enabling the student to complete his course of study; and except that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cancellation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Cancellation Where all or any part of a loan, or interest, is canceled under this section, the Secretary shall pay to the school an amount equal to the school’s proportionate share of the canceled portion, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Installments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Installments Any loan for any year by a school from a student loan fund established pursuant to an agreement under this part shall be made in such installments as may be provided in regulations of the Secretary or such agreement and, upon notice to the Secretary by the school that any recipient of a loan is failing to maintain satisfactory standing, any or all further installments of his loan shall be withheld, as may be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability to eligible students in need</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability to eligible students in need An agreement under this part with any school shall include provisions designed to make loans from the student loan fund established thereunder reasonably available (to the extent of the available funds in such fund) to all eligible students in the school in need thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalty for late payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Penalty for late payment Subject to regulations of the Secretary and in accordance with this section, a school shall assess a charge with respect to a loan from the loan fund established pursuant to an agreement under this part for failure of the borrower to pay all or any part of an installment when it is due and, in the case of a borrower who is entitled to deferment of the loan under subsection (b)(2) or cancellation of part or all of the loan under subsection (b)(3), for any failure to file timely and satisfactory evidence of such entitlement. No such charge may be made if the payment of such installment or the filing of such evidence is made within 60 days after the date on which such installment or filing is due. The amount of any such charge may not exceed an amount equal to 6 percent of the amount of such installment. The school may elect to add the amount of any such charge to the principal amount of the loan as of the first day after the day on which such installment or e</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum monthly repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Minimum monthly repayment A school may provide in accordance with regulations of the Secretary, that during the repayment period of a loan from a loan fund established pursuant to an agreement under this part payments of principal and interest by the borrower with respect to all the outstanding loans made to him from loan funds so established shall be at a rate equal to not less than $40 per month.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan cancellation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Loan cancellation Notwithstanding the amendment made by section 6(b) of the Nurse Training Act of 1971 to this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Loan repayment Upon application by a person who received, and is under an obligation to repay, any loan made to such person as a nursing student, the Secretary may undertake to repay (without liability to the applicant) all or any part of such loan, and any interest or portion thereof outstanding thereon, upon his determination, pursuant to regulations establishing criteria therefor, that the applicant—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297b_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection by Secretary of loan in default; preconditions and procedures applicable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Collection by Secretary of loan in default; preconditions and procedures applicable The Secretary is authorized to attempt to collect any loan which was made under this part, which is in default, and which was referred to the Secretary by a school of nursing with which the Secretary has an agreement under this part, on behalf of that school under such terms and conditions as the Secretary may prescribe (including reimbursement from the school’s student loan fund for expenses the Secretary may reasonably incur in attempting collection), but only if the school has complied with such requirements as the Secretary may specify by regulation with respect to the collection of loans under this part. A loan so referred shall be treated as a debt subject to section 5514 of title 5. Amounts collected shall be deposited in the school’s student loan fund. Whenever the Secretary desires the institution of a civil action regarding any such loan, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorne</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>