<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_297n"><akn:num>297n</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan repayment and scholarship programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 297n. Loan repayment and scholarship programs(a) In generalIn the case of any individual—(1) who has received a baccalaureate or associate degree in nursing (or an equivalent degree), a diploma in nursing, or a graduate degree in nursing;

(2) who obtained (A) one or more loans from a loan fund established under subpart II,11 See References in Text note below. or (B) any other educational loan for nurse training costs; and

(3) who enters into an agreement with the Secretary to serve as nurse for a period of not less than two years at a health care facility with a critical shortage of nurses, or in a 22 So in original. Probably should be “an”. accredited school of nursing, as defined by section 296(2) of this title, as nurse faculty;


the Secretary shall make payments in accordance with subsection (b), for and on behalf of that individual, on the principal of and interest on any loan of that individual described in paragraph (2) of this subsection which is outstanding on the date the individual begins the service specified in the agreement described in paragraph (3) of this subsection.

(b) Manner of paymentsThe payments described in subsection (a) shall be made by the Secretary as follows:(1) Upon completion by the individual for whom the payments are to be made of the first year of the service specified in the agreement entered into with the Secretary under subsection (a), the Secretary shall pay 30 percent of the principal of, and the interest on each loan of such individual described in subsection (a)(2) which is outstanding on the date the individual began such practice.

(2) Upon completion by that individual of the second year of such service, the Secretary shall pay another 30 percent of the principal of, and the interest on each such loan.

(3) Upon completion by that individual of a third year of such service, the Secretary shall pay another 25 percent of the principal of, and the interest on each such loan.


(c) Payment by due dateNotwithstanding the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of any individual— the Secretary shall make payments in accordance with subsection (b), for and on behalf of that individual, on the principal of and interest on any loan of that individual described in paragraph (2) of this subsection which is outstanding on the date the individual begins the service specified in the agreement described in paragraph (3) of this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Manner of payments The payments described in subsection (a) shall be made by the Secretary as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment by due date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Payment by due date Notwithstanding the requirement of completion of practice specified in subsection (b), the Secretary shall, on or before the due date thereof, pay any loan or loan installment which may fall due within the period of service for which the borrower may receive payments under this subsection, upon the declaration of such borrower, at such times and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe (and supported by such other evidence as the Secretary may reasonably require), that the borrower is then serving as described by subsection (a)(3), and that the borrower will continue to so serve for the period required (in the absence of this subsection) to entitle the borrower to have made the payments provided by this subsection for such period; except that not more than 85 percent of the principal of any such loan shall be paid pursuant to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scholarship program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Scholarship program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferences regarding participants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Preferences regarding participants In entering into agreements under subsection (a) or (d), the Secretary shall give preference to qualified applicants with the greatest financial need.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Condition of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Condition of agreement The Secretary may make payments under subsection (a) on behalf of an individual only if the agreement under such subsection provides that section 298b–7(c) 1 of this title is applicable to the individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Breach of agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Breach of agreement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports Not later than 18 months after August 1, 2002, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Congress a report describing the programs carried out under this section, including statements regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297n_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Allocations Of the amounts appropriated under section 298d(b) of this title,,33 So in original. the Secretary may, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, allocate amounts between the program under subsection (a) and the program under subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>