<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297t" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297t/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/297t/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_297t"><akn:num>297t</akn:num><akn:heading>National Advisory Council on Nurse Education and Practice</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 297t. National Advisory Council on Nurse Education and Practice(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the National Advisory Council on Nurse Education and Practice (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Council”).


(b) Composition(1) In generalThe Advisory Council shall be composed of—(A) not less than 21, nor more than 23 individuals, who are not officers or employees of the Federal Government, appointed by the Secretary without regard to the Federal civil service laws, of which—(i) 2 shall be selected from full-time students enrolled in schools of nursing;

(ii) 2 shall be selected from the general public;

(iii) 2 shall be selected from practicing professional nurses; and

(iv) 9 shall be selected from among the leading authorities in the various fields of nursing, higher, secondary education, and associate degree schools of nursing, and from representatives of advanced education nursing groups (such as nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, nurse anesthetists, and clinical nurse specialists), hospitals, and other institutions and organizations which provide nursing services; and


(B) the Secretary (or the delegate of the Secretary (who shall be an ex officio member and shall serve as the Chairperson)).


(2) AppointmentNot later than 90 days after November 13, 1998, the Secretary shall appoint the members of the Advisory Council and each such member shall serve a 4 year term. In making such appointments, the Secretary shall ensure a fair balance between the nursing professions, a broad geographic representation of members and a balance between urban and rural members. Members shall be appointed based on their competence, interest, and knowledge of the mission of the profession involved. A majority of the members shall be nurses.


(3) Minority representationIn appointing the members of the Advisory Council under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall ensure the adequate representation of minorities.



(c) Vacancie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the National Advisory Council on Nurse Education and Practice (in this section referred to as the “Advisory Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Vacancies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties The Advisory Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings and documents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings and documents</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Compensation and expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Funding Amounts appropriated for carrying out parts B, C, and D may be utilized by the Secretary to support the nurse education and practice activities of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_297t_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5 shall apply to the Advisory Committee under this section only to the extent that the provisions of chapter 10 of title 5 do not conflict with the requirements of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>