<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/298" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/298/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/298/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_298"><akn:num>298</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive geriatric education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 298. Comprehensive geriatric education(a) Program authorizedThe Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to develop and implement, in coordination with programs under section 294c of this title, programs and initiatives to train and educate individuals in providing geriatric care for the elderly.


(b) Use of fundsAn eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use funds under such grant to—(1) provide training to individuals who will provide geriatric care for the elderly;

(2) develop and disseminate curricula relating to the treatment of the health problems of elderly individuals;

(3) train faculty members in geriatrics;

(4) provide continuing education to individuals who provide geriatric care; or

(5) establish traineeships for individuals who are preparing for advanced education nursing degrees in geriatric nursing, long-term care, gero-psychiatric nursing or other nursing areas that specialize in the care of the elderly population.


(c) ApplicationAn eligible entity desiring a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.


(d) Eligible entityFor purposes of this section, the term “eligible entity” includes a school of nursing, a health care facility, a program leading to certification as a certified nurse assistant, a partnership of such a school and facility, or a partnership of such a program and facility.


(e) Authorization of appropriationsThere are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2014.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title VIII, § 865, formerly § 855, as added Pub. L. 107–205, title II, § 202(a), Aug. 1, 2002, 116 Stat. 816; renumbered § 865 and amended Pub. L. 111–148, title V, §§ 5305(c), 5310(b)(10)(A), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 625, 631.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 298, act July 1, 1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_298_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program authorized The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to develop and implement, in coordination with programs under section 294c of this title, programs and initiatives to train and educate individuals in providing geriatric care for the elderly.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_298_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of funds An eligible entity that receives a grant under subsection (a) shall use funds under such grant to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_298_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application An eligible entity desiring a grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_298_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible entity For purposes of this section, the term “eligible entity” includes a school of nursing, a health care facility, a program leading to certification as a certified nurse assistant, a partnership of such a school and facility, or a partnership of such a program and facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_298_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2010 through 2014.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>