<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2991f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2991f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2991f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2991f"><akn:num>2991f</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of plans to State and local officials</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2991f. Submission of plans to State and local officials(a) Submission to governing body of Indian reservation or Alaska Native villageNo financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village, unless a plan setting forth the project has been submitted to the governing body of that reservation or village and the plan has not been disapproved by the governing body within thirty days of its submission.


(b) Notification to chief executive officer of State or TerritoryNo financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out in a State or Territory other than on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village or Hawaiian Homestead, unless the Commissioner has notified the chief executive officer of the State or Territory of the decision of the Commissioner to provide that assistance.


(c) Notification to local governing officials of political subdivisionNo financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out in a city, county, or other major political subdivision of a State or Territory, other than on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village, or Hawaiian Homestead, unless the Commissioner has notified the local governing officials of the political subdivision of the decision of the Commissioner to provide that assistance.


(Pub. L. 88–452, title VIII, § 808, formerly § 807, as added Pub. L. 93–644, § 11, Jan. 4, 1975, 88 Stat. 2325; amended Pub. L. 95–568, § 17(a)(40), Nov. 2, 1978, 92 Stat. 2443; renumbered § 808 and amended Pub. L. 100–175, title V, §§ 502(3), 504(b)(3), </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2991f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission to governing body of Indian reservation or Alaska Native village</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submission to governing body of Indian reservation or Alaska Native village No financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village, unless a plan setting forth the project has been submitted to the governing body of that reservation or village and the plan has not been disapproved by the governing body within thirty days of its submission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2991f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to chief executive officer of State or Territory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification to chief executive officer of State or Territory No financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out in a State or Territory other than on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village or Hawaiian Homestead, unless the Commissioner has notified the chief executive officer of the State or Territory of the decision of the Commissioner to provide that assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2991f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to local governing officials of political subdivision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification to local governing officials of political subdivision No financial assistance may be provided to any project under section 2991b of this title or any research, demonstration, or pilot project under section 2991d of this title, which is to be carried out in a city, county, or other major political subdivision of a State or Territory, other than on or in an Indian reservation or Alaska Native village, or Hawaiian Homestead, unless the Commissioner has notified the local governing officials of the political subdivision of the decision of the Commissioner to provide that assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>