<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2996e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2996e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/2996e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_2996e"><akn:num>2996e</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers, duties, and limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 2996e. Powers, duties, and limitations(a) Powers of nonprofit corporation; additional powersTo the extent consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, the Corporation shall exercise the powers conferred upon a nonprofit corporation by the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (except for section 1005(o) of title 29 of the District of Columbia Code). In addition, the Corporation is authorized—(1)(A) to provide financial assistance to qualified programs furnishing legal assistance to eligible clients, and to make grants to and contracts with—(i) individuals, partnerships, firms, corporations, and nonprofit organizations, and

(ii) State and local governments (only upon application by an appropriate State or local agency or institution and upon a special determination by the Board that the arrangements to be made by such agency or institution will provide services which will not be provided adequately through non-governmental arrangements),


for the purpose of providing legal assistance to eligible clients under this subchapter, and (B) to make such other grants and contracts as are necessary to carry out the purposes and provisions of this subchapter;


(2) to accept in the name of the Corporation, and employ or dispose of in furtherance of the purposes of this subchapter, any money or property, real, personal, or mixed, tangible or intangible, received by gift, devise, bequest, or otherwise; and

(3) to undertake directly, or by grant or contract, the following activities relating to the delivery of legal assistance—(A) research, except that broad general legal or policy research unrelated to representation of eligible clients may not be undertaken by grant or contract,

(B) training and technical assistance, and

(C) to serve as a clearinghouse for information.



(b) Disciplinary powers; representational questions; interference with professional responsibilities of attorneys; bar membership; restrictions; languages other than English(1)(A) The Cor</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of nonprofit corporation; additional powers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Powers of nonprofit corporation; additional powers To the extent consistent with the provisions of this subchapter, the Corporation shall exercise the powers conferred upon a nonprofit corporation by the District of Columbia Nonprofit Corporation Act (except for section 1005(o) of title 29 of the District of Columbia Code). In addition, the Corporation is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disciplinary powers; representational questions; interference with professional responsibilities of attorneys; bar membership; restrictions; languages other than English</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disciplinary powers; representational questions; interference with professional responsibilities of attorneys; bar membership; restrictions; languages other than English</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation in litigation; lobbying activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participation in litigation; lobbying activities The Corporation shall not itself—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Miscellaneous prohibitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Political activities of Corporation employees and staff attorneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Political activities of Corporation employees and staff attorneys</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_2996e_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Harassment; malicious abuse of legal process</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Harassment; malicious abuse of legal process If an action is commenced by the Corporation or by a recipient and a final order is entered in favor of the defendant and against the Corporation or a recipient’s plaintiff, the court shall, upon motion by the defendant and upon a finding by the court that the action was commenced or pursued for the sole purpose of harassment of the defendant or that the Corporation or a recipient’s plaintiff maliciously abused legal process, enter an order (which shall be appealable before being made final) awarding reasonable costs and legal fees incurred by the defendant in defense of the action, except when in contravention of a State law, a rule of court, or a statute of general applicability. Any such costs and fees shall be directly paid by the Corporation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>