<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–31" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–31/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–31/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_299b_31"><akn:num>299b–31</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality measure development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 299b–31. Quality measure development(a) Quality measureIn this subpart, the term “quality measure” means a standard for measuring the performance and improvement of population health or of health plans, providers of services, and other clinicians in the delivery of health care services.


(b) Identification of quality measures(1) IdentificationThe Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall identify, not less often than triennially, gaps where no quality measures exist and existing quality measures that need improvement, updating, or expansion, consistent with the national strategy under section 280j of this title, to the extent available, for use in Federal health programs. In identifying such gaps and existing quality measures that need improvement, the Secretary shall take into consideration—(A) the gaps identified by the entity with a contract under section 1890(a) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395aaa(a)] and other stakeholders;

(B) quality measures identified by the pediatric quality measures program under section 1139A of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1320b–9a]; and

(C) quality measures identified through the Medicaid Quality Measurement Program under section 1139B of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1320b–9b].


(2) PublicationThe Secretary shall make available to the public on an Internet website a report on any gaps identified under paragraph (1) and the process used to make such identification.



(c) Grants or contracts for quality measure development(1) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants, contracts, or intergovernmental agreements to eligible entities for purposes of developing, improving, updating, or expanding quality measures identified under subsection (b).


(2) Prioritization in the development of quality measuresIn awarding grants, contracts, or agreements under this subsection, the Secretary s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality measure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Quality measure In this subpart, the term “quality measure” means a standard for measuring the performance and improvement of population health or of health plans, providers of services, and other clinicians in the delivery of health care services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of quality measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification of quality measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants or contracts for quality measure development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants or contracts for quality measure development</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other activities by the Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other activities by the Secretary The Secretary may use amounts available under this section to update and test, where applicable, quality measures endorsed by the entity with a contract under section 1890(a) of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395aaa(a)] or adopted by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination of grants The Secretary shall ensure that grants or contracts awarded under this section are coordinated with grants and contracts awarded under sections 1139A(5) 22 So in original. The subsection designation is missing. and 1139B(4)(A) 2 of the Social Security Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_31_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of outcome measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Development of outcome measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>