<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299b–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_299b_7"><akn:num>299b–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Research on outcomes of health care items and services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 299b–7. Research on outcomes of health care items and services(a) Research, demonstrations, and evaluations(1) Improvement of effectiveness and efficiency(A) In generalTo improve the quality, effectiveness, and efficiency of health care delivered pursuant to the programs established under titles XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq., 1396 et seq., 1397aa et seq.], the Secretary 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (in this section referred to as the “Director”), shall conduct and support research to meet the priorities and requests for scientific evidence and information identified by such programs with respect to—(i) the outcomes, comparative clinical effectiveness, and appropriateness of health care items and services (including prescription drugs); and

(ii) strategies for improving the efficiency and effectiveness of such programs, including the ways in which such items and services are organized, managed, and delivered under such programs.


(B) SpecificationTo respond to priorities and information requests in subparagraph (A), the Secretary may conduct or support, by grant, contract, or interagency agreement, research, demonstrations, evaluations, technology assessments, or other activities, including the provision of technical assistance, scientific expertise, or methodological assistance.



(2) Priorities(A) In generalThe Secretary shall establish a process to develop priorities that will guide the research, demonstrations, and evaluation activities undertaken pursuant to this section.


(B) Initial listNot later than 6 months after December 8, 2003, the Secretary shall establish an initial list of priorities for research related to health care items and services (including prescription drugs).


(C) ProcessIn carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary—(i) shall ensure that there is broad and ongoing consultation with rele</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, demonstrations, and evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Research, demonstrations, and evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research with respect to dissemination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Research with respect to dissemination The Secretary, acting through the Director, may conduct or support research with respect to improving methods of disseminating information in accordance with subsection (a)(3)(C).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on CMS</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation on CMS The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services may not use data obtained in accordance with this section to withhold coverage of a prescription drug.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299b_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2004, and such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>