<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_299c_5"><akn:num>299c–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain administrative authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 299c–5. Certain administrative authorities(a) Deputy director and other officers and employees(1) Deputy directorThe Director may appoint a deputy director for the Agency.


(2) Other officers and employeesThe Director may appoint and fix the compensation of such officers and employees as may be necessary to carry out this subchapter. Except as otherwise provided by law, such officers and employees shall be appointed in accordance with the civil service laws and their compensation fixed in accordance with title 5.



(b) FacilitiesThe Secretary, in carrying out this subchapter—(1) may acquire, without regard to section 8141 of title 40, by lease or otherwise through the Administrator of General Services, buildings or portions of buildings in the District of Columbia or communities located adjacent to the District of Columbia for use for a period not to exceed 10 years; and

(2) may acquire, construct, improve, repair, operate, and maintain laboratory, research, and other necessary facilities and equipment, and such other real or personal property (including patents) as the Secretary deems necessary.


(c) Provision of financial assistanceThe Director, in carrying out this subchapter, may make grants to public and nonprofit entities and individuals, and may enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with public and private entities and individuals.


(d) Utilization of certain personnel and resources(1) Department of Health and Human ServicesThe Director, in carrying out this subchapter, may utilize personnel and equipment, facilities, and other physical resources of the Department of Health and Human Services, permit appropriate (as determined by the Secretary) entities and individuals to utilize the physical resources of such Department, and provide technical assistance and advice.


(2) Other agenciesThe Director, in carrying out this subchapter, may use, with their consent, the services, equipment, personnel, information, and facilities of other Federal, St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy director and other officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deputy director and other officers and employees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Facilities The Secretary, in carrying out this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Provision of financial assistance The Director, in carrying out this subchapter, may make grants to public and nonprofit entities and individuals, and may enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with public and private entities and individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of certain personnel and resources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Utilization of certain personnel and resources</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Consultants The Secretary, in carrying out this subchapter, may secure, from time to time and for such periods as the Director deems advisable but in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, the assistance and advice of consultants from the United States or abroad.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Experts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Experts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_5_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary and uncompensated services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Voluntary and uncompensated services The Director, in carrying out this subchapter, may accept voluntary and uncompensated services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>