<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/299c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_299c"><akn:num>299c</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council for Healthcare Research and Quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 299c. Advisory Council for Healthcare Research and Quality(a) EstablishmentThere is established an advisory council to be known as the National Advisory Council for Healthcare Research and Quality.


(b) Duties(1) In generalThe Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary and the Director with respect to activities proposed or undertaken to carry out the mission of the Agency under section 299(b) of this title.


(2) Certain recommendationsActivities of the Advisory Council under paragraph (1) shall include making recommendations to the Director regarding—(A) priorities regarding health care research, especially studies related to quality, outcomes, cost and the utilization of, and access to, health care services;

(B) the field of health care research and related disciplines, especially issues related to training needs, and dissemination of information pertaining to health care quality; and

(C) the appropriate role of the Agency in each of these areas in light of private sector activity and identification of opportunities for public-private sector partnerships.



(c) Membership(1) In generalThe Advisory Council shall, in accordance with this subsection, be composed of appointed members and ex officio members. All members of the Advisory Council shall be voting members other than the individuals designated under paragraph (3)(B) as ex officio members.


(2) Appointed membersThe Secretary shall appoint to the Advisory Council 21 appropriately qualified individuals. At least 17 members of the Advisory Council shall be representatives of the public who are not officers or employees of the United States and at least 1 member who shall be a specialist in the rural aspects of 1 or more of the professions or fields described in subparagraphs (A) through (G). The Secretary shall ensure that the appointed members of the Council, as a group, are representative of professions and entities concerned with, or affected by, activities under this subchapter and under section 132</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established an advisory council to be known as the National Advisory Council for Healthcare Research and Quality.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Membership</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Vacancies If a member of the Advisory Council appointed under subsection (c)(2) does not serve the full term applicable under subsection (d), the individual appointed to fill the resulting vacancy shall be appointed for the remainder of the term of the predecessor of the individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chair</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Chair The Director shall, from among the members of the Advisory Council appointed under subsection (c)(2), designate an individual to serve as the chair of the Advisory Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Meetings The Advisory Council shall meet not less than once during each discrete 4-month period and shall otherwise meet at the call of the Director or the chair.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation and reimbursement of expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Compensation and reimbursement of expenses</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staff</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Staff The Director shall provide to the Advisory Council such staff, information, and other assistance as may be necessary to carry out the duties of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_299c_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Duration Notwithstanding section 1013(a) of title 5, the Advisory Council shall continue in existence until otherwise provided by law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>