<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300aa_21"><akn:num>300aa–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to bring actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300aa–21. Authority to bring actions(a) ElectionAfter judgment has been entered by the United States Court of Federal Claims or, if an appeal is taken under section 300aa–12(f) of this title, after the appellate court’s mandate is issued, the petitioner who filed the petition under section 300aa–11 of this title shall file with the clerk of the United States Court of Federal Claims—(1) if the judgment awarded compensation, an election in writing to receive the compensation or to file a civil action for damages for such injury or death, or

(2) if the judgment did not award compensation, an election in writing to accept the judgment or to file a civil action for damages for such injury or death.


An election shall be filed under this subsection not later than 90 days after the date of the court’s final judgment with respect to which the election is to be made. If a person required to file an election with the court under this subsection does not file the election within the time prescribed for filing the election, such person shall be deemed to have filed an election to accept the judgment of the court. If a person elects to receive compensation under a judgment of the court in an action for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine before October 1, 1988, or is deemed to have accepted the judgment of the court in such an action, such person may not bring or maintain a civil action for damages against a vaccine administrator or manufacturer for the vaccine-related injury or death for which the judgment was entered. For limitations on the bringing of civil actions for vaccine-related injuries or deaths associated with the administration of a vaccine after October 1, 1988, see section 300aa–11(a)(2) of this title.

(b) Continuance or withdrawal of petitionA petitioner under a petition filed under section 300aa–11 of this title may submit to the United States Court of Federal Claims a notice in writing choosing to continue or t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election After judgment has been entered by the United States Court of Federal Claims or, if an appeal is taken under section 300aa–12(f) of this title, after the appellate court’s mandate is issued, the petitioner who filed the petition under section 300aa–11 of this title shall file with the clerk of the United States Court of Federal Claims— An election shall be filed under this subsection not later than 90 days after the date of the court’s final judgment with respect to which the election is to be made. If a person required to file an election with the court under this subsection does not file the election within the time prescribed for filing the election, such person shall be deemed to have filed an election to accept the judgment of the court. If a person elects to receive compensation under a judgment of the court in an action for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine before October 1, 1988, or is deemed to have accepted the judg</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuance or withdrawal of petition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Continuance or withdrawal of petition A petitioner under a petition filed under section 300aa–11 of this title may submit to the United States Court of Federal Claims a notice in writing choosing to continue or to withdraw the petition if— Such a notice shall be filed within 30 days of the provision of the notice required by section 300aa–12(g) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations of actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations of actions A civil action for damages arising from a vaccine-related injury or death for which a petition was filed under section 300aa–11 of this title shall, except as provided in section 300aa–16(c) of this title, be brought within the period prescribed by limitations of actions under State law applicable to such civil action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>