<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–15" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–15/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–15/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300aa_15"><akn:num>300aa–15</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300aa–15. Compensation(a) General ruleCompensation awarded under the Program to a petitioner under section 300aa–11 of this title for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine after October 1, 1988, shall include the following:(1)(A) Actual unreimbursable expenses incurred from the date of the judgment awarding such expenses and reasonable projected unreimbursable expenses which—(i) result from the vaccine-related injury for which the petitioner seeks compensation,

(ii) have been or will be incurred by or on behalf of the person who suffered such injury, and

(iii)(I) have been or will be for diagnosis and medical or other remedial care determined to be reasonably necessary, or

(II) have been or will be for rehabilitation, developmental evaluation, special education, vocational training and placement, case management services, counseling, emotional or behavioral therapy, residential and custodial care and service expenses, special equipment, related travel expenses, and facilities determined to be reasonably necessary.



(B) Subject to section 300aa–16(a)(2) of this title, actual unreimbursable expenses incurred before the date of the judgment awarding such expenses which—(i) resulted from the vaccine-related injury for which the petitioner seeks compensation,

(ii) were incurred by or on behalf of the person who suffered such injury, and

(iii) were for diagnosis, medical or other remedial care, rehabilitation, developmental evaluation, special education, vocational training and placement, case management services, counseling, emotional or behavioral therapy, residential and custodial care and service expenses, special equipment, related travel expenses, and facilities determined to be reasonably necessary.



(2) In the event of a vaccine-related death, an award of $250,000 for the estate of the deceased.

(3)(A) In the case of any person who has sustained a vaccine-related injury after attaining the age of 18 and whose</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule Compensation awarded under the Program to a petitioner under section 300aa–11 of this title for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine after October 1, 1988, shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vaccines administered before effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Vaccines administered before effective date Compensation awarded under the Program to a petitioner under section 300aa–11 of this title for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine before October 1, 1988, may include the compensation described in paragraphs (1)(A) and (2) of subsection (a) and may also include an amount, not to exceed a combined total of $30,000, for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Residential and custodial care and service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Residential and custodial care and service The amount of any compensation for residential and custodial care and service expenses under subsection (a)(1) shall be sufficient to enable the compensated person to remain living at home.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of compensation prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Types of compensation prohibited Compensation awarded under the Program may not include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Attorneys’ fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Attorneys’ fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payment of compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Payment of compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program not primarily liable</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program not primarily liable Payment of compensation under the Program shall not be made for any item or service to the extent that payment has been made, or can reasonably be expected to be made, with respect to such item or service (1) under any State compensation program, under an insurance policy, or under any Federal or State health benefits program (other than under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.]), or (2) by an entity which provides health services on a prepaid basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability of health insurance carriers, prepaid health plans, and benefit providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Liability of health insurance carriers, prepaid health plans, and benefit providers No policy of health insurance may make payment of benefits under the policy secondary to the payment of compensation under the Program and— may make the provision of health services or health benefits secondary to the payment of compensation under the Program, except that this subsection shall not apply to the provision of services or benefits under title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.].</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Source of compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Source of compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_15_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization For the payment of compensation under the Program to a petitioner for a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine before October 1, 1988, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Health and Human Services $80,000,000 for fiscal year 1989, $80,000,000 for fiscal year 1990, $80,000,000 for fiscal year 1991, $80,000,000 for fiscal year 1992, $110,000,000 for fiscal year 1993, and $110,000,000 for each succeeding fiscal year in which a payment of compensation is required under subsection (f)(4)(B). Amounts appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>