<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300aa–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300aa_13"><akn:num>300aa–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of eligibility and compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300aa–13. Determination of eligibility and compensation(a) General rule(1) Compensation shall be awarded under the Program to a petitioner if the special master or court finds on the record as a whole—(A) that the petitioner has demonstrated by a preponderance of the evidence the matters required in the petition by section 300aa–11(c)(1) of this title, and

(B) that there is not a preponderance of the evidence that the illness, disability, injury, condition, or death described in the petition is due to factors unrelated to the administration of the vaccine described in the petition.


The special master or court may not make such a finding based on the claims of a petitioner alone, unsubstantiated by medical records or by medical opinion.

(2) For purposes of paragraph (1), the term “factors unrelated to the administration of the vaccine”—(A) does not include any idiopathic, unexplained, unknown, hypothetical, or undocumentable cause, factor, injury, illness, or condition, and

(B) may, as documented by the petitioner’s evidence or other material in the record, include infection, toxins, trauma (including birth trauma and related anoxia), or metabolic disturbances which have no known relation to the vaccine involved, but which in the particular case are shown to have been the agent or agents principally responsible for causing the petitioner’s illness, disability, injury, condition, or death.



(b) Matters to be considered(1) In determining whether to award compensation to a petitioner under the Program, the special master or court shall consider, in addition to all other relevant medical and scientific evidence contained in the record—(A) any diagnosis, conclusion, medical judgment, or autopsy or coroner’s report which is contained in the record regarding the nature, causation, and aggravation of the petitioner’s illness, disability, injury, condition, or death, and

(B) the results of any diagnostic or evaluative test which are contained in the record and the s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters to be considered</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Matters to be considered</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300aa_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Record” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Record” defined For purposes of this section, the term “record” means the record established by the special masters of the United States Court of Federal Claims in a proceeding on a petition filed under section 300aa–11 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>