<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300a"><akn:num>300a</akn:num><akn:heading>Formula grants to States for family planning services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300a. Formula grants to States for family planning services(a) Authority of Secretary; prerequisitesThe Secretary is authorized to make grants, from allotments made under subsection (b), to State health authorities to assist in planning, establishing, maintaining, coordinating, and evaluating family planning services. No grant may be made to a State health authority under this section unless such authority has submitted, and had approved by the Secretary, a State plan for a coordinated and comprehensive program of family planning services.


(b) Factors determining amount of State allotmentsThe sums appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section shall be allotted to the States by the Secretary on the basis of the population and the financial need of the respective States.


(c) “State” definedFor the purposes of this section, the term “State” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the District of Columbia, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.


(d) Authorization of appropriationsFor the purpose of making grants under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1971; $15,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1972; and $20,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1973.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title X, § 1002, as added Pub. L. 91–572, § 6(c), Dec. 24, 1970, 84 Stat. 1506; amended Pub. L. 94–484, title IX, § 905(b)(1), Oct. 12, 1976, 90 Stat. 2325.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1976—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 94–484 defined “State” to include Northern Mariana Islands.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Study of State Delivery of Services; Report to CongressPub. L. 97–35, title IX, § 931(c), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 570, directed Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study of possible ways of State delivery of services for which assistance is authorized by title X of the Public Health Service Ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; prerequisites The Secretary is authorized to make grants, from allotments made under subsection (b), to State health authorities to assist in planning, establishing, maintaining, coordinating, and evaluating family planning services. No grant may be made to a State health authority under this section unless such authority has submitted, and had approved by the Secretary, a State plan for a coordinated and comprehensive program of family planning services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Factors determining amount of State allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Factors determining amount of State allotments The sums appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section shall be allotted to the States by the Secretary on the basis of the population and the financial need of the respective States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“State” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “State” defined For the purposes of this section, the term “State” includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the District of Columbia, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of making grants under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1971; $15,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1972; and $20,000,000 for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1973.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>