<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300b–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300b–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300b–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300b_3"><akn:num>300b–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Application; special consideration to prior sickle cell anemia grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300b–3. Application; special consideration to prior sickle cell anemia grant recipients(a) Manner of submission; contentsA grant or contract under this part may be made upon application submitted to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing and accompanied by such information, as the Secretary may require, including assurances for an evaluation whether performed by the applicant or by the Secretary. Such grant or contract may be made available on less than a statewide or regional basis. Each applicant shall—(1) provide that the programs and activities for which assistance under this part is sought will be administered by or under the supervision of the applicant;

(2) provide for strict confidentiality of all test results, medical records, and other information regarding testing, diagnosis, counseling, or treatment of any person treated, except for (A) such information as the patient (or his guardian) gives informed consent to be released, or (B) statistical data compiled without reference to the identity of any such patient;

(3) provide for community representation where appropriate in the development and operation of voluntary genetic testing or counseling programs funded by a grant or contract under this part; and

(4) establish fiscal control and fund accounting procedures as may be necessary to assure proper disbursement of and accounting of Federal funds paid to the applicant under this part.


(b) Considerations for grants and contracts under section 300b–1 of this titleIn making grants and entering into contracts for any fiscal year under section 241 of this title for projects described in section 300b–1 of this title the Secretary shall give special consideration to applications from entities that received grants from, or entered into contracts with, the Secretary for the preceding fiscal year for the conduct of comprehensive sickle cell centers or sickle cell screening and education clinics.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XI, § 1104, a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300b_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of submission; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Manner of submission; contents A grant or contract under this part may be made upon application submitted to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing and accompanied by such information, as the Secretary may require, including assurances for an evaluation whether performed by the applicant or by the Secretary. Such grant or contract may be made available on less than a statewide or regional basis. Each applicant shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300b_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations for grants and contracts under section 300b–1 of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Considerations for grants and contracts under In making grants and entering into contracts for any fiscal year under section 241 of this title for projects described in section 300b–1 of this title the Secretary shall give special consideration to applications from entities that received grants from, or entered into contracts with, the Secretary for the preceding fiscal year for the conduct of comprehensive sickle cell centers or sickle cell screening and education clinics.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>