<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300bb–8" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300bb–8/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300bb–8/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300bb_8"><akn:num>300bb–8</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300bb–8. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter—(1) Group health planThe term “group health plan” has the meaning given such term in 5000(b) 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of title 26. Such term shall not include any plan substantially all of the coverage under which is for qualified long-term care services (as defined in section 7702B(c) of title 26). Such term shall not include any qualified small employer health reimbursement arrangement (as defined in section 9831(d)(2) of title 26).


(2) Covered employeeThe term “covered employee” means an individual who is (or was) provided coverage under a group health plan by virtue of the performance of services by the individual for 1 or more persons maintaining the plan (including as an employee defined in section 401(c)(1) of title 26).


(3) Qualified beneficiary(A) In generalThe term “qualified beneficiary” means, with respect to a covered employee under a group health plan, any other individual who, on the day before the qualifying event for that employee, is a beneficiary under the plan—(i) as the spouse of the covered employee, or

(ii) as the dependent child of the employee.


Such term shall also include a child who is born to or placed for adoption with the covered employee during the period of continuation coverage under this subchapter.

(B) Special rule for terminations and reduced employmentIn the case of a qualifying event described in section 300bb–3(2) of this title, the term “qualified beneficiary” includes the covered employee.



(4) Plan administratorThe term “plan administrator” has the meaning given the term “administrator” by section 1002(16)(A) of title 29.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXII, § 2208, as added Pub. L. 99–272, title X, § 10003(a), Apr. 7, 1986, 100 Stat. 236; amended Pub. L. 100–647, title III, § 3011(b)(7), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3625; Pub. L. 101–239, title VI, § 6801(c)(1), Dec. 19, 1989, 103 Stat. 2297; Pub. L. 104–191, title I, § 102(d),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300bb_8_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Group health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Group health plan The term “group health plan” has the meaning given such term in 5000(b) 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of title 26. Such term shall not include any plan substantially all of the coverage under which is for qualified long-term care services (as defined in section 7702B(c) of title 26). Such term shall not include any qualified small employer health reimbursement arrangement (as defined in section 9831(d)(2) of title 26).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300bb_8_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Covered employee The term “covered employee” means an individual who is (or was) provided coverage under a group health plan by virtue of the performance of services by the individual for 1 or more persons maintaining the plan (including as an employee defined in section 401(c)(1) of title 26).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300bb_8_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified beneficiary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Qualified beneficiary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300bb_8_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plan administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Plan administrator The term “plan administrator” has the meaning given the term “administrator” by section 1002(16)(A) of title 29.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>