<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–17" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–17/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–17/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300cc_17"><akn:num>300cc–17</akn:num><akn:heading>Information services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300cc–17. Information services(a) Establishment of programThe Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate a program with respect to information on research, treatment, and prevention activities relating to infection with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome. The program shall, with respect to the agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services, be integrated and coordinated.


(b) Toll-free telephone communications for health care entities(1) After consultation with the Director of the Office of AIDS Research, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Secretary shall provide for toll-free telephone communications to provide medical and technical information with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome to health care professionals, allied health care providers, and to professionals providing emergency health services.

(2) Information provided pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—(A) information on prevention of exposure to, and the transmission of, the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome; and

(B) information contained in the data banks established in subsections (c) and (d).



(c) Data bank on research information(1) After consultation with the Director of the Office of AIDS Research, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the National Library of Medicine, the Secretary shall establish a data bank of information on the results of research with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome conducted in the United States and other countries.

(2) In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall collect, catalog, store, and disseminate the information described in such paragraph. To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall make such information available to researchers, physicians, and other appropriate individuals, of countries other than the United States.


(d) Da</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_17_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of program The Secretary shall establish, maintain, and operate a program with respect to information on research, treatment, and prevention activities relating to infection with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome. The program shall, with respect to the agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services, be integrated and coordinated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_17_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Toll-free telephone communications for health care entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Toll-free telephone communications for health care entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_17_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data bank on research information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Data bank on research information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_17_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data bank on clinical trials and treatments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data bank on clinical trials and treatments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_17_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements with respect to data bank on clinical trials and treatments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirements with respect to data bank on clinical trials and treatments The Data Bank shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>