<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300c–14" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300c–14/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300c–14/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300c_14"><akn:num>300c–14</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300c–14. Report to Congress(a) In generalNot later than 2 years after December 31, 2020, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that contains, with respect to the reporting period—(1) information regarding the incidence and number of sudden unexpected infant death and sudden unexpected death in childhood (including the number of such infant and child deaths that remain unexplained after investigation), including, to the extent practicable—(A) a summary of such information by racial and ethnic group, and by State;

(B) aggregate information obtained from death scene investigations and autopsies; and

(C) recommendations for reducing the incidence of sudden unexpected infant death and sudden unexpected death in childhood;


(2) an assessment of the extent to which various approaches of reducing and preventing sudden unexpected infant death and sudden unexpected death in childhood have been effective; and

(3) a description of the activities carried out under section 300c–11 of this title.


(b) DefinitionsIn this section, the terms “sudden unexpected infant death” and “sudden unexpected death in childhood” have the meanings given such terms in section 300c–11 of this title.


(Pub. L. 116–273, § 3, Dec. 31, 2020, 134 Stat. 3354.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Scarlett’s Sunshine on Sudden Unexpected Death Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300c_14_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 2 years after December 31, 2020, and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that contains, with respect to the reporting period—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300c_14_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions In this section, the terms “sudden unexpected infant death” and “sudden unexpected death in childhood” have the meanings given such terms in section 300c–11 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>