<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–40b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–40b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–40b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300cc_40b"><akn:num>300cc–40b</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council; coordinating committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300cc–40b. Advisory Council; coordinating committees(a) Advisory Council(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish an advisory council for the purpose of providing advice to the Director of the Office on carrying out this part. (Such council is referred to in this subsection as the “Advisory Council”.)


(2) Composition, compensation, terms, chair, etc.Subsections (b) through (g) of section 284a of this title apply to the Advisory Council to the same extent and in the same manner as such subsections apply to advisory councils for the national research institutes, except that—(A) in addition to the ex officio members specified in section 284a(b)(2) of this title, there shall serve as such members of the Advisory Council a representative from the advisory council of each of the National Cancer Institute and the National Institute on Allergy and Infectious Diseases; and

(B) with respect to the other national research institutes, there shall serve as ex officio members of such Council, in addition to such members specified in subparagraph (A), a representative from the advisory council of each of the 2 institutes that receive the greatest funding for AIDS activities.



(b) Individual coordinating committees regarding research disciplines(1) In generalThe Director of the Office shall establish, for each research discipline in which any activity under the plan required in section 300cc–40c of this title is carried out, a committee for the purpose of providing advice to the Director of the Office on carrying out this part with respect to such discipline. (Each such committee is referred to in this subsection as a “coordinating committee”.)


(2) CompositionEach coordinating committee shall be composed of representatives of the agencies of the National Institutes of Health with significant responsibilities regarding the research discipline involved.



(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXIII, § 2352, as added Pub. L. 103–43, title XVIII, § 1801(a)(3), June 10, 1993, 107 St</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_40b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Advisory Council</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_40b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individual coordinating committees regarding research disciplines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Individual coordinating committees regarding research disciplines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>