<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–45" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–45/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–45/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300cc_45"><akn:num>300cc–45</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions regarding Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300cc–45. General provisions regarding Office(a) Administrative support for OfficeThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall provide administrative support and support services to the Director of the Office and shall ensure that such support takes maximum advantage of existing administrative structures at the agencies of the National Institutes of Health.


(b) EvaluationNot later than 5 years after June 10, 1993, the Secretary shall conduct an evaluation to—(1) determine the effect of this section on the planning and coordination of the AIDS research programs at the institutes, centers and divisions of the National Institutes of Health;

(2) evaluate the extent to which this part has eliminated the duplication of administrative resources among such Institutes, centers and divisions; and

(3) provide recommendations concerning future alterations with respect to this part.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this part:(1) The term “AIDS activities” means AIDS research and other activities that relate to acquired immune deficiency syndrome.

(2) The term “AIDS research” means research with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome.

(3) The term “Office” means the Office of AIDS Research.

(4) The term “Plan” means the plan required in section 300cc–40c(a)(1) of this title.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXIII, § 2359, as added Pub. L. 103–43, title XVIII, § 1803, June 10, 1993, 107 Stat. 198; amended Pub. L. 109–482, title I, § 104(b)(2)(F), Jan. 15, 2007, 120 Stat. 3693.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 109–482 substituted “Evaluation” for “Evaluation and report” in heading, struck out par. (1) designation before “Not later than”, redesignated subpars. (A) to (C) as pars. (1) to (3), respectively, and struck out heading and text of former par. (2). Text read as follows: “Not later than 1 year after the date on which the evaluation is commenced under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prepare and s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_45_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative support for Office</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Administrative support for Office The Secretary, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, shall provide administrative support and support services to the Director of the Office and shall ensure that such support takes maximum advantage of existing administrative structures at the agencies of the National Institutes of Health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_45_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation Not later than 5 years after June 10, 1993, the Secretary shall conduct an evaluation to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_45_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>