<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–43" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–43/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300cc–43/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300cc_43"><akn:num>300cc–43</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency Discretionary Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300cc–43. Emergency Discretionary Fund(a) In general(1) EstablishmentThere is established a fund consisting of such amounts as may be appropriated under subsection (g). Subject to the provisions of this section, the Director of the Office, after consultation with the advisory council established under section 300cc–40b of this title, may expend amounts in the Fund for the purpose of conducting and supporting such AIDS activities, including projects of AIDS research, as may be authorized in this chapter for the National Institutes of Health.


(2) Preconditions to use of FundAmounts in the Fund may be expended only if—(A) the Director identifies the particular set of AIDS activities for which such amounts are to be expended;

(B) the set of activities so identified constitutes either a new project or additional AIDS activities for an existing project;

(C) the Director of the Office has made a determination that there is a significant need for such set of activities; and

(D) as of June 30 of the fiscal year preceding the fiscal year in which the determination is made, such need was not provided for in any appropriations Act passed by the House of Representatives to make appropriations for the Departments of Labor, Health and Human Services (including the National Institutes of Health), Education, and related agencies for the fiscal year in which the determination is made.


(3) Two-year use of Fund for project involvedIn the case of an identified set of AIDS activities, obligations of amounts in the Fund may not be made for such set of activities after the expiration of the 2-year period beginning on the date on which the initial obligation of such amounts is made for such set.



(b) Peer reviewWith respect to an identified set of AIDS activities carried out with amounts in the Fund, this section may not be construed as waiving applicable requirements for peer review.


(c) Limitations on use of Fund(1) Construction of facilitiesAmounts in the Fund may not be use</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Peer review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Peer review With respect to an identified set of AIDS activities carried out with amounts in the Fund, this section may not be construed as waiving applicable requirements for peer review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on use of Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of limitation regarding number of employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of limitation regarding number of employees The purposes for which amounts in the Fund may be expended include the employment of individuals necessary to carry out identified sets of AIDS activities approved under subsection (a). Any individual employed under the preceding sentence may not be included in any determination of the number of full-time equivalent employees for the Department of Health and Human Services for the purpose of any limitation on the number of such employees established by law prior to, on, or after June 10, 1993.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300cc_43_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>