<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–31" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–31/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–31/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d_31"><akn:num>300d–31</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d–31. Definitions
For purposes of this part and parts A and B:(1) Designated trauma centerThe term “designated trauma center” means a trauma center designated in accordance with the modifications to the State plan described in section 300d–13 of this title.


(2) State plan regarding emergency medical servicesThe term “State plan”, with respect to the provision of emergency medical services, means a plan for a comprehensive, organized system to provide for the access, response, triage, field stabilization, transport, hospital stabilization, definitive care, and rehabilitation of patients of all ages with respect to emergency medical services.


(3) StateThe term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.


(4) TraumaThe term “trauma” means an injury resulting from exposure to—(A) a mechanical force; or

(B) another extrinsic agent, including an extrinsic agent that is thermal, electrical, chemical, or radioactive.


(5) Trauma care component of State planThe term “trauma care component”, with respect to components of the State plan for the provision of emergency medical services, means a plan for a comprehensive health care system, within rural and urban areas of the State, for the prompt recognition, prehospital care, emergency medical care, acute surgical and medical care, rehabilitation, and outcome evaluation of seriously injured patients.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XII, § 1231, as added Pub. L. 101–590, § 3, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 2926; amended Pub. L. 102–321, title VI, § 602(2), July 10, 1992, 106 Stat. 436; Pub. L. 103–183, title VI, § 601(f)(4), Dec. 14, 1993, 107 Stat. 2239; Pub. L. 113–152, § 2(a), Aug. 8, 2014, 128 Stat. 1825.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2014—Par. (4). Pub. L. 113–152 amended par. (4) generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The term ‘trauma’ means an injury res</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_31_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designated trauma center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Designated trauma center The term “designated trauma center” means a trauma center designated in accordance with the modifications to the State plan described in section 300d–13 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_31_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan regarding emergency medical services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) State plan regarding emergency medical services The term “State plan”, with respect to the provision of emergency medical services, means a plan for a comprehensive, organized system to provide for the access, response, triage, field stabilization, transport, hospital stabilization, definitive care, and rehabilitation of patients of all ages with respect to emergency medical services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_31_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) State The term “State” means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_31_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trauma</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Trauma The term “trauma” means an injury resulting from exposure to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_31_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trauma care component of State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Trauma care component of State plan The term “trauma care component”, with respect to components of the State plan for the provision of emergency medical services, means a plan for a comprehensive health care system, within rural and urban areas of the State, for the prompt recognition, prehospital care, emergency medical care, acute surgical and medical care, rehabilitation, and outcome evaluation of seriously injured patients.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>