<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–14" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–14/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–14/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d_14"><akn:num>300d–14</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of submission to Secretary of trauma plan and certain information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d–14. Requirement of submission to Secretary of trauma plan and certain information(a) In generalFor each fiscal year, the Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless, subject to subsection (b), the State submits to the Secretary the trauma care component of the State plan for the provision of emergency medical services, including any changes to the trauma care component and any plans to address deficiencies in the trauma care component.


(b) Interim plan or description of effortsFor each fiscal year, if a State has not completed the trauma care component of the State plan described in subsection (a), the State may provide, in lieu of such completed component, an interim component or a description of efforts made toward the completion of the component.


(c) Information received by State reporting and analysis systemThe Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless the State agrees that the State will, not less than once each year, provide to the Secretary the information received by the State pursuant to section 300d–13(a)(7) of this title.


(d) Availability of emergency medical services in rural areasThe Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless—(1) the State identifies any rural area in the State for which—(A) there is no system of access to emergency medical services through the telephone number 911;

(B) there is no basic life-support system; or

(C) there is no advanced life-support system; and


(2) the State submits to the Secretary a list of rural areas identified pursuant to paragraph (1) or, if there are no such areas, a statement that there are no such areas.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XII, § 1214, as added Pub. L. 101–590, § 3, Nov. 16, 1990, 104 Stat. 2922; amended Pub. L. 110–23, § 8, May 3, 2007, 121 Stat. 96.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2007—Pub. L. 110–23 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, se</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_14_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For each fiscal year, the Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless, subject to subsection (b), the State submits to the Secretary the trauma care component of the State plan for the provision of emergency medical services, including any changes to the trauma care component and any plans to address deficiencies in the trauma care component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_14_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim plan or description of efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interim plan or description of efforts For each fiscal year, if a State has not completed the trauma care component of the State plan described in subsection (a), the State may provide, in lieu of such completed component, an interim component or a description of efforts made toward the completion of the component.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_14_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information received by State reporting and analysis system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Information received by State reporting and analysis system The Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless the State agrees that the State will, not less than once each year, provide to the Secretary the information received by the State pursuant to section 300d–13(a)(7) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_14_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of emergency medical services in rural areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Availability of emergency medical services in rural areas The Secretary may not make payments to a State under section 300d–11(a) of this title unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>