<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d_6"><akn:num>300d–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive grants for trauma centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d–6. Competitive grants for trauma centers(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall award not fewer than 4 multiyear contracts or competitive grants to eligible entities to support pilot projects to design, implement, and evaluate new or existing innovative models of regionalized, comprehensive, and accountable emergency medical and trauma systems, and improve access to trauma care within such systems.


(b) Eligible entity; regionIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(A) a State or consortia of States;

(B) an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization (as defined in section 5304 of title 25);

(C) a consortium of level I, II, or III trauma centers designated by applicable State or local agencies within an applicable State or region, and, as applicable, other emergency services providers; or

(D) a consortium or partnership of nonprofit Indian Health Service, Indian Tribal, and urban Indian trauma centers.


(2) RegionThe term “region” means an area within a State, an area that lies within multiple States, or a similar area (such as a multicounty area), as determined by the Secretary.


(3) Emergency servicesThe term “emergency services” includes acute, prehospital, and trauma care.



(c) Pilot projectsThe Secretary shall award a contract or grant under subsection (a) to an eligible entity to design, implement, and evaluate a new or existing emergency medical and trauma system. Such eligible entity shall use amounts awarded under this subsection to carry out 2 or more of the following activities:(1) Strengthening coordination and communication with public health and safety services, emergency medical services, medical facilities, trauma centers, and other entities in a region to develop approaches to improve situational awareness and emergency medical and trauma system access.

(2) Providing a mechanism, such as a regional medical direction or transport communications system</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall award not fewer than 4 multiyear contracts or competitive grants to eligible entities to support pilot projects to design, implement, and evaluate new or existing innovative models of regionalized, comprehensive, and accountable emergency medical and trauma systems, and improve access to trauma care within such systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entity; region</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible entity; region In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Pilot projects The Secretary shall award a contract or grant under subsection (a) to an eligible entity to design, implement, and evaluate a new or existing emergency medical and trauma system. Such eligible entity shall use amounts awarded under this subsection to carry out 2 or more of the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Requirement of matching funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Priority The Secretary shall give priority for the award of the contracts or grants described in subsection (a) to any eligible entity that serves a medically underserved population (as defined in section 254b(b)(3) of this title).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Report Not later than 90 days after the completion of a pilot project under subsection (a), the recipient of such contract or grant shall submit to the Secretary a report containing the results of an evaluation of the program, including an identification of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_6_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Dissemination of findings Not later than 1 year after the completion of the final project under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report describing the information contained in each report submitted pursuant to subsection (g) and any additional actions planned by the Secretary related to regionalized emergency care and trauma systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>