<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d"><akn:num>300d</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d. Establishment(a) In generalThe Secretary shall, with respect to trauma care—(1) conduct and support research, training, evaluations, and demonstration projects;

(2) foster the development of appropriate, modern systems of such care through the sharing of information among agencies and individuals involved in the study and provision of such care;

(3) collect, compile, analyze, and disseminate information on the achievements of, and problems experienced by, State and local agencies and private entities in providing trauma care and emergency medical services and, in so doing, give special consideration to the unique needs of rural areas and medically underserved areas;

(4) provide to State and local agencies technical assistance to enhance each State’s capability to develop, implement, and sustain the trauma care component of each State’s plan for the provision of emergency medical services; and

(5) promote the collection and categorization of trauma data in a consistent and standardized manner.


(b) Trauma care readiness and coordinationThe Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall support the efforts of States and consortia of States to coordinate and improve emergency medical services and trauma care during a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 247d of this title or a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 5170 or 5191, respectively, of this title. Such support may include—(1) developing, issuing, and updating guidance, as appropriate, to support the coordinated medical triage and evacuation to appropriate medical institutions based on patient medical need, taking into account regionalized systems of care;

(2) disseminating, as appropriate, information on evidence-based or evidence-informed trauma care practices, taking into consideration emergency medical services and trauma care systems, including such practices identified through activities co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall, with respect to trauma care—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trauma care readiness and coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Trauma care readiness and coordination The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response, shall support the efforts of States and consortia of States to coordinate and improve emergency medical services and trauma care during a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 247d of this title or a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 5170 or 5191, respectively, of this title. Such support may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts The Secretary may make grants, and enter into cooperative agreements and contracts, for the purpose of carrying out subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>