<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–81" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–81/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–81/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d_81"><akn:num>300d–81</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d–81. Grants to States(a) EstablishmentTo promote universal access to trauma care services provided by trauma centers and trauma-related physician specialties, the Secretary shall provide funding to States to enable such States to award grants to eligible entities for the purposes described in this section.


(b) Awarding of grants by StatesEach State may award grants to eligible entities within the State for the purposes described in subparagraph (d).


(c) Eligibility(1) In generalTo be eligible to receive a grant under subsection (b) an entity shall—(A) be—(i) a public or nonprofit trauma center or consortium thereof that meets that 11 So in original. Probably should be “the”. requirements of paragraphs (1), (2), and (5) of section 300d–41(b) of this title;

(ii) a safety net public or nonprofit trauma center that meets the requirements of paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 300d–41(b) of this title; or

(iii) a hospital in an underserved area (as defined by the State) that seeks to establish new trauma services; and


(B) submit to the State an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require.


(2) LimitationA State shall use at least 40 percent of the amount available to the State under this part for a fiscal year to award grants to safety net trauma centers described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii).



(d) Use of fundsThe recipient of a grant under subsection (b) shall carry out 1 or more of the following activities consistent with subsection (b):(1) Providing trauma centers with funding to support physician compensation in trauma-related physician specialties where shortages exist in the region involved, with priority provided to safety net trauma centers described in subsection (c)(1)(A)(ii).

(2) Providing for individual safety net trauma center fiscal stability and costs related to having service that is available 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, with priority provided to safety net trauma centers described i</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment To promote universal access to trauma care services provided by trauma centers and trauma-related physician specialties, the Secretary shall provide funding to States to enable such States to award grants to eligible entities for the purposes described in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Awarding of grants by States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Awarding of grants by States Each State may award grants to eligible entities within the State for the purposes described in subparagraph (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of funds The recipient of a grant under subsection (b) shall carry out 1 or more of the following activities consistent with subsection (b):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_81_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Distribution of funds The following shall apply with respect to grants provided in this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>