<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–72" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–72/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300d–72/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300d_72"><akn:num>300d–72</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting poison control center utilization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300d–72. Promoting poison control center utilization(a) In generalThe Secretary shall carry out, and expand upon, a national media campaign to educate and support outreach to the public and health care providers about poisoning and toxic exposure prevention and the availability of poison control center resources in local communities and to conduct advertising campaigns concerning the nationwide toll-free number and other available communication technologies established, implemented, or maintained under section 300d–71(a) of this title.


(b) Contract with entityThe Secretary may carry out subsection (a) by entering into contracts with one or more public or private entities, including nationally recognized organizations in the field of poison control and national media firms, for the development and implementation of a nationwide poisoning and toxic exposure prevention and poison control center awareness campaign, which may include—(1) the development and distribution of poisoning and toxic exposure prevention awareness materials, applicable public health emergency preparedness and response information, and poison control center awareness materials;

(2) television, radio, Internet, and newspaper public service announcements; and

(3) other activities to provide for public and professional awareness and education.


(c) Authorization of appropriationsThere is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $800,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XII, § 1272, as added Pub. L. 108–194, § 3, Dec. 19, 2003, 117 Stat. 2889; amended Pub. L. 110–377, § 4(a), Oct. 8, 2008, 122 Stat. 4064; Pub. L. 113–77, § 3, Jan. 24, 2014, 128 Stat. 644; Pub. L. 116–94, div. N, title I, § 403(b), Dec. 20, 2019, 133 Stat. 3114; Pub. L. 118–86, § 2(b), Sept. 26, 2024, 138 Stat. 1549.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2024—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 118–86 substituted “fiscal years 2025 through 2029” for “fiscal years 2020 through 2024”.
2019—Pub. L.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_72_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall carry out, and expand upon, a national media campaign to educate and support outreach to the public and health care providers about poisoning and toxic exposure prevention and the availability of poison control center resources in local communities and to conduct advertising campaigns concerning the nationwide toll-free number and other available communication technologies established, implemented, or maintained under section 300d–71(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_72_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract with entity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract with entity The Secretary may carry out subsection (a) by entering into contracts with one or more public or private entities, including nationally recognized organizations in the field of poison control and national media firms, for the development and implementation of a nationwide poisoning and toxic exposure prevention and poison control center awareness campaign, which may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300d_72_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $800,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2029.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>