<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300e"><akn:num>300e</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of health maintenance organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300e. Requirements of health maintenance organizations(a) “Health maintenance organization” definedFor purposes of this subchapter, the term “health maintenance organization” means a public or private entity which is organized under the laws of any State and which (1) provides basic and supplemental health services to its members in the manner prescribed by subsection (b), and (2) is organized and operated in the manner prescribed by subsection (c).


(b) Manner of supplying basic and supplemental health services to membersA health maintenance organization shall provide, without limitations as to time or cost other than those prescribed by or under this subchapter, basic and supplemental health services to its members in the following manner:(1) Each member is to be provided basic health services for a basic health services payment which (A) is to be paid on a periodic basis without regard to the dates health services (within the basic health services) are provided; (B) is fixed without regard to the frequency, extent, or kind of health service (within the basic health services) actually furnished; (C) except in the case of basic health services provided a member who is a full-time student (as defined by the Secretary) at an accredited institution of higher education, is fixed under a community rating system; and (D) may be supplemented by additional nominal payments which may be required for the provision of specific services (within the basic health services), except that such payments may not be required where or in such a manner that they serve (as determined under regulations of the Secretary) as a barrier to the delivery of health services. Such additional nominal payments shall be fixed in accordance with the regulations of the Secretary. If a health maintenance organization offers to its members the opportunity to obtain basic health services through a physician not described in subsection (b)(3)(A), the organization may require, in addition to payments de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Health maintenance organization” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) “Health maintenance organization” defined For purposes of this subchapter, the term “health maintenance organization” means a public or private entity which is organized under the laws of any State and which (1) provides basic and supplemental health services to its members in the manner prescribed by subsection (b), and (2) is organized and operated in the manner prescribed by subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manner of supplying basic and supplemental health services to members</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Manner of supplying basic and supplemental health services to members A health maintenance organization shall provide, without limitations as to time or cost other than those prescribed by or under this subchapter, basic and supplemental health services to its members in the following manner:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Organizational requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Organizational requirements Each health maintenance organization shall— The Secretary shall issue regulations stating the circumstances under which the Secretary, in administering paragraph (1)(A), will consider the resources of an organization which owns or controls a health maintenance organization. Such regulations shall require as a condition to consideration of resources that an organization which owns or controls a health maintenance organization shall provide satisfactory assurances that it will assume the financial obligations of the health maintenance organization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of rules by certain health maintenance organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application of rules by certain health maintenance organizations An organization that offers health benefits coverage shall not be considered as failing to meet the requirements of this section notwithstanding that it provides, with respect to coverage offered in connection with a group health plan in the small or large group market (as defined in section 300gg–91(e) of this title), an affiliation period consistent with the provisions of section 2701(g).1</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>