<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ee–32" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ee–32/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ee–32/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ee_32"><akn:num>300ee–32</akn:num><akn:heading>Public information campaigns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ee–32. Public information campaigns(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to public entities, and to nonprofit private entities concerned with acquired immune deficiency syndrome, and shall enter into contracts with public and private entities, for the development and delivery of public service announcements and paid advertising messages that warn individuals about activities which place them at risk of infection with the etiologic agent for such syndrome.


(b) Requirement of applicationThe Secretary may not provide financial assistance under subsection (a) unless—(1) an application for such assistance is submitted to the Secretary;

(2) with respect to carrying out the purpose for which the assistance is to be provided, the application provides assurances of compliance satisfactory to the Secretary; and

(3) the application otherwise is in such form, is made in such manner, and contains such agreements, assurances, and information as the Secretary determines to be necessary to carry out this section.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXV, formerly title XV, § 2522, as added Pub. L. 100–607, title II, § 221, Nov. 4, 1988, 102 Stat. 3103; renumbered title XXV, Pub. L. 101–93, § 5(e)(1), Aug. 16, 1989, 103 Stat. 612; amended Pub. L. 102–531, title III, § 312(d)(23), Oct. 27, 1992, 106 Stat. 3505.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1992—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 102–531 substituted “Centers for Disease Control and Prevention” for “Centers for Disease Control”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ee_32_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to public entities, and to nonprofit private entities concerned with acquired immune deficiency syndrome, and shall enter into contracts with public and private entities, for the development and delivery of public service announcements and paid advertising messages that warn individuals about activities which place them at risk of infection with the etiologic agent for such syndrome.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ee_32_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirement of application The Secretary may not provide financial assistance under subsection (a) unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>