<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300e–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300e_7"><akn:num>300e–7</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions relating to loan guarantees and loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300e–7. General provisions relating to loan guarantees and loans(a) Conditions(1) The Secretary may not approve an application for a loan guarantee under this subchapter unless he determines that (A) the terms, conditions, security (if any), and schedule and amount of repayments with respect to the loan are sufficient to protect the financial interests of the United States and are otherwise reasonable, including a determination that the rate of interest does not exceed such per centum per annum on the principal obligation outstanding as the Secretary determines to be reasonable, taking into account the range of interest rates prevailing in the private market for loans with similar maturities, terms, conditions, and security and the risks assumed by the United States, and (B) the loan would not be available on reasonable terms and conditions without the guarantee under this subchapter.

(2)(A) The United States shall be entitled to recover from the applicant for a loan guarantee under this subchapter the amount of any payment made pursuant to such guarantee, unless the Secretary for good cause waives such right of recovery; and, upon making any such payment, the United States shall be subrogated to all of the rights of the recipient of the payments with respect to which the guarantee was made.

(B) To the extent permitted by subparagraph (C), any terms and conditions applicable to a loan guarantee under this subchapter (including terms and conditions imposed under subparagraph (D)) may be modified by the Secretary to the extent he determines it to be consistent with the financial interest of the United States.

(C) Any loan guarantee made by the Secretary under this subchapter shall be incontestable (i) in the hands of an applicant on whose behalf such guarantee is made unless the applicant engaged in fraud or misrepresentation in securing such guarantee, and (ii) as to any person (or his successor in interest) who makes or contracts to make a loan to such applican</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Conditions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Sale of loans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan guarantee fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Loan guarantee fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Loan fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Loan fund There is established in the Treasury a loan fund (hereinafter in this subsection referred to as the “fund”) which shall be available to the Secretary without fiscal year limitation, in such amounts as may be specified from time to time in appropriation Acts, to enable him to make loans under this subchapter and to take the action authorized by subsection (f). There shall also be deposited in the fund amounts received by the Secretary as interest payments and repayment of principal on loans made under this subchapter and other property or assets derived by him from his operations respecting such loans, from the sale of loans under subsection (c) of this section, or from the sale of assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300e_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions to protect interest of United States in event of default</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Actions to protect interest of United States in event of default The Secretary may take such action as he deems appropriate to protect the interest of the United States in the event of a default on a loan made or guaranteed under this subchapter, including taking possession of, holding, and using real property pledged as security for such a loan or loan guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>