<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–53" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–53/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–53/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_53"><akn:num>300ff–53</akn:num><akn:heading>Preferences in making grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–53. Preferences in making grants(a) In generalIn making grants under section 300ff–51 of this title, the Secretary shall give preference to any qualified applicant experiencing an increase in the burden of providing services regarding HIV/AIDS, as indicated by the factors specified in subsection (b).


(b) Specification of factors(1) In generalIn the case of the geographic area with respect to which the entity involved is applying for a grant under section 300ff–51 of this title, the factors referred to in subsection (a), as determined for the period specified in paragraph (2), are—(A) the number of cases of HIV/AIDS;

(B) the rate of increase in such cases;

(C) the lack of availability of early intervention services;

(D) the number of other cases of sexually transmitted diseases, and 11 So in original. The word “and” probably should not appear. the number of cases of tuberculosis and of drug abuse 22 So in original. A comma probably should appear. and the number of cases of individuals co-infected with HIV/AIDS and hepatitis B or C;

(E) the rate of increase in each of the cases specified in subparagraph (D);

(F) the lack of availability of primary health services from providers other than such applicant; and

(G) the distance between such area and the nearest community that has an adequate level of availability of appropriate HIV-related services, and the length of time required to travel such distance.


(2) Relevant period of timeThe period referred to in paragraph (1) is the 2-year period preceding the fiscal year for which the entity involved is applying to receive a grant under section 300ff–51 of this title.



(c) Equitable allocationsIn providing preferences for purposes of subsection (b), the Secretary shall equitably allocate the preferences among urban and rural areas.


(d) Certain areasOf the applicants who qualify for preference under this section—(1) the Secretary shall give preference to applicants that will expend the grant under sectio</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_53_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In making grants under section 300ff–51 of this title, the Secretary shall give preference to any qualified applicant experiencing an increase in the burden of providing services regarding HIV/AIDS, as indicated by the factors specified in subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_53_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specification of factors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Specification of factors</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_53_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable allocations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equitable allocations In providing preferences for purposes of subsection (b), the Secretary shall equitably allocate the preferences among urban and rural areas.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_53_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain areas Of the applicants who qualify for preference under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>