<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–13" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–13/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–13/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_13"><akn:num>300ff–13</akn:num><akn:heading>Type and distribution of grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–13. Type and distribution of grants(a) Grants based on relative need of area(1) In generalIn carrying out section 300ff–11(a) of this title, the Secretary shall make a grant for each eligible area for which an application under section 300ff–15(a) of this title has been approved. Each such grant shall be made in an amount determined in accordance with paragraph (3).


(2) Expedited distributionNot later than 60 days after an appropriation becomes available to carry out this subpart for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall, except in the case of waivers granted under section 300ff–15(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, disburse 66⅔ percent of the amount made available under section 300ff–20(b) of this title for carrying out this subpart for such fiscal year through grants to eligible areas under section 300ff–11(a) of this title, in accordance with paragraphs (3) and (4).


(3) Amount of grant(A) In generalSubject to the extent of amounts made available in appropriations Acts, a grant made for purposes of this paragraph to an eligible area shall be made in an amount equal to the product of—(i) an amount equal to the amount available for distribution under paragraph (2) for the fiscal year involved; and

(ii) the percentage constituted by the ratio of the distribution factor for the eligible area to the sum of the respective distribution factors for all eligible areas;


which product shall then, as applicable, be increased under paragraph (4).

(B) Distribution factorFor purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the term “distribution factor” means an amount equal to the living cases of HIV/AIDS (reported to and confirmed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) in the eligible area involved, as determined under subparagraph (C).


(C) Living cases of HIV/AIDS(i) Requirement of names-based reportingExcept as provided in clause (ii), the number determined under this subparagraph for an eligible area for a fiscal year for pur</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_13_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants based on relative need of area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants based on relative need of area</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_13_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Supplemental grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_13_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Timeframe for obligation and expenditure of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Timeframe for obligation and expenditure of grant funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_13_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with priorities of HIV planning council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Compliance with priorities of HIV planning council Notwithstanding any other provision of this subpart, the Secretary, in carrying out section 300ff–11(a) of this title, may not make any grant under subsection (a) or (b) to an eligible area unless the application submitted by such area under section 300ff–15 of this title for the grant involved demonstrates that the grants made under subsections (a) and (b) to the area for the preceding fiscal year (if any) were expended in accordance with the priorities applicable to such year that were established, pursuant to section 300ff–12(b)(4)(C) of this title, by the planning council serving the area.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_13_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on the awarding of supplemental funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on the awarding of supplemental funds Not later than 45 days after the awarding of supplemental funds under this section, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report concerning such funds. Such report shall include information detailing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>