<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300f"><akn:num>300f</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300f. Definitions
For purposes of this subchapter:(1) The term “primary drinking water regulation” means a regulation which—(A) applies to public water systems;

(B) specifies contaminants which, in the judgment of the Administrator, may have any adverse effect on the health of persons;

(C) specifies for each such contaminant either—(i) a maximum contaminant level, if, in the judgment of the Administrator, it is economically and technologically feasible to ascertain the level of such contaminant in water in public water systems, or

(ii) if, in the judgment of the Administrator, it is not economically or technologically feasible to so ascertain the level of such contaminant, each treatment technique known to the Administrator which leads to a reduction in the level of such contaminant sufficient to satisfy the requirements of section 300g–1 of this title; and


(D) contains criteria and procedures to assure a supply of drinking water which dependably complies with such maximum contaminant levels; including accepted methods for quality control and testing procedures to insure compliance with such levels and to insure proper operation and maintenance of the system, and requirements as to (i) the minimum quality of water which may be taken into the system and (ii) siting for new facilities for public water systems.


At any time after promulgation of a regulation referred to in this paragraph, the Administrator may add equally effective quality control and testing procedures by guidance published in the Federal Register. Such procedures shall be treated as an alternative for public water systems to the quality control and testing procedures listed in the regulation.

(2) The term “secondary drinking water regulation” means a regulation which applies to public water systems and which specifies the maximum contaminant levels which, in the judgment of the Administrator, are requisite to protect the public welfare. Such regulations may apply to any contaminant in drinki</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “primary drinking water regulation” means a regulation which— At any time after promulgation of a regulation referred to in this paragraph, the Administrator may add equally effective quality control and testing procedures by guidance published in the Federal Register. Such procedures shall be treated as an alternative for public water systems to the quality control and testing procedures listed in the regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “secondary drinking water regulation” means a regulation which applies to public water systems and which specifies the maximum contaminant levels which, in the judgment of the Administrator, are requisite to protect the public welfare. Such regulations may apply to any contaminant in drinking water (A) which may adversely affect the odor or appearance of such water and consequently may cause a substantial number of the persons served by the public water system providing such water to discontinue its use, or (B) which may otherwise adversely affect the public welfare. Such regulations may vary according to geographic and other circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “maximum contaminant level” means the maximum permissible level of a contaminant in water which is delivered to any user of a public water system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public water system.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “supplier of water” means any person who owns or operates a public water system.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “contaminant” means any physical, chemical, biological, or radiological substance or matter in water.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “Agency” means the Environmental Protection Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “Council” means the National Drinking Water Advisory Council established under section 300j–5 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300f_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “municipality” means a city, town, or other public body created by or pursuant to State law, or an Indian Tribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>