<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–33" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–33/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–33/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_33"><akn:num>300ff–33</akn:num><akn:heading>Early diagnosis grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–33. Early diagnosis grant program(a) In generalIn the case of States whose laws or regulations are in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall make grants to such States for the purposes described in subsection (c).


(b) Description of compliant StatesFor purposes of subsection (a), the laws or regulations of a State are in accordance with this subsection if, under such laws or regulations (including programs carried out pursuant to the discretion of State officials), both of the policies described in paragraph (1) are in effect, or both of the policies described in paragraph (2) are in effect, as follows:(1)(A) Voluntary opt-out testing of pregnant women.

(B) Universal testing of newborns.


(2)(A) Voluntary opt-out testing of clients at sexually transmitted disease clinics.

(B) Voluntary opt-out testing of clients at substance abuse treatment centers.



The Secretary shall periodically ensure that the applicable policies are being carried out and recertify compliance.

(c) Use of fundsA State may use funds provided under subsection (a) for HIV/AIDS testing (including rapid testing), prevention counseling, treatment of newborns exposed to HIV/AIDS, treatment of mothers infected with HIV/AIDS, and costs associated with linking those diagnosed with HIV/AIDS to care and treatment for HIV/AIDS.


(d) ApplicationA State that is eligible for the grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary, in such form, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.


(e) Limitation on amount of grantA grant under subsection (a) to a State for a fiscal year may not be made in an amount exceeding $10,000,000.


(f) Rule of constructionNothing in this section shall be construed to pre-empt State laws regarding HIV/AIDS counseling and testing.


(g) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) The term “voluntary opt-out testing” means HIV/AIDS testing—(A) that</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In the case of States whose laws or regulations are in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall make grants to such States for the purposes described in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Description of compliant States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Description of compliant States For purposes of subsection (a), the laws or regulations of a State are in accordance with this subsection if, under such laws or regulations (including programs carried out pursuant to the discretion of State officials), both of the policies described in paragraph (1) are in effect, or both of the policies described in paragraph (2) are in effect, as follows: The Secretary shall periodically ensure that the applicable policies are being carried out and recertify compliance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds A State may use funds provided under subsection (a) for HIV/AIDS testing (including rapid testing), prevention counseling, treatment of newborns exposed to HIV/AIDS, treatment of mothers infected with HIV/AIDS, and costs associated with linking those diagnosed with HIV/AIDS to care and treatment for HIV/AIDS.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application A State that is eligible for the grant under subsection (a) shall submit an application to the Secretary, in such form, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitation on amount of grant A grant under subsection (a) to a State for a fiscal year may not be made in an amount exceeding $10,000,000.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rule of construction Nothing in this section shall be construed to pre-empt State laws regarding HIV/AIDS counseling and testing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_33_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization of appropriations Of the funds appropriated annually to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for HIV/AIDS prevention activities, $30,000,000 shall be made available for each of the fiscal years 2007 through 2009 for grants under subsection (a), of which $20,000,000 shall be made available for grants to States with the policies described in subsection (b)(1), and $10,000,000 shall be made available for grants to States with the policies described in subsection (b)(2). Funds provided under this section are available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>