<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–133" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–133/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–133/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_133"><akn:num>300ff–133</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for notification with respect to victims assisted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–133. Request for notification with respect to victims assisted(a) Initiation of process by employeeIf an emergency response employee believes that the employee may have been exposed to an infectious disease by a victim of an emergency who was transported to a medical facility as a result of the emergency, and if the employee attended, treated, assisted, or transported the victim pursuant to the emergency, then the designated officer of the employee shall, upon the request of the employee, carry out the duties described in subsection (b) regarding a determination of whether the employee may have been exposed to an infectious disease by the victim.


(b) Initial determination by designated officerThe duties referred to in subsection (a) are that—(1) the designated officer involved collect the facts relating to the circumstances under which, for purposes of subsection (a), the employee involved may have been exposed to an infectious disease; and

(2) the designated officer evaluate such facts and make a determination of whether, if the victim involved had any infectious disease included on the list issued under paragraph (1) of section 300ff–131(a) of this title, the employee would have been exposed to the disease under such facts, as indicated by the guidelines issued under paragraph (2) of such section.


(c) Submission of request to medical facility(1) In generalIf a designated officer makes a determination under subsection (b)(2) that an emergency response employee may have been exposed to an infectious disease, the designated officer shall submit to the medical facility to which the victim involved was transported a request for a response under subsection (d) regarding the victim of the emergency involved.


(2) Form of requestA request under paragraph (1) shall be in writing and be signed by the designated officer involved, and shall contain a statement of the facts collected pursuant to subsection (b)(1).



(d) Evaluation and response regarding request </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initiation of process by employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Initiation of process by employee If an emergency response employee believes that the employee may have been exposed to an infectious disease by a victim of an emergency who was transported to a medical facility as a result of the emergency, and if the employee attended, treated, assisted, or transported the victim pursuant to the emergency, then the designated officer of the employee shall, upon the request of the employee, carry out the duties described in subsection (b) regarding a determination of whether the employee may have been exposed to an infectious disease by the victim.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial determination by designated officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Initial determination by designated officer The duties referred to in subsection (a) are that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission of request to medical facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Submission of request to medical facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation and response regarding request to medical facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation and response regarding request to medical facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for making response</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Time for making response After receiving a request under subsection (c) (including any such request resubmitted under subsection (g)(2)), a medical facility shall make the applicable response specified in subsection (d) as soon as is practicable, but not later than 48 hours after receiving the request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Death of victim of emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Death of victim of emergency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_133_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance of public health officer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Assistance of public health officer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>