<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–23" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–23/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–23/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_23"><akn:num>300ff–23</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to establish HIV care consortia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–23. Grants to establish HIV care consortia(a) ConsortiaA State may, subject to subsection (f), use amounts provided under a grant awarded under section 300ff–21 of this title to provide assistance under section 300ff–22(a) of this title to an entity that—(1) is an association of one or more public, and one or more nonprofit private,11 So in original. The comma probably should follow parenthetical phrase. (or private for-profit providers or organizations if such entities are the only available providers of quality HIV care in the area) 1 health care and support service providers and community based organizations operating within areas determined by the State to be most affected by HIV/AIDS; and

(2) agrees to use such assistance for the planning, development and delivery, through the direct provision of services or through entering into agreements with other entities for the provision of such services, of comprehensive outpatient health and support services for individuals with HIV/AIDS, that may include—(A) essential health services such as case management services, medical, nursing, substance abuse treatment, mental health treatment, and dental care, diagnostics, monitoring, prophylactic treatment for opportunistic infections, treatment education to take place in the context of health care delivery, and medical follow-up services, mental health, developmental, and rehabilitation services, home health and hospice care; and

(B) essential support services such as transportation services, attendant care, homemaker services, day or respite care, benefits advocacy, advocacy services provided through public and nonprofit private entities, and services that are incidental to the provision of health care services for individuals with HIV/AIDS including nutrition services, housing referral services, and child welfare and family services (including foster care and adoption services).



An entity or entities of the type described in this subsection shall hereinafter </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consortia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consortia A State may, subject to subsection (f), use amounts provided under a grant awarded under section 300ff–21 of this title to provide assistance under section 300ff–22(a) of this title to an entity that— An entity or entities of the type described in this subsection shall hereinafter be referred to in this subchapter as a “consortium” or “consortia”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assurances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Family centered care” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Family centered care” defined As used in section 300ff–21 of this title, the term “family centered care” means the system of services described in this section that is targeted specifically to the special needs of infants, children, women, and families. Family centered care shall be based on a partnership between parents, professionals, and the community designed to ensure an integrated, coordinated, culturally sensitive, and community-based continuum of care for children, women, and families with HIV/AIDS.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority In providing assistance under subsection (a), the State shall, among applicants that meet the requirements of this section, give priority—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_23_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds; treatment as support services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation of funds; treatment as support services For purposes of the requirement of section 300ff–22(b)(1) of this title, expenditures of grants under section 300ff–21 of this title for or through consortia under this section are deemed to be support services, not core medical services. The preceding sentence may not be construed as having any legal effect on the provisions of subsection (a) that relate to authorized expenditures of the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>