<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–66" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–66/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–66/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_66"><akn:num>300ff–66</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision by Secretary of supplies and services in lieu of grant funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–66. Provision by Secretary of supplies and services in lieu of grant funds(a) In generalUpon the request of a grantee under this part, the Secretary may, subject to subsection (b), provide supplies, equipment, and services for the purpose of aiding the grantee in providing early intervention services and, for such purpose, may detail to the State any officer or employee of the Department of Health and Human Services.


(b) LimitationWith respect to a request described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall reduce the amount of payments under the grant involved by an amount equal to the costs of detailing personnel and the fair market value of any supplies, equipment, or services provided by the Secretary. The Secretary shall, for the payment of expenses incurred in complying with such request, expend the amounts withheld.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVI, § 2666, as added Pub. L. 101–381, title III, § 301(a), Aug. 18, 1990, 104 Stat. 614; amended Pub. L. 109–415, title VII, § 703, Dec. 19, 2006, 120 Stat. 2820; Pub. L. 111–87, § 2(a)(1), (3)(A), Oct. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 2885.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2009—Pub. L. 111–87 repealed Pub. L. 109–415, § 703, and revived the provisions of this section as in effect on Sept. 30, 2009. See 2006 Amendment note and Effective Date of 2009 Amendment; Revival of Section note below.
2006—Pub. L. 109–415, § 703, which directed repeal of this section effective Oct. 1, 2009, was itself repealed by Pub. L. 111–87, § 2(a)(1), effective Sept. 30, 2009.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2009 Amendment; Revival of SectionFor provisions that repeal by section 2(a)(1) of Pub. L. 111–87 of section 703 of Pub. L. 109–415 be effective Sept. 30, 2009, and that the provisions of this section as in effect on Sept. 30, 2009, be revived, see section 2(a)(2), (3)(A) of Pub. L. 111–87, set out as a note under section 300ff–11 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_66_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Upon the request of a grantee under this part, the Secretary may, subject to subsection (b), provide supplies, equipment, and services for the purpose of aiding the grantee in providing early intervention services and, for such purpose, may detail to the State any officer or employee of the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_66_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation With respect to a request described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall reduce the amount of payments under the grant involved by an amount equal to the costs of detailing personnel and the fair market value of any supplies, equipment, or services provided by the Secretary. The Secretary shall, for the payment of expenses incurred in complying with such request, expend the amounts withheld.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>