<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–83" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–83/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–83/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_83"><akn:num>300ff–83</akn:num><akn:heading>Public health emergency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–83. Public health emergency(a) In generalIn an emergency area and during an emergency period, the Secretary shall have the authority to waive such requirements of this subchapter to improve the health and safety of those receiving care under this subchapter and the general public, except that the Secretary may not expend more than 5 percent of the funds allocated under this subchapter for sections 300ff–29a of this title and section 11 So in original. The word “section” probably should not appear. 300ff–13(b) of this title.


(b) Emergency area and emergency periodIn this section:(1) Emergency areaThe term “emergency area” means a geographic area in which there exists—(A) an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act [50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.] or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act [42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.]; or

(B) a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 247d of this title.


(2) Emergency periodThe term “emergency period” means the period in which there exists—(A) an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; or

(B) a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 247d of this title.



(c) Unobligated fundsIf funds under a grant under this section are not expended for an emergency in the fiscal year in which the emergency is declared, such funds shall be returned to the Secretary for reallocation under sections 300ff–13(b) and 300ff–29a of this title.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVI, § 2683, as added and amended Pub. L. 109–415, title V, § 501, title VII, § 703, Dec. 19, 2006, 120 Stat. 2813, 2820; Pub. L. 111–87, § 2(a)(1), (3)(A), Oct. 30, 2009, 123 Stat. 2885.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe National Emergencies Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A), (2)(A), is Pub. L. 94–412, Sept. 14, 1976, 9</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_83_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In an emergency area and during an emergency period, the Secretary shall have the authority to waive such requirements of this subchapter to improve the health and safety of those receiving care under this subchapter and the general public, except that the Secretary may not expend more than 5 percent of the funds allocated under this subchapter for sections 300ff–29a of this title and section 11 So in original. The word “section” probably should not appear. 300ff–13(b) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_83_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency area and emergency period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emergency area and emergency period In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_83_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unobligated funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Unobligated funds If funds under a grant under this section are not expended for an emergency in the fiscal year in which the emergency is declared, such funds shall be returned to the Secretary for reallocation under sections 300ff–13(b) and 300ff–29a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>