<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–20" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–20/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–20/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_20"><akn:num>300ff–20</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–20. Authorization of appropriations(a) In generalFor the purpose of carrying out this part, there are authorized to be appropriated $604,000,000 for fiscal year 2007, $626,300,000 for fiscal year 2008, $649,500,000 for fiscal year 2009, $681,975,000 for fiscal year 2010, $716,074,000 for fiscal year 2011, $751,877,000 for fiscal year 2012, and $789,471,000 for fiscal year 2013. Amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence for a fiscal year are available for obligation by the Secretary until the end of the second succeeding fiscal year.


(b) Reservation of amounts(1) Fiscal year 2007Of the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2007, the Secretary shall reserve—(A) $458,310,000 for grants under subpart I; and

(B) $145,690,000 for grants under section 300ff–19 of this title.


(2) Subsequent fiscal yearsOf the amount appropriated under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2008 and each subsequent fiscal year—(A) the Secretary shall reserve an amount for grants under subpart I; and

(B) the Secretary shall reserve an amount for grants under section 300ff–19 of this title.



(c) Transfer of certain amounts; change in status as eligible area or transitional areaNotwithstanding subsection (b):(1) If a metropolitan area is an eligible area under subpart I for a fiscal year, but for a subsequent fiscal year ceases to be an eligible area by reason of section 300ff–11(b) of this title—(A)(i) the amount reserved under paragraph (1)(A) or (2)(A) of subsection (b) of this section for the first such subsequent year of not being an eligible area is deemed to be reduced by an amount equal to the amount of the grant made pursuant to section 300ff–13(a) of this title for the metropolitan area for the preceding fiscal year; and

(ii)(I) if the metropolitan area qualifies for such first subsequent fiscal year as a transitional area under 300ff–19 11 So in original. Probably should be preceded by “section”. of this title, the amount reserved under paragraph (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_20_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the purpose of carrying out this part, there are authorized to be appropriated $604,000,000 for fiscal year 2007, $626,300,000 for fiscal year 2008, $649,500,000 for fiscal year 2009, $681,975,000 for fiscal year 2010, $716,074,000 for fiscal year 2011, $751,877,000 for fiscal year 2012, and $789,471,000 for fiscal year 2013. Amounts appropriated under the preceding sentence for a fiscal year are available for obligation by the Secretary until the end of the second succeeding fiscal year.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_20_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reservation of amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_20_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of certain amounts; change in status as eligible area or transitional area</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Transfer of certain amounts; change in status as eligible area or transitional area Notwithstanding subsection (b):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_20_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain transfers; allocations between programs under subpart I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certain transfers; allocations between programs under subpart I With respect to paragraphs (1)(B)(i) and (2)(A)(ii) of subsection (c), the Secretary shall administer any reductions under such paragraphs for a fiscal year in accordance with the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_20_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules of construction regarding first subsequent fiscal year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules of construction regarding first subsequent fiscal year Paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (c) apply with respect to each series of fiscal years during which a metropolitan area is an eligible area under subpart I or a transitional area under section 300ff–19 of this title for a fiscal year and then for a subsequent fiscal year ceases to be such an area by reason of section 300ff–11(b) or 300ff–19(c)(2) of this title, respectively, rather than applying to a single such series. Paragraph (3) of subsection (c) applies with respect to each series of fiscal years during which a metropolitan area is a transitional area under section 300ff–19 of this title for a fiscal year and then for a subsequent fiscal year becomes an eligible area under subpart I, rather than applying to a single such series.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>