<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–19" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–19/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ff–19/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ff_19"><akn:num>300ff–19</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ff–19. Establishment of program(a) In generalThe Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make grants for the purpose of providing services described in section 300ff–14 of this title in transitional areas, subject to the same provisions regarding the allocation of grant funds as apply under subsection (c) of such section.


(b) Transitional areasFor purposes of this section, the term “transitional area” means, subject to subsection (c), a metropolitan area for which there has been reported to and confirmed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention a cumulative total of at least 1,000, but fewer than 2,000, cases of AIDS during the most recent period of 5 calendar years for which such data are available.


(c) Certain eligibility rules(1) Fiscal year 2011With respect to grants under subsection (a) for fiscal year 2011, a metropolitan area that received funding under subpart I for fiscal year 2010 but does not for fiscal year 2011 qualify under such subpart as an eligible area and does not qualify under subsection (b) as a transitional area shall, notwithstanding subsection (b), be considered a transitional area.


(2) Continued status as transitional area(A) In generalNotwithstanding subsection (b), a metropolitan area that is a transitional area for a fiscal year continues, except as provided in subparagraph (B), to be a transitional area until the metropolitan area fails, for three consecutive fiscal years—(i) to qualify under such subsection as a transitional area; and

(ii) subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), to have a cumulative total of 1,500 or more living cases of AIDS (reported to and confirmed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention) as of December 31 of the most recent calendar year for which such data is available.


(B) Permitting margin of error applicable to certain metropolitan areasIn applying subparagraph (A)(ii) for a fiscal year </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_19_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall make grants for the purpose of providing services described in section 300ff–14 of this title in transitional areas, subject to the same provisions regarding the allocation of grant funds as apply under subsection (c) of such section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_19_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transitional areas For purposes of this section, the term “transitional area” means, subject to subsection (c), a metropolitan area for which there has been reported to and confirmed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention a cumulative total of at least 1,000, but fewer than 2,000, cases of AIDS during the most recent period of 5 calendar years for which such data are available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_19_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain eligibility rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Certain eligibility rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ff_19_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of certain provisions of subpart I</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application of certain provisions of subpart I</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>