<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_6"><akn:num>300gg–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive health insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–6. Comprehensive health insurance coverage(a) Coverage for essential health benefits packageA health insurance issuer that offers health insurance coverage in the individual or small group market shall ensure that such coverage includes the essential health benefits package required under section 18022(a) of this title.


(b) Cost-sharing under group health plansA group health plan shall ensure that any annual cost-sharing imposed under the plan does not exceed the limitations provided for under paragraph (1) of section 18022(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.


(c) Child-only plansIf a health insurance issuer offers health insurance coverage in any level of coverage specified under section 18022(d) of this title, the issuer shall also offer such coverage in that level as a plan in which the only enrollees are individuals who, as of the beginning of a plan year, have not attained the age of 21.


(d) Dental onlyThis section shall not apply to a plan described in section 18031(d)(2)(B)(ii) 1 of this title.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2707, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1201(4), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 161; amended Pub. L. 113–93, title II, § 213(b), Apr. 1, 2014, 128 Stat. 1047.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 18022(c) of this title, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “section 1302(c)”, and was translated as meaning section 1302(c) of Pub. L. 111–148, par. (1) of which relates to annual limitation on cost-sharing, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.
Section 18031(d)(2)(B)(ii) of this title, referred to in subsec. (d), was in the original “section 1302(d)(2)(B)(ii)(I)”, and was translated as meaning section 1311(d)(2)(B)(ii) of Pub. L. 111–148, which relates to offering of stand-alone dental benefits, to reflect the probable intent of Congress.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 300gg–6, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2706, as added Pub. L. 105–277, div. A, § 101(f) [title IX,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage for essential health benefits package</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coverage for essential health benefits package A health insurance issuer that offers health insurance coverage in the individual or small group market shall ensure that such coverage includes the essential health benefits package required under section 18022(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-sharing under group health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Cost-sharing under group health plans A group health plan shall ensure that any annual cost-sharing imposed under the plan does not exceed the limitations provided for under paragraph (1) of section 18022(c) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Child-only plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Child-only plans If a health insurance issuer offers health insurance coverage in any level of coverage specified under section 18022(d) of this title, the issuer shall also offer such coverage in that level as a plan in which the only enrollees are individuals who, as of the beginning of a plan year, have not attained the age of 21.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dental only</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Dental only This section shall not apply to a plan described in section 18031(d)(2)(B)(ii) 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>