<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300g_1"><akn:num>300g–1</akn:num><akn:heading>National drinking water regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300g–1. National drinking water regulations(a) National primary drinking water regulations; maximum contaminant level goals; simultaneous publication of regulations and goals(1) Effective on June 19, 1986, each national interim or revised primary drinking water regulation promulgated under this section before June 19, 1986, shall be deemed to be a national primary drinking water regulation under subsection (b). No such regulation shall be required to comply with the standards set forth in subsection (b)(4) unless such regulation is amended to establish a different maximum contaminant level after June 19, 1986.

(2) After June 19, 1986, each recommended maximum contaminant level published before June 19, 1986, shall be treated as a maximum contaminant level goal.

(3) Whenever a national primary drinking water regulation is proposed under subsection (b) for any contaminant, the maximum contaminant level goal for such contaminant shall be proposed simultaneously. Whenever a national primary drinking water regulation is promulgated under subsection (b) for any contaminant, the maximum contaminant level goal for such contaminant shall be published simultaneously.

(4) Paragraph (3) shall not apply to any recommended maximum contaminant level published before June 19, 1986.


(b) Standards(1) Identification of contaminants for listing.—(A) General authority.—The Administrator shall, in accordance with the procedures established by this subsection, publish a maximum contaminant level goal and promulgate a national primary drinking water regulation for a contaminant (other than a contaminant referred to in paragraph (2) for which a national primary drinking water regulation has been promulgated as of August 6, 1996) if the Administrator determines that—(i) the contaminant may have an adverse effect on the health of persons;

(ii) the contaminant is known to occur or there is a substantial likelihood that the contaminant will occur in public water systems with a frequency</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>National primary drinking water regulations; maximum contaminant level goals; simultaneous publication of regulations and goals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) National primary drinking water regulations; maximum contaminant level goals; simultaneous publication of regulations and goals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secondary regulations; publication of proposed regulations; promulgation; amendments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secondary regulations; publication of proposed regulations; promulgation; amendments The Administrator shall publish proposed national secondary drinking water regulations within 270 days after December 16, 1974. Within 90 days after publication of any such regulation, he shall promulgate such regulation with such modifications as he deems appropriate. Regulations under this subsection may be amended from time to time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; public hearings; administrative consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations; public hearings; administrative consultations Regulations under this section shall be prescribed in accordance with section 553 of title 5 (relating to rulemaking), except that the Administrator shall provide opportunity for public hearing prior to promulgation of such regulations. In proposing and promulgating regulations under this section, the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary and the National Drinking Water Advisory Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Science Advisory Board comments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Science Advisory Board comments The Administrator shall request comments from the Science Advisory Board (established under the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1978) prior to proposal of a maximum contaminant level goal and national primary drinking water regulation. The Board shall respond, as it deems appropriate, within the time period applicable for promulgation of the national primary drinking water standard concerned. This subsection shall, under no circumstances, be used to delay final promulgation of any national primary drinking water standard.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>