<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–46" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–46/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–46/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_46"><akn:num>300gg–46</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to enrollees of individual market coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–46. Disclosure to enrollees of individual market coverage(a) In generalA health insurance issuer offering individual health insurance coverage or a health insurance issuer offering short-term limited duration insurance coverage shall make disclosures to enrollees in such coverage, as described in subsection (b), and reports to the Secretary, as described in subsection (c), regarding direct or indirect compensation provided by the issuer to an agent or broker associated with enrolling individuals in such coverage.


(b) DisclosureA health insurance issuer described in subsection (a) shall disclose to an enrollee the amount of direct or indirect compensation provided to an agent or broker for services provided by such agent or broker associated with plan selection and enrollment. Such disclosure shall be—(1) made prior to the individual finalizing plan selection; and

(2) included on any documentation confirming the individual’s enrollment.


(c) ReportingA health insurance issuer described in subsection (a) shall annually report to the Secretary, prior to the beginning of open enrollment, any direct or indirect compensation provided to an agent or broker associated with enrolling individuals in such coverage.


(d) RulemakingNot later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall finalize, through notice-and-comment rulemaking, the timing, form, and manner in which issuers described in subsection (a) are required to make the disclosures described in subsection (b) and the reports described in subsection (c). Such rulemaking may also include adjustments to notice requirements to reflect the different processes for plan renewals, in order to provide enrollees with full, timely information.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2746, as added Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title II, § 202(c), Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2899.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection applicable beginning 1 year after Dec. 27, 2020, see section 202(e)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_46_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A health insurance issuer offering individual health insurance coverage or a health insurance issuer offering short-term limited duration insurance coverage shall make disclosures to enrollees in such coverage, as described in subsection (b), and reports to the Secretary, as described in subsection (c), regarding direct or indirect compensation provided by the issuer to an agent or broker associated with enrolling individuals in such coverage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_46_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosure A health insurance issuer described in subsection (a) shall disclose to an enrollee the amount of direct or indirect compensation provided to an agent or broker for services provided by such agent or broker associated with plan selection and enrollment. Such disclosure shall be—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_46_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting A health insurance issuer described in subsection (a) shall annually report to the Secretary, prior to the beginning of open enrollment, any direct or indirect compensation provided to an agent or broker associated with enrolling individuals in such coverage.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_46_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rulemaking</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rulemaking Not later than 1 year after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall finalize, through notice-and-comment rulemaking, the timing, form, and manner in which issuers described in subsection (a) are required to make the disclosures described in subsection (b) and the reports described in subsection (c). Such rulemaking may also include adjustments to notice requirements to reflect the different processes for plan renewals, in order to provide enrollees with full, timely information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>