<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–93" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–93/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–93/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_93"><akn:num>300gg–93</akn:num><akn:heading>Health insurance consumer information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–93. Health insurance consumer information(a) In generalThe Secretary shall award grants to States to enable such States (or the Exchanges operating in such States) to establish, expand, or provide support for—(1) offices of health insurance consumer assistance; or

(2) health insurance ombudsman programs.


(b) Eligibility(1) In generalTo be eligible to receive a grant, a State shall designate an independent office of health insurance consumer assistance, or an ombudsman, that, directly or in coordination with State health insurance regulators and consumer assistance organizations, receives and responds to inquiries and complaints concerning health insurance coverage with respect to Federal health insurance requirements and under State law.


(2) CriteriaA State that receives a grant under this section shall comply with criteria established by the Secretary for carrying out activities under such grant.



(c) DutiesThe office of health insurance consumer assistance or health insurance ombudsman shall—(1) assist with the filing of complaints and appeals, including filing appeals with the internal appeal or grievance process of the group health plan or health insurance issuer involved and providing information about the external appeal process;

(2) collect, track, and quantify problems and inquiries encountered by consumers;

(3) educate consumers on their rights and responsibilities with respect to group health plans and health insurance coverage;

(4) assist consumers with enrollment in a group health plan or health insurance coverage by providing information, referral, and assistance; and

(5) resolve problems with obtaining premium tax credits under section 36B of title 26.


(d) Data collectionAs a condition of receiving a grant under subsection (a), an office of health insurance consumer assistance or ombudsman program shall be required to collect and report data to the Secretary on the types of problems and inquiries encountered by consumers. The Secre</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_93_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall award grants to States to enable such States (or the Exchanges operating in such States) to establish, expand, or provide support for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_93_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_93_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The office of health insurance consumer assistance or health insurance ombudsman shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_93_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Data collection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Data collection As a condition of receiving a grant under subsection (a), an office of health insurance consumer assistance or ombudsman program shall be required to collect and report data to the Secretary on the types of problems and inquiries encountered by consumers. The Secretary shall utilize such data to identify areas where more enforcement action is necessary and shall share such information with State insurance regulators, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of the Treasury for use in the enforcement activities of such agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_93_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>