<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300g_6"><akn:num>300g–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of lead pipes, solder, and flux</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300g–6. Prohibition on use of lead pipes, solder, and flux(a) In general(1) Prohibitions(A) In generalNo person may use any pipe, any pipe or plumbing fitting or fixture, any solder, or any flux, after June 19, 1986, in the installation or repair of—(i) any public water system; or

(ii) any plumbing in a residential or nonresidential facility providing water for human consumption,


that is not lead free (within the meaning of subsection (d)).

(B) Leaded jointsSubparagraph (A) shall not apply to leaded joints necessary for the repair of cast iron pipes.



(2) Public notice requirements(A) In generalEach owner or operator of a public water system shall identify and provide notice to persons that may be affected by lead contamination of their drinking water where such contamination results from either or both of the following:(i) The lead content in the construction materials of the public water distribution system.

(ii) Corrosivity of the water supply sufficient to cause leaching of lead.


The notice shall be provided in such manner and form as may be reasonably required by the Administrator. Notice under this paragraph shall be provided notwithstanding the absence of a violation of any national drinking water standard.

(B) Contents of noticeNotice under this paragraph shall provide a clear and readily understandable explanation of—(i) the potential sources of lead in the drinking water,

(ii) potential adverse health effects,

(iii) reasonably available methods of mitigating known or potential lead content in drinking water,

(iv) any steps the system is taking to mitigate lead content in drinking water, and

(v) the necessity for seeking alternative water supplies, if any.



(3) Unlawful actsEffective 2 years after August 6, 1996, it shall be unlawful—(A) for any person to introduce into commerce any pipe, or any pipe or plumbing fitting or fixture, that is not lead free, except for a pipe that is used in manufacturing or industrial processing;

(B) for any</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Penalties If the Administrator determines that a State is not enforcing the requirements of subsection (a) as required pursuant to subsection (b), the Administrator may withhold up to 5 percent of Federal funds available to that State for State program grants under section 300j–2(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of lead free</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Definition of lead free</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Plumbing fittings and fixtures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Plumbing fittings and fixtures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_6_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public education</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Public education</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>