<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–53" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–53/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–53/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_53"><akn:num>300gg–53</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of health discrimination on the basis of genetic information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–53. Prohibition of health discrimination on the basis of genetic information(a) Prohibition on genetic information as a condition of eligibility(1) In generalA health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in the individual market may not establish rules for the eligibility (including continued eligibility) of any individual to enroll in individual health insurance coverage based on genetic information.


(2) Rule of constructionNothing in paragraph (1) or in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) shall be construed to preclude a health insurance issuer from establishing rules for eligibility for an individual to enroll in individual health insurance coverage based on the manifestation of a disease or disorder in that individual, or in a family member of such individual where such family member is covered under the policy that covers such individual.



(b) Prohibition on genetic information in setting premium rates(1) In generalA health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in the individual market shall not adjust premium or contribution amounts for an individual on the basis of genetic information concerning the individual or a family member of the individual.


(2) Rule of constructionNothing in paragraph (1) or in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (e) shall be construed to preclude a health insurance issuer from adjusting premium or contribution amounts for an individual on the basis of a manifestation of a disease or disorder in that individual, or in a family member of such individual where such family member is covered under the policy that covers such individual. In such case, the manifestation of a disease or disorder in one individual cannot also be used as genetic information about other individuals covered under the policy issued to such individual and to further increase premiums or contribution amounts.



(c) Prohibition on genetic information as preexisting condition(1) In generalA health insurance issuer offe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on genetic information as a condition of eligibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition on genetic information as a condition of eligibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on genetic information in setting premium rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition on genetic information in setting premium rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on genetic information as preexisting condition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition on genetic information as preexisting condition</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Genetic testing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Genetic testing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on collection of genetic information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prohibition on collection of genetic information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_53_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Genetic information of a fetus or embryo</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Genetic information of a fetus or embryo Any reference in this part to genetic information concerning an individual or family member of an individual shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>