<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–18" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–18/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–18/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_18"><akn:num>300gg–18</akn:num><akn:heading>Bringing down the cost of health care coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–18. Bringing down the cost of health care coverage(a) Clear accounting for costsA health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage (including a grandfathered health plan) shall, with respect to each plan year, submit to the Secretary a report concerning the ratio of the incurred loss (or incurred claims) plus the loss adjustment expense (or change in contract reserves) to earned premiums. Such report shall include the percentage of total premium revenue, after accounting for collections or receipts for risk adjustment and risk corridors and payments of reinsurance, that such coverage expends—(1) on reimbursement for clinical services provided to enrollees under such coverage;

(2) for activities that improve health care quality; and

(3) on all other non-claims costs, including an explanation of the nature of such costs, and excluding Federal and State taxes and licensing or regulatory fees.


The Secretary shall make reports received under this section available to the public on the Internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services.

(b) Ensuring that consumers receive value for their premium payments(1) Requirement to provide value for premium payments(A) RequirementBeginning not later than January 1, 2011, a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage (including a grandfathered health plan) shall, with respect to each plan year, provide an annual rebate to each enrollee under such coverage, on a pro rata basis, if the ratio of the amount of premium revenue expended by the issuer on costs described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) to the total amount of premium revenue (excluding Federal and State taxes and licensing or regulatory fees and after accounting for payments or receipts for risk adjustment, risk corridors, and reinsurance under sections 18061, 18062, and 18063 of this title) for the plan year (except as provided in subparagraph (B)(ii)), is less than—(i) wi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_18_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clear accounting for costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Clear accounting for costs A health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage (including a grandfathered health plan) shall, with respect to each plan year, submit to the Secretary a report concerning the ratio of the incurred loss (or incurred claims) plus the loss adjustment expense (or change in contract reserves) to earned premiums. Such report shall include the percentage of total premium revenue, after accounting for collections or receipts for risk adjustment and risk corridors and payments of reinsurance, that such coverage expends— The Secretary shall make reports received under this section available to the public on the Internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_18_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring that consumers receive value for their premium payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Ensuring that consumers receive value for their premium payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_18_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions Not later than December 31, 2010, and subject to the certification of the Secretary, the National Association of Insurance Commissioners shall establish uniform definitions of the activities reported under subsection (a) and standardized methodologies for calculating measures of such activities, including definitions of which activities, and in what regard such activities, constitute activities described in subsection (a)(2). Such methodologies shall be designed to take into account the special circumstances of smaller plans, different types of plans, and newer plans.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_18_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Adjustments The Secretary may adjust the rates described in subsection (b) if the Secretary determines appropriate on account of the volatility of the individual market due to the establishment of State Exchanges.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_18_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard hospital charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Standard hospital charges Each hospital operating within the United States shall for each year establish (and update) and make public (in accordance with guidelines developed by the Secretary) a list of the hospital’s standard charges for items and services provided by the hospital, including for diagnosis-related groups established under section 1395ww(d)(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>