<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–21" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–21/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–21/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_21"><akn:num>300gg–21</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of certain plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–21. Exclusion of certain plans(a) Limitation on application of provisions relating to group health plans(1) In generalThe requirements of subparts 1 and 2 11 See References in Text note below. and part D shall apply with respect to group health plans only—(A) subject to paragraph (2), in the case of a plan that is a nonfederal governmental plan, and

(B) with respect to health insurance coverage offered in connection with a group health plan (including such a plan that is a church plan or a governmental plan).


(2) Treatment of non-Federal governmental plans(A) Election to be excludedExcept as provided in subparagraph (D) or (E), if the plan sponsor of a nonfederal governmental plan which is a group health plan to which the provisions of subparts 1 and 2 1 otherwise apply makes an election under this subparagraph (in such form and manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe), then the requirements of such subparts insofar as they apply directly to group health plans (and not merely to group health insurance coverage) shall not apply to such governmental plans for such period except as provided in this paragraph.


(B) Period of electionAn election under subparagraph (A) shall apply—(i) for a single specified plan year, or

(ii) in the case of a plan provided pursuant to a collective bargaining agreement, for the term of such agreement.


An election under clause (i) may be extended through subsequent elections under this paragraph.

(C) Notice to enrolleesUnder such an election, the plan shall provide for—(i) notice to enrollees (on an annual basis and at the time of enrollment under the plan) of the fact and consequences of such election, and

(ii) certification and disclosure of creditable coverage under the plan with respect to enrollees in accordance with section 2701(e).1


(D) Election not applicable to requirements concerning genetic informationThe election described in subparagraph (A) shall not be available with respect to the provisions o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_21_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on application of provisions relating to group health plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitation on application of provisions relating to group health plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_21_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Exception for certain benefits The requirements of subparts 1 and 2 1 and part D shall not apply to any individual coverage or any group health plan (or group health insurance coverage) in relation to its provision of excepted benefits described in section 300gg–91(c)(1) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_21_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for certain benefits if certain conditions met</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Exception for certain benefits if certain conditions met</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_21_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment of partnerships</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Treatment of partnerships For purposes of this part and part D—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>