<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_12"><akn:num>300gg–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on rescissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–12. Prohibition on rescissions
A group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall not rescind such plan or coverage with respect to an enrollee once the enrollee is covered under such plan or coverage involved, except that this section shall not apply to a covered individual who has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or makes an intentional misrepresentation of material fact as prohibited by the terms of the plan or coverage. Such plan or coverage may not be cancelled except with prior notice to the enrollee, and only as permitted under section 300gg–2(b) 11 See References in Text note below. or 300gg–42(b) of this title.
(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2712, as added Pub. L. 111–148, title I, § 1001(5), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 131.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextSection 300gg–2(b) of this title, referred to in text, was in the original a reference to section “2702(c)” of act July 1, 1944, which was translated as meaning section 2703(b) of act July 1, 1944, to reflect the probable intent of Congress. Section 2702(c), which is classified to section 300gg–1 of this title, relates to special rules for network plans, while section 2703(b) specifies the reasons for which a health insurance issuer may nonrenew or discontinue health insurance coverage offered in connection with a health insurance coverage offering in the group or individual market. Section 300gg–2(b) also parallels section 300gg–42(b) which appears in the same context in this section as the reference to section 300gg–2(b).

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 300gg–12, act July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2712, as added Pub. L. 104–191, title I, § 102(a), Aug. 21, 1996, 110 Stat. 1964, which related to guaranteed renewability of coverage for employers in a group market, was renumbered section 2732 of act July 1, 1944, amended, and transferred to subsecs. (b) to (e) of section 300gg–2 of this title, by Pub. L</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>