<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_9"><akn:num>300gg–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–9. Disclosure of information(a) Disclosure of information by health plan issuersIn connection with the offering of any health insurance coverage to a small employer or an individual, a health insurance issuer—(1) shall make a reasonable disclosure to such employer, or individual, as applicable,,11 So in original. as part of its solicitation and sales materials, of the availability of information described in subsection (b), and

(2) upon request of such a 22 So in original. Probably should be “an”. employer, or individual, as applicable,,1 provide such information.


(b) Information described(1) In generalSubject to paragraph (3), with respect to a health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage to a 2 employer, or individual, as applicable,,1 information described in this subsection is information concerning—(A) the provisions of such coverage concerning issuer’s right to change premium rates and the factors that may affect changes in premium rates; and

(B) the benefits and premiums available under all health insurance coverage for which the employer, or individual, as applicable, is qualified.


(2) Form of informationInformation under this subsection shall be provided to employers, or individuals, as applicable, in a manner determined to be understandable by the average employer, or individual, as applicable,,1 and shall be sufficient to reasonably inform employers, or individuals, as applicable, of their rights and obligations under the health insurance coverage.


(3) ExceptionAn issuer is not required under this section to disclose any information that is proprietary and trade secret information under applicable law.



(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2709, formerly § 2713, as added Pub. L. 104–191, title I, § 102(a), Aug. 21, 1996, 110 Stat. 1966; renumbered § 2733, renumbered § 2709, and amended Pub. L. 111–148, title I, §§ 1001(3), 1563(c)(10), formerly § 1562(c)(10), title X, § 10107(b)(1), Mar. 23, 2010, 124 Stat. 130, 268, 911.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of information by health plan issuers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Disclosure of information by health plan issuers In connection with the offering of any health insurance coverage to a small employer or an individual, a health insurance issuer—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information described</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Information described</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>