<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–22" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–22/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–22/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_22"><akn:num>300gg–22</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–22. Enforcement(a) State enforcement(1) State authoritySubject to section 300gg–23 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, each State may require that health insurance issuers that issue, sell, renew, or offer health insurance coverage in the State in the individual or group market meet the requirements of this part and part D with respect to such issuers.


(2) Failure to implement provisionsIn the case of a determination by the Secretary that a State has failed to substantially enforce a provision (or provisions) in this part or part D with respect to health insurance issuers in the State, the Secretary shall enforce such provision (or provisions) under subsection (b) insofar as they relate to the issuance, sale, renewal, and offering of health insurance coverage in connection with group health plans or individual health insurance coverage in such State.



(b) Secretarial enforcement authority(1) LimitationThe provisions of this subsection shall apply to enforcement of a provision (or provisions) of this part or part D only—(A) as provided under subsection (a)(2); and

(B) with respect to individual health insurance coverage or group health plans that are non-Federal governmental plans.


(2) Imposition of penaltiesIn the cases described in paragraph (1)—(A) In generalSubject to the succeeding provisions of this subsection, any non-Federal governmental plan that is a group health plan and any health insurance issuer that fails to meet a provision of this part or part D applicable to such plan or issuer is subject to a civil money penalty under this subsection.


(B) Liability for penaltyIn the case of a failure by—(i) a health insurance issuer, the issuer is liable for such penalty, or

(ii) a group health plan that is a non-Federal governmental plan which is—(I) sponsored by 2 or more employers, the plan is liable for such penalty, or

(II) not so sponsored, the employer is liable for such penalty.



(C) Amount of penalty(i) In generalThe m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_22_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_22_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial enforcement authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Secretarial enforcement authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>