<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300g_9"><akn:num>300g–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Capacity development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300g–9. Capacity development(a) State authority for new systemsA State shall receive only 80 percent of the allotment that the State is otherwise entitled to receive under section 300j–12 of this title (relating to State loan funds) unless the State has obtained the legal authority or other means to ensure that all new community water systems and new nontransient, noncommunity water systems commencing operation after October 1, 1999, demonstrate technical, managerial, and financial capacity with respect to each national primary drinking water regulation in effect, or likely to be in effect, on the date of commencement of operations.


(b) Systems in significant noncompliance(1) ListBeginning not later than 1 year after August 6, 1996, each State shall prepare, periodically update, and submit to the Administrator a list of community water systems and nontransient, noncommunity water systems that have a history of significant noncompliance with this subchapter (as defined in guidelines issued prior to August 6, 1996, or any revisions of the guidelines that have been made in consultation with the States) and, to the extent practicable, the reasons for noncompliance.


(2) ReportNot later than 5 years after August 6, 1996, and as part of the capacity development strategy of the State, each State shall report to the Administrator on the success of enforcement mechanisms and initial capacity development efforts in assisting the public water systems listed under paragraph (1) to improve technical, managerial, and financial capacity.


(3) WithholdingThe list and report under this subsection shall be considered part of the capacity development strategy of the State required under subsection (c) of this section for purposes of the withholding requirements of section 300j–12(a)(1)(G)(i) of this title (relating to State loan funds).



(c) Capacity development strategy(1) In generalBeginning 4 years after August 6, 1996, a State shall receive only—(A) 90 percent in fiscal ye</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State authority for new systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State authority for new systems A State shall receive only 80 percent of the allotment that the State is otherwise entitled to receive under section 300j–12 of this title (relating to State loan funds) unless the State has obtained the legal authority or other means to ensure that all new community water systems and new nontransient, noncommunity water systems commencing operation after October 1, 1999, demonstrate technical, managerial, and financial capacity with respect to each national primary drinking water regulation in effect, or likely to be in effect, on the date of commencement of operations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Systems in significant noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Systems in significant noncompliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Capacity development strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Capacity development strategy</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Variances and exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Variances and exemptions Based on information obtained under subsection (c)(3), the Administrator shall, as appropriate, modify regulations concerning variances and exemptions for small public water systems to ensure flexibility in the use of the variances and exemptions. Nothing in this subsection shall be interpreted, construed, or applied to affect or alter the requirements of section 300g–4 or 300g–5 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small public water systems technology assistance centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Small public water systems technology assistance centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_9_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental finance centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Environmental finance centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>