<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–117" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–117/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–117/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_117"><akn:num>300gg–117</akn:num><akn:heading>Other patient protections</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–117. Other patient protections(a) Choice of health care professionalIf a group health plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, requires or provides for designation by a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee of a participating primary care provider, then the plan or issuer shall permit each participant, beneficiary, and enrollee to designate any participating primary care provider who is available to accept such individual.


(b) Access to pediatric care(1) Pediatric careIn the case of a person who has a child who is a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee under a group health plan, or group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, if the plan or issuer requires or provides for the designation of a participating primary care provider for the child, the plan or issuer shall permit such person to designate a physician (allopathic or osteopathic) who specializes in pediatrics as the child’s primary care provider if such provider participates in the network of the plan or issuer.


(2) ConstructionNothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to waive any exclusions of coverage under the terms and conditions of the plan or health insurance coverage with respect to coverage of pediatric care.



(c) Patient access to obstetrical and gynecological care(1) General rights(A) Direct accessA group health plan, or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, described in paragraph (2) may not require authorization or referral by the plan, issuer, or any person (including a primary care provider described in paragraph (2)(B)) in the case of a female participant, beneficiary, or enrollee who seeks coverage for obstetrical or gynecological care provided by a participating health care professional who specializes in obstetrics or gynecology. Such professional shall agree to otherwise adhere to such plan’s or issuer’s policies and procedures, including proc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_117_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Choice of health care professional</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Choice of health care professional If a group health plan, or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, requires or provides for designation by a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee of a participating primary care provider, then the plan or issuer shall permit each participant, beneficiary, and enrollee to designate any participating primary care provider who is available to accept such individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_117_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to pediatric care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Access to pediatric care</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_117_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Patient access to obstetrical and gynecological care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Patient access to obstetrical and gynecological care</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>