<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–136" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–136/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–136/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_136"><akn:num>300gg–136</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of information upon request and for scheduled appointments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–136. Provision of information upon request and for scheduled appointments
Each health care provider and health care facility shall, beginning January 1, 2022, in the case of an individual who schedules an item or service to be furnished to such individual by such provider or facility at least 3 business days before the date such item or service is to be so furnished, not later than 1 business day after the date of such scheduling (or, in the case of such an item or service scheduled at least 10 business days before the date such item or service is to be so furnished (or if requested by the individual), not later than 3 business days after the date of such scheduling or such request)—(1) inquire if such individual is enrolled in a group health plan, group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, or a Federal health care program (and if is so enrolled in such plan or coverage, seeking to have a claim for such item or service submitted to such plan or coverage); and

(2) provide a notification (in clear and understandable language) of the good faith estimate of the expected charges for furnishing such item or service (including any item or service that is reasonably expected to be provided in conjunction with such scheduled item or service and such an item or service reasonably expected to be so provided by another health care provider or health care facility), with the expected billing and diagnostic codes for any such item or service, to—(A) in the case the individual is enrolled in such a plan or such coverage (and is seeking to have a claim for such item or service submitted to such plan or coverage), such plan or issuer of such coverage; and

(B) in the case the individual is not described in subparagraph (A) and not enrolled in a Federal health care program, the individual.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XXVII, § 2799B–6, as added Pub. L. 116–260, div. BB, title I, § 112, Dec. 27, 2020, 134 Stat. 2866.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_136_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) inquire if such individual is enrolled in a group health plan, group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, or a Federal health care program (and if is so enrolled in such plan or coverage, seeking to have a claim for such item or service submitted to such plan or coverage); and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_136_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) provide a notification (in clear and understandable language) of the good faith estimate of the expected charges for furnishing such item or service (including any item or service that is reasonably expected to be provided in conjunction with such scheduled item or service and such an item or service reasonably expected to be so provided by another health care provider or health care facility), with the expected billing and diagnostic codes for any such item or service, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>