<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–42" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–42/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–42/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_42"><akn:num>300gg–42</akn:num><akn:heading>Guaranteed renewability of individual health insurance coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–42. Guaranteed renewability of individual health insurance coverage(a) In generalExcept as provided in this section, a health insurance issuer that provides individual health insurance coverage to an individual shall renew or continue in force such coverage at the option of the individual.


(b) General exceptionsA health insurance issuer may nonrenew or discontinue health insurance coverage of an individual in the individual market based only on one or more of the following:(1) Nonpayment of premiumsThe individual has failed to pay premiums or contributions in accordance with the terms of the health insurance coverage or the issuer has not received timely premium payments.


(2) FraudThe individual has performed an act or practice that constitutes fraud or made an intentional misrepresentation of material fact under the terms of the coverage.


(3) Termination of planThe issuer is ceasing to offer coverage in the individual market in accordance with subsection (c) and applicable State law.


(4) Movement outside service areaIn the case of a health insurance issuer that offers health insurance coverage in the market through a network plan, the individual no longer resides, lives, or works in the service area (or in an area for which the issuer is authorized to do business) but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health status-related factor of covered individuals.


(5) Association membership ceasesIn the case of health insurance coverage that is made available in the individual market only through one or more bona fide associations, the membership of the individual in the association (on the basis of which the coverage is provided) ceases but only if such coverage is terminated under this paragraph uniformly without regard to any health status-related factor of covered individuals.



(c) Requirements for uniform termination of coverage(1) Particular type of coverage not offeredIn any case in which an iss</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_42_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Except as provided in this section, a health insurance issuer that provides individual health insurance coverage to an individual shall renew or continue in force such coverage at the option of the individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_42_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General exceptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General exceptions A health insurance issuer may nonrenew or discontinue health insurance coverage of an individual in the individual market based only on one or more of the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_42_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for uniform termination of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements for uniform termination of coverage</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_42_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exception for uniform modification of coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exception for uniform modification of coverage At the time of coverage renewal, a health insurance issuer may modify the health insurance coverage for a policy form offered to individuals in the individual market so long as such modification is consistent with State law and effective on a uniform basis among all individuals with that policy form.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_42_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application to coverage offered only through associations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application to coverage offered only through associations In applying this section in the case of health insurance coverage that is made available by a health insurance issuer in the individual market to individuals only through one or more associations, a reference to an “individual” is deemed to include a reference to such an association (of which the individual is a member).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>