<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–17" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–17/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–17/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_17"><akn:num>300gg–17</akn:num><akn:heading>Ensuring the quality of care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–17. Ensuring the quality of care(a) Quality reporting(1) In generalNot later than 2 years after March 23, 2010, the Secretary, in consultation with experts in health care quality and stakeholders, shall develop reporting requirements for use by a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, with respect to plan or coverage benefits and health care provider reimbursement structures that—(A) improve health outcomes through the implementation of activities such as quality reporting, effective case management, care coordination, chronic disease management, and medication and care compliance initiatives, including through the use of the medical homes model as defined for purposes of section 3602 11 See References in Text note below. of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, for treatment or services under the plan or coverage;

(B) implement activities to prevent hospital readmissions through a comprehensive program for hospital discharge that includes patient-centered education and counseling, comprehensive discharge planning, and post discharge reinforcement by an appropriate health care professional;

(C) implement activities to improve patient safety and reduce medical errors through the appropriate use of best clinical practices, evidence based medicine, and health information technology under the plan or coverage; and

(D) implement wellness and health promotion activities.


(2) Reporting requirements(A) In generalA group health plan and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall annually submit to the Secretary, and to enrollees under the plan or coverage, a report on whether the benefits under the plan or coverage satisfy the elements described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (1).


(B) Timing of reportsA report under subparagraph (A) shall be made available to an enrollee under the plan or coverage during each open enrollment pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_17_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Quality reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Quality reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_17_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Wellness and prevention programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Wellness and prevention programs For purposes of subsection (a)(1)(D), wellness and health promotion activities may include personalized wellness and prevention services, which are coordinated, maintained or delivered by a health care provider, a wellness and prevention plan manager, or a health, wellness or prevention services organization that conducts health risk assessments or offers ongoing face-to-face, telephonic or web-based intervention efforts for each of the program’s participants, and which may include the following wellness and prevention efforts:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_17_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of Second Amendment gun rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Protection of Second Amendment gun rights</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_17_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Regulations Not later than 2 years after March 23, 2010, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations that provide criteria for determining whether a reimbursement structure is described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_17_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Study and report Not later than 180 days after the date on which regulations are promulgated under subsection (c),22 So in original. Probably should be “subsection (d),”. the Government Accountability Office shall review such regulations and conduct a study and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report regarding the impact the activities under this section have had on the quality and cost of health care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>