<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–41" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–41/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300gg–41/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300gg_41"><akn:num>300gg–41</akn:num><akn:heading>Guaranteed availability of individual health insurance coverage to certain individuals with prior gr</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300gg–41. Guaranteed availability of individual health insurance coverage to certain individuals with prior group coverage(a) Guaranteed availability(1) In generalSubject to the succeeding subsections of this section and section 300gg–44 of this title, each health insurance issuer that offers health insurance coverage (as defined in section 300gg–91(b)(1) of this title) in the individual market in a State may not, with respect to an eligible individual (as defined in subsection (b)) desiring to enroll in individual health insurance coverage—(A) decline to offer such coverage to, or deny enrollment of, such individual; or

(B) impose any preexisting condition exclusion (as defined in section 2701(b)(1)(A)) 11 See References in Text note below. with respect to such coverage.


(2) Substitution by State of acceptable alternative mechanismThe requirement of paragraph (1) shall not apply to health insurance coverage offered in the individual market in a State in which the State is implementing an acceptable alternative mechanism under section 300gg–44 of this title.



(b) “Eligible individual” definedIn this part, the term “eligible individual” means an individual—(1)(A) for whom, as of the date on which the individual seeks coverage under this section, the aggregate of the periods of creditable coverage (as defined in section 2701(c)) 1 is 18 or more months and (B) whose most recent prior creditable coverage was under a group health plan, governmental plan, or church plan (or health insurance coverage offered in connection with any such plan);


(2) who is not eligible for coverage under (A) a group health plan, (B) part A or part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1395c et seq., 1395j et seq.], or (C) a State plan under title XIX of such Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] (or any successor program), and does not have other health insurance coverage;

(3) with respect to whom the most recent coverage within the coverage period described in paragraph (1)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guaranteed availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Guaranteed availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Eligible individual” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) “Eligible individual” defined In this part, the term “eligible individual” means an individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative coverage permitted where no State mechanism</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Alternative coverage permitted where no State mechanism</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules for network plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Special rules for network plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>22 So in original. Two subsecs. (e) have been enacted. Application of financial capacity limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>2 Market requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300gg_41_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Construction Nothing in this section shall be construed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>