<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300g–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300g_7"><akn:num>300g–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Monitoring of contaminants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300g–7. Monitoring of contaminants(a) Interim monitoring relief authority(1) In generalA State exercising primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems may modify the monitoring requirements for any regulated or unregulated contaminants for which monitoring is required other than microbial contaminants (or indicators thereof), disinfectants and disinfection byproducts or corrosion byproducts for an interim period to provide that any public water system serving 10,000 persons or fewer shall not be required to conduct additional quarterly monitoring during an interim relief period for such contaminants if—(A) monitoring, conducted at the beginning of the period for the contaminant concerned and certified to the State by the public water system, fails to detect the presence of the contaminant in the ground or surface water supplying the public water system; and

(B) the State, considering the hydrogeology of the area and other relevant factors, determines in writing that the contaminant is unlikely to be detected by further monitoring during such period.


(2) Termination; timing of monitoringThe interim relief period referred to in paragraph (1) shall terminate when permanent monitoring relief is adopted and approved for such State, or at the end of 36 months after August 6, 1996, whichever comes first. In order to serve as a basis for interim relief, the monitoring conducted at the beginning of the period must occur at the time determined by the State to be the time of the public water system’s greatest vulnerability to the contaminant concerned in the relevant ground or surface water, taking into account in the case of pesticides the time of application of the pesticide for the source water area and the travel time for the pesticide to reach such waters and taking into account, in the case of other contaminants, seasonality of precipitation and contaminant travel time.



(b) Permanent monitoring relief authority(1) In generalEach State exercising pr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim monitoring relief authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Interim monitoring relief authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permanent monitoring relief authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permanent monitoring relief authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment as NPDWR</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Treatment as NPDWR All monitoring relief granted by a State to a public water system for a regulated contaminant under subsection (a) or (b) shall be treated as part of the national primary drinking water regulation for that contaminant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300g_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other monitoring relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Other monitoring relief Nothing in this section shall be construed to affect the authority of the States under applicable national primary drinking water regulations to alter monitoring requirements through waivers or other existing authorities. The Administrator shall periodically review and, as appropriate, revise such authorities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>