<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300h"><akn:num>300h</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations for State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300h. Regulations for State programs(a) Publication of proposed regulations; promulgation; amendments; public hearings; administrative consultations(1) The Administrator shall publish proposed regulations for State underground injection control programs within 180 days after December 16, 1974. Within 180 days after publication of such proposed regulations, he shall promulgate such regulations with such modifications as he deems appropriate. Any regulation under this subsection may be amended from time to time.

(2) Any regulation under this section shall be proposed and promulgated in accordance with section 553 of title 5 (relating to rulemaking), except that the Administrator shall provide opportunity for public hearing prior to promulgation of such regulations. In proposing and promulgating regulations under this section the Administrator shall consult with the Secretary, the National Drinking Water Advisory Council, and other appropriate Federal entities and with interested State entities.


(b) Minimum requirements; restrictions(1) Regulations under subsection (a) for State underground injection programs shall contain minimum requirements for effective programs to prevent underground injection which endangers drinking water sources within the meaning of subsection (d)(2). Such regulations shall require that a State program, in order to be approved under section 300h–1 of this title—(A) shall prohibit, effective on the date on which the applicable underground injection control program takes effect, any underground injection in such State which is not authorized by a permit issued by the State (except that the regulations may permit a State to authorize underground injection by rule);

(B) shall require (i) in the case of a program which provides for authorization of underground injection by permit, that the applicant for the permit to inject must satisfy the State that the underground injection will not endanger drinking water sources, and (ii) in the case of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of proposed regulations; promulgation; amendments; public hearings; administrative consultations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Publication of proposed regulations; promulgation; amendments; public hearings; administrative consultations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum requirements; restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Minimum requirements; restrictions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary permits; notice and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Temporary permits; notice and hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Underground injection” defined; underground injection endangerment of drinking water sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Underground injection” defined; underground injection endangerment of drinking water sources For purposes of this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>