<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300h_2"><akn:num>300h–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300h–2. Enforcement of program(a) Notice to State and violator; issuance of administrative order; civil action(1) Whenever the Administrator finds during a period during which a State has primary enforcement responsibility for underground water sources (within the meaning of section 300h–1(b)(3) of this title or section 300h–4(c) of this title) that any person who is subject to a requirement of an applicable underground injection control program in such State is violating such requirement, he shall so notify the State and the person violating such requirement. If beyond the thirtieth day after the Administrator’s notification the State has not commenced appropriate enforcement action, the Administrator shall issue an order under subsection (c) requiring the person to comply with such requirement or the Administrator shall commence a civil action under subsection (b).

(2) Whenever the Administrator finds during a period during which a State does not have primary enforcement responsibility for underground water sources that any person subject to any requirement of any applicable underground injection control program in such State is violating such requirement, the Administrator shall issue an order under subsection (c) requiring the person to comply with such requirement or the Administrator shall commence a civil action under subsection (b).


(b) Civil and criminal actionsCivil actions referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be brought in the appropriate United States district court. Such court shall have jurisdiction to require compliance with any requirement of an applicable underground injection program or with an order issued under subsection (c). The court may enter such judgment as protection of public health may require. Any person who violates any requirement of an applicable underground injection control program or an order requiring compliance under subsection (c)—(1) shall be subject to a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice to State and violator; issuance of administrative order; civil action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice to State and violator; issuance of administrative order; civil action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil and criminal actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Civil and criminal actions Civil actions referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a) shall be brought in the appropriate United States district court. Such court shall have jurisdiction to require compliance with any requirement of an applicable underground injection program or with an order issued under subsection (c). The court may enter such judgment as protection of public health may require. Any person who violates any requirement of an applicable underground injection control program or an order requiring compliance under subsection (c)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Administrative orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State authority to adopt or enforce laws or regulations respecting underground injection unaf­fected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State authority to adopt or enforce laws or regulations respecting underground injection unaf­fected Nothing in this subchapter shall diminish any authority of a State or political subdivision to adopt or enforce any law or regulation respecting underground injection but no such law or regulation shall relieve any person of any requirement otherwise applicable under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>