<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300h_1"><akn:num>300h–1</akn:num><akn:heading>State primary enforcement responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300h–1. State primary enforcement responsibility(a) List of States in need of a control program; amendment of listWithin 180 days after December 16, 1974, the Administrator shall list in the Federal Register each State for which in his judgment a State underground injection control program may be necessary to assure that underground injection will not endanger drinking water sources. Such list may be amended from time to time.


(b) State applications; notice to Administrator of compliance with revised or added requirements; approval or disapproval by Administrator; duration of State primary enforcement responsibility; public hearing(1)(A) Each State listed under subsection (a) shall within 270 days after the date of promulgation of any regulation under section 300h of this title (or, if later, within 270 days after such State is first listed under subsection (a)) submit to the Administrator an application which contains a showing satisfactory to the Administrator that the State—(i) has adopted after reasonable notice and public hearings, and will implement, an underground injection control program which meets the requirements of regulations in effect under section 300h of this title; and

(ii) will keep such records and make such reports with respect to its activities under its underground injection control program as the Administrator may require by regulation.


The Administrator may, for good cause, extend the date for submission of an application by any State under this subparagraph for a period not to exceed an additional 270 days.

(B) Within 270 days of any amendment of a regulation under section 300h of this title revising or adding any requirement respecting State underground injection control programs, each State listed under subsection (a) shall submit (in such form and manner as the Administrator may require) a notice to the Administrator containing a showing satisfactory to him that the State underground injection control program meets the revised or</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of States in need of a control program; amendment of list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) List of States in need of a control program; amendment of list Within 180 days after December 16, 1974, the Administrator shall list in the Federal Register each State for which in his judgment a State underground injection control program may be necessary to assure that underground injection will not endanger drinking water sources. Such list may be amended from time to time.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State applications; notice to Administrator of compliance with revised or added requirements; approval or disapproval by Administrator; duration of State primary enforcement responsibility; public hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State applications; notice to Administrator of compliance with revised or added requirements; approval or disapproval by Administrator; duration of State primary enforcement responsibility; public hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program by Administrator for State without primary enforcement responsibility; restrictions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Program by Administrator for State without primary enforcement responsibility; restrictions If the Administrator disapproves a State’s program (or part thereof) under subsection (b)(2), if the Administrator determines under subsection (b)(3) that a State no longer meets the requirements of clause (i) or (ii) of subsection (b)(1)(A), or if a State fails to submit an application or notice before the date of expiration of the period specified in subsection (b)(1), the Administrator shall by regulation within 90 days after the date of such disapproval, determination, or expiration (as the case may be) prescribe (and may from time to time by regulation revise) a program applicable to such State meeting the requirements of section 300h(b) of this title. Such program may not include requirements which interfere with or impede— unless such requirements are essential to assure that underground sources of drinking water will not be endangered by such injection. Such program shall apply in su</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Applicable underground injection control program” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Applicable underground injection control program” defined For purposes of this subchapter, the term “applicable underground injection control program” with respect to a State means the program (or most recent amendment thereof) (1) which has been adopted by the State and which has been approved under subsection (b), or (2) which has been prescribed by the Administrator under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Primary enforcement responsibility by Indian Tribe</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Primary enforcement responsibility by Indian Tribe An Indian Tribe may assume primary enforcement responsibility for underground injection control under this section consistent with such regulations as the Administrator has prescribed pursuant to this part and section 300j–11 of this title. The area over which such Indian Tribe exercises governmental jurisdiction need not have been listed under subsection (a) of this section, and such Tribe need not submit an application to assume primary enforcement responsibility within the 270-day deadline noted in subsection (b)(1)(A) of this section. Until an Indian Tribe assumes primary enforcement responsibility, the currently applicable underground injection control program shall continue to apply. If an applicable underground injection control program does not exist for an Indian Tribe, the Administrator shall prescribe such a program pursuant to subsection (c) of this section, and consistent with section 300h(b) of this title, within 270 </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>