<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–10" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–10/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–10/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300hh_10"><akn:num>300hh–10</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of preparedness for and response to all-hazards public health emergencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300hh–10. Coordination of preparedness for and response to all-hazards public health emergencies(a) In generalThere is established within the Department of Health and Human Services the position of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response. The President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint an individual to serve in such position. Such Assistant Secretary shall report to the Secretary.


(b) DutiesSubject to the authority of the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response shall utilize experience related to public health emergency preparedness and response, biodefense, medical countermeasures, and other relevant topics to carry out the following functions:(1) LeadershipServe as the principal advisor to the Secretary on all matters related to Federal public health and medical preparedness and response for public health emergencies and, consistent with the National Response Framework and other applicable provisions of law, assist the Secretary in carrying out the functions under section 300hh of this title.


(2) PersonnelRegister, credential, organize, train, equip, and have the authority to deploy Federal public health and medical personnel under the authority of the Secretary, including the National Disaster Medical System, and coordinate such personnel with the Medical Reserve Corps and the Emergency System for Advance Registration of Volunteer Health Professionals.


(3) CountermeasuresOversee advanced research, development, and procurement of qualified countermeasures (as defined in section 247d–6a of this title), security countermeasures (as defined in section 247d–6b of this title), and qualified pandemic or epidemic products (as defined in section 247d–6d of this title).


(4) Coordination(A) Federal integrationCoordinate with relevant Federal officials to ensure integration of Federal preparedness and response activities for public health emergencies.


(B) State, local, and tribal integrationCoordinate</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established within the Department of Health and Human Services the position of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response. The President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, shall appoint an individual to serve in such position. Such Assistant Secretary shall report to the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties Subject to the authority of the Secretary, the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response shall utilize experience related to public health emergency preparedness and response, biodefense, medical countermeasures, and other relevant topics to carry out the following functions:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions The Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public Health Emergency Medical Countermeasures Enterprise Strategy and Implementation Plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Public Health Emergency Medical Countermeasures Enterprise Strategy and Implementation Plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of national security</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Protection of national security In carrying out subsections (b)(7) and (d), the Secretary shall ensure that information and items that could compromise national security, contain confidential commercial information, or contain proprietary information are not disclosed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of national security from threats</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Protection of national security from threats</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_10_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appearances before Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Appearances before Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>