<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300hh_3"><akn:num>300hh–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300hh–3. Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy(a) In generalThere is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy (referred to in this section as the “Office”), which shall be headed by a Director (referred to in this section as the “Director”) appointed by the President and who shall be compensated at the rate provided for level II of the Executive Schedule in section 5313 of title 5. The President is authorized to appoint not more than 2 Associate Directors, who shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed that provided for level III of the Executive Schedule in section 5314 of such title. Associate Directors shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe.


(b) Functions of the DirectorThe primary function of the Director is to provide advice, within the Executive Office of the President, on policy related to preparedness for, and response to, pandemic and other biological threats that may impact national security, and support strategic coordination and communication with respect to relevant activities across the Federal Government. In addition to such other functions and activities as the President may assign, the Director, consistent with applicable laws and the National Response Framework, shall—(1) serve as the principal advisor to the President on all matters related to pandemic preparedness and response policy and make recommendations to the President regarding pandemic and other biological threats that may impact national security;

(2) coordinate Federal activities to prepare for, and respond to, pandemic and other biological threats, by—(A) providing strategic direction to the heads of applicable Federal departments, agencies, and offices, including—(i) the establishment, implementation, prioritization, and assessment of policy goals and objectives across the Executive Office of the President and such departments, agencies, and offices;

(ii) supporting the assessm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general There is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Pandemic Preparedness and Response Policy (referred to in this section as the “Office”), which shall be headed by a Director (referred to in this section as the “Director”) appointed by the President and who shall be compensated at the rate provided for level II of the Executive Schedule in section 5313 of title 5. The President is authorized to appoint not more than 2 Associate Directors, who shall be compensated at a rate not to exceed that provided for level III of the Executive Schedule in section 5314 of such title. Associate Directors shall perform such functions as the Director may prescribe.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions of the Director The primary function of the Director is to provide advice, within the Executive Office of the President, on policy related to preparedness for, and response to, pandemic and other biological threats that may impact national security, and support strategic coordination and communication with respect to relevant activities across the Federal Government. In addition to such other functions and activities as the President may assign, the Director, consistent with applicable laws and the National Response Framework, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support from other agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support from other agencies Each department, agency, and instrumentality of the executive branch of the Federal Government, including any independent agency, is authorized to support the Director by providing the Director such information as the Director determines necessary to carry out the functions of the Director under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparedness outlook report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preparedness outlook report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interdepartmental working group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interdepartmental working group The Director shall lead an interdepartmental working group that will meet on a regular basis to evaluate national biosecurity and pandemic preparedness issues and make recommendations to the heads of applicable Federal departments, agencies and offices. The working group shall consist of representatives from—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry Liaison</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Industry Liaison</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional functions of the Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional functions of the Director The Director, in addition to the other duties and functions set forth in this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Staffing and detailees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Staffing and detailees In carrying out functions under this section, the Director may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparedness review and report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Preparedness review and report The Director, in consultation with the heads of applicable Federal departments, agencies, and offices, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_3_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonduplication of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Nonduplication of effort The Director shall ensure that activities carried out under this section do not unnecessarily duplicate the efforts of other Federal departments, agencies, and offices.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>