<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300h–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300h_7"><akn:num>300h–7</akn:num><akn:heading>State programs to establish wellhead protection areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300h–7. State programs to establish wellhead protection areas(a) State programsThe Governor or Governor’s designee of each State shall, within 3 years of June 19, 1986, adopt and submit to the Administrator a State program to protect wellhead areas within their jurisdiction from contaminants which may have any adverse effect on the health of persons. Each State program under this section shall, at a minimum—(1) specify the duties of State agencies, local governmental entities, and public water supply systems with respect to the development and implementation of programs required by this section;

(2) for each wellhead, determine the wellhead protection area as defined in subsection (e) based on all reasonably available hydrogeologic information on ground water flow, recharge and discharge and other information the State deems necessary to adequately determine the wellhead protection area;

(3) identify within each wellhead protection area all potential anthropogenic sources of contaminants which may have any adverse effect on the health of persons;

(4) describe a program that contains, as appropriate, technical assistance, financial assistance, implementation of control measures, education, training, and demonstration projects to protect the water supply within wellhead protection areas from such contaminants;

(5) include contingency plans for the location and provision of alternate drinking water supplies for each public water system in the event of well or wellfield contamination by such contaminants; and

(6) include a requirement that consideration be given to all potential sources of such contaminants within the expected wellhead area of a new water well which serves a public water supply system.


(b) Public participationTo the maximum extent possible, each State shall establish procedures, including but not limited to the establishment of technical and citizens’ advisory committees, to encourage the public to participate in developing the protection progr</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State programs The Governor or Governor’s designee of each State shall, within 3 years of June 19, 1986, adopt and submit to the Administrator a State program to protect wellhead areas within their jurisdiction from contaminants which may have any adverse effect on the health of persons. Each State program under this section shall, at a minimum—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Public participation To the maximum extent possible, each State shall establish procedures, including but not limited to the establishment of technical and citizens’ advisory committees, to encourage the public to participate in developing the protection program for wellhead areas and source water assessment programs under section 300j–13 of this title. Such procedures shall include notice and opportunity for public hearing on the State program before it is submitted to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disapproval</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Federal assistance After the date 3 years after June 19, 1986, no State shall receive funds authorized to be appropriated under this section except for the purpose of implementing the program and requirements of paragraphs (4) and (6) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Wellhead protection area” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Wellhead protection area” defined As used in this section, the term “wellhead protection area” means the surface and subsurface area surrounding a water well or wellfield, supplying a public water system, through which contaminants are reasonably likely to move toward and reach such water well or wellfield. The extent of a wellhead protection area, within a State, necessary to provide protection from contaminants which may have any adverse effect on the health of persons is to be determined by the State in the program submitted under subsection (a). Not later than one year after June 19, 1986, the Administrator shall issue technical guidance which States may use in making such determinations. Such guidance may reflect such factors as the radius of influence around a well or wellfield, the depth of drawdown of the water table by such well or wellfield at any given point, the time or rate of travel of various contaminants in various hydrologic conditions, distance from the well or w</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Prohibitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Implementation Each State shall make every reasonable effort to implement the State wellhead area protection program under this section within 2 years of submitting the program to the Administrator. Each State shall submit to the Administrator a biennial status report describing the State’s progress in implementing the program. Such report shall include amendments to the State program for water wells sited during the biennial period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal agencies Each department, agency, and instrumentality of the executive, legislative, and judicial branches of the Federal Government having jurisdiction over any potential source of contaminants identified by a State program pursuant to the provisions of subsection (a)(3) shall be subject to and comply with all requirements of the State program developed according to subsection (a)(4) applicable to such potential source of contaminants, both substantive and procedural, in the same manner, and to the same extent, as any other person is subject to such requirements, including payment of reasonable charges and fees. The President may exempt any potential source under the jurisdiction of any department, agency, or instrumentality in the executive branch if the President determines it to be in the paramount interest of the United States to do so. No such exemption shall be granted due to the lack of an appropriation unless the President shall have specifically requested such app</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Additional requirement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300h_7_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Coordination with other laws Nothing in this section shall authorize or require any department, agency, or other instrumentality of the Federal Government or State or local government to apportion, allocate or otherwise regulate the withdrawal or beneficial use of ground or surface waters, so as to abrogate or modify any existing rights to water established pursuant to State or Federal law, including interstate compacts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>