<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–15" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–15/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300hh–15/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300hh_15"><akn:num>300hh–15</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteer Medical Reserve Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300hh–15. Volunteer Medical Reserve Corps(a) In generalNot later than 180 days after December 19, 2006, the Secretary, in collaboration with State, local, and tribal officials, shall build on State, local, and tribal programs in existence on December 19, 2006, to establish and maintain a Medical Reserve Corps (referred to in this section as the “Corps”) to provide for an adequate supply of volunteers in the case of a Federal, State, local, or tribal public health emergency. The Secretary may appoint a Director to head the Corps and oversee the activities of the Corps chapters that exist at the State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels.


(b) State, local, and tribal coordinationThe Corps shall be established using existing State, local, and tribal teams and shall not alter such teams.


(c) CompositionThe Corps shall be composed of individuals who—(1)(A) are health professionals who have appropriate professional training and expertise as determined appropriate by the Director of the Corps; or

(B) are non-health professionals who have an interest in serving in an auxiliary or support capacity to facilitate access to health care services in a public health emergency;


(2) are certified in accordance with the certification program developed under subsection (d);

(3) are geographically diverse in residence;

(4) have registered and carry out training exercises with a local chapter of the Medical Reserve Corps; and

(5) indicate whether they are willing to be deployed outside the area in which they reside in the event of a public health emergency.


(d) Certification; drills(1) CertificationThe Director, in collaboration with State, local, and tribal officials, shall establish a process for the periodic certification of individuals who volunteer for the Corps, as determined by the Secretary, which shall include the completion by each individual of the core training programs developed under section 247d–6 of this title, as required by the Director. Such certificat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 180 days after December 19, 2006, the Secretary, in collaboration with State, local, and tribal officials, shall build on State, local, and tribal programs in existence on December 19, 2006, to establish and maintain a Medical Reserve Corps (referred to in this section as the “Corps”) to provide for an adequate supply of volunteers in the case of a Federal, State, local, or tribal public health emergency. The Secretary may appoint a Director to head the Corps and oversee the activities of the Corps chapters that exist at the State, local, Tribal, and territorial levels.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State, local, and tribal coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State, local, and tribal coordination The Corps shall be established using existing State, local, and tribal teams and shall not alter such teams.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition The Corps shall be composed of individuals who—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification; drills</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Certification; drills</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deployment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Deployment During a public health emergency, the Secretary shall have the authority to activate and deploy willing members of the Corps to areas of need, taking into consideration the public health and medical expertise required, with the concurrence of the State, local, or tribal officials from the area where the members reside.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses and transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expenses and transportation While engaged in performing duties as a member of the Corps pursuant to an assignment by the Secretary (including periods of travel to facilitate such assignment), members of the Corps who are not otherwise employed by the Federal Government shall be allowed travel or transportation expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Identification The Secretary, in cooperation and consultation with the States, shall develop a Medical Reserve Corps Identification Card that describes the licensure and certification information of Corps members, as well as other identifying information determined necessary by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intermittent disaster-response personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Intermittent disaster-response personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300hh_15_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $11,200,000 for each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>