<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300i–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300i–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300i–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300i_2"><akn:num>300i–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Community water system risk and resilience</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300i–2. Community water system risk and resilience(a) Risk and resilience assessments(1) In generalEach community water system serving a population of greater than 3,300 persons shall conduct an assessment of the risks to, and resilience of, its system. Such an assessment—(A) shall include an assessment of—(i) the risk to the system from malevolent acts and natural hazards;

(ii) the resilience of the pipes and constructed conveyances, physical barriers, source water, water collection and intake, pretreatment, treatment, storage and distribution facilities, electronic, computer, or other automated systems (including the security of such systems) which are utilized by the system;

(iii) the monitoring practices of the system;

(iv) the financial infrastructure of the system;

(v) the use, storage, or handling of various chemicals by the system; and

(vi) the operation and maintenance of the system; and


(B) may include an evaluation of capital and operational needs for risk and resilience management for the system.


(2) Baseline informationThe Administrator, not later than August 1, 2019, after consultation with appropriate departments and agencies of the Federal Government and with State and local governments, shall provide baseline information on malevolent acts of relevance to community water systems, which shall include consideration of acts that may—(A) substantially disrupt the ability of the system to provide a safe and reliable supply of drinking water; or

(B) otherwise present significant public health or economic concerns to the community served by the system.


(3) Certification(A) CertificationEach community water system described in paragraph (1) shall submit to the Administrator a certification that the system has conducted an assessment complying with paragraph (1). Such certification shall be made prior to—(i) March 31, 2020, in the case of systems serving a population of 100,000 or more;

(ii) December 31, 2020, in the case of systems serving a </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Risk and resilience assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Risk and resilience assessments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency response plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Emergency response plan Each community water system serving a population greater than 3,300 shall prepare or revise, where necessary, an emergency response plan that incorporates findings of the assessment conducted under subsection (a) for such system (and any revisions thereto). Each community water system shall certify to the Administrator, as soon as reasonably possible after October 23, 2018, but not later than 6 months after completion of the assessment under subsection (a), that the system has completed such plan. The emergency response plan shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Coordination Community water systems shall, to the extent possible, coordinate with existing local emergency planning committees established pursuant to the Emergency Planning and Community Right-To-Know Act of 1986 (42 U.S.C. 11001 et seq.) when preparing or revising an assessment or emergency response plan under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Record maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Record maintenance Each community water system shall maintain a copy of the assessment conducted under subsection (a) and the emergency response plan prepared under subsection (b) (including any revised assessment or plan) for 5 years after the date on which a certification of such assessment or plan is submitted to the Administrator under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance to small public water systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Guidance to small public water systems The Administrator shall provide guidance and technical assistance to community water systems serving a population of less than 3,300 persons on how to conduct resilience assessments, prepare emergency response plans, and address threats from malevolent acts and natural hazards that threaten to disrupt the provision of safe drinking water or significantly affect the public health or significantly affect the safety or supply of drinking water provided to communities and individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Alternative preparedness and operational resilience programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Alternative preparedness and operational resilience programs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance and grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Technical assistance and grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300i_2_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions In this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>