<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ii–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ii–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300ii–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300ii_1"><akn:num>300ii–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Lifespan respite care grants and cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300ii–1. Lifespan respite care grants and cooperative agreements(a) PurposesThe purposes of this section are—(1) to expand and enhance respite care services to family caregivers;

(2) to improve the statewide dissemination and coordination of respite care; and

(3) to provide, supplement, or improve access and quality of respite care services to family caregivers, thereby reducing family caregiver strain.


(b) AuthorizationSubject to subsection (e), the Secretary is authorized to award grants or cooperative agreements for the purposes described in subsection (a) to eligible State agencies for which an application is submitted pursuant to subsection (d).


(c) Federal lifespan approachIn carrying out this section, the Secretary shall work in cooperation with the National Family Caregiver Support Program of the Administration on Aging and other respite care programs within the Department of Health and Human Services to ensure coordination of respite care services for family caregivers of children and adults with special needs.


(d) Application(1) SubmissionEach Governor desiring the eligible State agency of his or her State to receive a grant or cooperative agreement under this section shall submit an application on behalf of such agency to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary shall require.


(2) ContentsEach application submitted under this section shall include—(A) a description of the eligible State agency’s—(i) ability to work with other State and community-based agencies;

(ii) understanding of respite care and family caregiver issues across all age groups, disabilities, and chronic conditions; and

(iii) capacity to ensure meaningful involvement of family members, family caregivers, and care recipients;


(B) with respect to the population of family caregivers to whom respite care information or services will be provided or for whom respite care workers and volunteers will be recruited and trained, a d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purposes The purposes of this section are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authorization Subject to subsection (e), the Secretary is authorized to award grants or cooperative agreements for the purposes described in subsection (a) to eligible State agencies for which an application is submitted pursuant to subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal lifespan approach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal lifespan approach In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall work in cooperation with the National Family Caregiver Support Program of the Administration on Aging and other respite care programs within the Department of Health and Human Services to ensure coordination of respite care services for family caregivers of children and adults with special needs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority; considerations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Priority; considerations When awarding grants or cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of grant or cooperative agreement funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of grant or cooperative agreement funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Term of grants or cooperative agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Term of grants or cooperative agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300ii_1_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maintenance of effort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maintenance of effort Funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement and not supplant other Federal, State, and local funds available for respite care services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>