<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–24" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–24/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–24/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300j_24"><akn:num>300j–24</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead contamination in school drinking water</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300j–24. Lead contamination in school drinking water(a) Distribution of drinking water cooler listWithin 100 days after October 31, 1988, the Administrator shall distribute to the States a list of each brand and model of drinking water cooler identified and listed by the Administrator under section 300j–23(a) of this title.


(b) Guidance document and testing protocolThe Administrator shall publish a guidance document and a testing protocol to assist public water systems and schools in determining the source and degree of lead contamination in school drinking water supplies and in remedying such contamination. The guidance document shall include guidelines for sample preservation. The guidance document shall also include guidance to assist States, schools, public water systems, and the general public in ascertaining the levels of lead contamination in drinking water coolers and in taking appropriate action to reduce or eliminate such contamination. The guidance document shall contain a testing protocol for the identification of drinking water coolers which contribute to lead contamination in drinking water. Such document and protocol may be revised, republished and redistributed as the Administrator deems necessary. The Administrator shall distribute the guidance document and testing protocol to the States within 100 days after October 31, 1988.


(c) Dissemination to schools, etc.Each State shall provide for the dissemination to local educational agencies, private nonprofit elementary or secondary schools and to day care centers of the guidance document and testing protocol published under subsection (b), together with the list of drinking water coolers published under section 300j–23(a) of this title.


(d) Voluntary school and child care program lead testing and reduction grant program(1) DefinitionsIn this subsection:(A) Child care programThe term “child care program” has the meaning given the term “early childhood education program” in section 1003(8) of titl</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_24_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of drinking water cooler list</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Distribution of drinking water cooler list Within 100 days after October 31, 1988, the Administrator shall distribute to the States a list of each brand and model of drinking water cooler identified and listed by the Administrator under section 300j–23(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_24_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidance document and testing protocol</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guidance document and testing protocol The Administrator shall publish a guidance document and a testing protocol to assist public water systems and schools in determining the source and degree of lead contamination in school drinking water supplies and in remedying such contamination. The guidance document shall include guidelines for sample preservation. The guidance document shall also include guidance to assist States, schools, public water systems, and the general public in ascertaining the levels of lead contamination in drinking water coolers and in taking appropriate action to reduce or eliminate such contamination. The guidance document shall contain a testing protocol for the identification of drinking water coolers which contribute to lead contamination in drinking water. Such document and protocol may be revised, republished and redistributed as the Administrator deems necessary. The Administrator shall distribute the guidance document and testing protocol to the States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_24_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination to schools, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination to schools, etc. Each State shall provide for the dissemination to local educational agencies, private nonprofit elementary or secondary schools and to day care centers of the guidance document and testing protocol published under subsection (b), together with the list of drinking water coolers published under section 300j–23(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_24_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary school and child care program lead testing and reduction grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Voluntary school and child care program lead testing and reduction grant program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>