<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–18" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–18/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–18/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300j_18"><akn:num>300j–18</akn:num><akn:heading>Drinking water studies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300j–18. Drinking water studies(a) Subpopulations at greater risk(1) In generalThe Administrator shall conduct a continuing program of studies to identify groups within the general population that may be at greater risk than the general population of adverse health effects from exposure to contaminants in drinking water. The study shall examine whether and to what degree infants, children, pregnant women, the elderly, individuals with a history of serious illness, or other subpopulations that can be identified and characterized are likely to experience elevated health risks, including risks of cancer, from contaminants in drinking water.


(2) ReportNot later than 4 years after August 6, 1996, and periodically thereafter as new and significant information becomes available, the Administrator shall report to the Congress on the results of the studies.



(b) Biological mechanismsThe Administrator shall conduct biomedical studies to—(1) understand the mechanisms by which chemical contaminants are absorbed, distributed, metabolized, and eliminated from the human body, so as to develop more accurate physiologically based models of the phenomena;

(2) understand the effects of contaminants and the mechanisms by which the contaminants cause adverse effects (especially noncancer and infectious effects) and the variations in the effects among humans, especially subpopulations at greater risk of adverse effects, and between test animals and humans; and

(3) develop new approaches to the study of complex mixtures, such as mixtures found in drinking water, especially to determine the prospects for synergistic or antagonistic interactions that may affect the shape of the dose-response relationship of the individual chemicals and microbes, and to examine noncancer endpoints and infectious diseases, and susceptible individuals and subpopulations.


(c) Studies on harmful substances in drinking water(1) Development of studiesThe Administrator shall, not later than 180 days after</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_18_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Subpopulations at greater risk</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Subpopulations at greater risk</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_18_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Biological mechanisms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Biological mechanisms The Administrator shall conduct biomedical studies to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_18_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies on harmful substances in drinking water</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Studies on harmful substances in drinking water</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_18_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waterborne disease occurrence study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Waterborne disease occurrence study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>