<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–3d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–3d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–3d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300j_3d"><akn:num>300j–3d</akn:num><akn:heading>Water supply cost savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300j–3d. Water supply cost savings(a) Drinking water technology clearinghouseThe Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall—(1) develop a technology clearinghouse for information on the cost-effectiveness of innovative and alternative drinking water delivery systems, including wells and well systems; and

(2) disseminate such information to the public and to communities and not-for-profit organizations seeking Federal funding for drinking water delivery systems serving 500 or fewer persons.


(b) Water system assessmentIn any application for a grant or loan for the purpose of construction, replacement, or rehabilitation of a drinking water delivery system serving 500 or fewer persons, the funding for which would come from the Federal Government (either directly or through a State), a unit of local government or not-for-profit organization shall self-certify that the unit of local government or organization has considered, as an alternative drinking water supply, drinking water delivery systems sourced by publicly owned—(1) individual wells;

(2) shared wells; and

(3) community wells.


(c) Report to CongressNot later than 3 years after December 16, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that describes—(1) the use of innovative and alternative drinking water delivery systems described in this section;

(2) the range of cost savings for communities using innovative and alternative drinking water delivery systems described in this section; and

(3) the use of drinking water technical assistance programs operated by the Administrator and the Secretary of Agriculture.


(Pub. L. 114–322, title II, § 2108, Dec. 16, 2016, 130 Stat. 1728.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Water and Waste Act of 2016, and also as part of the Water Infrastructure Improvements for the Nation Act, also known as the WIIN Act, and not as part of the Public Health Service Act which compris</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_3d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Drinking water technology clearinghouse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Drinking water technology clearinghouse The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_3d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Water system assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Water system assessment In any application for a grant or loan for the purpose of construction, replacement, or rehabilitation of a drinking water delivery system serving 500 or fewer persons, the funding for which would come from the Federal Government (either directly or through a State), a unit of local government or not-for-profit organization shall self-certify that the unit of local government or organization has considered, as an alternative drinking water supply, drinking water delivery systems sourced by publicly owned—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_3d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress Not later than 3 years after December 16, 2016, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that describes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>