<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–19a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–19a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–19a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300j_19a"><akn:num>300j–19a</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance for small and disadvantaged communities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300j–19a. Assistance for small and disadvantaged communities(a) Definition of underserved communityIn this section:(1) In generalThe term “underserved community” means a political subdivision of a State that, as determined by the Administrator, has an inadequate system for obtaining drinking water.


(2) InclusionsThe term “underserved community” includes a political subdivision of a State that either, as determined by the Administrator—(A) does not have household drinking water or wastewater services; or

(B) is served by a public water system that violates, or exceeds, as applicable, a requirement of a national primary drinking water regulation issued under section 300g–1 of this title, including—(i) a maximum contaminant level;

(ii) a treatment technique; and

(iii) an action level.




(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Administrator shall establish a program under which grants are provided to eligible entities for use in carrying out projects and activities the primary purposes of which are to assist public water systems in meeting the requirements of this subchapter.


(2) InclusionsProjects and activities under paragraph (1) include—(A) investments necessary for the public water system to comply with the requirements of this subchapter;

(B) assistance that directly and primarily benefits the disadvantaged community on a per-household basis;

(C) programs to provide household water quality testing, including testing for unregulated contaminants;

(D) the purchase of point-of-entry or point-of-use filters and filtration systems that are certified by a third party using science-based test methods for the removal of contaminants of concern;

(E) investments necessary for providing accurate and current information about—(i) the need for filtration and filter safety, including proper use and maintenance practices; and

(ii) the options for replacing lead service lines (as defined in section 300j–19b(a) of this title) and removing other sources of lead in water;</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of underserved community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of underserved community In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligible entities Except for purposes of subsections (j) and (m), an eligible entity under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Priority In prioritizing projects and activities for implementation under this section, the Administrator shall give priority to projects and activities that benefit underserved communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Local participation In prioritizing projects and activities for implementation under this section, the Administrator shall consult with and consider the priorities of States, Indian Tribes, and local governments in which communities described in subsection (c)(2) are located.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical, managerial, and financial capability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Technical, managerial, and financial capability The Administrator may provide assistance to increase the technical, managerial, and financial capability of an eligible entity receiving a grant under this section if the Administrator determines that the eligible entity lacks appropriate technical, managerial, or financial capability and is not receiving such assistance under another Federal program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cost sharing Before providing a grant to an eligible entity under this section, the Administrator shall enter into a binding agreement with the eligible entity to require the eligible entity—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Waiver The Administrator may waive, in whole or in part, the requirement under subsection (g)(1) if the Administrator determines that an eligible entity is unable to pay, or would experience significant financial hardship if required to pay, the non-Federal share.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Limitation on use of funds Not more than 4 percent of funds made available for grants under this section may be used to pay the administrative costs of the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_19a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>State response to contaminants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) State response to contaminants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>