<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300j–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300j_9"><akn:num>300j–9</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300j–9. General provisions(a) Regulations; delegation of functions(1) The Administrator is authorized to prescribe such regulations as are necessary or appropriate to carry out his functions under this subchapter.

(2) The Administrator may delegate any of his functions under this subchapter (other than prescribing regulations) to any officer or employee of the Agency.


(b) Utilization of officers and employees of Federal agenciesThe Administrator, with the consent of the head of any other agency of the United States, may utilize such officers and employees of such agency as he deems necessary to assist him in carrying out the purposes of this subchapter.


(c) Assignment of Agency personnel to State or interstate agenciesUpon the request of a State or interstate agency, the Administrator may assign personnel of the Agency to such State or interstate agency for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.


(d) Payments of grants; adjustments; advances; reimbursement; installments; conditions; eligibility for grants; “nonprofit agency or institution” defined(1) The Administrator may make payments of grants under this subchapter (after necessary adjustment on account of previously made underpayments or overpayments) in advance or by way of reimbursement, and in such installments and on such conditions as he may determine.

(2) Financial assistance may be made available in the form of grants only to individuals and nonprofit agencies or institutions. For purposes of this paragraph, the term “nonprofit agency or institution” means an agency or institution no part of the net earnings of which inure, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.


(e) Labor standardsThe Administrator shall take such action as may be necessary to assure compliance with provisions of sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. The Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this subsection, the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; delegation of functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations; delegation of functions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of officers and employees of Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Utilization of officers and employees of Federal agencies The Administrator, with the consent of the head of any other agency of the United States, may utilize such officers and employees of such agency as he deems necessary to assist him in carrying out the purposes of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of Agency personnel to State or interstate agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assignment of Agency personnel to State or interstate agencies Upon the request of a State or interstate agency, the Administrator may assign personnel of the Agency to such State or interstate agency for the purposes of carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Payments of grants; adjustments; advances; reimbursement; installments; conditions; eligibility for grants; “nonprofit agency or institution” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Payments of grants; adjustments; advances; reimbursement; installments; conditions; eligibility for grants; “nonprofit agency or institution” defined</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labor standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Labor standards The Administrator shall take such action as may be necessary to assure compliance with provisions of sections 3141–3144, 3146, and 3147 of title 40. The Secretary of Labor shall have, with respect to the labor standards specified in this subsection, the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (15 F.R. 3176; 64 Stat. 1267) and section 3145 of title 40.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appearance and representation of Administrator through Attorney General or attorney appointees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appearance and representation of Administrator through Attorney General or attorney appointees The Administrator shall request the Attorney General to appear and represent him in any civil action instituted under this subchapter to which the Administrator is a party. Unless, within a reasonable time, the Attorney General notifies the Administrator that he will appear in such action, attorneys appointed by the Administrator shall appear and represent him.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Administrator under other provisions unaffected</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authority of Administrator under other provisions unaffected The provisions of this subchapter shall not be construed as affecting any authority of the Administrator under part G of subchapter II of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congressional committees; review by Office of Management and Budget: submittal of comments to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Reports to Congressional committees; review by Office of Management and Budget: submittal of comments to Congressional committees Not later than April 1 of each year, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report respecting the activities of the Agency under this subchapter and containing such recommendations for legislation as he considers necessary. The report of the Administrator under this subsection which is due not later than April 1, 1975, and each subsequent report of the Administrator under this subsection shall include a statement on the actual and anticipated cost to public water systems in each State of compliance with the requirements of this subchapter. The Office of Management and Budget may review any report required by this subsection before its submission to such committees of Congress, but the Office may not revise any such re</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300j_9_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discrimination prohibition; filing of complaint; investigation; orders of Secretary; notice and hearing; settlements; attorneys’ fees; judicial review; filing of petition; procedural requirements; stay of orders; exclusiveness of remedy; civil actions for enforcement of orders; appropriate relief; mandamus proceedings; prohibition inapplicable to undirected but deliberate violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Discrimination prohibition; filing of complaint; investigation; orders of Secretary; notice and hearing; settlements; attorneys’ fees; judicial review; filing of petition; procedural requirements; stay of orders; exclusiveness of remedy; civil actions for enforcement of orders; appropriate relief; mandamus proceedings; prohibition inapplicable to undirected but deliberate violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>