<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–32" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–32/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–32/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300jj_32"><akn:num>300jj–32</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information technology implementation assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300jj–32. Health information technology implementation assistance(a) Health information technology extension programTo assist health care providers to adopt, implement, and effectively use certified EHR technology that allows for the electronic exchange and use of health information, the Secretary, acting through the Office of the National Coordinator, shall establish a health information technology extension program to provide health information technology assistance services to be carried out through the Department of Health and Human Services. The National Coordinator shall consult with other Federal agencies with demonstrated experience and expertise in information technology services, such as the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in developing and implementing this program.


(b) Health Information Technology Research Center(1) In generalThe Secretary shall create a Health Information Technology Research Center (in this section referred to as the “Center”) to provide technical assistance and develop or recognize best practices to support and accelerate efforts to adopt, implement, and effectively utilize health information technology that allows for the electronic exchange and use of information in compliance with standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria adopted under section 300jj–14 of this title.


(2) InputThe Center shall incorporate input from—(A) other Federal agencies with demonstrated experience and expertise in information technology services such as the National Institute of Standards and Technology;

(B) users of health information technology, such as providers and their support and clerical staff and others involved in the care and care coordination of patients, from the health care and health information technology industry; and

(C) others as appropriate.


(3) PurposesThe purposes of the Center are to—(A) provide a forum for the exchange of knowledge and experience;

(B) accelerate the transfer of less</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_32_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information technology extension program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Health information technology extension program To assist health care providers to adopt, implement, and effectively use certified EHR technology that allows for the electronic exchange and use of health information, the Secretary, acting through the Office of the National Coordinator, shall establish a health information technology extension program to provide health information technology assistance services to be carried out through the Department of Health and Human Services. The National Coordinator shall consult with other Federal agencies with demonstrated experience and expertise in information technology services, such as the National Institute of Standards and Technology, in developing and implementing this program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_32_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health Information Technology Research Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Health Information Technology Research Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_32_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information technology regional extension centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Health information technology regional extension centers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>