<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300jj"><akn:num>300jj</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300jj. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Certified EHR technologyThe term “certified EHR technology” means a qualified electronic health record that is certified pursuant to section 300jj–11(c)(5) of this title as meeting standards adopted under section 300jj–14 of this title that are applicable to the type of record involved (as determined by the Secretary, such as an ambulatory electronic health record for office-based physicians or an inpatient hospital electronic health record for hospitals).


(2) Enterprise integrationThe term “enterprise integration” means the electronic linkage of health care providers, health plans, the government, and other interested parties, to enable the electronic exchange and use of health information among all the components in the health care infrastructure in accordance with applicable law, and such term includes related application protocols and other related standards.


(3) Health care providerThe term “health care provider” includes a hospital, skilled nursing facility, nursing facility, home health entity or other long term care facility, health care clinic, community mental health center (as defined in section 300x–2(b)(1) of this title), renal dialysis facility, blood center, ambulatory surgical center described in section 1395l(i) of this title,11 So in original. The words “ambulatory surgical center described in section 1395l(i) of this title” appear in two places. emergency medical services provider, Federally qualified health center, group practice, a pharmacist, a pharmacy, a laboratory, a physician (as defined in section 1395x(r) of this title), a practitioner (as described in section 1395u(b)(18)(C) of this title), a provider operated by, or under contract with, the Indian Health Service or by an Indian tribe (as defined in the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.]), tribal organization, or urban Indian organization (as defined in section 1603 of title 25), a rural health c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified EHR technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Certified EHR technology The term “certified EHR technology” means a qualified electronic health record that is certified pursuant to section 300jj–11(c)(5) of this title as meeting standards adopted under section 300jj–14 of this title that are applicable to the type of record involved (as determined by the Secretary, such as an ambulatory electronic health record for office-based physicians or an inpatient hospital electronic health record for hospitals).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enterprise integration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Enterprise integration The term “enterprise integration” means the electronic linkage of health care providers, health plans, the government, and other interested parties, to enable the electronic exchange and use of health information among all the components in the health care infrastructure in accordance with applicable law, and such term includes related application protocols and other related standards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health care provider</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Health care provider The term “health care provider” includes a hospital, skilled nursing facility, nursing facility, home health entity or other long term care facility, health care clinic, community mental health center (as defined in section 300x–2(b)(1) of this title), renal dialysis facility, blood center, ambulatory surgical center described in section 1395l(i) of this title,11 So in original. The words “ambulatory surgical center described in section 1395l(i) of this title” appear in two places. emergency medical services provider, Federally qualified health center, group practice, a pharmacist, a pharmacy, a laboratory, a physician (as defined in section 1395x(r) of this title), a practitioner (as described in section 1395u(b)(18)(C) of this title), a provider operated by, or under contract with, the Indian Health Service or by an Indian tribe (as defined in the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act [25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.]), tribal organization, or urban I</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Health information The term “health information” has the meaning given such term in section 1320d(4) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health information technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Health information technology The term “health information technology” means hardware, software, integrated technologies or related licenses, intellectual property, upgrades, or packaged solutions sold as services that are designed for or support the use by health care entities or patients for the electronic creation, maintenance, access, or exchange of health information 22 So in original. Probably should be followed by a period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Health plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Health plan The term “health plan” has the meaning given such term in section 1320d(5) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>HIT Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) HIT Advisory Committee The term “HIT Advisory Committee” means such Committee established under section 300jj–12(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Individually identifiable health information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Individually identifiable health information The term “individually identifiable health information” has the meaning given such term in section 1320d(6) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interoperability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Interoperability The term “interoperability”, with respect to health information technology, means such health information technology that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Laboratory</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Laboratory The term “laboratory” has the meaning given such term in section 263a(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>