<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300jj_12"><akn:num>300jj–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Health Information Technology Advisory Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300jj–12. Health Information Technology Advisory Committee(a) EstablishmentThere is established a Health Information Technology Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the “HIT Advisory Committee”) to recommend to the National Coordinator, consistent with the implementation of the strategic plan described in section 300jj–11(c)(3) of this title, policies, and, for purposes of adoption under section 300jj–14 of this title, standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria, relating to the implementation of a health information technology infrastructure, nationally and locally, that advances the electronic access, exchange, and use of health information. Such Committee shall serve to unify the roles of, and replace, the HIT Policy Committee and the HIT Standards Committee, as in existence before December 13, 2016.


(b) Duties(1) Recommendations on policy framework to advance an interoperable health information technology infrastructure(A) In generalThe HIT Advisory Committee shall recommend to the National Coordinator a policy framework for adoption by the Secretary consistent with the strategic plan under section 300jj–11(c)(3) of this title for advancing the target areas described in this subsection. Such policy framework shall seek to prioritize achieving advancements in the target areas specified in subparagraph (B) of paragraph (2) and may, to the extent consistent with this section, incorporate policy recommendations made by the HIT Policy Committee, as in existence before December 13, 2016.


(B) UpdatesThe HIT Advisory Committee shall propose updates to such recommendations to the policy framework and make new recommendations, as appropriate.



(2) General duties and target areas(A) In generalThe HIT Advisory Committee shall recommend to the National Coordinator for purposes of adoption under section 300jj–14 of this title, standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria and an order of priority for the de</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established a Health Information Technology Advisory Committee (referred to in this section as the “HIT Advisory Committee”) to recommend to the National Coordinator, consistent with the implementation of the strategic plan described in section 300jj–11(c)(3) of this title, policies, and, for purposes of adoption under section 300jj–14 of this title, standards, implementation specifications, and certification criteria, relating to the implementation of a health information technology infrastructure, nationally and locally, that advances the electronic access, exchange, and use of health information. Such Committee shall serve to unify the roles of, and replace, the HIT Policy Committee and the HIT Standards Committee, as in existence before December 13, 2016.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Measured progress in advancing priority areas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Measured progress in advancing priority areas</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership and operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Membership and operations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of chapter 10 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application of chapter 10 of title 5 Chapter 10 of title 5, other than section 1013 of title 5, shall apply to the HIT Advisory Committee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_12_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publication The Secretary shall provide for publication in the Federal Register and the posting on the Internet website of the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology of all policy recommendations made by the HIT Advisory Committee under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>