<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–19" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–19/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300jj–19/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300jj_19"><akn:num>300jj–19</akn:num><akn:heading>Miscellaneous provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300jj–19. Miscellaneous provisions(a) Relation to HIPAA privacy and security law(1) In generalWith respect to the relation of this subchapter to HIPAA privacy and security law:(A) This subchapter may not be construed as having any effect on the authorities of the Secretary under HIPAA privacy and security law.

(B) The purposes of this subchapter include ensuring that the health information technology standards and implementation specifications adopted under section 300jj–14 of this title take into account the requirements of HIPAA privacy and security law.


(2) DefinitionFor purposes of this section, the term “HIPAA privacy and security law” means—(A) the provisions of part C of title XI of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1320d et seq.], section 264 of the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996, and subtitle D of title IV 11 See References in Text note below. of the Health Information Technology for Economic and Clinical Health Act; and

(B) regulations under such provisions.



(b) FlexibilityIn administering the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary shall have flexibility in applying the definition of health care provider under section 300jj(3) of this title, including the authority to omit certain entities listed in such definition when applying such definition under this subchapter, where appropriate.


(c) Promoting patient access to electronic health information through health information exchanges(1) In generalThe Secretary shall use existing authorities to encourage partnerships between health information exchange organizations and networks and health care providers, health plans, and other appropriate entities with the goal of offering patients access to their electronic health information in a single, longitudinal format that is easy to understand, secure, and may be updated automatically.


(2) Education of providersThe Secretary, in coordination with the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Serv</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_19_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relation to HIPAA privacy and security law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Relation to HIPAA privacy and security law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_19_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Flexibility In administering the provisions of this subchapter, the Secretary shall have flexibility in applying the definition of health care provider under section 300jj(3) of this title, including the authority to omit certain entities listed in such definition when applying such definition under this subchapter, where appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_19_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promoting patient access to electronic health information through health information exchanges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Promoting patient access to electronic health information through health information exchanges</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_19_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Efforts to promote access to health information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Efforts to promote access to health information The National Coordinator and the Office for Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services shall jointly promote patient access to health information in a manner that would ensure that such information is available in a form convenient for the patient, in a reasonable manner, without burdening the health care provider involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300jj_19_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessibility of patient records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Accessibility of patient records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>