<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300l" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300l/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300l/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300l"><akn:num>300l</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of matching funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300l. Requirement of matching funds(a) In generalThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees, with respect to the costs to be incurred by the State in carrying out the purpose described in such section, to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in kind under subsection (b)) toward such costs in an amount equal to not less than $1 for each $3 of Federal funds provided in the grant. Such contributions may be made directly or through donations from public or private entities.


(b) Determination of amount of non-Federal contribution(1) In generalNon-Federal contributions required in subsection (a) may be in cash or in kind, fairly evaluated, including equipment or services (and excluding indirect or overhead costs). Amounts provided by the Federal Government, or services assisted or subsidized to any significant extent by the Federal Government, may not be included in determining the amount of such non-Federal contributions.


(2) Maintenance of effortIn making a determination of the amount of non-Federal contributions for purposes of subsection (a), the Secretary may include only non-Federal contributions in excess of the average amount of non-Federal contributions made by the State involved toward the purpose described in section 300k of this title for the 2-year period preceding the first fiscal year for which the State is applying to receive a grant under such section.


(3) Inclusion of relevant non-Federal contributions for medicaidIn making a determination of the amount of non-Federal contributions for purposes of subsection (a), the Secretary shall, subject to paragraphs (1) and (2) of this subsection, include any non-Federal amounts expended pursuant to title XIX of the Social Security Act [42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.] by the State involved toward the purpose described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 300k(a) of this title.



(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XV, § 1502, as added Pub. L. 101–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300l_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees, with respect to the costs to be incurred by the State in carrying out the purpose described in such section, to make available non-Federal contributions (in cash or in kind under subsection (b)) toward such costs in an amount equal to not less than $1 for each $3 of Federal funds provided in the grant. Such contributions may be made directly or through donations from public or private entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300l_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination of amount of non-Federal contribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Determination of amount of non-Federal contribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>