<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300mm–23" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300mm–23/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300mm–23/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300mm_23"><akn:num>300mm–23</akn:num><akn:heading>National arrangement for benefits for eligible individuals outside New York</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300mm–23. National arrangement for benefits for eligible individuals outside New York(a) In generalIn order to ensure reasonable access to benefits under this part for individuals who are enrolled WTC responders, screening-eligible WTC survivors, or certified-eligible WTC survivors and who reside in any State, as defined in section 201(f) of this title, outside the New York metropolitan area, the WTC Program Administrator shall establish a nationwide network of health care providers to provide monitoring and treatment benefits and initial health evaluations near such individuals’ areas of residence in such States. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preventing such individuals from being provided such monitoring and treatment benefits or initial health evaluation through any Clinical Center of Excellence.


(b) Network requirementsAny health care provider participating in the network under subsection (a) shall—(1) meet criteria for credentialing established by the Data Centers;

(2) follow the monitoring, initial health evaluation, and treatment protocols developed under section 300mm–4(a)(2)(A)(ii) of this title;

(3) collect and report data in accordance with section 300mm–3 of this title; and

(4) meet such fraud, quality assurance, and other requirements as the WTC Program Administrator establishes, including sections 1320a–7 through 1320a–7e of this title, as applied by section 300mm(d) of this title.


(c) Training and technical assistanceThe WTC Program Administer 11 So in original. Probably should be “Administrator”. may provide, including through contract, for the provision of training and technical assistance to health care providers participating in the network under subsection (a).


(d) Provision of services through the VA(1) In generalThe WTC Program Administrator may enter into an agreement with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the Secretary to provide services under this section through facilities of the Department of Veterans Aff</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300mm_23_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In order to ensure reasonable access to benefits under this part for individuals who are enrolled WTC responders, screening-eligible WTC survivors, or certified-eligible WTC survivors and who reside in any State, as defined in section 201(f) of this title, outside the New York metropolitan area, the WTC Program Administrator shall establish a nationwide network of health care providers to provide monitoring and treatment benefits and initial health evaluations near such individuals’ areas of residence in such States. Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as preventing such individuals from being provided such monitoring and treatment benefits or initial health evaluation through any Clinical Center of Excellence.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300mm_23_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Network requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Network requirements Any health care provider participating in the network under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300mm_23_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Training and technical assistance The WTC Program Administer 11 So in original. Probably should be “Administrator”. may provide, including through contract, for the provision of training and technical assistance to health care providers participating in the network under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300mm_23_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of services through the VA</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of services through the VA</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>