<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300n"><akn:num>300n</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional required agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300n. Additional required agreements(a) Priority for low-income womenThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that low-income women will be given priority in the provision of services and activities pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 300k(a) of this title.


(b) Limitation on imposition of fees for servicesThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that, if a charge is imposed for the provision of services or activities under the grant, such charge—(1) will be made according to a schedule of charges that is made available to the public;

(2) will be adjusted to reflect the income of the woman involved; and

(3) will not be imposed on any woman with an income of less than 100 percent of the official poverty line, as established by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and revised by the Secretary in accordance with section 9902(2) of this title.


(c) Statewide provision of services(1) In generalThe Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that services and activities under the grant will be made available throughout the State, including availability to members of any Indian tribe or tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 5304 of title 25).


(2) WaiverThe Secretary may waive the requirement established in paragraph (1) for a State if the Secretary determines that compliance by the State with the requirement would result in an inefficient allocation of resources with respect to carrying out the purpose described in section 300k(a) of this title.


(3) Grants to tribes and tribal organizations(A) The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may make grants to tribes and tribal organizations (as such terms are used in paragraph (1)) for the purpose of carrying out programs described in section 300k(a) of </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority for low-income women</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Priority for low-income women The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that low-income women will be given priority in the provision of services and activities pursuant to paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 300k(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on imposition of fees for services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on imposition of fees for services The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that, if a charge is imposed for the provision of services or activities under the grant, such charge—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statewide provision of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statewide provision of services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to items and services under other programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to items and services under other programs The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that the grant will not be expended to make payment for any item or service to the extent that payment has been made, or can reasonably be expected to be made, with respect to such item or service—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with other breast and cervical cancer programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination with other breast and cervical cancer programs The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that the services and activities funded through the grant shall be coordinated with other Federal, State, and local breast and cervical cancer programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation on administrative expenses The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that not more than 10 percent of the grant will be expended for administrative expenses with respect to the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restrictions on use of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Restrictions on use of grant The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that the grant will not be expended to provide inpatient hospital services for any individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Records and audits The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reports to Secretary The Secretary may not make a grant under section 300k of this title unless the State involved agrees to submit to the Secretary such reports as the Secretary may require with respect to the grant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>