<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300n–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300n_4"><akn:num>300n–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300n–4. Evaluations and reports(a) EvaluationsThe Secretary shall, directly or through contracts with public or private entities, provide for annual evaluations of programs carried out pursuant to section 300k of this title. Such evaluations shall include evaluations of—(1) the extent to which States carrying out such programs are in compliance with section 300k(a)(2) of this title and with section 300n(c) of this title; and

(2) the extent to which each State receiving a grant under this subchapter is in compliance with section 300l of this title, including identification of—(A) the amount of the non-Federal contributions by the State for the preceding fiscal year, disaggregated according to the source of the contributions; and

(B) the proportion of such amount of non-Federal contributions relative to the amount of Federal funds provided through the grant to the State for the preceding fiscal year.



(b) Report to CongressThe Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after April 20, 2007,11 See References in Text note below. and annually thereafter, submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, a report summarizing evaluations carried out pursuant to subsection (a) during the preceding fiscal year and making such recommendations for administrative and legislative initiatives with respect to this subchapter as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including recommendations regarding compliance by the States with section 300k(a)(2) of this title and with section 300n(c) of this title.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XV, § 1508, as added Pub. L. 101–354, § 2, Aug. 10, 1990, 104 Stat. 415; amended Pub. L. 103–183, title I, § 101(e), Dec. 14, 1993, 107 Stat. 2228; Pub. L. 110–18, § 2(3), Apr. 20, 2007, 121 Stat. 83.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextApril 20, 2007, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “the date of the enactment of the National Breast a</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluations The Secretary shall, directly or through contracts with public or private entities, provide for annual evaluations of programs carried out pursuant to section 300k of this title. Such evaluations shall include evaluations of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300n_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report to Congress The Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after April 20, 2007,11 See References in Text note below. and annually thereafter, submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate, a report summarizing evaluations carried out pursuant to subsection (a) during the preceding fiscal year and making such recommendations for administrative and legislative initiatives with respect to this subchapter as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including recommendations regarding compliance by the States with section 300k(a)(2) of this title and with section 300n(c) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>