<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300s_1"><akn:num>300s–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Medical facility project applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300s–1. Medical facility project applications(a) SubmissionsNo loan, loan guarantee, or grant may be made under part A or B for a medical facilities project unless an application for such project has been submitted to and approved by the Secretary. If two or more entities join in a project, an application for such project may be filed by any of such entities or by all of them.


(b) Form; required provisions; waiver; projects subject to requirements(1) An application for a medical facilities proj­ect shall be submitted in such form and manner as the Secretary shall by regulation prescribe and shall, except as provided in paragraph (2), set forth—(A) in the case of a modernization project for a medical facility for continuation of existing health services, a finding by the State Agency of a continued need for such services, and, in the case of any other project for a medical facility, a finding by the State Agency of the need for the new health services to be provided through the medical facility upon completion of the project;

(B) in the case of an application for a grant, assurances satisfactory to the Secretary that (i) the applicant making the application would not be able to complete the project for which the application is submitted without the grant applied for, and (ii) in the case of a project to construct a new medical facility, it would be inappropriate to convert an existing medical facility to provide the services to be provided through the new medical facility;

(C) in the case of a project for the discontinuance of a service or facility or the conversion of a service or a facility, an evaluation of the impact of such discontinuance or conversion on the provision of health care in the health service area in which such service was provided or facility located;

(D) a description of the site of such project;

(E) plans and specifications therefor which meet the requirements of the regulations prescribed under section 300s(2) of this title;

(F) reasona</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submissions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Submissions No loan, loan guarantee, or grant may be made under part A or B for a medical facilities project unless an application for such project has been submitted to and approved by the Secretary. If two or more entities join in a project, an application for such project may be filed by any of such entities or by all of them.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Form; required provisions; waiver; projects subject to requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Form; required provisions; waiver; projects subject to requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>