<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–3" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–3/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300s–3/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300s_3"><akn:num>300s–3</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300s–3. Definitions
Except as provided in section 300t–12(e) of this title, for purposes of this subchapter—(1) The term “hospital” includes general, tuberculosis, and other types of hospitals, and related facilities, such as laboratories, outpatient departments, nurses’ home facilities, extended care facilities, facilities related to programs for home health services, self-care units, and central service facilities, operated in connection with hospitals, and also includes education or training facilities for health professonal 11 So in original. Probably should be “professional”. personnel operated as an integral part of a hospital, but does not include any hospital furnishing primarily domiciliary care.

(2) The term “public health center” means a publicly owned facility for the provision of public health services, including related publicly owned facilities such as laboratories, clinics, and administrative offices operated in connection with such a facility.

(3) The term “nonprofit” as applied to any facility means a facility which is owned and operated by one or more nonprofit corporations or associations no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.

(4) The term “outpatient medical facility” means a medical facility (located in or apart from a hospital) for the diagnosis or diagnosis and treatment of ambulatory patients (including ambulatory inpatients)—(A) which is operated in connection with a hospital,

(B) in which patient care is under the professional supervision of persons licensed to practice medicine or surgery in the State, or in the case of dental diagnosis or treatment, under the professional supervision of persons licensed to practice dentistry in the State; or

(C) which offers to patients not requiring hospitalization the services of licensed physicians in various medical specialties, and which provides to its patients a reasonably full-range of diagnostic and trea</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “hospital” includes general, tuberculosis, and other types of hospitals, and related facilities, such as laboratories, outpatient departments, nurses’ home facilities, extended care facilities, facilities related to programs for home health services, self-care units, and central service facilities, operated in connection with hospitals, and also includes education or training facilities for health professonal 11 So in original. Probably should be “professional”. personnel operated as an integral part of a hospital, but does not include any hospital furnishing primarily domiciliary care.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “public health center” means a publicly owned facility for the provision of public health services, including related publicly owned facilities such as laboratories, clinics, and administrative offices operated in connection with such a facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “nonprofit” as applied to any facility means a facility which is owned and operated by one or more nonprofit corporations or associations no part of the net earnings of which inures, or may lawfully inure, to the benefit of any private shareholder or individual.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “outpatient medical facility” means a medical facility (located in or apart from a hospital) for the diagnosis or diagnosis and treatment of ambulatory patients (including ambulatory inpatients)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “rehabilitation facility” means a facility which is operated for the primary purpose of assisting in the rehabilitation of disabled persons through an integrated program of— under competent professional supervision, and in the case of which the major portion of the required evaluation and services is furnished within the facility; and either the facility is operated in connection with a hospital, or all medical and related health services are prescribed by, or are under the general direction of, persons licensed to practice medicine or surgery in the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “facility for long-term care” means a facility (including a skilled nursing or intermediate care facility) providing in-patient care for convalescent or chronic disease patients who required skilled nursing or intermediate care and related medical services—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “construction” means construction of new buildings and initial equipment of such buildings and, in any case in which it will help to provide a service not previously provided in the community, equipment of any buildings; including architects’ fees, but excluding the cost of off-site improvements and, except with respect to public health centers, the cost of the acquisition of land.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “cost” as applied to construction, modernization, or conversion means the amount found by the Secretary to be necessary for construction, modernization, or conversion, respectively, under a project, except that, in the case of a modernization project or a project assisted under part B, such term does not include any amount found by the Secretary to be attributable to expansion of the bed capacity of any facility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “modernization” includes the alteration, expansion, major repair (to the extent permitted by regulations), remodeling, replacement, and renovation of existing buildings (including initial equipment thereof), and the replacement of obsolete equipment of existing buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300s_3_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “title,” 22 So in original. The comma probably should follow the ending quotations. when used with reference to a site for a project, means a fee simple, or such other estate or interest (including a leasehold on which the rental does not exceed 4 per centum of the value of the land) as the Secretary finds sufficient to assure for a period of not less than twenty-five years’ undisturbed use and possession for the purposes of construction, modernization, or conversion and operation of the project for a period of not less than (A) twenty years in the case of a project assisted under an allotment or grant under this subchapter, or (B) the term of repayment of a loan made or guaranteed under this subchapter in the case of a project assisted by a loan or loan guarantee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>