<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–16" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–16/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–16/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300u_16"><akn:num>300u–16</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of substance use disorder information dashboard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300u–16. Establishment of substance use disorder information dashboard(a) In generalNot later than 6 months after October 24, 2018, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the Director of National Drug Control Policy, establish and periodically update, on the Internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a public information dashboard that—(1) provides links to information on programs within the Department of Health and Human Services related to the reduction of opioid and other substance use disorders;

(2) provides access, to the extent practicable and appropriate, to publicly available data, which may include data from agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services and—(A) other Federal agencies;

(B) State, local, and Tribal governments;

(C) nonprofit organizations;

(D) law enforcement;

(E) medical experts;

(F) public health educators; and

(G) research institutions regarding prevention, treatment, recovery, and other services for opioid and other substance use disorders;


(3) provides data on substance use disorder prevention and treatment strategies in different regions of and populations in the United States;

(4) identifies information on alternatives to controlled substances for pain management, such as approaches studied by the National Institutes of Health Pain Consortium, the National Center for Complimentary and Integrative Health, and other institutes and centers at the National Institutes of Health, as appropriate; and

(5) identifies guidelines and best practices for health care providers regarding treatment of substance use disorders.


(b) Controlled substance definedIn this section, the term “controlled substance” has the meaning given that term in section 802 of title 21.


(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XVII, § 1711, as added Pub. L. 115–271, title VII, § 7021, Oct. 24, 2018, 132 Stat. 4009.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
National Milestones To Measure Success in Cu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_16_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Not later than 6 months after October 24, 2018, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, in consultation with the Director of National Drug Control Policy, establish and periodically update, on the Internet website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a public information dashboard that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_16_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Controlled substance defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Controlled substance defined In this section, the term “controlled substance” has the meaning given that term in section 802 of title 21.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>