<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–4" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–4/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–4/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300u_4"><akn:num>300u–4</akn:num><akn:heading>Status reports to President and Congress; study of health education and preventive health services w</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300u–4. Status reports to President and Congress; study of health education and preventive health services with respect to insurance coverage(a) The Secretary shall, not later than two years after June 23, 1976, and biannually thereafter, submit to the President for transmittal to Congress a report on the status of health information and health promotion, preventive health services, and education in the appropriate use of health care. Each such report shall include—(1) a statement of the activities carried out under this subchapter since the last report and the extent to which each such activity achieves the purposes of this subchapter;

(2) an assessment of the manpower resources needed to carry out programs relating to health information and health promotion, preventive health services, and education in the appropriate use of health care, and a statement describing the activities currently being carried out under this subchapter designed to prepare teachers and other manpower for such programs;

(3) the goals and strategy formulated pursuant to section 300u(a)(1) of this title, the models and standards developed under this subchapter, and the results of the study required by subsection (b) of this section; and

(4) such recommendations as the Secretary considers appropriate for legislation respecting health information and health promotion, preventive health services, and education in the appropriate use of health care, including recommendations for revisions to and extension of this subchapter.


(b) The Secretary shall conduct a study of health education services and preventive health services to determine the coverage of such services under public and private health insurance programs, including the extent and nature of such coverage and the cost sharing requirements required by such programs for coverage of such services.

(July 1, 1944, ch. 373, title XVII, § 1705, as added Pub. L. 94–317, title I, § 102, June 23, 1976, 90 Stat. 699; amended Pub. L. 104–66,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_4_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Secretary shall, not later than two years after June 23, 1976, and biannually thereafter, submit to the President for transmittal to Congress a report on the status of health information and health promotion, preventive health services, and education in the appropriate use of health care. Each such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_4_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The Secretary shall conduct a study of health education services and preventive health services to determine the coverage of such services under public and private health insurance programs, including the extent and nature of such coverage and the cost sharing requirements required by such programs for coverage of such services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>