<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–5" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–5/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–5/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300u_5"><akn:num>300u–5</akn:num><akn:heading>Centers for research and demonstration of health promotion and disease prevention</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300u–5. Centers for research and demonstration of health promotion and disease prevention(a) Establishment; grants; contracts; research and demonstration projectsThe Secretary shall make grants or enter into contracts with academic health centers for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of centers for research and demonstration with respect to health promotion and disease prevention. Centers established, maintained, or operated under this section shall undertake research and demonstration projects in health promotion, disease prevention, and improved methods of appraising health hazards and risk factors, and shall serve as demonstration sites for the use of new and innovative research in public health techniques to prevent chronic diseases.


(b) Location; types of research and projectsEach center established, maintained, or operated under this section shall—(1) be located in an academic health center with—(A) a multidisciplinary faculty with expertise in public health and which has working relationships with relevant groups in such fields as medicine, psychology, nursing, social work, education and business;

(B) graduate training programs relevant to disease prevention;

(C) a core faculty in epidemiology, biostatistics, social sciences, behavioral and environmental health sciences, and health administration;

(D) a demonstrated curriculum in disease prevention;

(E) a capability for residency training in public health or preventive medicine; and

(F) such other qualifications as the Secretary may prescribe;


(2) conduct—(A) health promotion and disease prevention research, including retrospective studies and longitudinal prospective studies in population groups and communities;

(B) demonstration projects for the delivery of services relating to health promotion and disease prevention to defined population groups using, as appropriate, community outreach and organization techniques and other methods of educating and motivating communities; and

(C) ev</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_5_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; grants; contracts; research and demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; grants; contracts; research and demonstration projects The Secretary shall make grants or enter into contracts with academic health centers for the establishment, maintenance, and operation of centers for research and demonstration with respect to health promotion and disease prevention. Centers established, maintained, or operated under this section shall undertake research and demonstration projects in health promotion, disease prevention, and improved methods of appraising health hazards and risk factors, and shall serve as demonstration sites for the use of new and innovative research in public health techniques to prevent chronic diseases.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_5_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Location; types of research and projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Location; types of research and projects Each center established, maintained, or operated under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_5_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equitable geographic distribution of centers; procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equitable geographic distribution of centers; procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_5_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Academic health center” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Academic health center” defined For purposes of this section, the term “academic health center” means a school of medicine, a school of osteopathy, or a school of public health, as such terms are defined in section 292a(4) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_5_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for fiscal year 1992, and such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1993 through 2003.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>