<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–10" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–10/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–10/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300u_10"><akn:num>300u–10</akn:num><akn:heading>National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300u–10. National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council(a) EstablishmentThe President shall establish, within the Department of Health and Human Services, a council to be known as the “National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council” (referred to in this section as the “Council”).


(b) ChairpersonThe President shall appoint the Surgeon General to serve as the chairperson of the Council.


(c) CompositionThe Council shall be composed of—(1) the Secretary of Health and Human Services;

(2) the Secretary of Agriculture;

(3) the Secretary of Education;

(4) the Chairman of the Federal Trade Commission;

(5) the Secretary of Transportation;

(6) the Secretary of Labor;

(7) the Secretary of Homeland Security;

(8) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;

(9) the Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy;

(10) the Director of the Domestic Policy Council;

(11) the Assistant Secretary for Indian Affairs;

(12) the Chairman of the Corporation for National and Community Service; and

(13) the head of any other Federal agency that the chairperson determines is appropriate.


(d) Purposes and dutiesThe Council shall—(1) provide coordination and leadership at the Federal level, and among all Federal departments and agencies, with respect to prevention, wellness and health promotion practices, the public health system, and integrative health care in the United States;

(2) after obtaining input from relevant stakeholders, develop a national prevention, health promotion, public health, and integrative health care strategy that incorporates the most effective and achievable means of improving the health status of Americans and reducing the incidence of preventable illness and disability in the United States;

(3) provide recommendations to the President and Congress concerning the most pressing health issues confronting the United States and changes in Federal policy to achieve national wellness, health promotion</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The President shall establish, within the Department of Health and Human Services, a council to be known as the “National Prevention, Health Promotion and Public Health Council” (referred to in this section as the “Council”).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Chairperson</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Chairperson The President shall appoint the Surgeon General to serve as the chairperson of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition The Council shall be composed of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes and duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Purposes and duties The Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Meetings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Meetings The Council shall meet at the call of the Chairperson.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory Group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Advisory Group</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>National prevention and health promotion strategy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) National prevention and health promotion strategy Not later than 1 year after March 23, 2010, the Chairperson, in consultation with the Council, shall develop and make public a national prevention, health promotion and public health strategy, and shall review and revise such strategy periodically. Such strategy shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report Not later than July 1, 2010, and annually thereafter through January 1, 2015, the Council shall submit to the President and the relevant committees of Congress, a report that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_10_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Periodic reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Periodic reviews The Secretary shall conduct periodic reviews, not less than every 5 years, and evaluations of every Federal disease prevention and health promotion initiative, program, and agency. Such reviews shall be evaluated based on effectiveness in meeting metrics-based goals with an analysis posted on such agencies’ public Internet websites.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>