<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–12" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–12/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300u–12/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300u_12"><akn:num>300u–12</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach campaign regarding preventive benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300u–12. Education and outreach campaign regarding preventive benefits(a) In generalThe Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall provide for the planning and implementation of a national public–private partnership for a prevention and health promotion outreach and education campaign to raise public awareness of health improvement across the life span. Such campaign shall include the dissemination of information that—(1) describes the importance of utilizing preventive services to promote wellness, reduce health disparities, and mitigate chronic disease;

(2) promotes the use of preventive services recommended by the United States Preventive Services Task Force and the Community Preventive Services Task Force;

(3) encourages healthy behaviors linked to the prevention of chronic diseases;

(4) explains the preventive services covered under health plans offered through an Exchange;

(5) describes additional preventive care supported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Health Resources and Services Administration, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices, and other appropriate agencies; and

(6) includes general health promotion information.


(b) ConsultationIn coordinating the campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Institute of Medicine to provide ongoing advice on evidence-based scientific information for policy, program development, and evaluation.


(c) Media campaign(1) In generalNot later than 1 year after March 23, 2010, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish and implement a national science-based media campaign on health promotion and disease prevention.


(2) Requirement of campaignThe campaign implemented under paragraph (1)—(A) shall be designed to address proper nutrition, regular exercise, smoking cessation, obesit</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall provide for the planning and implementation of a national public–private partnership for a prevention and health promotion outreach and education campaign to raise public awareness of health improvement across the life span. Such campaign shall include the dissemination of information that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation In coordinating the campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with the Institute of Medicine to provide ongoing advice on evidence-based scientific information for policy, program development, and evaluation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Media campaign</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Media campaign</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Website</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Website The Secretary, in consultation with private-sector experts, shall maintain or enter into a contract to maintain an Internet website to provide science-based information on guidelines for nutrition, regular exercise, obesity reduction, smoking cessation, and specific chronic disease prevention. Such website shall be designed to provide information to health care providers and consumers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information through providers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dissemination of information through providers The Secretary, acting through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall develop and implement a plan for the dissemination of health promotion and disease prevention information consistent with national priorities, to health care providers who participate in Federal programs, including programs administered by the Indian Health Service, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the Health Resources and Services Administration, and Medicare and Medicaid.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personalized prevention plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Personalized prevention plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Internet portal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Internet portal The Secretary shall establish an Internet portal for accessing risk-assessment tools developed and maintained by private and academic entities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Priority funding Funding for the activities authorized under this section shall take priority over funding provided through the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for grants to States and other entities for similar purposes and goals as provided for in this section. Not to exceed $500,000,000 shall be expended on the campaigns and activities required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public awareness of preventive and obesity-related services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Public awareness of preventive and obesity-related services</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300u_12_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>