<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300w–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300w–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300w–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300w_1"><akn:num>300w–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300w–1. Allotments(a) Availability based upon prior year distributions(1) From the amounts appropriated under section 300w of this title for any fiscal year and available for allotment under this subsection, the Secretary shall allot to each State an amount which bears the same ratio to the available amounts for that fiscal year as the amounts provided by the Secretary under the provisions of law listed in paragraph (2) to the State and entities in the State for fiscal year 1981 bore to the total amount appropriated for such provisions of law for fiscal year 1981.

(2) The provisions of law referred to in paragraph (1) are the following provisions of law as in effect on September 30, 1981:(A) The authority for grants under section 247b of this title for preventive health service programs for the control of rodents.

(B) The authority for grants under section 247b of this title for establishing and maintaining community and school-based fluoridation programs.

(C) The authority for grants under section 247b of this title for preventive health service programs for hypertension.

(D) Sections 247b–1 11 See References in Text note below. and 247b–2 of this title.

(E) Section 246(d) 1 of this title.

(F) Section 255(a) 1 of this title.

(G) Sections 300d–1,1 300d–2,1 and 300d–3 1 of this title.



(b) PopulationFrom the amount required to be made available under section 300w(b) of this title for allotments under this subsection for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall make allotments to each State on the basis of the population of the State.


(c) Distribution of appropriated funds not allottedTo the extent that all the funds appropriated under section 300w of this title for a fiscal year and available for allotment in such fiscal year are not otherwise allotted to States because—(1) one or more States have not submitted an application or description of activities in accordance with section 300w–4 of this title for the fiscal year;

(2) one or more States have notifie</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300w_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability based upon prior year distributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability based upon prior year distributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300w_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Population From the amount required to be made available under section 300w(b) of this title for allotments under this subsection for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall make allotments to each State on the basis of the population of the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300w_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distribution of appropriated funds not allotted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Distribution of appropriated funds not allotted To the extent that all the funds appropriated under section 300w of this title for a fiscal year and available for allotment in such fiscal year are not otherwise allotted to States because— such excess shall be allotted among each of the remaining States in proportion to the amount otherwise allotted to such States for the fiscal year without regard to this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300w_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Distributions to Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Distributions to Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300w_1_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report on equitable distribution of available funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Report on equitable distribution of available funds The Secretary shall conduct a study for the purpose of devising a formula for the equitable distribution of funds available for allotment to the States under this section. In conducting the study, the Secretary shall take into account— Before June 30, 1982, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress respecting the development of a formula and make such recommendations as the Secretary may deem appropriate in order to ensure the most equitable distribution of funds under allotments under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>