<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–26" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–26/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–26/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300x_26"><akn:num>300x–26</akn:num><akn:heading>Sale of tobacco products to individuals under age of 21</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300x–26. Sale of tobacco products to individuals under age of 21(a) In generalA funding agreement for a grant under section 300x–21 of this title is that the State involved will—(1) annually conduct random, unannounced inspections to ensure that retailers do not sell tobacco products to individuals under the age of 21; and

(2) annually submit to the Secretary a report describing—(A) the activities carried out by the State to ensure that retailers do not sell tobacco products to individuals under the age of 21;

(B) the extent of success the State has achieved in ensuring that retailers do not sell tobacco products to individuals under the age of 21; and

(C) the strategies to be utilized by the State to ensure that retailers do not sell tobacco products to individuals under the age of 21 during the fiscal year for which the grant is sought.



(b) Noncompliance of State(1) In generalBefore making a grant under section 300x–21 of this title to a State, the Secretary shall make a determination of whether the State has maintained compliance with subsection (a). If, after notice to the State and an opportunity for a hearing, the Secretary determines that the State is not in compliance with such subsections, the Secretary shall reduce the amount of the allotment under such section for the State for the fiscal year involved by an amount up to 10 percent of the amount determined under section 300x–33 of this title for the State for the applicable fiscal year.


(2) Limitation(A) In generalA State shall not have funds withheld pursuant to paragraph (1) if such State for which the Secretary has made a determination of noncompliance under such paragraph—(i) certifies to the Secretary by May 1 of the fiscal year for which the funds are appropriated, consistent with subparagraph (B), that the State will commit additional State funds, in accordance with paragraph (1), to ensure that retailers do not sell tobacco products to individuals under 21 years of age;

(ii) agrees to c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_26_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A funding agreement for a grant under section 300x–21 of this title is that the State involved will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_26_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Noncompliance of State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Noncompliance of State</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_26_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation of reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Implementation of reporting requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_26_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transitional grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transitional grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_26_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to States related to the activities required under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>