<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–9" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–9/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–9/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300x_9"><akn:num>300x–9</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300x–9. Funding(a) Authorization of appropriationsFor the purpose of carrying out this subpart, and subpart III and section 290aa–4(c) of this title with respect to mental health, there are authorized to be appropriated $857,571,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.


(b) Allocations for technical assistance, data collection, and program evaluation(1) In generalFor the purpose of carrying out section 300x–58(a) of this title with respect to mental health and the purposes specified in paragraphs (2) and (3), the Secretary shall obligate 5 percent of the amounts appropriated under subsection (a) for a fiscal year.


(2) Data collectionThe purpose specified in this paragraph is carrying out sections 290aa–4(c) and 300y of this title with respect to mental health.


(3) Program evaluationThe purpose specified in this paragraph is the conduct of evaluations of prevention and treatment programs and services with respect to mental health to determine methods for improving the availability and quality of such programs and services.



(c) Early serious mental illness(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (2), a State shall expend not less than 10 percent of the amount the State receives for carrying out this section for each fiscal year to support evidence-based programs that address the needs of individuals with early serious mental illness, including psychotic disorders, regardless of the age of the individual at onset.


(2) State flexibilityIn lieu of expending 10 percent of the amount the State receives under this section for a fiscal year as required under paragraph (1), a State may elect to expend not less than 20 percent of such amount by the end of such succeeding fiscal year.



(d) Crisis care(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraph (3), a State shall expend at least 5 percent of the amount the State receives pursuant to section 300x of this title for each fiscal year to support evidenced-based programs that address the crisis care needs o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_9_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of appropriations For the purpose of carrying out this subpart, and subpart III and section 290aa–4(c) of this title with respect to mental health, there are authorized to be appropriated $857,571,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_9_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocations for technical assistance, data collection, and program evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocations for technical assistance, data collection, and program evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_9_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Early serious mental illness</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Early serious mental illness</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_9_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Crisis care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Crisis care</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>