<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300x_2"><akn:num>300x–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300x–2. Certain agreements(a) Allocation for systems of integrated services for children(1) In generalWith respect to children with a serious emotional disturbance, a funding agreement for a grant under section 300x of this title is that—(A) in the case of a grant for fiscal year 1993, the State involved will expend not less than 10 percent of the grant to increase (relative to fiscal year 1992) funding for the system of integrated services described in section 300x–1(b)(9) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title;

(B) in the case of a grant for fiscal year 1994, the State will expend not less than 10 percent of the grant to increase (relative to fiscal year 1993) funding for such system; and

(C) in the case of a grant for any subsequent fiscal year, the State will expend for such system not less than an amount equal to the amount expended by the State for fiscal year 1994.


(2) Waiver(A) Upon the request of a State, the Secretary may provide to the State a waiver of all or part of the requirement established in paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that the State is providing an adequate level of comprehensive community mental health services for children with a serious emotional distrubance,22 So in original. Probably should be “disturbance,”. as indicated by a comparison of the number of such children for which such services are sought with the availability in the State of the services.

(B) The Secretary shall approve or deny a request for a waiver under subparagraph (A) not later than 120 days after the date on which the request is made.

(C) Any waiver provided by the Secretary under subparagraph (A) shall be applicable only to the fiscal year involved.



(b) Providers of servicesA funding agreement for a grant under section 300x of this title for a State is that, with respect to the plan submitted under section 300x–1(a) of this title for the fiscal year involved—(1) services under the plan will be provided only through appropriate, quali</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation for systems of integrated services for children</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Allocation for systems of integrated services for children</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Providers of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Providers of services A funding agreement for a grant under section 300x of this title for a State is that, with respect to the plan submitted under section 300x–1(a) of this title for the fiscal year involved—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for mental health centers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for mental health centers The criteria referred to in subsection (b)(2) regarding community mental health centers are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>