<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–55" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–55/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300x–55/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300x_55"><akn:num>300x–55</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to comply with agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300x–55. Failure to comply with agreements(a) Suspension or termination of paymentsSubject to subsection (e), if the Secretary determines that a State has materially failed to comply with the agreements or other conditions required for the receipt of a grant under the program involved, the Secretary may in whole or in part suspend payments under the grant, terminate the grant for cause, or employ such other remedies (including the remedies provided for in subsections (b) and (c)) as may be legally available and appropriate in the circumstances involved.


(b) Repayment of payments(1) In generalSubject to subsection (e), the Secretary may require a State to repay with interest any payments received by the State under section 300x or 300x–21 of this title that the Secretary determines were not expended by the State in accordance with the agreements required under the program involved.


(2) Offset against paymentsIf a State fails to make a repayment required in paragraph (1), the Secretary may offset the amount of the repayment against the amount of any payment due to be paid to the State under the program involved.



(c) Withholding of payments(1) In generalSubject to subsections (e) and (g)(3), the Secretary may withhold payments due under section 300x or 300x–21 of this title if the Secretary determines that the State involved is not expending amounts received under the program involved in accordance with the agreements required under the program.


(2) Termination of withholdingThe Secretary shall cease withholding payments from a State under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines that there are reasonable assurances that the State will expend amounts received under the program involved in accordance with the agreements required under the program.



(d) Applicability of remedies to certain violations(1) In generalWith respect to agreements or other conditions for receiving a grant under the program involved, in the case of the failure of a State to maintain</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Suspension or termination of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Suspension or termination of payments Subject to subsection (e), if the Secretary determines that a State has materially failed to comply with the agreements or other conditions required for the receipt of a grant under the program involved, the Secretary may in whole or in part suspend payments under the grant, terminate the grant for cause, or employ such other remedies (including the remedies provided for in subsections (b) and (c)) as may be legally available and appropriate in the circumstances involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repayment of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withholding of payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of remedies to certain violations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability of remedies to certain violations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Opportunity for hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Opportunity for hearing Before taking action against a State under any of subsections (a) through (c) (or under a section referred to in subsection (d)(2), as the case may be), the Secretary shall provide to the State involved adequate notice and an opportunity for a hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of hearing in certain circumstances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Requirement of hearing in certain circumstances</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300x_55_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certain investigations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Certain investigations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>