<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300z–7" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300z–7/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/300z–7/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_300z_7"><akn:num>300z–7</akn:num><akn:heading>Research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 300z–7. Research(a) Grants and contracts; duration; renewal; amount(1) The Secretary may make grants and enter into contracts with public agencies or private organizations or institutions of higher education to support the research and dissemination activities described in paragraphs (4), (5), and (6) of section 300z(b) of this title.

(2) The Secretary may make grants or enter into contracts under this section for a period of one year. A grant or contract under this section for a project may be renewed for four additional one-year periods, which need not be consecutive.

(3) A grant or contract for any one-year period under this section may not exceed $100,000 for the direct costs of conducting research or disemination 11 So in original. Probably should be “dissemination”. activities under this section and may include such additional amounts for the indirect costs of conducting such activities as the Secretary determines appropriate. The Secretary may waive the preceding sentence with respect to a specific project if he determines that—(A) exceptional circumstances warrant such waiver and that the project will have national impact; or

(B) additional amounts are necessary for the direct costs of conducting limited demonstration projects for the provision of necessary services in order to provide data for research carried out under this subchapter.


(4) The amount of any grant or contract made under this section may remain available for obligation or expenditure after the close of the one-year period for which such grant or contract is made in order to assist the recipient in preparing the report required by subsection (f)(1).


(b) Scope of permissible activities(1) Funds provided for research under this section may be used for descriptive or explanatory surveys, longitudinal studies, or limited demonstration projects for services that are for the purpose of increasing knowledge and understanding of the matters described in paragraphs (4) and (5) of section 300z</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts; duration; renewal; amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants and contracts; duration; renewal; amount</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Scope of permissible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Scope of permissible activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications The Secretary may not make any grant or enter into any contract to support research or dissemination activities under this section unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with National Institutes of Health</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination with National Institutes of Health The Secretary shall, where appropriate, coordinate research and dissemination activities carried out under this section with research and dissemination activities carried out by the National Institutes of Health.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of applications for grants and contracts; establishment of review panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Review of applications for grants and contracts; establishment of review panel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_300z_7_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Reports</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>