<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3012" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3012/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3012/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3012"><akn:num>3012</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Assistant Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3012. Functions of Assistant Secretary(a) Duties and functions of AdministrationIt shall be the duty and function of the Administration to—(1) serve as the effective and visible advocate for older individuals within the Department of Health and Human Services and with other departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal Government by maintaining active review and commenting responsibilities over all Federal policies affecting older individuals;

(2) collect and disseminate information related to problems of the aged and aging;

(3) directly assist the Secretary in all matters pertaining to problems of the aged and aging;

(4) administer the grants provided by this chapter, but not approve an application submitted by an applicant for a grant for an activity under a provision of this chapter for which such applicant previously received a grant under such provision unless the Assistant Secretary determines—(A) the activity for which such application was submitted is being operated, or was operated, effectively to achieve its stated purpose; and

(B) such applicant has complied with the assurances provided to the Assistant Secretary with the application for such previous grant.11 So in original. The period probably should be a semicolon.


(5) develop plans, conduct and arrange for research in the field of aging, and assist in the establishment and implementation of programs designed to meet the health and economic needs of older individuals for supportive services, including nutrition, hospitalization, education and training services (including preretirement training, and continuing education), cultural experiences, activities, and services, including in the arts, low-cost transportation and housing, assistive technology, and health (including mental and behavioral health) services;

(6) provide technical assistance and consultation to States and political subdivisions thereof with respect to programs for the aged and aging;

(7) prepare, publish, and di</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions of Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Duties and functions of Administration It shall be the duty and function of the Administration to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and implementation of comprehensive, coordinated systems for long-term care</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Development and implementation of comprehensive, coordinated systems for long-term care To promote the development and implementation of comprehensive, coordinated systems at Federal, State, and local levels that enable older individuals to receive long-term care in home and community-based settings, in a manner responsive to the needs and preferences of older individuals and their family caregivers, the Assistant Secretary shall, consistent with the applicable provisions of this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Encouragement of participation by volunteer groups, utilization of older individuals, and cost savings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Encouragement of participation by volunteer groups, utilization of older individuals, and cost savings The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation for National and Community Service, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Center on Elder Abuse</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) National Center on Elder Abuse</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Aging Information Center</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) National Aging Information Center</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of performance outcome measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Development of performance outcome measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Training and provision of services addressing elder justice and exploitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Training and provision of services addressing elder justice and exploitation The Assistant Secretary shall, as appropriate, ensure that programs authorized under this chapter include appropriate training in the prevention of abuse, neglect, and exploitation and provision of services that address elder justice and the exploitation of older individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of funded centers and demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Publication of funded centers and demonstration projects The Assistant Secretary shall publish, on an annual basis, a list of centers and demonstration projects funded under each subchapter of this chapter. The Assistant Secretary shall ensure that this information is also directly provided to State agencies and area agencies on aging.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3012_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>RAISE Family Caregivers Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) RAISE Family Caregivers Act The Assistant Secretary shall carry out the RAISE Family Caregivers Act (42 U.S.C. 3030s note).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>