<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3015" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3015/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3015/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3015"><akn:num>3015</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts and donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3015. Gifts and donations(a) Gifts and donationsThe Assistant Secretary may accept, use, and dispose of, on behalf of the United States, gifts or donations (in cash or in kind, including voluntary and uncompensated services or property), which shall be available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (b). Gifts of cash and proceeds of the sale of property shall be available in addition to amounts appropriated to carry out this chapter.


(b) Use of gifts and donationsGifts and donations accepted pursuant to subsection (a) may be used either directly, or for grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private entities, for the following activities:(1) The design and implementation of demonstrations of innovative ideas and best practices in programs and services for older individuals.

(2) The planning and conduct of conferences for the purpose of exchanging information, among concerned individuals and public and private entities and organizations, relating to programs and services provided under this chapter and other programs and services for older individuals.

(3) The development, publication, and dissemination of informational materials (in print, visual, electronic, or other media) relating to the programs and services provided under this chapter and other matters of concern to older individuals.


(c) Ethics guidelinesThe Assistant Secretary shall establish written guidelines setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether a gift or donation should be declined under this section because the acceptance of the gift or donation would—(1) reflect unfavorably upon the ability of the Administration, the Department of Health and Human Services, or any employee of the Administration or Department, to carry out responsibilities or official duties under this chapter in a fair and objective manner; or

(2) compromise the integrity or the appearance of integrity of programs or services provided under this chapter or of any official invol</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3015_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts and donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Gifts and donations The Assistant Secretary may accept, use, and dispose of, on behalf of the United States, gifts or donations (in cash or in kind, including voluntary and uncompensated services or property), which shall be available until expended for the purposes specified in subsection (b). Gifts of cash and proceeds of the sale of property shall be available in addition to amounts appropriated to carry out this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3015_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of gifts and donations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Use of gifts and donations Gifts and donations accepted pursuant to subsection (a) may be used either directly, or for grants to or contracts with public or nonprofit private entities, for the following activities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3015_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Ethics guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Ethics guidelines The Assistant Secretary shall establish written guidelines setting forth the criteria to be used in determining whether a gift or donation should be declined under this section because the acceptance of the gift or donation would—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>