<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3026" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3026/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3026/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3026"><akn:num>3026</akn:num><akn:heading>Area plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3026. Area plans(a) Preparation and development by area agency on aging; requirementsEach area agency on aging designated under section 3025(a)(2)(A) of this title shall, in order to be approved by the State agency, prepare and develop an area plan for a planning and service area for a two-, three-, or four-year period determined by the State agency, with such annual adjustments as may be necessary. Each such plan shall be based upon a uniform format for area plans within the State prepared in accordance with section 3027(a)(1) of this title. Each such plan shall—(1) provide, through a comprehensive and coordinated system, for supportive services, nutrition services, and, where appropriate, for the establishment, maintenance, modernization, or construction of multipurpose senior centers (including a plan to use the skills and services of older individuals in paid and unpaid work, including multigenerational and older individual to older individual work), within the planning and service area covered by the plan, including determining the extent of need for supportive services, nutrition services, and multipurpose senior centers in such area (taking into consideration, among other things, the number of older individuals with low incomes residing in such area, the number of older individuals who have greatest economic need (with particular attention to low-income older individuals, including low-income minority older individuals, older individuals with limited English proficiency, and older individuals residing in rural areas) residing in such area, the number of older individuals who have greatest social need (with particular attention to low-income older individuals, including low-income minority older individuals, older individuals with limited English proficiency, and older individuals residing in rural areas) residing in such area, the number of older individuals at risk for institutional placement residing in such area, the number of older individuals at risk f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and development by area agency on aging; requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation and development by area agency on aging; requirements Each area agency on aging designated under section 3025(a)(2)(A) of this title shall, in order to be approved by the State agency, prepare and develop an area plan for a planning and service area for a two-, three-, or four-year period determined by the State agency, with such annual adjustments as may be necessary. Each such plan shall be based upon a uniform format for area plans within the State prepared in accordance with section 3027(a)(1) of this title. Each such plan shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment of preparation of area agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assessment of preparation of area agencies</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of requirements Each State, in approving area agency on aging plans under this section, shall waive the requirement described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a) for any category of services described in such paragraph if the area agency on aging demonstrates to the State agency that services being furnished for such category in the area are sufficient to meet the need for such services in such area and had conducted a timely public hearing upon request.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transportation services; funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transportation services; funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Confidentiality of information relating to legal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Confidentiality of information relating to legal assistance An area agency on aging may not require any provider of legal assistance under this subchapter to reveal any information that is protected by the attorney-client privilege.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of area funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Withholding of area funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3026_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>No restriction on provision of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) No restriction on provision of services Nothing in this chapter shall restrict an area agency on aging from providing services not provided or authorized by this chapter, including through—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>