<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030c–2" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030c–2/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030c–2/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3030c_2"><akn:num>3030c–2</akn:num><akn:heading>Consumer contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3030c–2. Consumer contributions(a) Cost sharing(1) In generalExcept as provided in paragraphs (2) and (3), a State is permitted to implement cost sharing for all services funded by this chapter by recipients of the services.


(2) ExceptionThe State is not permitted to implement the cost sharing described in paragraph (1) for the following services:(A) Information and assistance, outreach, benefits counseling, or case management services.

(B) Ombudsman, elder abuse prevention, legal assistance, or other consumer protection services.

(C) Congregate and home delivered meals.

(D) Any services delivered through tribal organizations.


(3) ProhibitionsA State or tribal organization shall not permit the cost sharing described in paragraph (1) for any services delivered through tribal organizations. A State shall not permit cost sharing by a low-income older individual if the income of such individual is at or below the Federal poverty line. A State may exclude from cost sharing low-income individuals whose incomes are above the Federal poverty line. A State shall not consider any assets, savings, or other property owned by older individuals when defining low-income individuals who are exempt from cost sharing, when creating a sliding scale for the cost sharing, or when seeking contributions from any older individual.


(4) Payment ratesIf a State permits the cost sharing described in paragraph (1), such State shall establish a sliding scale, based solely on individual income and the cost of delivering services.


(5) RequirementsIf a State permits the cost sharing described in paragraph (1), such State shall require each area agency on aging in the State to ensure that each service provider involved, and the area agency on aging, will—(A) protect the privacy and confidentiality of each older individual with respect to the declaration or nondeclaration of individual income and to any share of costs paid or unpaid by an individual;

(B) establish appropriate procedures</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030c_2_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030c_2_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Voluntary contributions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Voluntary contributions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030c_2_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Participation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030c_2_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluation Not later than 1 year after November 13, 2000, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary shall conduct a comprehensive evaluation of practices for cost sharing to determine its impact on participation rates (with particular attention to low-income older individuals, including low-income minority older individuals, older individuals with limited English proficiency, and older individuals residing in rural areas). If the Assistant Secretary finds that there is a disparate impact upon low-income or minority older individuals or older individuals residing in rural areas in any State or region within the State regarding the provision of services, the Assistant Secretary shall take corrective action to assure that such services are provided to all older individuals without regard to the cost sharing criteria.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030c_2_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Response to area agencies on aging</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Response to area agencies on aging</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>