<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3030a"><akn:num>3030a</akn:num><akn:heading>Nutrition services incentive program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3030a. Nutrition services incentive program(a) PurposeThe purpose of this section is to provide incentives to encourage and reward effective performance by States and tribal organizations in the efficient delivery of nutritious meals to older individuals.


(b) Allotment and provision and payment(1) The Secretary shall allot and provide, in accordance with this section, to or on behalf of each State agency with a plan approved under this subchapter for a fiscal year, and to or on behalf of each grantee with an application approved under subchapter X for such fiscal year, an amount bearing the same ratio to the total amount appropriated for such fiscal year under subsection (e) as the number of meals served in the State under such plan approved for the preceding fiscal year (or the number of meals served by the title VI [subchapter X] grantee, under such application approved for such preceding fiscal year), bears to the total number of such meals served in all States and by all title VI [subchapter X] grantees under all such plans and applications approved for such preceding fiscal year.

(2) For purposes of paragraph (1), in the case of a grantee that has an application approved under subchapter X for a fiscal year but that did not receive assistance under this section for the preceding fiscal year, the number of meals served by the title VI [subchapter X] grantee for the preceding fiscal year shall be deemed to equal the number of meals that the Assistant Secretary estimates will be served by the title VI [subchapter X] grantee in the fiscal year for which the application was approved.


(c) Donation of products(1) Agricultural commodities (including bonus commodities) and products purchased by the Secretary of Agriculture under section 612c of title 7, shall be donated to a recipient of a grant or contract to be used for providing nutrition services in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.

(2) The Commodity Credit Corporation shall dispose of food </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purpose of this section is to provide incentives to encourage and reward effective performance by States and tribal organizations in the efficient delivery of nutritious meals to older individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment and provision and payment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allotment and provision and payment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Donation of products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Donation of products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Option to obtain commodities from Secretary of Agriculture</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Option to obtain commodities from Secretary of Agriculture</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section (other than subsection (c)(1)) $171,273,830 for fiscal year 2020, $181,550,260 for fiscal year 2021, $192,443,275 for fiscal year 2022, $203,989,872 for fiscal year 2023, and $216,229,264 for fiscal year 2024.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3030a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Dissemination of information In each fiscal year, the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly disseminate to State agencies, title VI [subchapter X] grantees, area agencies on aging, and providers of nutrition services assisted under this subchapter, information concerning the foods available to such State agencies, title VI [subchapter X] grantees, area agencies on aging, and providers under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>