<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3030g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3030g"><akn:num>3030g</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3030g. Criteria
The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with recognized experts in the fields of nutrition science, dietetics, meal planning and food service management, and aging, shall develop minimum criteria of efficiency and quality for the furnishing of home delivered meal services for projects described in section 3030f of this title.
(Pub. L. 89–73, title III, § 337, as added Pub. L. 95–478, title I, § 103(b), Oct. 18, 1978, 92 Stat. 1536; amended Pub. L. 97–115, § 10(e), Dec. 29, 1981, 95 Stat. 1601; Pub. L. 100–175, title I, § 182(n), Nov. 29, 1987, 101 Stat. 967; Pub. L. 102–375, title III, § 315, Sept. 30, 1992, 106 Stat. 1239; Pub. L. 103–171, § 3(a)(13), Dec. 2, 1993, 107 Stat. 1990; Pub. L. 109–365, title III, § 315, Oct. 17, 2006, 120 Stat. 2548.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2006—Pub. L. 109–365 amended section generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with organizations of and for the aged, blind, and disabled, and with representatives from the American Dietetic Association, the Dietary Managers Association, the National Association of Area Agencies on Aging, the National Association of Nutrition and Aging Services Programs, the National Association of Meals Programs, Incorporated, and any other appropriate group, shall develop minimum criteria of efficiency and quality for the furnishing of home delivered meal services for projects described in section 3030f of this title. The criteria required by this section shall take into account the ability of established home delivered meals programs to continue such services without major alteration in the furnishing of such services.”
1993—Pub. L. 103–171 substituted “Assistant Secretary” for “Commissioner”.
1992—Pub. L. 102–375 inserted “the Dietary Managers Association,” after “Dietetic Association,”.
1987—Pub. L. 100–175 substituted “National Association of Area Agencies” for “Association of Area Agencies”.
1981—Pub. L. 97–115 substituted “National A</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>