<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3032f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3032f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3032f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3032f"><akn:num>3032f</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration, support, and research projects for multigenerational and civic engagement activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3032f. Demonstration, support, and research projects for multigenerational and civic engagement activities(a) Grants and contractsThe Assistant Secretary shall award grants to and enter into contracts with eligible organizations to carry out projects, serving individuals in younger generations and older individuals, to—(1) provide opportunities for older individuals to participate in multigenerational activities and civic engagement activities that contribute to the health and wellness of older individuals and individuals in younger generations by promoting—(A) meaningful roles for participants;

(B) reciprocity in relationship building;

(C) reduced social isolation and improved participant social connectedness;

(D) improved economic well-being for older individuals;

(E) increased lifelong learning; or

(F) support for caregivers of families by—(i) providing support for older relative caregivers (as defined in section 3030s(a) of this title) raising children (such as support for kinship navigator programs); or

(ii) involving volunteers who are older individuals who provide support and information to families who have a child with a disability or chronic illness, or other families in need of such family support;



(2) coordinate multigenerational activities and civic engagement activities, including multigenerational nutrition and meal service programs;

(3) promote volunteerism, including by providing opportunities for older individuals to become a mentor to individuals in younger generations; and

(4) facilitate development of, and participation in, multigenerational activities and civic engagement activities.


(b) Grant and contract periodsEach grant awarded and contract entered into under subsection (a) shall be for a period of not less than 36 months.


(c) Use of funds(1) In generalAn eligible organization shall use funds made available under a grant awarded, or a contract entered into, under this section to carry out a project described in subsection (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Grants and contracts The Assistant Secretary shall award grants to and enter into contracts with eligible organizations to carry out projects, serving individuals in younger generations and older individuals, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant and contract periods</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant and contract periods Each grant awarded and contract entered into under subsection (a) shall be for a period of not less than 36 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preference</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preference In awarding grants and entering into contracts to carry out a project described in subsection (a), the Assistant Secretary shall give preference to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Application To be eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract under subsection (a), an organization shall submit an application to the Assistant Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Assistant Secretary may reasonably require.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Eligible organizations Organizations eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract under subsection (a) shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Evaluation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3032f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>