<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3056"><akn:num>3056</akn:num><akn:heading>Older American community service employment program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3056. Older American community service employment program(a) In general(1) Establishment of programTo foster individual economic self-sufficiency and promote useful opportunities in community service activities (which shall include community service employment) for unemployed low-income persons who are age 55 or older, particularly persons who have poor employment prospects, and to increase the number of persons who may enjoy the benefits of unsubsidized employment in both the public and private sectors, the Secretary of Labor (referred to in this subchapter as the “Secretary”) may establish an older American community service employment program.


(2) Use of appropriated amountsAmounts appropriated to carry out this subchapter shall be used only to carry out the provisions contained in this subchapter.



(b) Grant authority(1) ProjectsTo carry out this subchapter, the Secretary may make grants to public and nonprofit private agencies and organizations, agencies of a State, and tribal organizations to carry out the program established under subsection (a). Such grants may provide for the payment of costs, as provided in subsection (c), of projects developed by such organizations and agencies in cooperation with the Secretary in order to make such program effective or to supplement such program. The Secretary shall make the grants from allotments made under section 3056d of this title, and in accordance with section 3056l of this title. No payment shall be made by the Secretary toward the cost of any project established or administered by such an organization or agency unless the Secretary determines that such project—(A) will provide community service employment only for eligible individuals except for necessary technical, administrative, and supervisory personnel, and such personnel will, to the fullest extent possible, be recruited from among eligible individuals;

(B)(i) will provide community service employment and other authorized activities for eligible ind</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Grant authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share and use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Federal share and use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Project description</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Project description Whenever a grantee conducts a project within a planning and service area in a State, such grantee shall conduct such project in consultation with the area agency on aging of the planning and service area and the local workforce development board and shall submit to the State agency, the local workforce development board, and the area agency on aging a description of such project to be conducted in the State, including the location of the project, 90 days prior to undertaking the project, for review and public comment according to guidelines the Secretary shall issue to assure efficient and effective coordination of projects under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pilot, demonstration, and evaluation projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Pilot, demonstration, and evaluation projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>