<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056p" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056p/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3056p/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3056p"><akn:num>3056p</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3056p. Definitions and rule(a) DefinitionsFor purposes of this subchapter:(1) Community serviceThe term “community service” means—(A) social, health, welfare, and educational services (including literacy tutoring), legal and other counseling services and assistance, including tax counseling and assistance and financial counseling, and library, recreational, and other similar services;

(B) conservation, maintenance, or restoration of natural resources;

(C) community betterment or beautification;

(D) antipollution and environmental quality efforts;

(E) weatherization activities;

(F) economic development; and

(G) such other services essential and necessary to the community as the Secretary determines by rule to be appropriate.


(2) Community service employmentThe term “community service employment” means part-time, temporary employment paid with grant funds in projects described in section 3056(b)(1)(D) of this title, through which eligible individuals are engaged in community service and receive work experience and job skills that can lead to unsubsidized employment.


(3) Eligible individual(A) In generalThe term “eligible individual” means an individual who is age 55 or older and who has a low income (including any such individual whose income is not more than 125 percent of the poverty line), excluding any income that is unemployment compensation, a benefit received under title XVI of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1381 et seq.), a payment made to or on behalf of veterans or former members of the Armed Forces under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or 25 percent of a benefit received under title II of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.), subject to subsection (b).


(B) Participation(i) ExclusionNotwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, the term “eligible individual” does not include an individual who has participated in projects under this subchapter for a period of 48 months in the aggregate (whether</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056p_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For purposes of this subchapter:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3056p_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Rule Pursuant to regulations prescribed by the Secretary, an eligible individual shall have priority for the community service employment and other authorized activities provided under this subchapter if the individual—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>