<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3057e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3057e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3057e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3057e"><akn:num>3057e</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3057e. Applications(a) Approval criteria; provisions and assurancesNo grant may be made under this part unless the eligible tribal organization submits an application to the Assistant Secretary which meets such criteria as the Assistant Secretary may by regulation prescribe. Each such application shall—(1) provide that the eligible tribal organization will evaluate the need for supportive and nutrition services among older individuals who are Indians to be represented by the tribal organization;

(2) provide for the use of such methods of administration as are necessary for the proper and efficient administration of the program to be assisted;

(3) provide that the tribal organization will make such reports in such form and containing such information, as the Assistant Secretary may reasonably require, and comply with such requirements as the Assistant Secretary may impose to assure the correctness of such reports;

(4) provide for periodic evaluation of activities and projects carried out under the application;

(5) establish objectives consistent with the purposes of this part toward which activities under the application will be directed, identify obstacles to the attainment of such objectives, and indicate the manner in which the tribal organization proposes to overcome such obstacles;

(6) provide for establishing and maintaining information and assistance services to assure that older individuals who are Indians to be served by the assistance made available under this part will have reasonably convenient access to such services;

(7) provide a preference for older individuals who are Indians for full or part-time staff positions wherever feasible;

(8) provide assurances that either directly or by way of grant or contract with appropriate entities nutrition services will be delivered to older individuals who are Indians represented by the tribal organization substantially in compliance with the provisions of part C of subchapter III, except that in any case </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval criteria; provisions and assurances</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Approval criteria; provisions and assurances No grant may be made under this part unless the eligible tribal organization submits an application to the Assistant Secretary which meets such criteria as the Assistant Secretary may by regulation prescribe. Each such application shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Population statistics development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Population statistics development For the purpose of any application submitted under this part, the tribal organization may develop its own population statistics, with approval from the Bureau of Indian Affairs, in order to establish eligibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by Assistant Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval by Assistant Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disapproval by Assistant Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disapproval by Assistant Secretary Whenever the Assistant Secretary determines not to approve an application submitted under subsection (a) the Assistant Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3057e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funds per year</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Funds per year Whenever the Assistant Secretary approves an application of a tribal organization under this part, funds shall be awarded for not less than 12 months.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>