<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3058b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3058b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3058b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3058b"><akn:num>3058b</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3058b. Allotment(a) In general(1) PopulationIn carrying out the program described in section 3058 of this title, the Assistant Secretary shall initially allot to each State, from the funds appropriated under section 3058a of this title for each fiscal year, an amount that bears the same ratio to the funds as the population of older individuals in the State bears to the population of older individuals in all States.


(2) Minimum allotments(A) In generalAfter making the initial allotments described in paragraph (1), the Assistant Secretary shall adjust the allotments on a pro rata basis in accordance with subparagraphs (B) and (C).


(B) General minimum allotments(i) Minimum allotment for StatesNo State shall be allotted less than one-half of 1 percent of the funds appropriated under section 3058a of this title for the fiscal year for which the determination is made.


(ii) Minimum allotment for territoriesGuam, the United States Virgin Islands, and the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, shall each be allotted not less than one-fourth of 1 percent of the funds appropriated under section 3058a of this title for the fiscal year for which the determination is made. American Samoa and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands shall each be allotted not less than one-sixteenth of 1 percent of the sum appropriated under section 3058a of this title for the fiscal year for which the determination is made.



(C) Minimum allotments for ombudsman and elder abuse programs(i) Ombudsman programNo State shall be allotted for a fiscal year, from the funds appropriated under section 3058a of this title and made available to carry out subpart II of this part, less than the amount allotted to the State under section 3024 of this title in fiscal year 2000 to carry out the State Long-Term Care Ombudsman program under subchapter III.


(ii) Elder abuse programsNo State shall be allotted for a fiscal year, from the funds appropriated under section 3058a of this title and mad</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reallotment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3058b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withholding If the Assistant Secretary finds that any State has failed to carry out this subchapter in accordance with the assurances made and description provided under section 3058d of this title, the Assistant Secretary shall withhold the allotment of funds to the State. The Assistant Secretary shall disburse the funds withheld directly to any public or nonprofit private institution or organization, agency, or political subdivision of the State submitting an approved plan containing the assurances and description.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>