<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_306"><akn:num>306</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 306. Definitions(a) For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “old-age assistance” means money payments to, or (if provided in or after the third month before the month in which the recipient makes application for assistance) medical care in behalf of or any type of remedial care recognized under State law in behalf of, needy individuals who are 65 years of age or older, but does not include any such payments to or care in behalf of any individual who is an inmate of a public institution (except as a patient in a medical institution). Such term also includes payments which are not included within the meaning of such term under the preceding sentence, but which would be so included except that they are made on behalf of such a needy individual to another individual who (as determined in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary) is interested in or concerned with the welfare of such needy individual, but only with respect to a State whose State plan approved under section 302 of this title includes provision for—(1) determination by the State agency that such needy individual has, by reason of his physical or mental condition, such inability to manage funds that making payments to him would be contrary to his welfare and, therefore, it is necessary to provide such assistance through payments described in this sentence;

(2) making such payments only in cases in which such payments will, under the rules otherwise applicable under the State plan for determining need and the amount of old-age assistance to be paid (and in conjunction with other income and resources), meet all the need of the individuals with respect to whom such payments are made;

(3) undertaking and continuing special efforts to protect the welfare of such individual and to improve, to the extent possible, his capacity for self-care and to manage funds;

(4) periodic review by such State agency of the determination under paragraph (1) of this subsection to ascertain whether condition</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) For the purposes of this subchapter, the term “old-age assistance” means money payments to, or (if provided in or after the third month before the month in which the recipient makes application for assistance) medical care in behalf of or any type of remedial care recognized under State law in behalf of, needy individuals who are 65 years of age or older, but does not include any such payments to or care in behalf of any individual who is an inmate of a public institution (except as a patient in a medical institution). Such term also includes payments which are not included within the meaning of such term under the preceding sentence, but which would be so included except that they are made on behalf of such a needy individual to another individual who (as determined in accordance with standards prescribed by the Secretary) is interested in or concerned with the welfare of such needy individual, but only with respect to a State whose State plan approved under section 302 of this ti</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) , (c) Repealed. Pub. L. 97–35, title XXI, § 2184(a)(5), Aug. 13, 1981, 95 Stat. 817.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>