<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3148" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3148/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3148/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3148"><akn:num>3148</akn:num><akn:heading>Investment priorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3148. Investment priorities(a) In generalSubject to subsection (b), for a project to be eligible for assistance under this subchapter, the project shall be consistent with 1 or more of the following investment priorities:(1) Critical infrastructureEconomic development planning or implementation projects that support development of public facilities, including basic public infrastructure, transportation infrastructure, or telecommunications infrastructure.


(2) WorkforceEconomic development planning or implementation projects that—(A) support job skills training to meet the hiring needs of the area in which the project is to be carried out and that result in well-paying jobs; or

(B) otherwise promote labor force participation.


(3) Innovation and entrepreneurshipEconomic development planning or implementation projects that—(A) support the development of innovation and entrepreneurship-related infrastructure;

(B) promote business development and lending; or

(C) foster the commercialization of new technologies that are creating technology-driven businesses and high-skilled, well-paying jobs of the future.


(4) Economic recovery resilienceEconomic development planning or implementation projects that enhance the ability of an area to withstand and recover from adverse short-term or long-term changes in economic conditions, including effects from industry contractions or economic impacts from natural disasters.


(5) ManufacturingEconomic development planning or implementation projects that encourage job creation, business expansion, technology and capital upgrades, and productivity growth in manufacturing, including efforts that contribute to the competitiveness and growth of domestic suppliers or the domestic production of innovative, high-value products and production technologies.



(b) ConditionsIf the Secretary plans to use an investment priority that is not described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public W</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3148_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general Subject to subsection (b), for a project to be eligible for assistance under this subchapter, the project shall be consistent with 1 or more of the following investment priorities:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3148_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Conditions If the Secretary plans to use an investment priority that is not described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a written notification that explains the basis for using that investment priority.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3148_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Savings clause Nothing in this section waives any other requirement of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>