<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3154a"><akn:num>3154a</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3154a. Performance awards(a) In generalThe Secretary may make a performance award in connection with a grant made, on or after October 27, 2004, to an eligible recipient for a project under section 3141 or 3149 of this title.


(b) Performance measures(1) RegulationsThe Secretary shall promulgate regulations to establish performance measures for making performance awards under subsection (a).


(2) ConsiderationsIn promulgating regulations under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consider the inclusion of performance measures that assess—(A) whether the recipient meets or exceeds scheduling goals;

(B) whether the recipient meets or exceeds job creation goals;

(C) amounts of private sector capital investments leveraged; and

(D) such other factors as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.



(c) Amount of awards(1) In generalThe Secretary shall base the amount of a performance award made under subsection (a) in connection with a grant on the extent to which a recipient meets or exceeds performance measures established in connection with the grant.


(2) Maximum amountThe amount of a performance award may not exceed 10 percent of the amount of the grant.



(d) Use of awardsA recipient of a performance award under subsection (a) may use the award for any eligible purpose under this chapter, in accordance with section 3212 of this title and such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate.


(e) Federal shareNotwithstanding section 3144 of this title, the funds of a performance award may be used to pay up to 100 percent of the cost of an eligible project or activity.


(f) Treatment in meeting non-Federal share requirementsFor the purposes of meeting the non-Federal share requirements under this, or any other, Act the funds of a performance award shall be treated as funds from a non-Federal source.


(g) Terms and conditionsIn making performance awards under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers to b</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary may make a performance award in connection with a grant made, on or after October 27, 2004, to an eligible recipient for a project under section 3141 or 3149 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Performance measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Amount of awards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Use of awards A recipient of a performance award under subsection (a) may use the award for any eligible purpose under this chapter, in accordance with section 3212 of this title and such regulations as the Secretary may promulgate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Federal share Notwithstanding section 3144 of this title, the funds of a performance award may be used to pay up to 100 percent of the cost of an eligible project or activity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Treatment in meeting non-Federal share requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Treatment in meeting non-Federal share requirements For the purposes of meeting the non-Federal share requirements under this, or any other, Act the funds of a performance award shall be treated as funds from a non-Federal source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Terms and conditions In making performance awards under subsection (a), the Secretary shall establish such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding The Secretary shall use any amounts made available for economic development assistance programs to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Reporting requirement The Secretary shall include information regarding performance awards made under this section in the annual report required under section 3213 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Comptroller General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Review by Comptroller General</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>