<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3154e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3154e"><akn:num>3154e</akn:num><akn:heading>Workforce training grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3154e. Workforce training grants(a) In generalOn the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants to support the development and expansion of innovative workforce training programs through sectoral partnerships leading to quality jobs and the acquisition of equipment or construction of facilities to support workforce development activities.


(b) Eligible usesFunds from a grant under this section may be used for—(1) acquisition or development of land and improvements to house workforce training activities;

(2) acquisition, design and engineering, construction, rehabilitation, alteration, expansion, or improvement of such a facility, including related equipment and machinery;

(3) acquisition of machinery or equipment to support workforce training activities;

(4) planning, technical assistance, and training;

(5) sector partnerships development, program design, and program implementation; and

(6) in the case of an eligible recipient that is a State, subject to subsection (c), a State program to support individual trainees for employment in critical industries with high demand and vacancies necessary for further economic development of the applicable State that—(A) requires significant post-secondary training; but

(B) does not require a post-secondary degree.



(c) State grant pilot program(1) In generalThe Secretary may award grants to States for the purpose described in subsection (b)(6).


(2) ApplicationTo be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, the Chief Executive of a State shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, which shall include, at a minimum, the following:(A) A method for identifying critical industry sectors driving in-State economic growth that face staffing challenges for in-demand jobs and careers.

(B) A governance structure for the implementation of the program established by the State, including defined roles f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general On the application of an eligible recipient, the Secretary may make grants to support the development and expansion of innovative workforce training programs through sectoral partnerships leading to quality jobs and the acquisition of equipment or construction of facilities to support workforce development activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible uses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligible uses Funds from a grant under this section may be used for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State grant pilot program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State grant pilot program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3154e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Coordination The Secretary shall coordinate the development of new workforce development models with the Secretary of Labor and the Secretary of Education.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>