<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3193" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3193/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3193/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3193"><akn:num>3193</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with other persons and agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3193. Consultation with other persons and agencies(a) Consultation on problems relating to employmentThe Secretary may consult with any persons, including representatives of labor, management, agriculture, and government, who can assist in addressing the problems of area and regional unemployment or underemployment.


(b) Consultation on administration of chapterThe Secretary may provide for such consultation with interested Federal agencies as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in the performance of the duties of the Secretary under this chapter.


(Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 503, as added Pub. L. 105–393, title I, § 102(a), Nov. 13, 1998, 112 Stat. 3610.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 3193, Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 514, as added Pub. L. 93–423, § 11, Sept. 27, 1974, 88 Stat. 1162, provided for the acquisition and disposal of excess property from the Administrator of General Services by the Federal cochairman of each regional action planning commission, prior to repeal by Pub. L. 94–519, §§ 6, 9, Oct. 17, 1976, 90 Stat. 2456, 2457, effective Oct. 17, 1977.
A prior section 503 of Pub. L. 89–136 was classified to section 3183 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 97–35, § 1821(a)(8).

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Feb. 11, 1999, see section 105 of Pub. L. 105–393, set out as a note under section 3121 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3193_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation on problems relating to employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consultation on problems relating to employment The Secretary may consult with any persons, including representatives of labor, management, agriculture, and government, who can assist in addressing the problems of area and regional unemployment or underemployment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3193_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation on administration of chapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation on administration of chapter The Secretary may provide for such consultation with interested Federal agencies as the Secretary determines to be appropriate in the performance of the duties of the Secretary under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>