<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3199" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3199/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3199/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3199"><akn:num>3199</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3199. Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience(a) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish an Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience—(1) to direct and implement the post-disaster economic recovery responsibilities of the Economic Development Administration pursuant to subsections (c)(2) and (e) of section 3149 of this title and section 3233 of this title;

(2) to direct and implement economic recovery and enhanced resilience support function activities as directed under the National Disaster Recovery Framework; and

(3) support long-term economic recovery in communities in which a major disaster or emergency has been declared under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.), or otherwise impacted by an event of national significance, as determined by the Secretary, through—(A) convening and deploying an economic development assessment team;

(B) hosting or attending convenings related to identification of additional Federal, State, local, and philanthropic entities and resources;

(C) exploring potential flexibilities related to existing awards;

(D) provision of technical assistance through staff or contractual resources; and

(E) other activities determined by the Secretary to be appropriate.



(b) Appointment authorities(1) AppointmentThe Secretary is authorized to appoint such temporary personnel as may be necessary to carry out the responsibilities of the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of chapter 33 of title 5 governing appointments in the competitive service.


(2) Conversion of employeesNotwithstanding chapter 33 of title 5, or any other provision of law relating to the examination, certification, and appointment of individuals in the competitive service, a temporary employee appointed under this subsection may be selected by the Secretary for a permanent appointment in the competitive service in the Economic Development Administration un</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Secretary shall establish an Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilience—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appointment authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disaster team</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Disaster team</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3199_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual reports Not later than July 1, 2026, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>