<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3200" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3200/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3200/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3200"><akn:num>3200</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical Assistance Liaisons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3200. Technical Assistance Liaisons(a) In generalA Regional Director of a regional office of the Economic Development Administration may designate a staff member to act as a “Technical Assistance Liaison” for any State served by the regional office.


(b) RoleA Technical Assistance Liaison shall—(1) work in coordination with an Economic Development Representative to provide technical assistance, in addition to technical assistance under section 3147 of this title, to eligible recipients that are underresourced communities, as determined by the Technical Assistance Liaison, that submit applications for assistance under subchapter II; and

(2) at the request of an eligible recipient that submitted an application for assistance under subchapter II, provide technical feedback on unsuccessful grant applications.


(c) Technical assistanceThe Secretary may enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with an eligible recipient for the purpose of providing technical assistance to eligible recipients that are underresourced communities that have submitted or may submit an application for assistance under this chapter.


(Pub. L. 89–136, title V, § 510, as added Pub. L. 118–272, div. B, title II, § 2229, Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 3195.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general A Regional Director of a regional office of the Economic Development Administration may designate a staff member to act as a “Technical Assistance Liaison” for any State served by the regional office.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Role</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Role A Technical Assistance Liaison shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3200_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance The Secretary may enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with an eligible recipient for the purpose of providing technical assistance to eligible recipients that are underresourced communities that have submitted or may submit an application for assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>