<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3401" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3401/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3401/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3401"><akn:num>3401</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3401. Declaration of policy
It is the policy of the Congress that certain persons charged with or convicted of violating Federal criminal laws, who are determined to be addicted to narcotic drugs, and likely to be rehabilitated through treatment, should, in lieu of prosecution or sentencing, be civilly committed for confinement and treatment designed to effect their restoration to health, and return to society as useful members.
It is the further policy of the Congress that certain persons addicted to narcotic drugs who are not charged with the commission of any offense should be afforded the opportunity, through civil commitment, for treatment, in order that they may be rehabilitated and returned to society as useful members and in order that society may be protected more effectively from crime and delinquency which result from narcotic addiction.
(Pub. L. 89–793, § 2, Nov. 8, 1966, 80 Stat. 1438.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was not enacted as part of the Narcotic Addict Rehabilitation Act of 1966, which is classified to subchapters II and III of this chapter, chapter 314 (section 4251 et seq.) of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, and chapter 175 (section 2901 et seq.) of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DatePub. L. 89–793, title VI, § 605, Nov. 8, 1966, 80 Stat. 1450, provided that: “Title I of this Act [enacting chapter 175 (§ 2901 et seq.) of Title 28, Judiciary and Judicial Procedure] shall take effect three months after the date of its enactment [Nov. 8, 1966], and shall apply to any case pending in a district court of the United States in which an appearance has not been made prior to such effective date. Titles II [enacting chapter 314 (§ 4251 et seq.) of Title 18, Crimes and Criminal Procedure] and V of this Act [amending section 7237(d) of Title 26, Internal Revenue Code and enacting provisions set out as note under section 4202 of Title 18] shall take effect three months af</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>