<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3515d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3515d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3515d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3515d"><akn:num>3515d</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenses of Office of Inspector General; protective services; investigating non-payment of child sup</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3515d. Expenses of Office of Inspector General; protective services; investigating non-payment of child support
For expenses necessary for the Office of Inspector General in carrying out the provisions of the Inspector General Act of 1978, as amended, $33,849,000: Provided, That of such amount, necessary sums are available for providing protective services to the Secretary and investigating non-payment of child support cases for which non-payment is a Federal offense under section 228 of title 18, each of which activities is hereby authorized in this and subsequent fiscal years.
(Pub. L. 106–554, § 1(a)(1) [title II], Dec. 21, 2000, 114 Stat. 2763, 2763A–24.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Inspector General Act of 1978, referred to in text, is Pub. L. 95–452, Oct. 12, 1978, 92 Stat. 1101, which was set out in the Appendix to Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, and was substantially repealed and restated in chapter 4 (§ 401 et seq.) of Title 5 by Pub. L. 117–286, §§ 3(b), 7, Dec. 27, 2022, 136 Stat. 4206, 4361. For disposition of sections of the Act into chapter 4 of Title 5, see Disposition Table preceding section 101 of Title 5.

Codification
Section is from the Department of Health and Human Services Appropriations Act, 2001.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>