<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3533" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3533/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3533/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3533"><akn:num>3533</akn:num><akn:heading>Officers of Department</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3533. Officers of Department(a) Deputy Secretary, Assistant Secretaries, and General Counsel(1) There shall be in the Department a Deputy Secretary, 7 Assistant Secretaries, and a General Counsel, who shall be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall perform such functions, powers, and duties as the Secretary shall prescribe from time to time.

(2) There shall be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Public Affairs, who shall be appointed by the President and shall perform such functions, powers, and duties as the Secretary shall prescribe from time to time.


(b) Federal Housing CommissionerThere shall be in the Department a Federal Housing Commissioner, who shall be one of the Assistant Secretaries, who shall head a Federal Housing Administration within the Department, who shall have such duties and powers as may be prescribed by the Secretary, and who shall administer, under the supervision and direction of the Secretary, departmental programs relating to the private mortgage market. The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that managers of Federal Housing Administration programs, at each level of the Department, shall be accountable for program operation, risk management, management of cash and other Federal assets, and program financing related to activities over which such managers have responsibility.


(c) Director of Urban Program Coordination; designation; powers and duties; studies of urban and community problems and recommendations for administration of Federal programs affecting such problemsThere shall be in the Department a Director of Urban Program Coordination, who shall be designated by the Secretary. He shall assist the Secretary in carrying out his responsibilities to the President with respect to achieving maximum coordination of the programs of the various departments and agencies of the Government which have a major impact on community development. In providing such assis</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deputy Secretary, Assistant Secretaries, and General Counsel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Deputy Secretary, Assistant Secretaries, and General Counsel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Housing Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal Housing Commissioner There shall be in the Department a Federal Housing Commissioner, who shall be one of the Assistant Secretaries, who shall head a Federal Housing Administration within the Department, who shall have such duties and powers as may be prescribed by the Secretary, and who shall administer, under the supervision and direction of the Secretary, departmental programs relating to the private mortgage market. The Secretary shall ensure, to the extent practicable, that managers of Federal Housing Administration programs, at each level of the Department, shall be accountable for program operation, risk management, management of cash and other Federal assets, and program financing related to activities over which such managers have responsibility.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director of Urban Program Coordination; designation; powers and duties; studies of urban and community problems and recommendations for administration of Federal programs affecting such problems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Director of Urban Program Coordination; designation; powers and duties; studies of urban and community problems and recommendations for administration of Federal programs affecting such problems There shall be in the Department a Director of Urban Program Coordination, who shall be designated by the Secretary. He shall assist the Secretary in carrying out his responsibilities to the President with respect to achieving maximum coordination of the programs of the various departments and agencies of the Government which have a major impact on community development. In providing such assistance, the Director shall make such studies of urban and community problems as the Secretary shall request, and shall develop recommendations relating to the administration of Federal programs affecting such problems, particularly with respect to achieving effective cooperation among the Federal, State, and local agencies concerned. Subject to the direction of the Secretary, the Director shall, in car</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant to Secretary; designation; duty to provide information and advice to nonprofit project sponsors</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistant to Secretary; designation; duty to provide information and advice to nonprofit project sponsors There shall be in the Department an Assistant to the Secretary, designated by the Secretary, who shall be responsible for providing information and advice to nonprofit organizations desiring to sponsor housing projects assisted under programs administered by the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs; report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Special Assistant for Indian and Alaska Native Programs; report to Congress</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal Housing Administration Comptroller</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Federal Housing Administration Comptroller There shall be in the Department a Federal Housing Administration Comptroller, designated by the Secretary, who shall be responsible for overseeing the financial operations of the Federal Housing Administration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Housing Counseling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Office of Housing Counseling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3533_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Special Assistant for Veterans Affairs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>