<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3535" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3535/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3535/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3535"><akn:num>3535</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3535. Administrative provisions(a) Transfer of personnel, assets, etc.The personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, or other funds held, used, arising from, or available or to be made available in connection with, the functions, powers, and duties transferred by section 3534 of this title are hereby transferred with such functions, powers, and duties, respectively.


(b) Repealed. Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 807(d), Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 544

(c) Employment, compensation, authority, and duties of personnelThe Secretary is authorized, subject to the civil service and classification laws, to select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as shall be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter and to prescribe their authority and duties: Provided, That any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, the Secretary may fix the compensation for not more than six positions in the Department at the annual rate applicable to positions in level V of the Executive Schedule provided by subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5.


(d) Delegation of authority; rules and regulationsThe Secretary may delegate any of his functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of the Department as he may designate, may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions, powers, and duties as he may deem desirable, and may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out his functions, powers, and duties.


(e) Temporary employment of experts or consultants; compensationThe Secretary may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, at rates for individuals not to exceed the per diem equivalent to the highest rate for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5. The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts with p</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of personnel, assets, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of personnel, assets, etc. The personnel employed in connection with, and the assets, liabilities, contracts, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, authorizations, allocations, or other funds held, used, arising from, or available or to be made available in connection with, the functions, powers, and duties transferred by section 3534 of this title are hereby transferred with such functions, powers, and duties, respectively.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 90–448, title VIII, § 807(d), Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 544</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment, compensation, authority, and duties of personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment, compensation, authority, and duties of personnel The Secretary is authorized, subject to the civil service and classification laws, to select, appoint, employ, and fix the compensation of such officers and employees, including attorneys, as shall be necessary to carry out the provisions of this chapter and to prescribe their authority and duties: Provided, That any other provision of law to the contrary notwithstanding, the Secretary may fix the compensation for not more than six positions in the Department at the annual rate applicable to positions in level V of the Executive Schedule provided by subchapter II of chapter 53 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of authority; rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Delegation of authority; rules and regulations The Secretary may delegate any of his functions, powers, and duties to such officers and employees of the Department as he may designate, may authorize such successive redelegations of such functions, powers, and duties as he may deem desirable, and may make such rules and regulations as may be necessary to carry out his functions, powers, and duties.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Temporary employment of experts or consultants; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Temporary employment of experts or consultants; compensation The Secretary may obtain services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, at rates for individuals not to exceed the per diem equivalent to the highest rate for grade GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5. The Secretary is authorized to enter into contracts with private companies for the provision of such managerial support to the Federal Housing Administration as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including but not limited to the management of insurance risk and the improvement of the delivery of mortgage insurance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Working capital fund; establishment; uses; appropriations; capitalization; reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Working capital fund; establishment; uses; appropriations; capitalization; reimbursement The Secretary is authorized to establish a working capital fund, to be available without fiscal year limitation, for expenses necessary for the maintenance and operation of such common administrative services as he shall find to be desirable in the interest of economy and efficiency in the Department, including such services as a central supply service for stationery and other supplies and equipment for which adequate stocks may be maintained to meet in whole or in part the requirements of the Department and its agencies; central messenger, mail, telephone, and other communications services; office space; central services for document reproduction and for graphics and visual aids; and a central library service. In addition to amounts appropriated to provide capital for said fund, which appropriations are hereby authorized, the fund shall be capitalized by transfer to it of such stock of supplie</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Seal</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Seal The Secretary shall cause a seal of office to be made for the Department of such device as he shall approve, and judicial notice shall be taken of such seal.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial transactions, finality; checking accounts for funds in Treasury; availability of funds for administrative expenses; consolidation of cash for banking and checking purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Financial transactions, finality; checking accounts for funds in Treasury; availability of funds for administrative expenses; consolidation of cash for banking and checking purposes Except as such authority is otherwise expressly provided in any other Act administered by the Secretary, such financial transactions of the Secretary as the making of loans or grants (and vouchers approved by the Secretary in connection with such financial transactions) shall be final and conclusive upon all officers of the Government. Funds made available to the Secretary pursuant to any provision of law for such financial transactions shall be deposited in a checking account or accounts with the Treasury of the United States. Such funds and any receipts and assets obtained or held by the Secretary in connection with such financial transactions shall be available, in such amounts as may from year to year be authorized by the Congress, for the administrative expenses of the Secretary in connection with </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Foreclosure of property; actions for protection and enforcement of rights; purchase of property; dealing with property after such acquisition; deprivation of State court civil and criminal jurisdiction; impairment of civil rights under State laws; application of section 6101 of title 41; annual payments in lieu of local property taxes; sale and exchanges of property; insurance; modification of interest, time for installment payment, and other terms; other covenants, conditions, and provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Foreclosure of property; actions for protection and enforcement of rights; purchase of property; dealing with property after such acquisition; deprivation of State court civil and criminal jurisdiction; impairment of civil rights under State laws; application of Except as such authority is otherwise expressly provided in any other Act administered by the Secretary, the Secretary is authorized to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3535_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees and charges</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Fees and charges Notwithstanding any other provision of law the Secretary is authorized to establish fees and charges, chargeable against program beneficiaries and project participants, which shall be adequate to cover over the long run, costs of inspection, project review and financing service, audit by Federal or federally authorized auditors, and other beneficial rights, privileges, licenses, and services. Such fees and charges heretofore or hereafter collected shall be considered nonadministrative and shall remain available for operating expenses of the Department in providing similar services on a consolidated basis.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>