<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3537a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3537a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3537a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3537a"><akn:num>3537a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition of advance disclosure of funding decisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3537a. Prohibition of advance disclosure of funding decisions(a) Prohibited actionsDuring any selection process, no officer or employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall knowingly disclose any covered selection information regarding such selection, directly or indirectly, to any person other than a person authorized by the Secretary to receive such information.


(b) Administrative remediesIf the Secretary receives or obtains information providing a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Secretary shall—(1) in the case of a selection that has not been made, determine whether to terminate the selection process or take other appropriate actions; and

(2) in the case of a selection that has been made, determine whether to—(A) void or rescind the selection, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;

(B) impose sanctions upon the violating applicant selected, subject to review and determination on the record after opportunity for a hearing;

(C) permit the violating applicant selected to continue to participate in the program; or

(D) take any other actions that the Secretary considers appropriate.



(c) Civil money penalties(1) In generalWhenever any employee of the Department knowingly and materially violates the prohibition in subsection (a), the Secretary may impose a civil money penalty on the employee in accordance with the provisions of this subsection. This penalty shall be in addition to any other available civil remedy or any available criminal penalty and may be imposed whether or not the Secretary takes other disciplinary actions.


(2) AmountThe amount of the penalty, as determined by the Secretary, may not exceed $10,000 for each violation.


(3) Agency procedures(A) EstablishmentThe Secretary shall establish standards and procedures governing the imposition of civil money penalties under this subsection. The standards and procedures—(i) shall provid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibited actions During any selection process, no officer or employee of the Department of Housing and Urban Development shall knowingly disclose any covered selection information regarding such selection, directly or indirectly, to any person other than a person authorized by the Secretary to receive such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative remedies If the Secretary receives or obtains information providing a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of subsection (a) has occurred, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Civil money penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criminal penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Criminal penalties Whoever willfully violates subsection (a) by making a disclosure prohibited by subsection (a) to any applicant, or any officer, employee, representative, agent, or consultant of any applicant, shall be imprisoned not more than 5 years, or fined in accordance with title 18, or both.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations The Secretary shall issue such regulations as the Secretary deems appropriate to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3537a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Applicability This section shall apply only with respect to violations that occur on or after December, 15, 1989.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>