<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3545" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3545/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3545/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3545"><akn:num>3545</akn:num><akn:heading>HUD accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3545. HUD accountability(a) Notice regarding assistance(1) Publication of notice of availabilityThe Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the availability of any assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary.


(2) Publication of application proceduresThe Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a description of the form and procedures by which application for the assistance may be made, and any deadlines relating to the award or allocation of the assistance. Such description shall be designed to help eligible applicants to apply for such assistance.


(3) Publication of selection criteriaNot less than 30 days before any deadline by which applications or requests for assistance under any program or discretionary fund administered by the Secretary must be submitted, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the criteria by which selection for the assistance will be made. Subject to section 1439 of this title, such criteria shall include any objective measures of housing need, project merit, or efficient use of resources that the Secretary determines are appropriate and consistent with the statute under which the assistance is made available.


(4) Documentation of decisions(A) The Secretary shall award or allocate assistance only in response to a written application in a form approved in advance by the Secretary, except where other award or allocation procedures are specified in statute.

(B) The Secretary shall ensure that documentation and other information regarding each application for assistance is sufficient to indicate the basis on which any award or allocation was made or denied. The preceding sentence shall apply to—(i) any application for an award or allocation of assistance made by the Secretary to a State, unit of general local government, or other recipient of assistance, and

(ii) any application for a subsequent award or allocation of such assistance by such State, unit of genera</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice regarding assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notice regarding assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosures by applicants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Disclosures by applicants The Secretary shall require the disclosure of information with respect to any application for assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department for a project application submitted to the Secretary or to any State or unit of general local government by any applicant who has received or, in the determination of the Secretary, can reasonably be expected to receive assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department in excess of $200,000 in the aggregate during any fiscal year or such lower amount as the Secretary may establish by regulation. Such information shall include the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Updating of disclosure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Updating of disclosure During the period when an application is pending or assistance is being provided, the applicant shall update the disclosure required under the previous subsection within 30 days of any substantial change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Limitation of assistance The Secretary shall certify that assistance within the jurisdiction of the Department, as such term is defined in subsection (m), except that for purposes of this subsection such term shall not include any mortgage insurance provided pursuant to title II of the National Housing Act (12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.) 11 So in original. Probably should be followed by a comma. to any housing project shall not be more than is necessary to provide affordable housing after taking account of assistance described in subsection (b)(1). The Secretary shall adjust the amount of such assistance awarded or allocated to an applicant to compensate in whole or in part, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, for any changes reported under subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Administrative remedies If the Secretary receives or obtains information providing a reasonable basis to believe that a violation of subsection (b) or (c) has occurred, the Secretary shall— The Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a descriptive statement of each determination made and action taken under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil money penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Civil money penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Agency procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review of agency determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Judicial review of agency determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Action to collect penalty</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Action to collect penalty If any person fails to comply with the determination or order of the Secretary imposing a civil money penalty under subsection (f), after the determination or order is no longer subject to review as provided by subsections (g)(1) and (h), the Secretary may request the Attorney General of the United States to bring an action in an appropriate United States district court to obtain a monetary judgment against the person and such other relief as may be available. The monetary judgment may, in the court’s discretion, include the attorneys’ fees and other expenses incurred by the United States in connection with the action. In an action under this subsection, the validity and appropriateness of the Secretary’s determination or order imposing the penalty shall not be subject to review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3545_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Settlement by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Settlement by Secretary The Secretary may compromise, modify, or remit any civil money penalty which may be, or has been, imposed under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>