<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3546" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3546/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3546/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3546"><akn:num>3546</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of domestic products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3546. Use of domestic products(a) Prohibition against fraudulent use of “Made in America” labelsA person shall not intentionally affix a label bearing the inscription of “Made in America”, or any inscription with that meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States, if that product is not a domestic product.


(b) ReportThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each submit, before January 1, 1994, a report to the Congress on procurements of products that are not domestic products.


(c) “Domestic product” definedFor the purposes of this section, the term “domestic product” means a product—(1) that is manufactured or produced in the United States; and

(2) at least 50 percent of the cost of the articles, materials, or supplies of which are mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States.


(Pub. L. 102–550, title IX, § 920, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3883.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992, and not as part of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3546_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition against fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels A person shall not intentionally affix a label bearing the inscription of “Made in America”, or any inscription with that meaning, to any product sold in or shipped to the United States, if that product is not a domestic product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3546_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Report The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall each submit, before January 1, 1994, a report to the Congress on procurements of products that are not domestic products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3546_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Domestic product” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Domestic product” defined For the purposes of this section, the term “domestic product” means a product—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>