<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3608" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3608/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3608/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3608"><akn:num>3608</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3608. Administration(a) Authority and responsibilityThe authority and responsibility for administering this Act shall be in the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.


(b) Assistant SecretaryThe Department of Housing and Urban Development shall be provided an additional Assistant Secretary.


(c) Delegation of authority; appointment of administrative law judges; location of conciliation meetings; administrative reviewThe Secretary may delegate any of his functions, duties, and powers to employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development or to boards of such employees, including functions, duties, and powers with respect to investigating, conciliating, hearing, determining, ordering, certifying, reporting, or otherwise acting as to any work, business, or matter under this subchapter. The person to whom such delegations are made with respect to hearing functions, duties, and powers shall be appointed and shall serve in the Department of Housing and Urban Development in compliance with sections 3105, 3344, 5372, and 7521 of title 5. Insofar as possible, conciliation meetings shall be held in the cities or other localities where the discriminatory housing practices allegedly occurred. The Secretary shall by rule prescribe such rights of appeal from the decisions of his administrative law judges to other administrative law judges or to other officers in the Department, to boards of officers or to himself, as shall be appropriate and in accordance with law.


(d) Cooperation of Secretary and executive departments and agencies in administration of housing and urban development programs and activities to further fair housing purposesAll executive departments and agencies shall administer their programs and activities relating to housing and urban development (including any Federal agency having regulatory or supervisory authority over financial institutions) in a manner affirmatively to further the purposes of this subchapter and shall cooperate with the S</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority and responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority and responsibility The authority and responsibility for administering this Act shall be in the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistant Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Assistant Secretary The Department of Housing and Urban Development shall be provided an additional Assistant Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delegation of authority; appointment of administrative law judges; location of conciliation meetings; administrative review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Delegation of authority; appointment of administrative law judges; location of conciliation meetings; administrative review The Secretary may delegate any of his functions, duties, and powers to employees of the Department of Housing and Urban Development or to boards of such employees, including functions, duties, and powers with respect to investigating, conciliating, hearing, determining, ordering, certifying, reporting, or otherwise acting as to any work, business, or matter under this subchapter. The person to whom such delegations are made with respect to hearing functions, duties, and powers shall be appointed and shall serve in the Department of Housing and Urban Development in compliance with sections 3105, 3344, 5372, and 7521 of title 5. Insofar as possible, conciliation meetings shall be held in the cities or other localities where the discriminatory housing practices allegedly occurred. The Secretary shall by rule prescribe such rights of appeal from the decisions of h</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperation of Secretary and executive departments and agencies in administration of housing and urban development programs and activities to further fair housing purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Cooperation of Secretary and executive departments and agencies in administration of housing and urban development programs and activities to further fair housing purposes All executive departments and agencies shall administer their programs and activities relating to housing and urban development (including any Federal agency having regulatory or supervisory authority over financial institutions) in a manner affirmatively to further the purposes of this subchapter and shall cooperate with the Secretary to further such purposes.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Functions of Secretary The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3608_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions of law applicable to Department programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Provisions of law applicable to Department programs The provisions of law and Executive orders to which subsection (e)(6) applies are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>