<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3610" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3610/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3610/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3610"><akn:num>3610</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative enforcement; preliminary matters</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3610. Administrative enforcement; preliminary matters(a) Complaints and answers(1)(A)(i) An aggrieved person may, not later than one year after an alleged discriminatory housing practice has occurred or terminated, file a complaint with the Secretary alleging such discriminatory housing practice. The Secretary, on the Secretary’s own initiative, may also file such a complaint.

(ii) Such complaints shall be in writing and shall contain such information and be in such form as the Secretary requires.

(iii) The Secretary may also investigate housing practices to determine whether a complaint should be brought under this section.


(B) Upon the filing of such a complaint—(i) the Secretary shall serve notice upon the aggrieved person acknowledging such filing and advising the aggrieved person of the time limits and choice of forums provided under this subchapter;

(ii) the Secretary shall, not later than 10 days after such filing or the identification of an additional respondent under paragraph (2), serve on the respondent a notice identifying the alleged discriminatory housing practice and advising such respondent of the procedural rights and obligations of respondents under this subchapter, together with a copy of the original complaint;

(iii) each respondent may file, not later than 10 days after receipt of notice from the Secretary, an answer to such complaint; and

(iv) the Secretary shall make an investigation of the alleged discriminatory housing practice and complete such investigation within 100 days after the filing of the complaint (or, when the Secretary takes further action under subsection (f)(2) with respect to a complaint, within 100 days after the commencement of such further action), unless it is impracticable to do so.


(C) If the Secretary is unable to complete the investigation within 100 days after the filing of the complaint (or, when the Secretary takes further action under subsection (f)(2) with respect to a complaint, within 100 days after </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Complaints and answers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Complaints and answers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Investigative report and conciliation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Investigative report and conciliation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to comply with conciliation agreement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Failure to comply with conciliation agreement Whenever the Secretary has reasonable cause to believe that a respondent has breached a conciliation agreement, the Secretary shall refer the matter to the Attorney General with a recommendation that a civil action be filed under section 3614 of this title for the enforcement of such agreement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibitions and requirements with respect to disclosure of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prohibitions and requirements with respect to disclosure of information</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prompt judicial action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prompt judicial action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Referral for State or local proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Referral for State or local proceedings</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reasonable cause determination and effect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Reasonable cause determination and effect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3610_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Service of copies of charge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Service of copies of charge After the Secretary issues a charge under this section, the Secretary shall cause a copy thereof, together with information as to how to make an election under section 3612(a) of this title and the effect of such an election, to be served—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>