<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3612" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3612/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3612/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3612"><akn:num>3612</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3612. Enforcement by Secretary(a) Election of judicial determinationWhen a charge is filed under section 3610 of this title, a complainant, a respondent, or an aggrieved person on whose behalf the complaint was filed, may elect to have the claims asserted in that charge decided in a civil action under subsection (o) in lieu of a hearing under subsection (b). The election must be made not later than 20 days after the receipt by the electing person of service under section 3610(h) of this title or, in the case of the Secretary, not later than 20 days after such service. The person making such election shall give notice of doing so to the Secretary and to all other complainants and respondents to whom the charge relates.


(b) Administrative law judge hearing in absence of electionIf an election is not made under subsection (a) with respect to a charge filed under section 3610 of this title, the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for a hearing on the record with respect to a charge issued under section 3610 of this title. The Secretary shall delegate the conduct of a hearing under this section to an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 of title 5. The administrative law judge shall conduct the hearing at a place in the vicinity in which the discriminatory housing practice is alleged to have occurred or to be about to occur.


(c) Rights of partiesAt a hearing under this section, each party may appear in person, be represented by counsel, present evidence, cross-examine witnesses, and obtain the issuance of subpoenas under section 3611 of this title. Any aggrieved person may intervene as a party in the proceeding. The Federal Rules of Evidence apply to the presentation of evidence in such hearing as they would in a civil action in a United States district court.


(d) Expedited discovery and hearing(1) Discovery in administrative proceedings under this section shall be conducted as expeditiously and inexpensively as possible, consistent with the n</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of judicial determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Election of judicial determination When a charge is filed under section 3610 of this title, a complainant, a respondent, or an aggrieved person on whose behalf the complaint was filed, may elect to have the claims asserted in that charge decided in a civil action under subsection (o) in lieu of a hearing under subsection (b). The election must be made not later than 20 days after the receipt by the electing person of service under section 3610(h) of this title or, in the case of the Secretary, not later than 20 days after such service. The person making such election shall give notice of doing so to the Secretary and to all other complainants and respondents to whom the charge relates.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative law judge hearing in absence of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Administrative law judge hearing in absence of election If an election is not made under subsection (a) with respect to a charge filed under section 3610 of this title, the Secretary shall provide an opportunity for a hearing on the record with respect to a charge issued under section 3610 of this title. The Secretary shall delegate the conduct of a hearing under this section to an administrative law judge appointed under section 3105 of title 5. The administrative law judge shall conduct the hearing at a place in the vicinity in which the discriminatory housing practice is alleged to have occurred or to be about to occur.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of parties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Rights of parties At a hearing under this section, each party may appear in person, be represented by counsel, present evidence, cross-examine witnesses, and obtain the issuance of subpoenas under section 3611 of this title. Any aggrieved person may intervene as a party in the proceeding. The Federal Rules of Evidence apply to the presentation of evidence in such hearing as they would in a civil action in a United States district court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited discovery and hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Expedited discovery and hearing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution of charge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Resolution of charge Any resolution of a charge before a final order under this section shall require the consent of the aggrieved person on whose behalf the charge is issued.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect of trial of civil action on administrative proceedings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Effect of trial of civil action on administrative proceedings An administrative law judge may not continue administrative proceedings under this section regarding any alleged discriminatory housing practice after the beginning of the trial of a civil action commenced by the aggrieved party under an Act of Congress or a State law, seeking relief with respect to that discriminatory housing practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hearings, findings and conclusions, and order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Hearings, findings and conclusions, and order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review by Secretary; service of final order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Review by Secretary; service of final order</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Judicial review</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3612_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Court enforcement of administrative order upon petition by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Court enforcement of administrative order upon petition by Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>