<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3614" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3614/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3614/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3614"><akn:num>3614</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement by Attorney General</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3614. Enforcement by Attorney General(a) Pattern or practice casesWhenever the Attorney General has reasonable cause to believe that any person or group of persons is engaged in a pattern or practice of resistance to the full enjoyment of any of the rights granted by this subchapter, or that any group of persons has been denied any of the rights granted by this subchapter and such denial raises an issue of general public importance, the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court.


(b) On referral of discriminatory housing practice or conciliation agreement for enforcement(1)(A) The Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court for appropriate relief with respect to a discriminatory housing practice referred to the Attorney General by the Secretary under section 3610(g) of this title.

(B) A civil action under this paragraph may be commenced not later than the expiration of 18 months after the date of the occurrence or the termination of the alleged discriminatory housing practice.


(2)(A) The Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court for appropriate relief with respect to breach of a conciliation agreement referred to the Attorney General by the Secretary under section 3610(c) of this title.

(B) A civil action may be commenced under this paragraph not later than the expiration of 90 days after the referral of the alleged breach under section 3610(c) of this title.



(c) Enforcement of subpoenasThe Attorney General, on behalf of the Secretary, or other party at whose request a subpoena is issued, under this subchapter, may enforce such subpoena in appropriate proceedings in the United States district court for the district in which the person to whom the subpoena was addressed resides, was served, or transacts business.


(d) Relief which may be granted in civil actions under subsections (a) and (b)(1) In a civil ac</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pattern or practice cases</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pattern or practice cases Whenever the Attorney General has reasonable cause to believe that any person or group of persons is engaged in a pattern or practice of resistance to the full enjoyment of any of the rights granted by this subchapter, or that any group of persons has been denied any of the rights granted by this subchapter and such denial raises an issue of general public importance, the Attorney General may commence a civil action in any appropriate United States district court.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>On referral of discriminatory housing practice or conciliation agreement for enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) On referral of discriminatory housing practice or conciliation agreement for enforcement</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement of subpoenas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Enforcement of subpoenas The Attorney General, on behalf of the Secretary, or other party at whose request a subpoena is issued, under this subchapter, may enforce such subpoena in appropriate proceedings in the United States district court for the district in which the person to whom the subpoena was addressed resides, was served, or transacts business.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relief which may be granted in civil actions under subsections (a) and (b)</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relief which may be granted in civil actions under subsections (a) and (b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3614_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intervention in civil actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Intervention in civil actions Upon timely application, any person may intervene in a civil action commenced by the Attorney General under subsection (a) or (b) which involves an alleged discriminatory housing practice with respect to which such person is an aggrieved person or a conciliation agreement to which such person is a party. The court may grant such appropriate relief to any such intervening party as is authorized to be granted to a plaintiff in a civil action under section 3613 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>