<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3616a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3616a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/3616a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_3616a"><akn:num>3616a</akn:num><akn:heading>Fair housing initiatives program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 3616a. Fair housing initiatives program(a) In generalThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) may make grants to, or (to the extent of amounts provided in appropriation Acts) enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, State or local governments or their agencies, public or private nonprofit organizations or institutions, or other public or private entities that are formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices, to develop, implement, carry out, or coordinate—(1) programs or activities designed to obtain enforcement of the rights granted by title VIII of the Act of April 11, 1968 [42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.] (commonly referred to as the Civil Rights Act of 1968), or by State or local laws that provide rights and remedies for alleged discriminatory housing practices that are substantially equivalent to the rights and remedies provided in such title VIII, through such appropriate judicial or administrative proceedings (including informal methods of conference, conciliation, and persuasion) as are available therefor; and

(2) education and outreach programs designed to inform the public concerning rights and obligations under the laws referred to in paragraph (1).


(b) Private enforcement initiatives(1) In generalThe Secretary shall use funds made available under this subsection to conduct, through contracts with private nonprofit fair housing enforcement organizations, investigations of violations of the rights granted under title VIII of the Civil Rights Act of 1968 [42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.], and such enforcement activities as appropriate to remedy such violations. The Secretary may enter into multiyear contracts and take such other action as is appropriate to enhance the effectiveness of such investigations and enforcement activities.


(2) ActivitiesThe Secretary shall use funds made available under this subsection to conduct, through contracts with private</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) may make grants to, or (to the extent of amounts provided in appropriation Acts) enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, State or local governments or their agencies, public or private nonprofit organizations or institutions, or other public or private entities that are formulating or carrying out programs to prevent or eliminate discriminatory housing practices, to develop, implement, carry out, or coordinate—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Private enforcement initiatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Private enforcement initiatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding of fair housing organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Funding of fair housing organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Education and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Education and outreach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Program administration</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. $21,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 and $26,000,000 for fiscal year 1994, of which— Any amount appropriated under this section shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualified fair housing enforcement organization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Qualified fair housing enforcement organization</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Prohibition on use of funds None of the funds authorized under this section may be used by the Secretary for purposes of settling claims, satisfying judgments or fulfilling court orders in any litigation action involving either the Department or housing providers funded by the Department. None of the funds authorized under this section may be used by the Department for administrative costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_3616a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Reporting requirements Not later than 180 days after the close of each fiscal year in which assistance under this section is furnished, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the Congress a comprehensive report which shall contain—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>