<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4004" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4004/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4004/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4004"><akn:num>4004</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions applicable to Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4004. Definitions applicable to Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012(a) In generalIn this subtitle, the following definitions shall apply:(1) 100-year floodplainThe term “100-year floodplain” means that area which is subject to inundation from a flood having a 1-percent chance of being equaled or exceeded in any given year.


(2) 500-year floodplainThe term “500-year floodplain” means that area which is subject to inundation from a flood having a 0.2-percent chance of being equaled or exceeded in any given year.


(3) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.


(4) National Flood Insurance ProgramThe term “National Flood Insurance Program” means the program established under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4011 et seq.).


(5) Write Your OwnThe term “Write Your Own” means the cooperative undertaking between the insurance industry and the Federal Insurance Administration which allows participating property and casualty insurance companies to write and service standard flood insurance policies.



(b) Common terminologyExcept as otherwise provided in this subtitle, any terms used in this subtitle shall have the meaning given to such terms under section 1370 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4121).


(Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100202, July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 916.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis subtitle, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), is subtitle A (§§ 100201–100249) of title II of div. F of Pub. L. 112–141, July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 916, known as the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012. For complete classification of this subtitle to the Code, see Short Title of 2012 Amendment note set out under section 4001 of this title and Tables.
The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, referred to in subsec. (a)(4), is title XIII of Pub. L. 90–448, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 572, which is classified principally to this chapter</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general In this subtitle, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4004_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Common terminology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Common terminology Except as otherwise provided in this subtitle, any terms used in this subtitle shall have the meaning given to such terms under section 1370 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4121).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>