<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4005" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4005/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4005/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4005"><akn:num>4005</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions applicable to Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4005. Definitions applicable to Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014
For purposes of this title,11 See References in Text note below. the following definitions shall apply:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.


(2) National Flood Insurance ProgramThe term “National Flood Insurance Program” means the program established under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.).


(Pub. L. 113–89, § 2, Mar. 21, 2014, 128 Stat. 1020.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis title, referred to in text, probably should read “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 113–89, Mar. 21, 2014, 128 Stat. 1020, known as the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014, which does not contain titles. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2014 Amendment note set out under section 4001 of this title and Tables.
The National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, referred to in par. (2), is title XIII of Pub. L. 90–448, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 572, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4001 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4005_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Administrator The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4005_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>National Flood Insurance Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) National Flood Insurance Program The term “National Flood Insurance Program” means the program established under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>