<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4051" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4051/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4051/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4051"><akn:num>4051</akn:num><akn:heading>Industry flood insurance pool; requirements for participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4051. Industry flood insurance pool; requirements for participation(a) The Administrator is authorized to encourage and otherwise assist any insurance companies and other insurers which meet the requirements prescribed under subsection (b) to form, associate, or otherwise join together in a pool—(1) in order to provide the flood insurance coverage authorized under subchapter I; and

(2) for the purpose of assuming, including as reinsurance of coverage provided by the flood insurance program, on such terms and conditions as may be agreed upon, such financial responsibility as will enable such companies and other insurers, with the Federal financial and other assistance available under this chapter, to assume a reasonable proportion of responsibility for the adjustment and payment of claims for losses under the flood insurance program.


(b) In order to promote the effective administration of the flood insurance program under this part, and to assure that the objectives of this chapter are furthered, the Administrator is authorized to prescribe appropriate requirements for insurance companies and other insurers participating in such pool including, but not limited to, minimum requirements for capital or surplus or assets.

(Pub. L. 90–448, title XIII, § 1331, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 582; Pub. L. 98–181, title I [title IV, § 451(d)(1)], Nov. 30, 1983, 97 Stat. 1229; Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, §§ 100232(d)(1), 100238(b)(1), July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 954, 958.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsecs. (a)(2) and (b), was in the original a reference to “this title” meaning title XIII of Pub. L. 90–448, Aug. 1, 1968, 82 Stat. 572, known as the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4001 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2012—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 112–141, § 100238(b)(1), substituted “Admini</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4051_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) The Administrator is authorized to encourage and otherwise assist any insurance companies and other insurers which meet the requirements prescribed under subsection (b) to form, associate, or otherwise join together in a pool—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4051_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In order to promote the effective administration of the flood insurance program under this part, and to assure that the objectives of this chapter are furthered, the Administrator is authorized to prescribe appropriate requirements for insurance companies and other insurers participating in such pool including, but not limited to, minimum requirements for capital or surplus or assets.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>