<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/406" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/406/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/406/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_406"><akn:num>406</akn:num><akn:heading>Representation of claimants before Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 406. Representation of claimants before Commissioner(a) Recognition of representatives; fees for representation before Commissioner(1) The Commissioner of Social Security may prescribe rules and regulations governing the recognition of agents or other persons, other than attorneys as hereinafter provided, representing claimants before the Commissioner of Social Security, and may require of such agents or other persons, before being recognized as representatives of claimants that they shall show that they are of good character and in good repute, possessed of the necessary qualifications to enable them to render such claimants valuable service, and otherwise competent to advise and assist such claimants in the presentation of their cases. An attorney in good standing who is admitted to practice before the highest court of the State, Territory, District, or insular possession of his residence or before the Supreme Court of the United States or the inferior Federal courts, shall be entitled to represent claimants before the Commissioner of Social Security. Notwithstanding the preceding sentences, the Commissioner, after due notice and opportunity for hearing, (A) may refuse to recognize as a representative, and may disqualify a representative already recognized, any attorney who has been disbarred or suspended from any court or bar to which he or she was previously admitted to practice or who has been disqualified from participating in or appearing before any Federal program or agency, and (B) may refuse to recognize, and may disqualify, as a non-attorney representative any attorney who has been disbarred or suspended from any court or bar to which he or she was previously admitted to practice. A representative who has been disqualified or suspended pursuant to this section from appearing before the Social Security Administration as a result of collecting or receiving a fee in excess of the amount authorized shall be barred from appearing before the Social Security A</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_406_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition of representatives; fees for representation before Commissioner</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recognition of representatives; fees for representation before Commissioner</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_406_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees for representation before court</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fees for representation before court</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_406_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of options for obtaining attorneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of options for obtaining attorneys The Commissioner of Social Security shall notify each claimant in writing, together with the notice to such claimant of an adverse determination, of the options for obtaining attorneys to represent individuals in presenting their cases before the Commissioner of Social Security. Such notification shall also advise the claimant of the availability to qualifying claimants of legal services organizations which provide legal services free of charge.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_406_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment on attorneys</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assessment on attorneys</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_406_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extension of fee withholding and assessment procedures to qualified non-attorney representatives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Extension of fee withholding and assessment procedures to qualified non-attorney representatives</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>