<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/407" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/407/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/407/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_407"><akn:num>407</akn:num><akn:heading>Assignment of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 407. Assignment of benefits(a) In generalThe right of any person to any future payment under this subchapter shall not be transferable or assignable, at law or in equity, and none of the moneys paid or payable or rights existing under this subchapter shall be subject to execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, or to the operation of any bankruptcy or insolvency law.


(b) Amendment of sectionNo other provision of law, enacted before, on, or after April 20, 1983, may be construed to limit, supersede, or otherwise modify the provisions of this section except to the extent that it does so by express reference to this section.


(c) Withholding of taxesNothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit withholding taxes from any benefit under this subchapter, if such withholding is done pursuant to a request made in accordance with section 3402(p)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by the person entitled to such benefit or such person’s representative payee.


(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title II, § 207, 49 Stat. 624; Aug. 10, 1939, ch. 666, title II, § 201, 53 Stat. 1362, 1372; Pub. L. 98–21, title III, § 335(a), Apr. 20, 1983, 97 Stat. 130; Pub. L. 105–277, div. J, title IV, § 4005(a), Oct. 21, 1998, 112 Stat. 2681–911.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Internal Revenue Code of 1986, referred to in subsec. (c), is classified generally to Title 26, Internal Revenue Code.

Codification
In subsec. (b), “April 20, 1983” substituted for “the date of the enactment of this section”, which was translated as meaning the date of enactment of this subsection, as the probable intent of Congress.

Amendments1998—Subsec. (c). Pub. L. 105–277 added subsec. (c).
1983—Pub. L. 98–21 designated existing provisions as subsec. (a) and added subsec. (b).
1939—Act Aug. 10, 1939, amended section generally, incorporating provisions of former section 408 of this title.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 1983 AmendmentPub. L. 98–2</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The right of any person to any future payment under this subchapter shall not be transferable or assignable, at law or in equity, and none of the moneys paid or payable or rights existing under this subchapter shall be subject to execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, or to the operation of any bankruptcy or insolvency law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amendment of section No other provision of law, enacted before, on, or after April 20, 1983, may be construed to limit, supersede, or otherwise modify the provisions of this section except to the extent that it does so by express reference to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_407_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding of taxes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Withholding of taxes Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit withholding taxes from any benefit under this subchapter, if such withholding is done pursuant to a request made in accordance with section 3402(p)(1) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 by the person entitled to such benefit or such person’s representative payee.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>