<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/410" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/410/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/410/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_410"><akn:num>410</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions relating to employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 410. Definitions relating to employment
For the purposes of this subchapter—(a) EmploymentThe term “employment” means any service performed after 1936 and prior to 1951 which was employment for the purposes of this subchapter under the law applicable to the period in which such service was performed, and any service, of whatever nature, performed after 1950 (A) by an employee for the person employing him, irrespective of the citizenship or residence of either, (i) within the United States, or (ii) on or in connection with an American vessel or American aircraft under a contract of service which is entered into within the United States or during the performance of which and while the employee is employed on the vessel or aircraft it touches at a port in the United States, if the employee is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft when outside the United States, or (B) outside the United States by a citizen or resident of the United States as an employee (i) of an American employer (as defined in subsection (e) of this section), or (ii) of a foreign affiliate (as defined in section 3121(l)(6) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986) of an American employer during any period for which there is in effect an agreement, entered into pursuant to section 3121(l) of such Code, with respect to such affiliate, or (C) if it is service, regardless of where or by whom performed, which is designated as employment or recognized as equivalent to employment under an agreement entered into under section 433 of this title; except that, in the case of service performed after 1950, such term shall not include—(1) Service performed by foreign agricultural workers lawfully admitted to the United States from the Bahamas, Jamaica, and the other British West Indies, or from any other foreign country or possession thereof, on a temporary basis to perform agricultural labor;

(2) Domestic service performed in a local college club, or local chapter of a college fraternity or so</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Employment The term “employment” means any service performed after 1936 and prior to 1951 which was employment for the purposes of this subchapter under the law applicable to the period in which such service was performed, and any service, of whatever nature, performed after 1950 (A) by an employee for the person employing him, irrespective of the citizenship or residence of either, (i) within the United States, or (ii) on or in connection with an American vessel or American aircraft under a contract of service which is entered into within the United States or during the performance of which and while the employee is employed on the vessel or aircraft it touches at a port in the United States, if the employee is employed on and in connection with such vessel or aircraft when outside the United States, or (B) outside the United States by a citizen or resident of the United States as an employee (i) of an American employer (as defined in subsection (e) of this section), or (ii) of a </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Included and excluded service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Included and excluded service If the services performed during one-half or more of any pay period by an employee for the person employing him constitute employment, all the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment; but if the services performed during more than one-half of any such pay period by an employee for the person employing him do not constitute employment, then none of the services of such employee for such period shall be deemed to be employment. As used in this subsection, the term “pay period” means a period (of not more than thirty-one consecutive days) for which a payment of remuneration is ordinarily made to the employee by the person employing him. This subsection shall not be applicable with respect to services performed in a pay period by an employee for the person employing him, where any of such service is excepted by paragraph (9) of subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>American vessel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) American vessel The term “American vessel” means any vessel documented or numbered under the laws of the United States; and includes any vessel which is neither documented or numbered under the laws of the United States nor documented under the laws of any foreign country, if its crew is employed solely by one or more citizens or residents of the United States or corporations organized under the laws of the United States or of any State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>American aircraft</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) American aircraft The term “American aircraft” means an aircraft registered under the laws of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>American employer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) American employer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agricultural labor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Agricultural labor The term “agricultural labor” includes all service performed— The provisions of subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (4) of this subsection shall not be deemed to be applicable with respect to service performed in connection with commercial canning or commercial freezing or in connection with any agricultural or horticultural commodity after its delivery to a terminal market for distribution for consumption.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Farm</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Farm The term “farm” includes stock, dairy, poultry, fruit, fur-bearing animal, and truck farms, plantations, ranches, nurseries, ranges, greenhouses or other similar structures used primarily for the raising of agricultural or horticultural commodities, and orchards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>State</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) State The term “State” includes the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) United States The term “United States” when used in a geographical sense means the States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_410_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Employee The term “employee” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>