<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4101b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4101b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4101b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4101b"><akn:num>4101b</akn:num><akn:heading>National Flood Mapping Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4101b. National Flood Mapping Program(a) Reviewing, updating, and maintaining mapsThe Administrator, in coordination with the Technical Mapping Advisory Council established under section 4101a of this title, shall establish an ongoing program under which the Administrator shall review, update, and maintain National Flood Insurance Program rate maps in accordance with this section.


(b) Mapping(1) In generalIn carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—(A) identify, review, update, maintain, and publish National Flood Insurance Program rate maps with respect to—(i) all populated areas and areas of possible population growth located within the 100-year floodplain;

(ii) all populated areas and areas of possible population growth located within the 500-year floodplain;

(iii) areas of residual risk, including areas that are protected by levees, dams, and other flood control structures;

(iv) areas that could be inundated as a result of the failure of a levee, dam, or other flood control structure;

(v) areas that are protected by non-structural flood mitigation features; and

(vi) the level of protection provided by flood control structures and by non-structural flood mitigation features;


(B) establish or update flood-risk zone data in all such areas, and make estimates with respect to the rates of probable flood caused loss for the various flood risk zones for each such area; and

(C) use, in identifying, reviewing, updating, maintaining, or publishing any National Flood Insurance Program rate map required under this section or under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (42 U.S.C. 4011 et seq.), the most accurate topography and elevation data available.


(2) Mapping elementsEach map updated under this section shall—(A) assess the accuracy of current ground elevation data used for hydrologic and hydraulic modeling of flooding sources and mapping of the flood hazard and wherever necessary acquire new ground elevation dat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reviewing, updating, and maintaining maps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reviewing, updating, and maintaining maps The Administrator, in coordination with the Technical Mapping Advisory Council established under section 4101a of this title, shall establish an ongoing program under which the Administrator shall review, update, and maintain National Flood Insurance Program rate maps in accordance with this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mapping</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mapping</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Standards In updating and maintaining maps under this section, the Administrator shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Communication and outreach</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Communication and outreach</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Community remapping request</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Community remapping request Upon the adoption by the Administrator of any recommendation by the Technical Mapping Advisory Council for reviewing, updating, or maintaining National Flood Insurance Program rate maps in accordance with this section, a community that believes that its flood insurance rates in effect prior to adoption would be affected by the adoption of such recommendation may submit a request for an update of its rate maps, which may be considered at the Administrator’s sole discretion. The Administrator shall establish a protocol for the evaluation of such community map update requests.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4101b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $400,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2013 through 2017.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>