<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4104a"><akn:num>4104a</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4104a. Notice requirements(a) Notification of special flood hazards(1) Regulated lending institutionsEach Federal entity for lending regulation (after consultation and coordination with the Financial Institutions Examination Council) shall by regulation require regulated lending institutions, as a condition of making, increasing, extending, or renewing any loan secured by improved real estate or a mobile home that the regulated lending institution determines is located or is to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator under this chapter or the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 as an area having special flood hazards, to notify the purchaser or lessee (or obtain satisfactory assurances that the seller or lessor has notified the purchaser or lessee) and the servicer of the loan of such special flood hazards, in writing, a reasonable period in advance of the signing of the purchase agreement, lease, or other documents involved in the transaction. The regulations shall also require that the regulated lending institution retain a record of the receipt of the notices by the purchaser or lessee and the servicer.


(2) Federal agency lendersEach Federal agency lender shall by regulation require notification in the manner provided under paragraph (1) with respect to any loan that is made by the Federal agency lender and secured by improved real estate or a mobile home located or to be located in an area that has been identified by the Administrator under this chapter or the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 as an area having special flood hazards. Any regulations issued under this paragraph shall be consistent with and substantially identical to the regulations issued under paragraph (1).


(3) Contents of noticeWritten notification required under this subsection shall include—(A) a warning, in a form to be established by the Administrator, stating that the building on the improved real estate securing the loan is located, or the mobile h</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of special flood hazards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Notification of special flood hazards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of change of servicer</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of change of servicer</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of expiration of insurance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notification of expiration of insurance The Administrator (or the designee of the Administrator) shall, not less than 45 days before the expiration of any contract for flood insurance under this chapter, issue notice of such expiration by first class mail to the owner of the property covered by the contract, the servicer of any loan secured by the property covered by the contract, and (if known to the Administrator) the owner of the loan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>