<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104–1" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104–1/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4104–1/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4104_1"><akn:num>4104–1</akn:num><akn:heading>Scientific Resolution Panel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4104–1. Scientific Resolution Panel(a) Availability(1) In generalPursuant to the authority provided under section 4104(e) of this title, the Administrator shall make available an independent review panel, to be known as the Scientific Resolution Panel, to any community—(A) that has—(i) filed a timely map appeal in accordance with section 4104 of this title;

(ii) completed 60 days of consultation with the Federal Emergency Management Agency on the appeal; and

(iii) not allowed more than 120 days, or such longer period as may be provided by the Administrator by waiver, to pass since the end of the appeal period; or


(B) that has received an unsatisfactory ruling under the map revision process established pursuant to section 4101(f) of this title.


(2) Appeals by owners and lesseesIf a community and an owner or lessee of real property within the community appeal a proposed determination of a flood elevation under section 4104(b) of this title, upon the request of the community—(A) the owner or lessee shall submit scientific and technical data relating to the appeals to the Scientific Resolution Panel; and

(B) the Scientific Resolution Panel shall make a determination with respect to the appeals in accordance with subsection (c).


(3) DefinitionFor purposes of paragraph (1)(B), an “unsatisfactory ruling” means that a community—(A) received a revised Flood Insurance Rate Map from the Federal Emergency Management Agency, via a Letter of Final Determination, after September 30, 2008, and prior to July 6, 2012;

(B) has subsequently applied for a Letter of Map Revision or Physical Map Revision with the Federal Emergency Management Agency; and

(C) has received an unfavorable ruling on their request for a map revision.



(b) MembershipThe Scientific Resolution Panel made available under subsection (a) shall consist of 5 members with expertise that relates to the creation and study of flood hazard maps and flood insurance. The Scientific Resolution Panel may include </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104_1_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Availability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104_1_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Membership</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Membership The Scientific Resolution Panel made available under subsection (a) shall consist of 5 members with expertise that relates to the creation and study of flood hazard maps and flood insurance. The Scientific Resolution Panel may include representatives from Federal agencies not involved in the mapping study in question and from other impartial experts. Employees of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may not serve on the Scientific Resolution Panel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104_1_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4104_1_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maps used for insurance and mandatory purchase requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Maps used for insurance and mandatory purchase requirements With respect to any community that has a dispute that is being considered by the Scientific Resolution Panel formed pursuant to this subsection, the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall ensure that for each such community that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>