<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4106" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4106/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4106/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4106"><akn:num>4106</akn:num><akn:heading>Nonparticipation in flood insurance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4106. Nonparticipation in flood insurance program(a) Prohibition against Federal approval of financial assistanceNo Federal officer or agency shall approve any financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes on and after July 1, 1975, for use in any area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards unless the community in which such area is situated is then participating in the national flood insurance program.


(b) Notification of purchaser or lessee of property in flood hazard area of availability of Federal disaster relief assistance in event of a flood disasterIn addition to the requirements of section 4104a of this title, each Federal entity for lending regulation shall by regulation require the regulated lending institutions described in such section, and each Federal agency lender shall issue regulations requiring the Federal agency lender, described in such section to notify (as a condition of making, increasing, extending, or renewing any loan secured by property described in such section) the purchaser or lessee of such property of whether, in the event of a disaster caused by flood to such property, Federal disaster relief assistance will be available to such property.


(Pub. L. 93–234, title II, § 202, Dec. 31, 1973, 87 Stat. 982; Pub. L. 94–50, title III, § 303, July 2, 1975, 89 Stat. 256; Pub. L. 94–198, Dec. 31, 1975, 89 Stat. 1116; Pub. L. 94–375, § 14(a), Aug. 3, 1976, 90 Stat. 1075; Pub. L. 95–128, title VII, § 703(a), Oct. 12, 1977, 91 Stat. 1144; Pub. L. 98–181, title I [title IV, § 451(e)(1)], Nov. 30, 1983, 97 Stat. 1229; Pub. L. 103–325, title V, § 511(b), Sept. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 2256; Pub. L. 112–141, div. F, title II, § 100238(a)(1), July 6, 2012, 126 Stat. 958.)

Editorial Notes
Codification
Section was enacted as part of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973, and not as part of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 which comprises this chapter.

Amendments2012—Subsec. (a).</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4106_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition against Federal approval of financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition against Federal approval of financial assistance No Federal officer or agency shall approve any financial assistance for acquisition or construction purposes on and after July 1, 1975, for use in any area that has been identified by the Administrator as an area having special flood hazards unless the community in which such area is situated is then participating in the national flood insurance program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4106_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of purchaser or lessee of property in flood hazard area of availability of Federal disaster relief assistance in event of a flood disaster</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notification of purchaser or lessee of property in flood hazard area of availability of Federal disaster relief assistance in event of a flood disaster In addition to the requirements of section 4104a of this title, each Federal entity for lending regulation shall by regulation require the regulated lending institutions described in such section, and each Federal agency lender shall issue regulations requiring the Federal agency lender, described in such section to notify (as a condition of making, increasing, extending, or renewing any loan secured by property described in such section) the purchaser or lessee of such property of whether, in the event of a disaster caused by flood to such property, Federal disaster relief assistance will be available to such property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>