<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4336e"><akn:num>4336e</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4336e. Definitions
In this subchapter:(1) Categorical exclusionThe term “categorical exclusion” means a category of actions that a Federal agency has determined normally does not significantly affect the quality of the human environment within the meaning of section 4332(2)(C) of this title.


(2) Cooperating agencyThe term “cooperating agency” means any Federal, State, Tribal, or local agency that has been designated as a cooperating agency under section 4336a(a)(3) of this title.


(3) CouncilThe term “Council” means the Council on Environmental Quality established in subchapter II.


(4) Environmental assessmentThe term “environmental assessment” means an environmental assessment prepared under section 4336(b)(2) of this title.


(5) Environmental documentThe term “environmental document” means an environmental impact statement, an environmental assessment, or a finding of no significant impact.


(6) Environmental impact statementThe term “environmental impact statement” means a detailed written statement that is required by section 4332(2)(C) of this title.


(7) Finding of no significant impactThe term “finding of no significant impact” means a determination by a Federal agency that a proposed agency action does not require the issuance of an environmental impact statement.


(8) Participating Federal agencyThe term “participating Federal agency” means a Federal agency participating in an environmental review or authorization of an action.


(9) Lead agencyThe term “lead agency” means, with respect to a proposed agency action—(A) the agency that proposed such action; or

(B) if there are 2 or more involved Federal agencies with respect to such action, the agency designated under section 4336a(a)(1) of this title.


(10) Major Federal action(A) In generalThe term “major Federal action” means an action that the agency carrying out such action determines is subject to substantial Federal control and responsibility.


(B) ExclusionThe term “major Federal action”</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Categorical exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Categorical exclusion The term “categorical exclusion” means a category of actions that a Federal agency has determined normally does not significantly affect the quality of the human environment within the meaning of section 4332(2)(C) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cooperating agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Cooperating agency The term “cooperating agency” means any Federal, State, Tribal, or local agency that has been designated as a cooperating agency under section 4336a(a)(3) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Council The term “Council” means the Council on Environmental Quality established in subchapter II.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental assessment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Environmental assessment The term “environmental assessment” means an environmental assessment prepared under section 4336(b)(2) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental document</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Environmental document The term “environmental document” means an environmental impact statement, an environmental assessment, or a finding of no significant impact.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Environmental impact statement The term “environmental impact statement” means a detailed written statement that is required by section 4332(2)(C) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Finding of no significant impact</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Finding of no significant impact The term “finding of no significant impact” means a determination by a Federal agency that a proposed agency action does not require the issuance of an environmental impact statement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Participating Federal agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Participating Federal agency The term “participating Federal agency” means a Federal agency participating in an environmental review or authorization of an action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Lead agency The term “lead agency” means, with respect to a proposed agency action—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336e_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Major Federal action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Major Federal action</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>