<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4336a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4336a"><akn:num>4336a</akn:num><akn:heading>Timely and unified Federal reviews</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4336a. Timely and unified Federal reviews(a) Lead agency(1) Designation(A) In generalIf there are two or more participating Federal agencies, such agencies shall determine, by letter or memorandum, which agency shall be the lead agency based on consideration of the—(i) magnitude of agency’s involvement;

(ii) project approval or disapproval authority;

(iii) expertise concerning the action’s environmental effects;

(iv) duration of agency’s involvement; and

(v) sequence of agency’s involvement.


(B) Joint lead agenciesIn making a determination under subparagraph (A), the participating Federal agencies may appoint such State, Tribal, or local agencies as joint lead agencies as the involved Federal agencies shall determine appropriate. Joint lead agencies shall jointly fulfill the role described in paragraph (2).



(2) RoleA lead agency shall, with respect to a proposed agency action—(A) supervise the preparation of an environmental document if, with respect to such proposed agency action, there is more than one participating Federal agency;

(B) request the participation of each cooperating agency at the earliest practicable time;

(C) in preparing an environmental document, give consideration to any analysis or proposal created by a cooperating agency;

(D) develop a schedule, in consultation with each cooperating agency, the applicant, and such other entities as the lead agency determines appropriate, for completion of any environmental review, permit, or authorization required to carry out the proposed agency action;

(E) if the lead agency determines that a review, permit, or authorization will not be completed in accordance with the schedule developed under subparagraph (D), notify the agency responsible for issuing such review, permit, or authorization of the discrepancy and request that such agency take such measures as such agency determines appropriate to comply with such schedule; and

(F) meet with a cooperating agency that requests such a meeting.


</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Lead agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Lead agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>One document</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) One document To the extent practicable, if a proposed agency action will require action by more than one Federal agency and the lead agency has determined that it requires preparation of an environmental document, the lead and cooperating agencies shall evaluate the proposal in a single environmental document.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request for public comment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Request for public comment Each notice of intent to prepare an environmental impact statement under section 4332 of this title shall include a request for public comment on alternatives or impacts and on relevant information, studies, or analyses with respect to the proposed agency action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statement of purpose and need</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Statement of purpose and need Each environmental document shall include a statement of purpose and need that briefly summarizes the underlying purpose and need for the proposed agency action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Page limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Page limits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sponsor preparation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Sponsor preparation A lead agency shall prescribe procedures to allow a project sponsor to prepare an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement under the supervision of the agency. Such agency may provide such sponsor with appropriate guidance and assist in the preparation. The lead agency shall independently evaluate the environmental document and shall take responsibility for the contents.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deadlines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Deadlines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4336a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Report</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>