<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4364" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4364/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4364/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4364"><akn:num>4364</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure of funds for research and development related to regulatory program activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4364. Expenditure of funds for research and development related to regulatory program activities(a) Coordination, etc., with research needs and priorities of program offices and Environmental Protection AgencyThe Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assure that the expenditure of any funds appropriated pursuant to this Act or any other provision of law for environmental research and development related to regulatory program activities shall be coordinated with and reflect the research needs and priorities of the program offices, as well as the overall research needs and priorities of the Agency, including those defined in the five-year research plan.


(b) Program offices subject to coverageFor purposes of subsection (a), the appropriate program offices are—(1) the Office of Air and Waste Management, for air quality activities;

(2) the Office of Water and Hazardous Materials, for water quality activities and water supply activities;

(3) the Office of Pesticides, for environmental effects of pesticides;

(4) the Office of Solid Waste, for solid waste activities;

(5) the Office of Toxic Substances, for toxic substance activities;

(6) the Office of Radiation Programs, for radiation activities; and

(7) the Office of Noise Abatement and Control, for noise activities.


(c) Report to Congress; contentsThe Administrator shall submit to the President and the Congress a report concerning the most appropriate means of assuring, on a continuing basis, that the research efforts of the Agency reflect the needs and priorities of the regulatory program offices, while maintaining a high level of scientific quality. Such report shall be submitted on or before March 31, 1978.


(Pub. L. 95–155, § 7, Nov. 8, 1977, 91 Stat. 1259.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 95–155, Nov. 8, 1977, 91 Stat. 1257, known as the Environmental Research, Development, and Demonstration Authorization Act of 1978, which to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4364_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination, etc., with research needs and priorities of program offices and Environmental Protection Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordination, etc., with research needs and priorities of program offices and Environmental Protection Agency The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall assure that the expenditure of any funds appropriated pursuant to this Act or any other provision of law for environmental research and development related to regulatory program activities shall be coordinated with and reflect the research needs and priorities of the program offices, as well as the overall research needs and priorities of the Agency, including those defined in the five-year research plan.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4364_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program offices subject to coverage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program offices subject to coverage For purposes of subsection (a), the appropriate program offices are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4364_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress; contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report to Congress; contents The Administrator shall submit to the President and the Congress a report concerning the most appropriate means of assuring, on a continuing basis, that the research efforts of the Agency reflect the needs and priorities of the regulatory program offices, while maintaining a high level of scientific quality. Such report shall be submitted on or before March 31, 1978.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>