<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4368b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4368b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4368b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4368b"><akn:num>4368b</akn:num><akn:heading>General assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4368b. General assistance program(a) Short titleThis section may be cited as the “Indian Environmental General Assistance Program Act of 1992”.


(b) PurposesThe purposes of this section are to—(1) provide general assistance grants to Indian tribal governments and intertribal consortia to build capacity to administer environmental regulatory programs that may be delegated by the Environmental Protection Agency on Indian lands; and

(2) provide technical assistance from the Environmental Protection Agency to Indian tribal governments and intertribal consortia in the development of multimedia programs to address environmental issues on Indian lands.


(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “Indian tribal government” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community, including any Alaska Native village or regional or village corporation (as defined in, or established pursuant to, the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C.A. 1601, et seq.)), which is recognized as eligible for the special services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.

(2) The term “intertribal consortia” or “intertribal consortium” means a partnership between two or more Indian tribal governments authorized by the governing bodies of those tribes to apply for and receive assistance pursuant to this section.

(3) The term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.


(d) General assistance program(1) The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall establish an Indian Environmental General Assistance Program that provides grants to eligible Indian tribal governments or intertribal consortia to cover the costs of planning, developing, and establishing environmental protection programs consistent with other applicable provisions of law providing for enforcement of such laws by Indian tribes on Indian lands.

(2) Each grant awarded for general assistance under this </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Short title This section may be cited as the “Indian Environmental General Assistance Program Act of 1992”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of this section are to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>General assistance program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) General assistance program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>No reduction in amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) No reduction in amounts In no case shall the award of a general assistance grant to an Indian tribal government or intertribal consortium under this section result in a reduction of Environmental Protection Agency grants for environmental programs to that tribal government or consortium. Nothing in this section shall preclude an Indian tribal government or intertribal consortium from receiving individual media grants or cooperative agreements. Funds provided by the Environmental Protection Agency through the general assistance program shall be used by an Indian tribal government or intertribal consortium to supplement other funds provided by the Environmental Protection Agency through individual media grants or cooperative agreements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expenditure of general assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Expenditure of general assistance Any general assistance under this section shall be expended for the purpose of planning, developing, and establishing the capability to implement programs administered by the Environmental Protection Agency and specified in the assistance agreement. Purposes and programs authorized under this section shall include the development and implementation of solid and hazardous waste programs for Indian lands. An Indian tribal government or intertribal consortium receiving general assistance pursuant to this section shall utilize such funds for programs and purposes to be carried out in accordance with the terms of the assistance agreement. Such programs and general assistance shall be carried out in accordance with the purposes and requirements of applicable provisions of law, including the Solid Waste Disposal Act (42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Authorization There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the provisions of this section, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997, and 1998.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4368b_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Report to Congress The Administrator shall transmit an annual report to the appropriate Committees of the Congress with jurisdiction over the applicable environmental laws and Indian tribes describing which Indian tribes or intertribal consortia have been granted approval by the Administrator pursuant to law to enforce certain environmental laws and the effectiveness of any such enforcement.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>