<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370j" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370j/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370j/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4370j"><akn:num>4370j</akn:num><akn:heading>Municipal Ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4370j. Municipal Ombudsman(a) EstablishmentThere is established within the Office of the Administrator an Office of the Municipal Ombudsman, to be headed by a Municipal Ombudsman.


(b) General dutiesThe duties of the Municipal Ombudsman shall include the provision of—(1) technical assistance to municipalities seeking to comply with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.]; and

(2) information to the Administrator to help the Administrator ensure that agency policies are implemented by all offices of the Environmental Protection Agency, including regional offices.


(c) Actions requiredThe Municipal Ombudsman shall work with appropriate offices at the headquarters and regional offices of the Environmental Protection Agency to ensure that a municipality seeking assistance is provided information regarding—(1) available Federal financial assistance for which the municipality is eligible;

(2) flexibility available under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act; and

(3) the opportunity to develop an integrated plan under section 402(s) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1342(s)].


(d) Information sharingThe Municipal Ombudsman shall publish on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency—(1) general information relating to—(A) the technical assistance referred to in subsection (b)(1);

(B) the financial assistance referred to in subsection (c)(1);

(C) the flexibility referred to in subsection (c)(2); and

(D) any resources developed by the Administrator related to integrated plans under section 402(s) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act [33 U.S.C. 1342(s)]; and


(2) a copy of each permit, order, or judicial consent decree that implements or incorporates such an integrated plan.


(Pub. L. 115–436, § 4, Jan. 14, 2019, 132 Stat. 5560.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Federal Water Pollution Control Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is act June 30, 1948, ch. 758, as amended generally by Pub. L. 92–500</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370j_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There is established within the Office of the Administrator an Office of the Municipal Ombudsman, to be headed by a Municipal Ombudsman.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370j_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General duties The duties of the Municipal Ombudsman shall include the provision of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370j_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Actions required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Actions required The Municipal Ombudsman shall work with appropriate offices at the headquarters and regional offices of the Environmental Protection Agency to ensure that a municipality seeking assistance is provided information regarding—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370j_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Information sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Information sharing The Municipal Ombudsman shall publish on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>