<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370m–6" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370m–6/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4370m–6/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4370m_6"><akn:num>4370m–6</akn:num><akn:heading>Litigation, judicial review, and savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4370m–6. Litigation, judicial review, and savings provision(a) Limitations on claims(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law, a claim arising under Federal law seeking judicial review of any authorization issued by a Federal agency for a covered project shall be barred unless—(A) the claim is filed not later than 2 years after the date of publication in the Federal Register of notice of final agency action on the authorization, unless a shorter time is specified in the Federal law under which judicial review is allowed; and

(B) in the case of an action pertaining to an environmental review conducted under NEPA—(i) the claim is filed by a party that submitted a comment during the environmental review; and

(ii) any commenter filed a sufficiently detailed comment so as to put the lead agency on notice of the issue on which the party seeks judicial review, or the lead agency did not provide a reasonable opportunity for such a comment on that issue.



(2) New information(A) In generalThe head of a lead agency or participating agency shall consider new information received after the close of a comment period if the information satisfies the requirements under regulations implementing NEPA.


(B) Separate actionIf Federal law requires the preparation of a supplemental environmental impact statement or other supplemental environmental document, the preparation of such document shall be considered a separate final agency action and the deadline for filing a claim for judicial review of the agency action shall be 2 years after the date on which a notice announcing the final agency action is published in the Federal Register, unless a shorter time is specified in the Federal law under which judicial review is allowed.



(3) Rule of constructionNothing in this subsection creates a right to judicial review or places any limit on filing a claim that a person has violated the terms of an authorization.



(b) Preliminary injunctive reliefIn addition to consid</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370m_6_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on claims</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Limitations on claims</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370m_6_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preliminary injunctive relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Preliminary injunctive relief In addition to considering any other applicable equitable factors, in any action seeking a temporary restraining order or preliminary injunction against an agency or a project sponsor in connection with review or authorization of a covered project, the court shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370m_6_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Judicial review Except as provided in subsection (a), nothing in this subchapter affects the reviewability of any final Federal agency action in a court of competent jurisdiction.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370m_6_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings clause</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Savings clause Nothing in this subchapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4370m_6_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations Nothing in this subchapter preempts, limits, or interferes with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>