<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4372" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4372/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4372/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4372"><akn:num>4372</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Environmental Quality</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4372. Office of Environmental Quality(a) Establishment; Director; Deputy DirectorThere is established in the Executive Office of the President an office to be known as the Office of Environmental Quality (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Office”). The Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality established by Public Law 91–190 shall be the Director of the Office. There shall be in the Office a Deputy Director who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.


(b) Compensation of Deputy DirectorThe compensation of the Deputy Director shall be fixed by the President at a rate not in excess of the annual rate of compensation payable to the Deputy Director of the Office of Management and Budget.


(c) Employment of personnel, experts, and consultants; compensationThe Director is authorized to employ such officers and employees (including experts and consultants) as may be necessary to enable the Office to carry out its functions under this chapter and Public Law 91–190, except that he may employ no more than ten specialists and other experts without regard to the provisions of title 5, governing appointments in the competitive service, and pay such specialists and experts without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, but no such specialist or expert shall be paid at a rate in excess of the maximum rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5.


(d) Duties and functions of DirectorIn carrying out his functions the Director shall assist and advise the President on policies and programs of the Federal Government affecting environmental quality by—(1) providing the professional and administrative staff and support for the Council on Environmental Quality established by Public Law 91–190;

(2) assisting the Federal agencies and departments in appraising the effectiveness of existing an</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4372_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment; Director; Deputy Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment; Director; Deputy Director There is established in the Executive Office of the President an office to be known as the Office of Environmental Quality (hereafter in this chapter referred to as the “Office”). The Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality established by Public Law 91–190 shall be the Director of the Office. There shall be in the Office a Deputy Director who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4372_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation of Deputy Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compensation of Deputy Director The compensation of the Deputy Director shall be fixed by the President at a rate not in excess of the annual rate of compensation payable to the Deputy Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4372_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment of personnel, experts, and consultants; compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Employment of personnel, experts, and consultants; compensation The Director is authorized to employ such officers and employees (including experts and consultants) as may be necessary to enable the Office to carry out its functions under this chapter and Public Law 91–190, except that he may employ no more than ten specialists and other experts without regard to the provisions of title 5, governing appointments in the competitive service, and pay such specialists and experts without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, but no such specialist or expert shall be paid at a rate in excess of the maximum rate for GS–18 of the General Schedule under section 5332 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4372_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and functions of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties and functions of Director In carrying out his functions the Director shall assist and advise the President on policies and programs of the Federal Government affecting environmental quality by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4372_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director to contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authority of Director to contract The Director is authorized to contract with public or private agencies, institutions, and organizations and with individuals without regard to section 3324(a) and (b) of title 31 and section 6101 of title 41 in carrying out his functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>