<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4601" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4601/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4601/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4601"><akn:num>4601</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4601. Definitions
As used in this chapter—(1) The term “Federal agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality in the executive branch of the Government, any wholly owned Government corporation, the Architect of the Capitol, the Federal Reserve banks and branches thereof, and any person who has the authority to acquire property by eminent domain under Federal law.

(2) The term “State” means any of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any political subdivision thereof.

(3) The term “State agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality of a State or of a political subdivision of a State, any department, agency, or instrumentality of 2 or more States or of 2 or more political subdivisions of a State or States, and any person who has the authority to acquire property by eminent domain under State law.

(4) The term “Federal financial assistance” means a grant, loan, or contribution provided by the United States, except any Federal guarantee or insurance, any interest reduction payment to an individual in connection with the purchase and occupancy of a residence by that individual, and any annual payment or capital loan to the District of Columbia.

(5) The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.

(6)(A) The term “displaced person” means, except as provided in subparagraph (B)—(i) any person who moves from real property, or moves his personal property from real property—(I) as a direct result of a written notice of intent to acquire or the acquisition of such real property in whole or in part for a program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance; or

(II) on which such person is a residential tenant or conducts a small business, a farm operation, or a business defined in paragraph (7)(D), as a direct result of reh</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “Federal agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality in the executive branch of the Government, any wholly owned Government corporation, the Architect of the Capitol, the Federal Reserve banks and branches thereof, and any person who has the authority to acquire property by eminent domain under Federal law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “State” means any of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, any territory or possession of the United States, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and any political subdivision thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “State agency” means any department, agency, or instrumentality of a State or of a political subdivision of a State, any department, agency, or instrumentality of 2 or more States or of 2 or more political subdivisions of a State or States, and any person who has the authority to acquire property by eminent domain under State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “Federal financial assistance” means a grant, loan, or contribution provided by the United States, except any Federal guarantee or insurance, any interest reduction payment to an individual in connection with the purchase and occupancy of a residence by that individual, and any annual payment or capital loan to the District of Columbia.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “person” means any individual, partnership, corporation, or association.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “business” means any lawful activity, excepting a farm operation, conducted primarily—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “farm operation” means any activity conducted solely or primarily for the production of one or more agricultural products or commodities, including timber, for sale or home use, and customarily producing such products or commodities in sufficient quantity to be capable of contributing materially to the operator’s support.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “mortgage” means such classes of liens as are commonly given to secure advances on, or the unpaid purchase price of, real property, under the laws of the State in which the real property is located, together with the credit instruments, if any, secured thereby.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4601_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “comparable replacement dwelling” means any dwelling that is (A) decent, safe, and sanitary; (B) adequate in size to accommodate the occupants; (C) within the financial means of the displaced person; (D) functionally equivalent; (E) in an area not subject to unreasonable adverse environmental conditions; and (F) in a location generally not less desirable than the location of the displaced person’s dwelling with respect to public utilities, facilities, services, and the displaced person’s place of employment.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>