<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4621" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4621/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4621/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4621"><akn:num>4621</akn:num><akn:heading>Declaration of findings and policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4621. Declaration of findings and policy(a) FindingsThe Congress finds and declares that—(1) displacement as a direct result of programs or projects undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance is caused by a number of activities, including rehabilitation, demolition, code enforcement, and acquisition;

(2) relocation assistance policies must provide for fair, uniform, and equitable treatment of all affected persons;

(3) the displacement of businesses often results in their closure;

(4) minimizing the adverse impact of displacement is essential to maintaining the economic and social well-being of communities; and

(5) implementation of this chapter has resulted in burdensome, inefficient, and inconsistent compliance requirements and procedures which will be improved by establishing a lead agency and allowing for State certification and implementation.


(b) PolicyThis subchapter establishes a uniform policy for the fair and equitable treatment of persons displaced as a direct result of programs or projects undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance. The primary purpose of this subchapter is to ensure that such persons shall not suffer disproportionate injuries as a result of programs and projects designed for the benefit of the public as a whole and to minimize the hardship of displacement on such persons.


(c) Congressional intentIt is the intent of Congress that—(1) Federal agencies shall carry out this subchapter in a manner which minimizes waste, fraud, and mismanagement and reduces unnecessary administrative costs borne by States and State agencies in providing relocation assistance;

(2) uniform procedures for the administration of relocation assistance shall, to the maximum extent feasible, assure that the unique circumstances of any displaced person are taken into account and that persons in essentially similar circumstances are accorded equal treatment under this chapter;

(3) the improvement of housing c</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4621_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings The Congress finds and declares that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4621_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Policy This subchapter establishes a uniform policy for the fair and equitable treatment of persons displaced as a direct result of programs or projects undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance. The primary purpose of this subchapter is to ensure that such persons shall not suffer disproportionate injuries as a result of programs and projects designed for the benefit of the public as a whole and to minimize the hardship of displacement on such persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4621_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional intent</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Congressional intent It is the intent of Congress that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>