<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4626" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4626/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4626/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4626"><akn:num>4626</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing replacement by Federal agency as last resort</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4626. Housing replacement by Federal agency as last resort(a) If a program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance cannot proceed on a timely basis because comparable replacement dwellings are not available, and the head of the displacing agency determines that such dwellings cannot otherwise be made available, the head of the displacing agency may take such action as is necessary or appropriate to provide such dwellings by use of funds authorized for such project. The head of the displacing agency may use this section to exceed the maximum amounts which may be paid under sections 4623 and 4624 of this title on a case-by-case basis for good cause as determined in accordance with such regulations as the head of the lead agency shall issue.

(b) No person shall be required to move from his dwelling on account of any program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance, unless the head of the displacing agency is satisfied that comparable replacement housing is available to such person.

(Pub. L. 91–646, title II, § 206, Jan. 2, 1971, 84 Stat. 1898; Pub. L. 100–17, title IV, § 409, Apr. 2, 1987, 101 Stat. 253.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1987—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 100–17 amended subsec. (a) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (a) read as follows: “If a Federal project cannot proceed to actual construction because comparable replacement sale or rental housing is not available, and the head of the Federal agency determines that such housing cannot otherwise be made available he may take such action as is necessary or appropriate to provide such housing by use of funds authorized for such project.”
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 100–17 amended subsec. (b) generally. Prior to amendment, subsec. (b) read as follows: “No person shall be required to move from his dwelling on or after January 2, 1971, on account of any Federal project, unless the Federal agency head is satisfied that replacement housing, in acc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4626_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) If a program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance cannot proceed on a timely basis because comparable replacement dwellings are not available, and the head of the displacing agency determines that such dwellings cannot otherwise be made available, the head of the displacing agency may take such action as is necessary or appropriate to provide such dwellings by use of funds authorized for such project. The head of the displacing agency may use this section to exceed the maximum amounts which may be paid under sections 4623 and 4624 of this title on a case-by-case basis for good cause as determined in accordance with such regulations as the head of the lead agency shall issue.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4626_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) No person shall be required to move from his dwelling on account of any program or project undertaken by a Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance, unless the head of the displacing agency is satisfied that comparable replacement housing is available to such person.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>