<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4634" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4634/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4634/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4634"><akn:num>4634</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4634. Agency coordination(a) Agency capacityEach Federal agency responsible for funding or carrying out relocation and acquisition activities shall have adequately trained personnel and such other resources as are necessary to manage and oversee the relocation and acquisition program of the Federal agency in accordance with this chapter.


(b) Interagency agreementsNot later than 1 year after July 6, 2012, each Federal agency responsible for funding relocation and acquisition activities (other than the agency serving as the lead agency) shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the lead agency that—(1) provides for periodic training of the personnel of the Federal agency, which in the case of a Federal agency that provides Federal financial assistance, may include personnel of any displacing agency that receives Federal financial assistance;

(2) addresses ways in which the lead agency may provide assistance and coordination to the Federal agency relating to compliance with the 11 So in original. Probably should be “this”. chapter on a program or project basis; and

(3) addresses the funding of the training, assistance, and coordination activities provided by the lead agency, in accordance with subsection (c).


(c) Interagency payments(1) In generalFor the fiscal year that begins 1 year after July 6, 2012, and each fiscal year thereafter, each Federal agency responsible for funding relocation and acquisition activities (other than the agency serving as the lead agency) shall transfer to the lead agency for the fiscal year, such funds as are necessary, but not less than $35,000, to support the training, assistance, and coordination activities of the lead agency described in subsection (b).


(2) Included costsThe cost to a Federal agency of providing the funds described in paragraph (1) shall be included as part of the cost of 1 or more programs or projects undertaken by the Federal agency or with Federal financial assistance that result in the displacem</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4634_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agency capacity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Agency capacity Each Federal agency responsible for funding or carrying out relocation and acquisition activities shall have adequately trained personnel and such other resources as are necessary to manage and oversee the relocation and acquisition program of the Federal agency in accordance with this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4634_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Interagency agreements Not later than 1 year after July 6, 2012, each Federal agency responsible for funding relocation and acquisition activities (other than the agency serving as the lead agency) shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the lead agency that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4634_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Interagency payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>