<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4726" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4726/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4726/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4726"><akn:num>4726</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of Federal programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4726. Coordination of Federal programs
The Office, after consultation with other agencies concerned, shall—(1) coordinate the personnel administration support and technical assistance given to State and local governments and the support given State programs or projects to strengthen local government personnel administration, including the furnishing of needed personnel administration services and technical assistance, under authority of this chapter with any such support given under other Federal programs; and

(2) make such arrangements, including the collection, maintenance, and dissemination of data on grants for strengthening State and local government personnel administration and on grants to States for furnishing needed personnel administration services and technical assistance to local governments, as needed to avoid duplication and insure consistent administration of related Federal activities.

(Pub. L. 91–648, title II, § 206, Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1914; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, § 102, eff. Jan. 1, 1979, 43 F.R. 36037, 92 Stat. 3783.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in par. (1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 91–648, Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1909, known as the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4701 of this title and Tables.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
“Office”, meaning Office of Personnel Management, substituted in text for “Commission”, meaning Civil Service Commission, pursuant to Reorg. Plan No. 2 of 1978, § 102, 43 F.R. 36037, 92 Stat. 3783, set out under section 1101 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, which transferred functions vested by statute in Civil Service Commission and Chairman thereof to Director of Office of Personnel Management (except as otherwise specified), effective Jan. 1, 1979, as provided by section 1–102 </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4726_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) coordinate the personnel administration support and technical assistance given to State and local governments and the support given State programs or projects to strengthen local government personnel administration, including the furnishing of needed personnel administration services and technical assistance, under authority of this chapter with any such support given under other Federal programs; and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4726_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) make such arrangements, including the collection, maintenance, and dissemination of data on grants for strengthening State and local government personnel administration and on grants to States for furnishing needed personnel administration services and technical assistance to local governments, as needed to avoid duplication and insure consistent administration of related Federal activities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>