<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4742" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4742/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4742/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4742"><akn:num>4742</akn:num><akn:heading>Admission to Federal employee training programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4742. Admission to Federal employee training programs(a) State and local government officers and employeesIn accordance with such conditions as may be prescribed by the head of the Federal agency concerned, a Federal agency may admit State and local government employees and officials to agency training programs established for Federal professional, administrative, or technical personnel.


(b) Waiver of payments for training costsFederal agencies may waive, in whole or in part, payments from, or on behalf of, State and local governments for the costs of training provided under this section. Payments received by the Federal agency concerned for training under this section shall be credited to the appropriation or fund used for paying the training costs.


(c) Initial costs; reimbursement of other Federal agenciesThe Office may use appropriations authorized by this chapter to pay the initial additional developmental or overhead costs that are incurred by reason of admittance of State and local government employees to Federal training courses and to reimburse other Federal agencies for such costs.


(Pub. L. 91–648, title III, § 302, Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1916; 1978 Reorg. Plan No. 2, 102, eff. Jan. 1, 1979, 43 F.R. 36037, 92 Stat. 3783.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (c), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 91–648, Jan. 5, 1971, 84 Stat. 1909, known as the Intergovernmental Personnel Act of 1970, which enacted this chapter and sections 3371 to 3376 of Title 5, Government Organization and Employees, amended section 246(f) of this title, section 1304 of Title 5, repealed sections 1881 to 1888 of Title 7, Agriculture, and section 869b of Title 20, Education, and enacted provisions set out as notes under section 3371 of Title 5. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out section 4701 of this title and Tables.

Executive Documents

Transfer of Functions
“Office”, meaning Office</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4742_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local government officers and employees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State and local government officers and employees In accordance with such conditions as may be prescribed by the head of the Federal agency concerned, a Federal agency may admit State and local government employees and officials to agency training programs established for Federal professional, administrative, or technical personnel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4742_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of payments for training costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Waiver of payments for training costs Federal agencies may waive, in whole or in part, payments from, or on behalf of, State and local governments for the costs of training provided under this section. Payments received by the Federal agency concerned for training under this section shall be credited to the appropriation or fund used for paying the training costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4742_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Initial costs; reimbursement of other Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Initial costs; reimbursement of other Federal agencies The Office may use appropriations authorized by this chapter to pay the initial additional developmental or overhead costs that are incurred by reason of admittance of State and local government employees to Federal training courses and to reimburse other Federal agencies for such costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>