<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4743" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4743/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4743/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4743"><akn:num>4743</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to State and local governments for training</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4743. Grants to State and local governments for training(a) Amount of grants; executive certification; use restrictions; uses for non-Federal share; personnel training and education programs: innovation and diversity in development and executionIf in its judgment training is not adequately provided for under grant-in-aid or other statutes, the Office is authorized to make grants to State and general local governments for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs, on the certification of the Governor of that State, or the mayor or chief executive officer of the general local government, that the programs are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of section 4701 of this title, to train and educate their professional, administrative, and technical employees and officials. Such grants may not be used to cover costs of full-time graduate-level study, provided for in section 4745 of this title, or the costs of the construction or acquisition of training facilities. The State and local government share of the cost of developing and carrying out training and education plans and programs may include, but shall not consist solely of, the reasonable value of facilities and of supervisory and other personal services made available by such governments. The authority provided by this section shall be employed in such a manner as to encourage innovation and allow for diversity on the part of State and local governments in developing and carrying out training and education programs for their personnel.


(b) Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; waiver; development costsAn application for a grant from a State or general local government shall be made at such time or times, and shall contain such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4743_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grants; executive certification; use restrictions; uses for non-Federal share; personnel training and education programs: innovation and diversity in development and execution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amount of grants; executive certification; use restrictions; uses for non-Federal share; personnel training and education programs: innovation and diversity in development and execution If in its judgment training is not adequately provided for under grant-in-aid or other statutes, the Office is authorized to make grants to State and general local governments for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs, on the certification of the Governor of that State, or the mayor or chief executive officer of the general local government, that the programs are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of section 4701 of this title, to train and educate their professional, administrative, and technical employees and officials. Such grants </akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4743_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; waiver; development costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application; time of making; information; terms and conditions; waiver; development costs An application for a grant from a State or general local government shall be made at such time or times, and shall contain such information, as the Office may prescribe. The Office may make a grant under subsection (a) of this section, only if the application therefor meets requirements established by this subsection unless any requirement is specifically waived by the Office. Such grant to a State, or to a general local government under subsection (c) of this section, may cover the costs of developing the program covered by the application. The program covered by the application shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4743_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Population served; amount of grants; executive certification; State grant, conditions; terms and conditions; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Population served; amount of grants; executive certification; State grant, conditions; terms and conditions; waiver A grant authorized by subsection (a) of this section may be made to a general local government, or a combination of such governments, that serve a population of fifty thousand or more, for up to 75 per centum (or, with respect to fiscal years commencing after the expiration of three years following the effective date of the grant provisions of this chapter, for up to 50 per centum) of the costs of developing and carrying out programs or projects, on the certification of the mayor(s), or chief executive officer(s), of the general local government or combination of local governments that the programs or projects are consistent with the applicable principles set forth in clauses (1)–(6) of the third paragraph of section 4701 of this title to train and educate their professional, administrative, and technical employees and officials. Such a grant may not be made— Upon the</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4743_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gubernatorial review of application; disapproval explanation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Gubernatorial review of application; disapproval explanation An application to be submitted to the Office under subsection (c) of this section shall first be submitted by the general local government or combination of such governments to the Governor for review, comments, and recommendations. The Governor may refer the application to the State office designated under subsection (b)(1) of this section for review. Comments and recommendations (if any) made as a result of the review and a statement by the general local government or combination of such governments that it has considered the comments and recommendations of the Governor shall accompany the application to the Office. The application need not be accompanied by the comments and recommendations of the Governor if the general local government or combination of such governments certifies to the Office that the application has been before the Governor for review and comment for a period of sixty days without comment by the Gov</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>