<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4831" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4831/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4831/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4831"><akn:num>4831</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of lead-based paint</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4831. Use of lead-based paint(a) Prohibition by Secretary of Health and Human Services in application to cooking, drinking, or eating utensilsThe Secretary of Health and Human Services shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any cooking utensil, drinking utensil, or eating utensil manufactured and distributed after January 13, 1971.


(b) Prohibition by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of use in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by Federal Government or with Federal assistanceThe Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the use of lead-based paint in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by the Federal Government, or with Federal assistance in any form after January 13, 1971.


(c) Prohibition by Consumer Product Safety Commission in application to toys or furniture articlesThe Consumer Product Safety Commission shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any toy or furniture article.


(Pub. L. 91–695, title IV, § 401, Jan. 13, 1971, 84 Stat. 2079; Pub. L. 93–151, § 5, Nov. 9, 1973, 87 Stat. 566; Pub. L. 94–317, title II, § 204(b), June 23, 1976, 90 Stat. 705; Pub. L. 96–88, title V, § 509(b), Oct. 17, 1979, 93 Stat. 695.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextJanuary 13, 1971, referred to in subsecs. (a) and (b), was in the original “the date of enactment of this Act”.

Amendments1976—Pub. L. 94–317 amended section generally, designating existing provisions as subsec. (a), striking out requirement of consultation with Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and provisions relating to prohibition of use of lead based paint in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by Federal Government or with Federal assistance, and adding subsecs. (</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4831_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition by Secretary of Health and Human Services in application to cooking, drinking, or eating utensils</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Prohibition by Secretary of Health and Human Services in application to cooking, drinking, or eating utensils The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any cooking utensil, drinking utensil, or eating utensil manufactured and distributed after January 13, 1971.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4831_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of use in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by Federal Government or with Federal assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Prohibition by Secretary of Housing and Urban Development of use in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by Federal Government or with Federal assistance The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall take steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the use of lead-based paint in residential structures constructed or rehabilitated by the Federal Government, or with Federal assistance in any form after January 13, 1971.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4831_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibition by Consumer Product Safety Commission in application to toys or furniture articles</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prohibition by Consumer Product Safety Commission in application to toys or furniture articles The Consumer Product Safety Commission shall take such steps and impose such conditions as may be necessary or appropriate to prohibit the application of lead-based paint to any toy or furniture article.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>