<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4851b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4851b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4851b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4851b"><akn:num>4851b</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4851b. Definitions
For the purposes of this chapter, the following definitions shall apply:(1) AbatementThe term “abatement” means any set of measures designed to permanently eliminate lead-based paint hazards in accordance with standards established by appropriate Federal agencies. Such term includes—(A) the removal of lead-based paint and lead-contaminated dust, the permanent containment or encapsulation of lead-based paint, the replacement of lead-painted surfaces or fixtures, and the removal or covering of lead contaminated soil; and

(B) all preparation, cleanup, disposal, and postabatement clearance testing activities associated with such measures.


(2) Accessible surfaceThe term “accessible surface” means an interior or exterior surface painted with lead-based paint that is accessible for a young child to mouth or chew.


(3) Certified contractorThe term “certified contractor” means—(A) a contractor, inspector, or supervisor who has completed a training program certified by the appropriate Federal agency and has met any other requirements for certification or licensure established by such agency or who has been certified by any State through a program which has been found by such Federal agency to be at least as rigorous as the Federal certification program; and

(B) workers or designers who have fully met training requirements established by the appropriate Federal agency.


(4) Contract for the purchase and sale of residential real propertyThe term “contract for the purchase and sale of residential real property” means any contract or agreement in which one party agrees to purchase an interest in real property on which there is situated 1 or more residential dwellings used or occupied, or intended to be used or occupied, in whole or in part, as the home or residence of 1 or more persons.


(5) Deteriorated paintThe term “deteriorated paint” means any interior or exterior paint that is peeling, chipping, chalking or cracking or any paint located on an int</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abatement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1) Abatement The term “abatement” means any set of measures designed to permanently eliminate lead-based paint hazards in accordance with standards established by appropriate Federal agencies. Such term includes—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:heading>Accessible surface</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(2) Accessible surface The term “accessible surface” means an interior or exterior surface painted with lead-based paint that is accessible for a young child to mouth or chew.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certified contractor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(3) Certified contractor The term “certified contractor” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract for the purchase and sale of residential real property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(4) Contract for the purchase and sale of residential real property The term “contract for the purchase and sale of residential real property” means any contract or agreement in which one party agrees to purchase an interest in real property on which there is situated 1 or more residential dwellings used or occupied, or intended to be used or occupied, in whole or in part, as the home or residence of 1 or more persons.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:heading>Deteriorated paint</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(5) Deteriorated paint The term “deteriorated paint” means any interior or exterior paint that is peeling, chipping, chalking or cracking or any paint located on an interior or exterior surface or fixture that is damaged or deteriorated.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(6) Evaluation The term “evaluation” means risk assessment, inspection, or risk assessment and inspection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally assisted housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(7) Federally assisted housing The term “federally assisted housing” means residential dwellings receiving project-based assistance under programs including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally owned housing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(8) Federally owned housing The term “federally owned housing” means residential dwellings owned or managed by a Federal agency, or for which a Federal agency is a trustee or conservator. For the purpose of this paragraph, the term “Federal agency” includes the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Farmers Home Administration, the Resolution Trust Corporation, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the General Services Administration, the Department of Defense, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of the Interior, the Department of Transportation, and any other Federal agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federally supported work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) Federally supported work The term “federally supported work” means any lead hazard evaluation or reduction activities conducted in federally owned or assisted housing or funded in whole or in part through any financial assistance program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Farmers Home Administration, or the Department of Veterans Affairs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4851b_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:heading>Friction surface</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(10) Friction surface The term “friction surface” means an interior or exterior surface that is subject to abrasion or friction, including certain window, floor, and stair surfaces.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>