<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4855" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4855/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4855/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4855"><akn:num>4855</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal implementation and insurance study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4855. Federal implementation and insurance study(a) Federal implementation studyThe Comptroller General of the United States shall assess the effectiveness of Federal enforcement and compliance with lead safety laws and regulations, including any changes needed in annual inspection procedures to identify lead-based paint hazards in units receiving assistance under subsections (b) and (o) of section 1437f of this title.


(b) Insurance studyThe Comptroller General of the United States shall assess the availability of liability insurance for owners of residential housing that contains lead-based paint and persons engaged in lead-based paint hazard evaluation and reduction activities. In carrying out the assessment, the Comptroller General shall—(1) analyze any precedents in the insurance industry for the containment and abatement of environmental hazards, such as asbestos, in federally assisted housing;

(2) provide an assessment of the recent insurance experience in the public housing lead hazard identification and reduction program; and

(3) recommend measures for increasing the availability of liability insurance to owners and contractors engaged in federally supported work.


(Pub. L. 102–550, title X, § 1056, Oct. 28, 1992, 106 Stat. 3926.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4855_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal implementation study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Federal implementation study The Comptroller General of the United States shall assess the effectiveness of Federal enforcement and compliance with lead safety laws and regulations, including any changes needed in annual inspection procedures to identify lead-based paint hazards in units receiving assistance under subsections (b) and (o) of section 1437f of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4855_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Insurance study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Insurance study The Comptroller General of the United States shall assess the availability of liability insurance for owners of residential housing that contains lead-based paint and persons engaged in lead-based paint hazard evaluation and reduction activities. In carrying out the assessment, the Comptroller General shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>