<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4904" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4904/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4904/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4904"><akn:num>4904</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of major noise sources</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4904. Identification of major noise sources(a) Development and publication of criteria(1) The Administrator shall, after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies and within nine months of October 27, 1972, develop and publish criteria with respect to noise. Such criteria shall reflect the scientific knowledge most useful in indicating the kind and extent of all identifiable effects on the public health or welfare which may be expected from differing quantities and qualities of noise.

(2) The Administrator shall, after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies and within twelve months of October 27, 1972, publish information on the levels of environmental noise the attainment and maintenance of which in defined areas under various conditions are requisite to protect the public health and welfare with an adequate margin of safety.


(b) Compilation and publication of reports on noise sources and control technologyThe Administrator shall, after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, compile and publish a report or series of reports (1) identifying products (or classes of products) which in his judgment are major sources of noise, and (2) giving information on techniques for control of noise from such products, including available data on the technology, costs, and alternative methods of noise control. The first such report shall be published not later than eighteen months after October 27, 1972.


(c) Supplemental criteria and reportsThe Administrator shall from time to time review and, as appropriate, revise or supplement any criteria or reports published under this section.


(d) Publication in Federal RegisterAny report (or revision thereof) under subsection (b)(1) identifying major noise sources shall be published in the Federal Register. The publication or revision under this section of any criteria or information on control techniques shall be announced in the Federal Register, and copies shall be made available to the general public.


(Pu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4904_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development and publication of criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Development and publication of criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4904_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compilation and publication of reports on noise sources and control technology</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compilation and publication of reports on noise sources and control technology The Administrator shall, after consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, compile and publish a report or series of reports (1) identifying products (or classes of products) which in his judgment are major sources of noise, and (2) giving information on techniques for control of noise from such products, including available data on the technology, costs, and alternative methods of noise control. The first such report shall be published not later than eighteen months after October 27, 1972.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4904_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental criteria and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Supplemental criteria and reports The Administrator shall from time to time review and, as appropriate, revise or supplement any criteria or reports published under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4904_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication in Federal Register</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication in Federal Register Any report (or revision thereof) under subsection (b)(1) identifying major noise sources shall be published in the Federal Register. The publication or revision under this section of any criteria or information on control techniques shall be announced in the Federal Register, and copies shall be made available to the general public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>