<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4905"><akn:num>4905</akn:num><akn:heading>Noise emission standards for products distributed in commerce</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4905. Noise emission standards for products distributed in commerce(a) Proposed regulations(1) The Administrator shall publish proposed regulations, meeting the requirements of subsection (c), for each product—(A) which is identified (or is part of a class identified) in any report published under section 4904(b)(1) of this title as a major source of noise,

(B) for which, in his judgment, noise emission standards are feasible, and

(C) which falls in one of the following categories:(i) Construction equipment.

(ii) Transportation equipment (including recreational vehicles and related equipment).

(iii) Any motor or engine (including any equipment of which an engine or motor is an integral part).

(iv) Electrical or electronic equipment.



(2)(A) Initial proposed regulations under paragraph (1) shall be published not later than eighteen months after October 27, 1972, and shall apply to any product described in paragraph (1) which is identified (or is a part of a class identified) as a major source of noise in any report published under section 4904(b)(1) of this title on or before the date of publication of such initial proposed regulations.

(B) In the case of any product described in paragraph (1) which is identified (or is part of a class identified) as a major source of noise in a report published under section 4904(b)(1) of this title after publication of the initial proposed regulations under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, regulations under paragraph (1) for such product shall be proposed and published by the Administrator not later than eighteen months after such report is published.


(3) After proposed regulations respecting a product have been published under paragraph (2), the Administrator shall, unless in his judgment noise emission standards are not feasible for such product, prescribe regulations, meeting the requirements of subsection (c), for such product—(A) not earlier than six months after publication of such proposed regulations, and

(B</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Proposed regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Proposed regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority to publish regulations not otherwise required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Authority to publish regulations not otherwise required The Administrator may publish proposed regulations, meeting the requirements of subsection (c), for any product for which he is not required by subsection (a) to prescribe regulations but for which, in his judgment, noise emission standards are feasible and are requisite to protect the public health and welfare. Not earlier than six months after the date of publication of such proposed regulations respecting such product, he may prescribe regulations, meeting the requirements of subsection (c), for such product.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of regulations; appropriate consideration of other standards; participation by interested persons; revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of regulations; appropriate consideration of other standards; participation by interested persons; revision</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Warranty by manufacturer of conformity of product with regulations; transfer of cost obligation from manufacturer to dealer prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Warranty by manufacturer of conformity of product with regulations; transfer of cost obligation from manufacturer to dealer prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State and local regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4905_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of notice of receipt of revision petitions and proposed revised regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Publication of notice of receipt of revision petitions and proposed revised regulations At any time after the promulgation of regulations respecting a product under this section, a State or political subdivision thereof may petition the Administrator to revise such standard on the grounds that a more stringent standard under subsection (c) of this section is necessary to protect the public health and welfare. The Administration shall publish notice of receipt of such petition in the Federal Register and shall within ninety days of receipt of such petition respond by (1) publication of proposed revised regulations in accordance with subsection (c)(3) of this section, or (2) publication in the Federal Register of a decision not to publish such proposed revised regulations at that time, together with a detailed explanation for such decision.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>