<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4917" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4917/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4917/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4917"><akn:num>4917</akn:num><akn:heading>Motor carrier noise emission standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4917. Motor carrier noise emission standards(a) Regulations; standards; consultation with Secretary of Transportation(1) Within nine months after October 27, 1972, the Administrator shall publish proposed noise emission regulations for motor carriers engaged in interstate commerce. Such proposed regulations shall include noise emission standards setting such limits on noise emissions resulting from operation of motor carriers engaged in interstate commerce which reflect the degree of noise reduction achievable through the application of the best available technology, taking into account the cost of compliance. These regulations shall be in addition to any regulations that may be proposed under section 4905 of this title.

(2) Within ninety days after the publication of such regulations as may be proposed under paragraph (1) of this subsection, and subject to the provisions of section 4915 of this title, the Administrator shall promulgate final regulations. Such regulations may be revised from time to time, in accordance with this subsection.

(3) Any standard or regulation, or revision thereof, proposed under this subsection shall be promulgated only after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation in order to assure appropriate consideration for safety and technological availability.

(4) Any regulation or revision thereof promulgated under this subsection shall take effect after such period as the Administrator finds necessary, after consultation with the Secretary of Transportation, to permit the development and application of the requisite technology, giving appropriate consideration to the cost of compliance within such period.


(b) Regulations to insure compliance with noise emission standardsThe Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to insure compliance with all standards promulgated by the Administrator under this section. The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out such regulations </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4917_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; standards; consultation with Secretary of Transportation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations; standards; consultation with Secretary of Transportation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4917_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations to insure compliance with noise emission standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations to insure compliance with noise emission standards The Secretary of Transportation, after consultation with the Administrator shall promulgate regulations to insure compliance with all standards promulgated by the Administrator under this section. The Secretary of Transportation shall carry out such regulations through the use of his powers and duties of enforcement and inspection authorized by subtitle IV of title 49 and the Department of Transportation Act. Regulations promulgated under this section shall be subject to the provisions of sections 4909, 4910, 4911, and 4915 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4917_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State and local standards and controls</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State and local standards and controls</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4917_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Motor carrier” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Motor carrier” defined For purposes of this section, the term “motor carrier” includes a motor carrier and motor private carrier as those terms are defined in section 13102 of title 49.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>