<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4953" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4953/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/4953/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_4953"><akn:num>4953</akn:num><akn:heading>Selection and assignment of volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 4953. Selection and assignment of volunteers(a) Covered projects and programsThe Director, on the receipt of applications by public or nonprofit private organizations to receive volunteers under this part, may assign volunteers selected under subsection (b) to work in appropriate projects and programs sponsored by such organizations, including work—(1) in meeting the health, education, welfare, or related needs of Indians living on reservations or Federal trust lands, of migratory and seasonal farmworkers and their families, and of residents of the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, or the Virgin Islands;

(2) in the care and rehabilitation of mentally ill, developmentally disabled, and other individuals with disabilities, especially individuals with severe disabilities;

(3) in addressing the problems of the homeless, unemployed individuals, and low-income youths;

(4) in addressing the special needs connected with alcohol and drug abuse through prevention, education, rehabilitation, treatment, and related activities, consistent with the purpose of this part;

(5) in addressing significant health care problems, including mental illness, chronic and life-threatening illnesses, and health care for homeless individuals (especially homeless children) through prevention, treatment, and community-based care activities;

(6) in connection with programs or activities authorized, supported, or of a character eligible for assistance under this chapter or the Community Service Block Grant Act [42 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.], titles VIII and X of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2991 et seq., 2996 et seq.], the Head Start Act [42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.], the Community Economic Development Act of 1981 [42 U.S.C. 9801 et seq.], or other similar Acts, in furtherance of the purpose of this subchapter;

(7) in strengthening, supplementing, and expanding efforts to address the problem </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Covered projects and programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Covered projects and programs The Director, on the receipt of applications by public or nonprofit private organizations to receive volunteers under this part, may assign volunteers selected under subsection (b) to work in appropriate projects and programs sponsored by such organizations, including work—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recruitment and placement procedures for local and national placement of volunteers; establishment, requirements, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recruitment and placement procedures for local and national placement of volunteers; establishment, requirements, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public awareness and recruit activities; dissemination of information; reimbursement of costs; coordination; obligation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public awareness and recruit activities; dissemination of information; reimbursement of costs; coordination; obligation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provision of plans to volunteers for job advancement; coordination with private industry councils or local workforce investment boards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Provision of plans to volunteers for job advancement; coordination with private industry councils or local workforce investment boards The Director shall provide each low-income community volunteer with an individual plan for job advancement or for transition to a situation leading to gainful employment. Whenever feasible, such efforts shall be coordinated with an appropriate local workforce development board established under section 3122 of title 29.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Educational and vocational counseling for volunteers; Director to provide</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Educational and vocational counseling for volunteers; Director to provide The Director may provide or arrange for educational and vocational counseling of volunteers and recent former volunteers under this part to (1) encourage them to use, in the national interest, the skills and experience which they have derived from their training and service, particularly working in combating poverty as members of the helping professions, and (2) promote the development of appropriate opportunities for the use of such skills and experience, and the placement therein of such volunteers.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions; restrictions on political activities; place of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Terms and conditions; restrictions on political activities; place of service Except as provided in subsection (e), the assignment of volunteers under this section shall be on such terms and conditions (including restrictions on political activities that appropriately recognize the special status of volunteers living among the persons or groups served by programs to which they have been assigned) as the Director may determine, including work assignments in their own or nearby communities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program or project submittal to Governor; commencement and termination of service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Program or project submittal to Governor; commencement and termination of service Volunteers under this part shall not be assigned to work in a program or project in any community unless the application for such program or project contains evidence of local support and has been submitted to the Governor or other chief executive officer of the State concerned. In the event of a timely request in writing, supported by a statement of reasons, by the Governor or other chief executive officer of the State concerned, the Director shall terminate a program or proj­ect or the assignment of a volunteer to a program or project not later than 30 days after the date such request is received by the Director, or at such later date as is agreed upon by the Director and such Governor or other chief executive officer.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interagency agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Interagency agreements The Director is encouraged to enter into agreements with other Federal agencies to use VISTA volunteers in furtherance of program objectives that are consistent with the purposes described in section 4951 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_4953_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Agreements with nonprofit organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Agreements with nonprofit organizations The Director may enter into agreements under which public and private nonprofit organizations, with sufficient financial capacity and size, pay for all or a portion of the costs of supporting the service of volunteers under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>