<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5013" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5013/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5013/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5013"><akn:num>5013</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants and contracts for volunteer service projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5013. Grants and contracts for volunteer service projects(a) Costs of project development and operationThe Director is authorized to make grants to or contracts with public and nonprofit private agencies and organizations to pay part or all of the cost of development and operation of projects (including direct payments to individuals serving under this part in the same manner as provided in section 5011(a) of this title) designed for the purpose of providing opportunities for low-income persons age 55 or older to serve as “senior companions” to persons with exceptional needs. Senior companions may provide services designed to help older persons requiring long-term care, including services to persons receiving home health care, nursing care, home-delivered meals or other nutrition services; services designed to help persons deinstitutionalized from mental hospitals, nursing homes, and other institutions; and services designed to assist persons having developmental disabilities and other special needs for companionship.


(b) Application of other lawsSubsections (d), (e), and (f) of section 5011 of this title, and such other provisions of part B as the Director determines to be necessary, shall apply to this part, except that for purposes of this part any reference in such subsections and such provisions to part B shall be deemed to be a reference to this part.


(c) Senior companion projects to assist homebound elderly(1) The Director is authorized to make grants or contracts after 11 So in original. Probably should be “under”. subsection (a) for senior companion projects to assist homebound elderly individuals to remain in their own homes and to enable institutionalized elderly individuals to return to home care settings.

(2)(A) The Director is authorized to recruit, subject to subparagraph (B), senior companion volunteer trainers who on the basis of experience (such as, doctors, nurses, home economists, social workers) will be used to train senior companion volu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5013_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Costs of project development and operation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Costs of project development and operation The Director is authorized to make grants to or contracts with public and nonprofit private agencies and organizations to pay part or all of the cost of development and operation of projects (including direct payments to individuals serving under this part in the same manner as provided in section 5011(a) of this title) designed for the purpose of providing opportunities for low-income persons age 55 or older to serve as “senior companions” to persons with exceptional needs. Senior companions may provide services designed to help older persons requiring long-term care, including services to persons receiving home health care, nursing care, home-delivered meals or other nutrition services; services designed to help persons deinstitutionalized from mental hospitals, nursing homes, and other institutions; and services designed to assist persons having developmental disabilities and other special needs for companionship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5013_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application of other laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application of other laws Subsections (d), (e), and (f) of section 5011 of this title, and such other provisions of part B as the Director determines to be necessary, shall apply to this part, except that for purposes of this part any reference in such subsections and such provisions to part B shall be deemed to be a reference to this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5013_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Senior companion projects to assist homebound elderly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Senior companion projects to assist homebound elderly</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>