<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5024" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5024/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5024/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5024"><akn:num>5024</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of locally generated contributions in National Senior Service Corps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5024. Use of locally generated contributions in National Senior Service Corps
Whenever locally generated contributions made to National Senior Service Corps projects under this subchapter are in excess of the amount required by the Director, the Director may not restrict the manner in which such contributions are expended if expenditures from locally generated contributions are not inconsistent with the provisions of this chapter.
(Pub. L. 93–113, title II, § 224, as added Pub. L. 98–288, § 16(a), May 21, 1984, 98 Stat. 194; amended Pub. L. 99–551, § 10(b)(1), Oct. 27, 1986, 100 Stat. 3077; Pub. L. 101–204, title IX, § 902(6), Dec. 7, 1989, 103 Stat. 1826; Pub. L. 103–82, title III, § 341(b)(3), Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 904; Pub. L. 103–304, § 3(b)(9), Aug. 23, 1994, 108 Stat. 1568; Pub. L. 111–13, title II, § 2146(c), Apr. 21, 2009, 123 Stat. 1589.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–113, Oct. 1, 1973, 87 Stat. 394, known as the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 4950 of this title and Tables.

Amendments2009—Pub. L. 111–13 substituted “Service” for “Volunteer” in section catchline and “Service Corps” for “Volunteer Corps” in text.
1994—Pub. L. 103–304 substituted “National Senior Volunteer Corps projects” for “volunteer projects for older Americans”.
1993—Pub. L. 103–82 amended section catchline and in text directed substitution of “National Senior Volunteer Corps projects” for “volunteer projects for Older Americans”, which could not be executed because the phrase “volunteer projects for Older Americans” did not appear in text.
1989—Pub. L. 101–204 substituted “projects” for “programs”.
1986—Pub. L. 99–551 amended directory language of Pub. L. 98–288 to correct an error, and did not involve any change in text.

Statutory Notes </akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>