<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5025/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5025/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5025"><akn:num>5025</akn:num><akn:heading>Programs of national significance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5025. Programs of national significance(a) Program grants for national problems of local concern; minimum amounts available; scope; implementation(1) With not less than one-third of the funds made available under subsection (d) in each fiscal year, the Director shall make grants under the programs authorized in parts A, B, and C to support programs that address national problems of local concern.

(2) An applicant for a grant under paragraph (1) shall determine whether the program to be supported by the grant is a program under part A, B, or C, and shall submit an application as required for such program.

(3) Each program for which a grant is received under this subsection shall be carried out in accordance with the requirements applicable to the program under part A, B, or C under which the program supported by such grant is to be carried out.

(4) To the maximum extent practicable, the Director shall ensure that not less than 25 percent of the funds appropriated under this section are used to award grants—(A) to applicants for grants under this section that are not receiving assistance from the Corporation at the time of such grant award; or

(B) to applicants from locations where no programs supported under part A, B, or C are in effect at the time of such grant award.


(5) Notwithstanding paragraph (4), if, for a fiscal year, less than 25 percent of the applicants for grants under this section are applicants described in paragraph (4), the Director may use an amount that is greater than 75 percent of the funds appropriated under this subsection to award grants to applicants that are already receiving assistance from the Corporation at the time of such grant award.


(b) Program grants for problems concerning NationThe Director shall make grants under subsection (a) to support one or more of the following programs to address problems that concern the Nation:(1) Programs that assist individuals with chronic and debilitating illnesses, such as acquired immune d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5025_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program grants for national problems of local concern; minimum amounts available; scope; implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Program grants for national problems of local concern; minimum amounts available; scope; implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5025_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Program grants for problems concerning Nation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Program grants for problems concerning Nation The Director shall make grants under subsection (a) to support one or more of the following programs to address problems that concern the Nation:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5025_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of applicant; supplemental nature of funds available</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Eligibility of applicant; supplemental nature of funds available</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5025_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of funds available for grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Amount of funds available for grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5025_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information respecting grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Dissemination of information respecting grants The Director shall widely disseminate information on grants that may be made under subsection (a) to field personnel of the Corporation and to community volunteer organizations that request such information.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>