<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5028" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5028/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5028/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5028"><akn:num>5028</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5028. Authority of Director(a) In generalThe Director is authorized to make grants to or enter into contracts with public or nonprofit organizations, including organizations funded under part A, B, or C, for the purposes of demonstrating innovative activities involving older Americans as volunteers. The Director may support under this part both volunteers receiving stipends and volunteers not receiving stipends.


(b) ActivitiesAn organization that receives a grant or enters into a contract under subsection (a) may use funds made available through the grant or contract for activities such as—(1) linking youth groups and older American organizations in volunteer activities;

(2) involving older volunteers in programs and activities different from programs and activities supported in the community; and

(3) testing whether older American volunteer programs may contribute to new objectives or certain national priorities.


(Pub. L. 93–113, title II, § 231, as added Pub. L. 103–82, title III, § 351, Sept. 21, 1993, 107 Stat. 906.)

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 1993, see section 392 of Pub. L. 103–82, set out as an Effective Date of 1993 Amendment note under section 4951 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5028_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Director is authorized to make grants to or enter into contracts with public or nonprofit organizations, including organizations funded under part A, B, or C, for the purposes of demonstrating innovative activities involving older Americans as volunteers. The Director may support under this part both volunteers receiving stipends and volunteers not receiving stipends.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5028_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Activities An organization that receives a grant or enters into a contract under subsection (a) may use funds made available through the grant or contract for activities such as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>