<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/503" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/503/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/503/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_503"><akn:num>503</akn:num><akn:heading>State laws</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 503. State laws(a) Provisions requiredThe Secretary of Labor shall make no certification for payment to any State unless he finds that the law of such State, approved by the Secretary of Labor under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act [26 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.], includes provision for—(1) Such methods of administration (including after January 1, 1940, methods relating to the establishment and maintenance of personnel standards on a merit basis, except that the Secretary of Labor shall exercise no authority with respect to the selection, tenure of office, and compensation of any individual employed in accordance with such methods) as are found by the Secretary of Labor to be reasonably calculated to insure full payment of unemployment compensation when due; and

(2) Payment of unemployment compensation solely through public employment offices or such other agencies as the Secretary of Labor may approve; and

(3) Opportunity for a fair hearing, before an impartial tribunal, for all individuals whose claims for unemployment compensation are denied; and

(4) The payment of all money received in the unemployment fund of such State (except for refunds of sums erroneously paid into such fund and except for refunds paid in accordance with the provisions of section 3305(b) of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act [26 U.S.C. 3305(b)]), immediately upon such receipt, to the Secretary of the Treasury to the credit of the unemployment trust fund 11 So in original. Probably should be “Unemployment Trust Fund”. established by section 1104 of this title; and

(5) Expenditure of all money withdrawn from an unemployment fund of such State, in the payment of unemployment compensation, exclusive of expenses of administration, and for refunds of sums erroneously paid into such fund and refunds paid in accordance with the provisions of section 3305(b) of the Federal Unemployment Tax Act [26 U.S.C. 3305(b)]: Provided, That an amount equal to the amount of employee payments into the unemployment </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Provisions required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Provisions required The Secretary of Labor shall make no certification for payment to any State unless he finds that the law of such State, approved by the Secretary of Labor under the Federal Unemployment Tax Act [26 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.], includes provision for—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to comply; payments stopped</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Failure to comply; payments stopped Whenever the Secretary of Labor, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State agency charged with the administration of the State law, finds that in the administration of the law there is— the Secretary of Labor shall notify such State agency that further payments will not be made to the State until the Secretary of Labor is satisfied that there is no longer any such denial or failure to comply. Until he is so satisfied he shall make no further certification to the Secretary of the Treasury with respect to such State: Provided, That there shall be no finding under clause (1) until the question of entitlement shall have been decided by the highest judicial authority given jurisdiction under such State law: Provided further, That any costs may be paid with respect to any claimant by a State and included as costs of administration of its law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Denial of certification; availability of records to Railroad Retirement Board; cooperation with Federal agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Denial of certification; availability of records to Railroad Retirement Board; cooperation with Federal agencies The Secretary of Labor shall make no certification for payment to any State if he finds, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing to the State agency charged with the administration of the State law—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of unemployment compensation information; coordination with supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits agencies; non-compliance of State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Disclosure of unemployment compensation information; coordination with supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits agencies; non-compliance of State agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of wage information; non-compliance of State agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Disclosure of wage information; non-compliance of State agency</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Income and eligibility verification system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Income and eligibility verification system The State agency charged with the administration of the State law shall provide that information shall be requested and exchanged for purposes of income and eligibility verification in accordance with a State system which meets the requirements of section 1320b–7 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of unemployment benefit payments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Recovery of unemployment benefit payments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure to Secretary of Health and Human Services of wage and unemployment compensation claims information; suspension by Secretary of Labor of payments to State for noncompliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disclosure to Secretary of Health and Human Services of wage and unemployment compensation claims information; suspension by Secretary of Labor of payments to State for noncompliance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to State employment records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Access to State employment records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_503_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Worker profiling</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Worker profiling</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>