<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/505" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/505/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/505/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_505"><akn:num>505</akn:num><akn:heading>Demonstration projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 505. Demonstration projects(a) State demonstration projects authorizedThe Secretary of Labor may enter into agreements, with up to 10 States that submit an application described in subsection (b), for the purpose of allowing such States to conduct demonstration projects to test and evaluate measures designed—(1) to expedite the reemployment of individuals who have established a benefit year and are otherwise eligible to claim unemployment compensation under the State law of such State; or

(2) to improve the effectiveness of a State in carrying out its State law with respect to reemployment.


(b) Application for demonstration project; required contentThe Governor of any State desiring to conduct a demonstration project under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Labor. Any such application shall include—(1) a general description of the proposed demonstration project, including the authority (under the laws of the State) for the measures to be tested, as well as the period of time during which such demonstration project would be conducted;

(2) if a waiver under subsection (c) is requested, a statement describing the specific aspects of the project to which the waiver would apply and the reasons why such waiver is needed;

(3) a description of the goals and the expected programmatic outcomes of the demonstration project, including how the project would contribute to the objective described in subsection (a)(1), subsection (a)(2), or both;

(4) assurances (accompanied by supporting analysis) that the demonstration project would operate for a period of at least 1 calendar year and not result in any increased net costs to the State’s account in the Unemployment Trust Fund;

(5) a description of the manner in which the State—(A) will conduct an impact evaluation, using a methodology appropriate to determine the effects of the demonstration project, including on individual skill levels, earnings, and employment retention; and

(B) will determine </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>State demonstration projects authorized</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) State demonstration projects authorized The Secretary of Labor may enter into agreements, with up to 10 States that submit an application described in subsection (b), for the purpose of allowing such States to conduct demonstration projects to test and evaluate measures designed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application for demonstration project; required content</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application for demonstration project; required content The Governor of any State desiring to conduct a demonstration project under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary of Labor. Any such application shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of certain requirements allowed</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of certain requirements allowed The Secretary of Labor may waive any of the requirements of section 3304(a)(4) of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or of paragraph (1) or (5) of section 503(a) of this title, to the extent and for the period the Secretary of Labor considers necessary to enable the State to carry out a demonstration project under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time for demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time for demonstration project A demonstration project under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on activities Activities that may be pursued under a demonstration project under this section are limited to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification of approval or denial of application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Notification of approval or denial of application The Secretary of Labor shall, in the case of any State for which an application is submitted under subsection (b)— Public notice under paragraph (2) may be provided through the Internet or other appropriate means. Any application under this section that has not been denied within the 30-day period described in paragraph (1) shall be deemed approved, and public notice of any approval under this sentence shall be provided within 10 days thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination of demonstration project</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Termination of demonstration project The Secretary of Labor may terminate a demonstration project under this section if the Secretary determines that the State has violated the substantive terms or conditions of the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_505_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Funding Funding certified under section 502(a) of this title may be used for an approved demonstration project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>