<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/506" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/506/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/506/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_506"><akn:num>506</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to States for reemployment services and eligibility assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 506. Grants to States for reemployment services and eligibility assessments(a) In generalThe Secretary of Labor (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall award grants under this section for a fiscal year to eligible States to conduct a program of reemployment services and eligibility assessments for claimants for regular compensation, including claimants referred to reemployment services as described in section 503(j) of this title, for weeks in such fiscal year for which such claimants receive unemployment compensation.


(b) PurposesThe purposes of this section are to accomplish the following goals:(1) To improve employment outcomes of individuals that receive unemployment compensation and to reduce the average duration of receipt of such compensation through employment.

(2) To strengthen program integrity and reduce improper payments of unemployment compensation by States through the detection and prevention of such payments to individuals who are not eligible for such compensation.

(3) To promote alignment with the broader vision of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.) of increased program integration and service delivery for job seekers, including claimants for unemployment compensation.

(4) To establish reemployment services and eligibility assessments as an entry point for individuals receiving unemployment compensation into other workforce system partner programs.


(c) Evidence-based standards(1) In generalIn carrying out a State program of reemployment services and eligibility assessments using grant funds awarded to the State under this section, a State shall use such funds only for interventions demonstrated to reduce the number of weeks for which program participants receive unemployment compensation by improving employment outcomes for program participants.


(2) Expanding evidence-based interventionsIn addition to the requirement imposed by paragraph (1), a State shall—(A) for fiscal years 2023 and 20</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary of Labor (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”) shall award grants under this section for a fiscal year to eligible States to conduct a program of reemployment services and eligibility assessments for claimants for regular compensation, including claimants referred to reemployment services as described in section 503(j) of this title, for weeks in such fiscal year for which such claimants receive unemployment compensation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purposes The purposes of this section are to accomplish the following goals:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence-based standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Evidence-based standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Evaluations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) State plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notification to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Notification to Congress Not later than 90 days prior to making any changes to the allocation formula or the criteria developed pursuant to subsection (f)(5)(A), the Secretary shall submit to Congress, including to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, a notification of any such change.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplement not supplant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Supplement not supplant Funds made available to carry out this section shall be used to supplement the level of Federal, State, and local public funds that, in the absence of such availability, would be expended to provide reemployment services and eligibility assessments to individuals receiving unemployment compensation, and in no case to supplant such Federal, State, or local public funds.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_506_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>