<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5102" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5102/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5102/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5102"><akn:num>5102</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory board on child abuse and neglect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5102. Advisory board on child abuse and neglect(a) AppointmentThe Secretary may appoint an advisory board to make recommendations to the Secretary and to the appropriate committees of Congress concerning specific issues relating to child abuse and neglect.


(b) Solicitation of nominationsThe Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for the appointment of members of the advisory board under subsection (a).


(c) CompositionIn establishing the board under subsection (a), the Secretary shall appoint members from the general public who are individuals knowledgeable in child abuse and neglect prevention, intervention, treatment, or research, and with due consideration to representation of ethnic or racial minorities and diverse geographic areas, and who represent—(1) law (including the judiciary);

(2) psychology (including child development);

(3) social services (including child protective services);

(4) health care providers (including pediatricians);

(5) State and local government;

(6) organizations providing services to disabled persons;

(7) organizations providing services to adolescents;

(8) teachers;

(9) parent self-help organizations;

(10) parents’ groups;

(11) voluntary groups;

(12) family rights groups;

(13) children’s rights advocates; and

(14) Indian tribes or tribal organizations.


(d) VacanciesAny vacancy in the membership of the board shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.


(e) Election of officersThe board shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson at its first meeting from among the members of the board.


(f) DutiesNot later than 1 year after the establishment of the board under subsection (a), the board shall submit to the Secretary and the appropriate committees of Congress a report, or interim report, containing—(1) recommendations on coordinating Federal, State, tribal, and local child abuse and neglect activities with similar activities at the Federa</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appointment The Secretary may appoint an advisory board to make recommendations to the Secretary and to the appropriate committees of Congress concerning specific issues relating to child abuse and neglect.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Solicitation of nominations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Solicitation of nominations The Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for the appointment of members of the advisory board under subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Composition In establishing the board under subsection (a), the Secretary shall appoint members from the general public who are individuals knowledgeable in child abuse and neglect prevention, intervention, treatment, or research, and with due consideration to representation of ethnic or racial minorities and diverse geographic areas, and who represent—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vacancies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Vacancies Any vacancy in the membership of the board shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Election of officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Election of officers The board shall elect a chairperson and vice-chairperson at its first meeting from among the members of the board.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5102_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Duties Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the board under subsection (a), the board shall submit to the Secretary and the appropriate committees of Congress a report, or interim report, containing—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>