<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5106f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5106f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5106f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5106f"><akn:num>5106f</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5106f. Reports(a) Coordination effortsNot later than 1 year after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on efforts to coordinate the objectives and activities of agencies and organizations that are responsible for programs and activities related to child abuse and neglect. Not later than 3 years after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to those committees a second report on such efforts during the 3-year period following December 20, 2010. Not later than 5 years after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to those committees a third report on such efforts during the 5-year period following December 20, 2010.


(b) Effectiveness of State programs and technical assistanceNot later than 2 years after December 20, 2010, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report evaluating the effectiveness of programs receiving assistance under section 5106a of this title in achieving the objectives of section 5106a of this title.


(c) Study and report relating to citizen review panels(1) In generalThe Secretary shall conduct a study to determine the effectiveness of citizen review panels, established under section 5106a(c) of this title, in achieving the stated function of such panels under section 5106a(c)(4)(A) of this title of—(A) examining the policies, procedures, and practices of State and local child protection agencies; and

(B) evaluating the extent to which such State and local child protection agencies are fulfilling their child protection responsibilities, as described in clauses (i) through (iii) of section 5106a(c)(4)(A) of this title.


(2) Content of studyThe study described in paragraph (1) shall be completed in a manner</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination efforts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Coordination efforts Not later than 1 year after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on efforts to coordinate the objectives and activities of agencies and organizations that are responsible for programs and activities related to child abuse and neglect. Not later than 3 years after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to those committees a second report on such efforts during the 3-year period following December 20, 2010. Not later than 5 years after December 20, 2010, the Secretary shall submit to those committees a third report on such efforts during the 5-year period following December 20, 2010.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effectiveness of State programs and technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Effectiveness of State programs and technical assistance Not later than 2 years after December 20, 2010, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report evaluating the effectiveness of programs receiving assistance under section 5106a of this title in achieving the objectives of section 5106a of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report relating to citizen review panels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Study and report relating to citizen review panels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5106f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study and report relating to immunity from prosecution for professional consultation in suspected and known instances of child abuse and neglect</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Study and report relating to immunity from prosecution for professional consultation in suspected and known instances of child abuse and neglect</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>