<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5116b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5116b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5116b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5116b"><akn:num>5116b</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount of grant</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5116b. Amount of grant(a) ReservationThe Secretary shall reserve 1 percent of the amount appropriated under section 5116i 11 See References in Text note below. of this title for a fiscal year to make allotments to Indian tribes and tribal organizations and migrant programs.


(b) Remaining amounts(1) In generalThe Secretary shall allot the amount appropriated under section 5116i 1 of this title for a fiscal year and remaining after the reservation under subsection (a) among the States as follows:(A) 70 percent70 percent of such amount appropriated shall be allotted among the States by allotting to each State an amount that bears the same proportion to such amount appropriated as the number of children under the age of 18 residing in the State bears to the total number of children under the age of 18 residing in all States (except that no State shall receive less than $175,000 under this subparagraph).


(B) 30 percent30 percent of such amount appropriated shall be allotted among the States by allotting to each State an amount that bears the same proportion to such amount appropriated as the amount of private, State or other non-Federal funds leveraged and directed through the currently designated State lead entity in the preceding fiscal year bears to the aggregate of the amounts leveraged by all States from private, State, or other non-Federal sources and directed through the current lead entity of such States in the preceding fiscal year.



(2) Additional requirementThe Secretary shall provide allotments under paragraph (1) to the State lead entity.



(c) AllocationFunds allotted to a State under this section—(1) shall be for a 3-year period; and

(2) shall be provided by the Secretary to the State on an annual basis, as described in subsection (b).


(Pub. L. 93–247, title II, § 203, as added Pub. L. 104–235, title I, § 121, Oct. 3, 1996, 110 Stat. 3082; amended Pub. L. 108–36, title I, § 123, June 25, 2003, 117 Stat. 815; Pub. L. 111–320, title I, § 134, Dec</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Reservation The Secretary shall reserve 1 percent of the amount appropriated under section 5116i 11 See References in Text note below. of this title for a fiscal year to make allotments to Indian tribes and tribal organizations and migrant programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Remaining amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Remaining amounts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5116b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation Funds allotted to a State under this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>