<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5133" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5133/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5133/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5133"><akn:num>5133</akn:num><akn:heading>Predisaster hazard mitigation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5133. Predisaster hazard mitigation(a) Definition of small impoverished communityIn this section, the term “small impoverished community” means a community of 3,000 or fewer individuals that is economically disadvantaged, as determined by the State in which the community is located and based on criteria established by the President.


(b) Establishment of programThe President may establish a program to provide technical and financial assistance to States and local governments to assist in the implementation of predisaster hazard mitigation measures that are cost-effective and are designed to reduce injuries, loss of life, and damage and destruction of property, including damage to critical services and facilities under the jurisdiction of the States or local governments.


(c) Approval by PresidentIf the President determines that a State or local government has identified natural disaster hazards in areas under its jurisdiction and has demonstrated the ability to form effective public-private natural disaster hazard mitigation partnerships, the President, using amounts in the National Public Infrastructure Predisaster Mitigation Fund established under subsection (i) (referred to in this section as the “Fund”), may provide technical and financial assistance to the State or local government to be used in accordance with subsection (e).


(d) State recommendations(1) In general(A) RecommendationsThe Governor of each State may recommend to the President not fewer than five local governments to receive assistance under this section.


(B) Deadline for submissionThe recommendations under subparagraph (A) shall be submitted to the President not later than October 1, 2001, and each October 1st thereafter or such later date in the year as the President may establish.


(C) CriteriaIn making recommendations under subparagraph (A), a Governor shall consider the criteria specified in subsection (g).



(2) Use(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), in providing </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of small impoverished community</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of small impoverished community In this section, the term “small impoverished community” means a community of 3,000 or fewer individuals that is economically disadvantaged, as determined by the State in which the community is located and based on criteria established by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of program The President may establish a program to provide technical and financial assistance to States and local governments to assist in the implementation of predisaster hazard mitigation measures that are cost-effective and are designed to reduce injuries, loss of life, and damage and destruction of property, including damage to critical services and facilities under the jurisdiction of the States or local governments.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval by President</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Approval by President If the President determines that a State or local government has identified natural disaster hazards in areas under its jurisdiction and has demonstrated the ability to form effective public-private natural disaster hazard mitigation partnerships, the President, using amounts in the National Public Infrastructure Predisaster Mitigation Fund established under subsection (i) (referred to in this section as the “Fund”), may provide technical and financial assistance to the State or local government to be used in accordance with subsection (e).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State recommendations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State recommendations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of technical and financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Uses of technical and financial assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Allocation of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for assistance awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Criteria for assistance awards In determining whether to provide technical and financial assistance to a State or local government under this section, the President shall provide financial assistance only in States that have received a major disaster declaration in the previous 7 years, or to any Indian tribal government located partially or entirely within the boundaries of such States, and take into account—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal share</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Federal share</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>National public infrastructure predisaster mitigation assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) National public infrastructure predisaster mitigation assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5133_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multihazard advisory maps</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Multihazard advisory maps</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>