<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5135" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5135/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5135/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5135"><akn:num>5135</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants to entities for establishment of hazard mitigation revolving loan funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5135. Grants to entities for establishment of hazard mitigation revolving loan funds(a) General authority(1) In generalThe Administrator may enter into agreements with eligible entities to make capitalization grants to such entities for the establishment of hazard mitigation revolving loan funds (referred to in this section as “entity loan funds”) for providing funding assistance to local governments to carry out eligible projects under this section to reduce disaster risks for homeowners, businesses, nonprofit organizations, and communities in order to decrease—(A) the loss of life and property;

(B) the cost of insurance; and

(C) Federal disaster payments.


(2) AgreementsAny agreement entered into under this section shall require the participating entity to—(A) comply with the requirements of this section; and

(B) use accounting, audit, and fiscal procedures conforming to generally accepted accounting standards.



(b) Application(1) In generalTo be eligible to receive a capitalization grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application that includes the following:(A) Project proposals comprised of local government hazard mitigation projects, on the condition that the entity provides public notice not less than 6 weeks prior to the submission of an application.

(B) An assessment of recurring major disaster vulnerabilities impacting the entity that demonstrates a risk to life and property.

(C) A description of how the hazard mitigation plan of the entity has or has not taken the vulnerabilities described in subparagraph (B) into account.

(D) A description about how the projects described in subparagraph (A) could conform with the hazard mitigation plan of the entity and of the unit of local government.

(E) A proposal of the systematic and regional approach to achieve resilience in a vulnerable area, including impacts to river basins, river corridors, watersheds, estuaries, bays, coastal regions, micro-basins, micro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Application</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Entity loan fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Entity loan fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Apportionment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Apportionment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental review of revolving loan fund projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental review of revolving loan fund projects The Administrator may delegate to a participating entity all of the responsibilities for environmental review, decision making, and action pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), and other applicable Federal environmental laws including the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.) and the National Historic Preservation Act of 1966 (54 U.S.C. 300101 et seq.) that would apply to the Administrator were the Administrator to undertake projects under this section as Federal projects so long as the participating entity carries out such responsibilities in the same manner and subject to the same requirements as if the Administrator carried out such responsibilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Use of funds</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Intended use plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Intended use plans</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits, reports, publications, and oversight</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Audits, reports, publications, and oversight</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations or guidance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Regulations or guidance The Administrator shall issue such regulations or guidance as are necessary to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5135_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Waiver authority Until such time as the Administrator issues final regulations to implement this section, the Administrator may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>