<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5150" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5150/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5150/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5150"><akn:num>5150</akn:num><akn:heading>Use of local firms and individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5150. Use of local firms and individuals(a) Contracts or agreements with private entities(1) In generalIn the expenditure of Federal funds for debris clearance, distribution of supplies, reconstruction, and other major disaster or emergency assistance activities which may be carried out by contract or agreement with private organizations, firms, or individuals, preference shall be given, to the extent feasible and practicable, to those organizations, firms, and individuals residing or doing business primarily in the area affected by such major disaster or emergency.


(2) ConstructionThis subsection shall not be considered to restrict the use of Department of Defense resources under this chapter in the provision of assistance in a major disaster.


(3) Specific geographic areaIn carrying out this section, a contract or agreement may be set aside for award based on a specific geographic area.



(b) Implementation(1) Contracts not to entities in areaAny expenditure of Federal funds for debris clearance, distribution of supplies, reconstruction, and other major disaster or emergency assistance activities which may be carried out by contract or agreement with private organizations, firms, or individuals, not awarded to an organization, firm, or individual residing or doing business primarily in the area affected by such major disaster shall be justified in writing in the contract file.


(2) TransitionFollowing the declaration of an emergency or major disaster, an agency performing response, relief, and reconstruction activities shall transition work performed under contracts in effect on the date on which the President declares the emergency or major disaster to organizations, firms, and individuals residing or doing business primarily in any area affected by the major disaster or emergency, unless the head of such agency determines that it is not feasible or practicable to do so.


(3) Formulation of requirementsThe head of a Federal agency, as feasible and practic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5150_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts or agreements with private entities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contracts or agreements with private entities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5150_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5150_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prior contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Prior contracts Nothing in this section shall be construed to require any Federal agency to breach or renegotiate any contract in effect before the occurrence of a major disaster or emergency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>