<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5151" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5151/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5151/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5151"><akn:num>5151</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination in disaster assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5151. Nondiscrimination in disaster assistance(a) Regulations for equitable and impartial relief operationsThe President shall issue, and may alter and amend, such regulations as may be necessary for the guidance of personnel carrying out Federal assistance functions at the site of a major disaster or emergency. Such regulations shall include provisions for insuring that the distribution of supplies, the processing of applications, and other relief and assistance activities shall be accomplished in an equitable and impartial manner, without discrimination on the grounds of race, color, religion, nationality, sex, age, disability, English proficiency, or economic status.


(b) Compliance with regulations as prerequisite to participation by other bodies in relief operationsAs a condition of participation in the distribution of assistance or supplies under this chapter or of receiving assistance under this chapter, governmental bodies and other organizations shall be required to comply with regulations relating to nondiscrimination promulgated by the President, and such other regulations applicable to activities within an area affected by a major disaster or emergency as he deems necessary for the effective coordination of relief efforts.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title III, § 308, formerly § 311, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 150; renumbered § 308 and amended Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 105(f), Nov. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 4691; Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 689a, Oct. 4, 2006, 120 Stat. 1449.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–288, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 143. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5121 of this title and Tables.

Prior ProvisionsA prior section 308 of Pub. L. 93–288 was renumbered section 305 by Pub. L. 100–707 and is classified to section 5148 of this title.

Amendments2006—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 109–295 inserted “disab</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5151_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations for equitable and impartial relief operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Regulations for equitable and impartial relief operations The President shall issue, and may alter and amend, such regulations as may be necessary for the guidance of personnel carrying out Federal assistance functions at the site of a major disaster or emergency. Such regulations shall include provisions for insuring that the distribution of supplies, the processing of applications, and other relief and assistance activities shall be accomplished in an equitable and impartial manner, without discrimination on the grounds of race, color, religion, nationality, sex, age, disability, English proficiency, or economic status.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5151_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with regulations as prerequisite to participation by other bodies in relief operations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Compliance with regulations as prerequisite to participation by other bodies in relief operations As a condition of participation in the distribution of assistance or supplies under this chapter or of receiving assistance under this chapter, governmental bodies and other organizations shall be required to comply with regulations relating to nondiscrimination promulgated by the President, and such other regulations applicable to activities within an area affected by a major disaster or emergency as he deems necessary for the effective coordination of relief efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>