<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5154a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5154a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5154a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5154a"><akn:num>5154a</akn:num><akn:heading>Prohibited flood disaster assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5154a. Prohibited flood disaster assistance(a) General prohibitionNotwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal disaster relief assistance made available in a flood disaster area may be used to make a payment (including any loan assistance payment) to a person for repair, replacement, or restoration for damage to any personal, residential, or commercial property if that person at any time has received flood disaster assistance that was conditional on the person first having obtained flood insurance under applicable Federal law and subsequently having failed to obtain and maintain flood insurance as required under applicable Federal law on such property.


(b) Transfer of property(1) Duty to notifyIn the event of the transfer of any property described in paragraph (3), the transferor shall, not later than the date on which such transfer occurs, notify the transferee in writing of the requirements to—(A) obtain flood insurance in accordance with applicable Federal law with respect to such property, if the property is not so insured as of the date on which the property is transferred; and

(B) maintain flood insurance in accordance with applicable Federal law with respect to such property.


Such written notification shall be contained in documents evidencing the transfer of ownership of the property.

(2) Failure to notifyIf a transferor described in paragraph (1) fails to make a notification in accordance with such paragraph and, subsequent to the transfer of the property—(A) the transferee fails to obtain or maintain flood insurance in accordance with applicable Federal law with respect to the property,

(B) the property is damaged by a flood disaster, and

(C) Federal disaster relief assistance is provided for the repair, replacement, or restoration of the property as a result of such damage,


the transferor shall be required to reimburse the Federal Government in an amount equal to the amount of the Federal disaster relief assistance provided with resp</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5154a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General prohibition Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal disaster relief assistance made available in a flood disaster area may be used to make a payment (including any loan assistance payment) to a person for repair, replacement, or restoration for damage to any personal, residential, or commercial property if that person at any time has received flood disaster assistance that was conditional on the person first having obtained flood insurance under applicable Federal law and subsequently having failed to obtain and maintain flood insurance as required under applicable Federal law on such property.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5154a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer of property</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5154a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5154a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Flood disaster area” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) “Flood disaster area” defined For purposes of this section, the term “flood disaster area” means an area with respect to which—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5154a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effective date This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to disasters declared after September 23, 1994.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>