<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5155" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5155/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5155/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5155"><akn:num>5155</akn:num><akn:heading>Duplication of benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5155. Duplication of benefits(a) General prohibitionThe President, in consultation with the head of each Federal agency administering any program providing financial assistance to persons, business concerns, or other entities suffering losses as a result of a major disaster or emergency, shall assure that no such person, business concern, or other entity will receive such assistance with respect to any part of such loss as to which he has received financial assistance under any other program or from insurance or any other source.


(b) Special rules(1) LimitationThis section shall not prohibit the provision of Federal assistance to a person who is or may be entitled to receive benefits for the same purposes from another source if such person has not received such other benefits by the time of application for Federal assistance and if such person agrees to repay all duplicative assistance to the agency providing the Federal assistance.


(2) ProceduresThe President shall establish such procedures as the President considers necessary to ensure uniformity in preventing duplication of benefits.


(3) Effect of partial benefitsReceipt of partial benefits for a major disaster or emergency shall not preclude provision of additional Federal assistance for any part of a loss or need for which benefits have not been provided.



(c) Recovery of duplicative benefitsA person receiving Federal assistance for a major disaster or emergency shall be liable to the United States to the extent that such assistance duplicates benefits available to the person for the same purpose from another source. The agency which provided the duplicative assistance shall collect such duplicative assistance from the recipient in accordance with chapter 37 of title 31, relating to debt collection, when the head of such agency considers it to be in the best interest of the Federal Government.


(d) Assistance not incomeFederal major disaster and emergency assistance provided to individuals and famili</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5155_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General prohibition</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General prohibition The President, in consultation with the head of each Federal agency administering any program providing financial assistance to persons, business concerns, or other entities suffering losses as a result of a major disaster or emergency, shall assure that no such person, business concern, or other entity will receive such assistance with respect to any part of such loss as to which he has received financial assistance under any other program or from insurance or any other source.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5155_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Special rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Special rules</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5155_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recovery of duplicative benefits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Recovery of duplicative benefits A person receiving Federal assistance for a major disaster or emergency shall be liable to the United States to the extent that such assistance duplicates benefits available to the person for the same purpose from another source. The agency which provided the duplicative assistance shall collect such duplicative assistance from the recipient in accordance with chapter 37 of title 31, relating to debt collection, when the head of such agency considers it to be in the best interest of the Federal Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5155_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance not income</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Assistance not income Federal major disaster and emergency assistance provided to individuals and families under this chapter, and comparable disaster assistance provided by States, local governments, and disaster assistance organizations, shall not be considered as income or a resource when determining eligibility for or benefit levels under federally funded income assistance or resource-tested benefit programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>