<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5165f"><akn:num>5165f</akn:num><akn:heading>National Urban Search and Rescue Response System</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5165f. National Urban Search and Rescue Response System(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the following definitions shall apply:(1) AdministratorThe term “Administrator” means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.


(2) AgencyThe term “Agency” means the Federal Emergency Management Agency.


(3) HazardThe term “hazard” has the meaning given the term in section 5195a of this title.


(4) Nonemployee System memberThe term “nonemployee System member” means a System member not employed by a sponsoring agency or participating agency.


(5) Participating agencyThe term “participating agency” means a State or local government, nonprofit organization, or private organization that has executed an agreement with a sponsoring agency to participate in the System.


(6) Sponsoring agencyThe term “sponsoring agency” means a State or local government that is the sponsor of a task force designated by the Administrator to participate in the System.


(7) SystemThe term “System” means the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System to be administered under this section.


(8) System memberThe term “System member” means an individual who is not a full-time employee of the Federal Government and who serves on a task force or on a System management or other technical team.


(9) Task forceThe term “task force” means an urban search and rescue team designated by the Administrator to participate in the System.



(b) General authoritySubject to the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall continue to administer the emergency response system known as the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System.


(c) FunctionsIn administering the System, the Administrator shall provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources to assist States and local governments in responding to hazards.


(d) Task forces(1) DesignationThe Administrator shall designate task forces to participate in the System. The Administration shall determine t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the following definitions shall apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) General authority Subject to the requirements of this section, the Administrator shall continue to administer the emergency response system known as the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions In administering the System, the Administrator shall provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources to assist States and local governments in responding to hazards.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Task forces</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Task forces</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management and technical teams</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Management and technical teams The Administrator shall maintain such management teams and other technical teams as the Administrator determines are necessary to administer the System.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appointment of System members into Federal service</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Appointment of System members into Federal service</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compensation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Compensation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Personal injury, illness, disability, or death</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Personal injury, illness, disability, or death</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Liability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Liability A System member appointed into Federal service under subsection (f)(1), while acting within the scope of the appointment, shall be considered to be an employee of the Federal Government under section 1346(b) of title 28 and chapter 171 of that title, relating to tort claims procedure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165f_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment and reemployment rights</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Employment and reemployment rights With respect to a System member who is not a regular full-time employee of a sponsoring agency or participating agency, the following terms and conditions apply:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>