<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5165b"><akn:num>5165b</akn:num><akn:heading>Management costs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5165b. Management costs(a) Definition of management costIn this section, the term “management cost” includes any indirect cost, any direct administrative cost, and any other administrative expense associated with a specific project under a major disaster, emergency, or disaster preparedness or mitigation activity or measure.


(b) Establishment of management cost rates(1) In generalNotwithstanding any other provision of law (including any administrative rule or guidance), the President shall by regulation implement management cost rates, for grantees and subgrantees, that shall be used to determine contributions under this chapter for management costs.


(2) Specific management costsThe Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall provide the following percentage rates, in addition to the eligible project costs, to cover direct and indirect costs of administering the following programs:(A) Hazard mitigationA grantee under section 5170c of this title may be reimbursed not more than 15 percent of the total amount of the grant award under such section of which not more than 10 percent may be used by the grantee and 5 percent by the subgrantee for such costs.


(B) Public assistanceA grantee under sections 5170b, 5172, 5173, and 5192 of this title may be reimbursed not more than 12 percent of the total award amount under such sections, of which not more than 7 percent may be used by the grantee and 5 percent by the subgrantee for such costs.




(c) ReviewThe President shall review the management cost rates established under subsection (b) not later than 3 years after the date of establishment of the rates and periodically thereafter.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title III, § 324, as added Pub. L. 106–390, title II, § 202(a), Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1560; amended Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1215, Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3449.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–288</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of management cost</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of management cost In this section, the term “management cost” includes any indirect cost, any direct administrative cost, and any other administrative expense associated with a specific project under a major disaster, emergency, or disaster preparedness or mitigation activity or measure.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of management cost rates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment of management cost rates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Review The President shall review the management cost rates established under subsection (b) not later than 3 years after the date of establishment of the rates and periodically thereafter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>