<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5165a"><akn:num>5165a</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum standards for public and private structures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5165a. Minimum standards for public and private structures(a) In generalAs a condition of receipt of a disaster loan or grant under this chapter—(1) the recipient shall carry out any repair or construction to be financed with the loan or grant in accordance with applicable standards of safety, decency, and sanitation and in conformity with applicable codes, specifications, and standards; and

(2) the President may require safe land use and construction practices, after adequate consultation with appropriate State and local government officials.


(b) Evidence of complianceA recipient of a disaster loan or grant under this chapter shall provide such evidence of compliance with this section as the President may require by regulation.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title III, § 323, as added Pub. L. 106–390, title I, § 104(a), Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1559.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis chapter, referred to in text, was in the original “this Act”, meaning Pub. L. 93–288, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 143. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5121 of this title and Tables.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general As a condition of receipt of a disaster loan or grant under this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evidence of compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evidence of compliance A recipient of a disaster loan or grant under this chapter shall provide such evidence of compliance with this section as the President may require by regulation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>