<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5165d"><akn:num>5165d</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of Small State and Rural Advocate</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5165d. Designation of Small State and Rural Advocate(a) In generalThe President shall designate in the Federal Emergency Management Agency a Small State and Rural Advocate.


(b) ResponsibilitiesThe Small State and Rural Advocate shall be an advocate for the fair treatment of small States and rural communities in the provision of assistance under this chapter.


(c) DutiesThe Small State and Rural Advocate shall—(1) participate in the disaster declaration process under section 5170 of this title and the emergency declaration process under section 5191 of this title, to ensure that the needs of rural communities are being addressed;

(2) assist small population States in the preparation of requests for major disaster or emergency declarations;

(3) assist States in the collection and presentation of material in the disaster or emergency declaration request relevant to demonstrate severe localized impacts within the State for a specific incident, including—(A) the per capita personal income by local area, as calculated by the Bureau of Economic Analysis;

(B) the disaster impacted population profile, as reported by the Bureau of the Census, including—(i) the percentage of the population for whom poverty status is determined;

(ii) the percentage of the population already receiving Government assistance such as Supplemental Security Income and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program benefits;

(iii) the pre-disaster unemployment rate;

(iv) the percentage of the population that is 65 years old and older;

(v) the percentage of the population 18 years old and younger;

(vi) the percentage of the population with a disability;

(vii) the percentage of the population who speak a language other than English and speak English less than “very well”; and

(viii) any unique considerations regarding American Indian and Alaskan Native Tribal populations raised in the State’s request for a major disaster declaration that may not be reflected in the data points referenced in th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President shall designate in the Federal Emergency Management Agency a Small State and Rural Advocate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Responsibilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Responsibilities The Small State and Rural Advocate shall be an advocate for the fair treatment of small States and rural communities in the provision of assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Duties The Small State and Rural Advocate shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>