<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5165/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5165"><akn:num>5165</akn:num><akn:heading>Mitigation planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5165. Mitigation planning(a) Requirement of mitigation planAs a condition of receipt of an increased Federal share for hazard mitigation measures under subsection (e), a State, local, or tribal government shall develop and submit for approval to the President a mitigation plan that outlines processes for identifying the natural hazards, risks, and vulnerabilities of the area under the jurisdiction of the government.


(b) Local and tribal plansEach mitigation plan developed by a local or tribal government shall—(1) describe actions to mitigate hazards, risks, and vulnerabilities identified under the plan; and

(2) establish a strategy to implement those actions.


(c) State plansThe State process of development of a mitigation plan under this section shall—(1) identify the natural hazards, risks, and vulnerabilities of areas in the State;

(2) support development of local mitigation plans;

(3) provide for technical assistance to local and tribal governments for mitigation planning; and

(4) identify and prioritize mitigation actions that the State will support, as resources become available.


(d) Funding(1) In generalFederal contributions under section 5170c of this title may be used to fund the development and updating of mitigation plans under this section.


(2) Maximum Federal contributionWith respect to any mitigation plan, a State, local, or tribal government may use an amount of Federal contributions under section 5170c of this title not to exceed 7 percent of the amount of such contributions available to the government as of a date determined by the government.



(e) Increased Federal share for hazard mitigation measures(1) In generalIf, at the time of the declaration of a major disaster or event under section 5187 of this title, a State has in effect an approved mitigation plan under this section, the President may increase to 20 percent, with respect to the major disaster or event under section 5187 of this title, the maximum percentage specified in t</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of mitigation plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirement of mitigation plan As a condition of receipt of an increased Federal share for hazard mitigation measures under subsection (e), a State, local, or tribal government shall develop and submit for approval to the President a mitigation plan that outlines processes for identifying the natural hazards, risks, and vulnerabilities of the area under the jurisdiction of the government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local and tribal plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Local and tribal plans Each mitigation plan developed by a local or tribal government shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) State plans The State process of development of a mitigation plan under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5165_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Increased Federal share for hazard mitigation measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Increased Federal share for hazard mitigation measures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>