<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5171" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5171/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5171/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5171"><akn:num>5171</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5171. Federal facilities(a) Repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of United States facilitiesThe President may authorize any Federal agency to repair, reconstruct, restore, or replace any facility owned by the United States and under the jurisdiction of such agency which is damaged or destroyed by any major disaster if he determines that such repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement is of such importance and urgency that it cannot reasonably be deferred pending the enactment of specific authorizing legislation or the making of an appropriation for such purposes, or the obtaining of congressional committee approval.


(b) Availability of funds appropriated to agency for repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of agency facilitiesIn order to carry out the provisions of this section, such repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement may be begun notwithstanding a lack or an insufficiency of funds appropriated for such purpose, where such lack or insufficiency can be remedied by the transfer, in accordance with law, of funds appropriated to that agency for another purpose.


(c) Steps for mitigation of hazardsIn implementing this section, Federal agencies shall evaluate the natural hazards to which these facilities are exposed and shall take appropriate action to mitigate such hazards, including safe land-use and construction practices, in accordance with standards prescribed by the President.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title IV, § 405, formerly § 401, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 153; renumbered § 405, Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 106(a)(2), Nov. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 4696.)

Editorial Notes
Prior ProvisionsA prior section 405 of Pub. L. 93–288 was classified to section 5175 of this title prior to repeal by Pub. L. 100–707.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of United States facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of United States facilities The President may authorize any Federal agency to repair, reconstruct, restore, or replace any facility owned by the United States and under the jurisdiction of such agency which is damaged or destroyed by any major disaster if he determines that such repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement is of such importance and urgency that it cannot reasonably be deferred pending the enactment of specific authorizing legislation or the making of an appropriation for such purposes, or the obtaining of congressional committee approval.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of funds appropriated to agency for repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of agency facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of funds appropriated to agency for repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement of agency facilities In order to carry out the provisions of this section, such repair, reconstruction, restoration, or replacement may be begun notwithstanding a lack or an insufficiency of funds appropriated for such purpose, where such lack or insufficiency can be remedied by the transfer, in accordance with law, of funds appropriated to that agency for another purpose.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5171_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Steps for mitigation of hazards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Steps for mitigation of hazards In implementing this section, Federal agencies shall evaluate the natural hazards to which these facilities are exposed and shall take appropriate action to mitigate such hazards, including safe land-use and construction practices, in accordance with standards prescribed by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>