<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5174"><akn:num>5174</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal assistance to individuals and households</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5174. Federal assistance to individuals and households(a) In general(1) Provision of assistanceIn accordance with this section, the President, in consultation with the Governor of a State, may provide financial assistance, and, if necessary, direct services, to individuals and households in the State who, as a direct result of a major disaster, have necessary expenses and serious needs in cases in which the individuals and households are unable to meet such expenses or needs through other means.


(2) Relationship to other assistanceUnder paragraph (1), an individual or household shall not be denied assistance under paragraph (1), (3), or (4) of subsection (c) solely on the basis that the individual or household has not applied for or received any loan or other financial assistance from the Small Business Administration or any other Federal agency.



(b) Housing assistance(1) EligibilityThe President may provide financial or other assistance under this section to individuals and households to respond to the disaster-related housing needs of individuals and households who are displaced from their predisaster primary residences or whose predisaster primary residences are rendered uninhabitable, or with respect to individuals with disabilities, rendered inaccessible or uninhabitable, as a result of damage caused by a major disaster.


(2) Determination of appropriate types of assistance(A) In generalThe President shall determine appropriate types of housing assistance to be provided under this section to individuals and households described in subsection (a)(1) based on considerations of cost effectiveness, convenience to the individuals and households, and such other factors as the President may consider appropriate.


(B) Multiple types of assistanceOne or more types of housing assistance may be made available under this section, based on the suitability and availability of the types of assistance, to meet the needs of individuals and households in the particular </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Housing assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Types of housing assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms and conditions relating to housing assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms and conditions relating to housing assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial assistance to address other needs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Financial assistance to address other needs</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>State role</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) State role</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost sharing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Cost sharing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Maximum amount of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Maximum amount of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Verification measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Verification measures In carrying out this section, the President shall develop a system, including an electronic database, that shall allow the President, or the designee of the President, to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Rules and regulations The President shall prescribe rules and regulations to carry out this section, including criteria, standards, and procedures for determining eligibility for assistance.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>