<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5174a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5174a"><akn:num>5174a</akn:num><akn:heading>Flexibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5174a. Flexibility(a) Waiver authority(1) DefinitionIn this subsection, the term “covered assistance” means assistance provided—(A) under section 5174 of this title; and

(B) in relation to a major disaster or emergency declared by the President under section 5170 or 5191, respectively, of this title on or after October 28, 2012.


(2) AuthorityNotwithstanding section 3716(e) of title 31, the Administrator—(A) except as provided in subparagraph (B), shall—(i) waive a debt owed to the United States related to covered assistance provided to an individual or household if the covered assistance was distributed based on an error by the Agency and such debt shall be construed as a hardship; and

(ii) waive a debt owed to the United States related to covered assistance provided to an individual or household if such assistance is subject to a claim or legal action, including in accordance with section 11 So in original. Probably should be a reference to section 317 of the Act. of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5160); and


(B) may not waive a debt under subparagraph (A) if the debt involves fraud, the presentation of a false claim, or misrepresentation by the debtor or any party having an interest in the claim.


(3) Monitoring of covered assistance distributed based on error(A) In generalThe Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security shall monitor the distribution of covered assistance to individuals and households to determine the percentage of such assistance distributed based on an error.


(B) Report on waiver authority based on excessive error rateIf the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security determines, with respect to any 12-month period, that the amount of covered assistance distributed based on an error by the Agency exceeds 4 percent of the total amount of covered assistance distributed—(i) the Inspector General shall notify the Administrator and publish the determination in the Fed</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Waiver authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recoupment of certain assistance prohibited</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Recoupment of certain assistance prohibited</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5174a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Statute of limitations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Statute of limitations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>