<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5184" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5184/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5184/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5184"><akn:num>5184</akn:num><akn:heading>Community disaster loans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5184. Community disaster loans(a) In generalThe President is authorized to make loans to any local government which may suffer a substantial loss of tax and other revenues as a result of a major disaster, and has demonstrated a need for financial assistance in order to perform its governmental functions.


(b) AmountThe amount of any such loan shall be based on need, shall not exceed—(1) 25 percent of the annual operating budget of that local government for the fiscal year in which the major disaster occurs, and shall not exceed $5,000,000; or

(2) if the loss of tax and other revenues of the local government as a result of the major disaster is at least 75 percent of the annual operating budget of that local government for the fiscal year in which the major disaster occurs, 50 percent of the annual operating budget of that local government for the fiscal year in which the major disaster occurs, and shall not exceed $5,000,000.


(c) Repayment(1) CancellationRepayment of all or any part of such loan to the extent that revenues of the local government during the three full fiscal year period following the major disaster are insufficient to meet the operating budget of the local government, including additional disaster-related expenses of a municipal operation character shall be cancelled.


(2) Condition on continuing eligibilityA local government shall not be eligible for further assistance under this section during any period in which the local government is in arrears with respect to a required repayment of a loan under this section.



(d) Effect on other assistanceAny loans made under this section shall not reduce or otherwise affect any grants or other assistance under this chapter.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title IV, § 417, formerly § 414(a), (b), May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 158; renumbered § 417, Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 106(j), Nov. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 4705; Pub. L. 106–390, title II, § 207, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1571; Pub. L. 109–347, title VI, § 608, Oct. 13,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5184_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President is authorized to make loans to any local government which may suffer a substantial loss of tax and other revenues as a result of a major disaster, and has demonstrated a need for financial assistance in order to perform its governmental functions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5184_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amount The amount of any such loan shall be based on need, shall not exceed—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5184_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repayment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repayment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5184_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effect on other assistance Any loans made under this section shall not reduce or otherwise affect any grants or other assistance under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>