<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5187" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5187/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5187/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5187"><akn:num>5187</akn:num><akn:heading>Fire management assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5187. Fire management assistance(a) In generalThe President is authorized to provide assistance, including grants, equipment, supplies, and personnel, to any State or local government for the mitigation, management, and control of any fire on public or private forest land or grassland that threatens such destruction as would constitute a major disaster.


(b) Coordination with State and tribal departments of forestryIn providing assistance under this section, the President shall coordinate with State and tribal departments of forestry.


(c) Essential assistanceIn providing assistance under this section, the President may use the authority provided under section 5170b of this title.


(d) Hazard mitigation assistanceWhether or not a major disaster is declared, the President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in accordance with section 5170c of this title in any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided under this section.


(e) Rules and regulationsThe President shall prescribe such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.


(Pub. L. 93–288, title IV, § 420, formerly § 417, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 158; renumbered § 420, Pub. L. 100–707, title I, § 106(j), Nov. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 4705; Pub. L. 106–390, title III, § 303(a), Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1572; Pub. L. 115–254, div. D, § 1204(a), Oct. 5, 2018, 132 Stat. 3438.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments2018—Subsecs. (d), (e). Pub. L. 115–254 added subsec. (d) and redesignated former subsec. (d) as (e).
2000—Pub. L. 106–390 amended section catchline and text generally. Prior to amendment, text read as follows: “The President is authorized to provide assistance, including grants, equipment, supplies, and personnel, to any State for the suppression of any fire on publicly or privately owned forest or grassland which threatens such destruction as would constitute a major disaster.”

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective Date of 2018 AmendmentAmendment by Pub. L. 115–</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5187_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The President is authorized to provide assistance, including grants, equipment, supplies, and personnel, to any State or local government for the mitigation, management, and control of any fire on public or private forest land or grassland that threatens such destruction as would constitute a major disaster.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5187_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination with State and tribal departments of forestry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Coordination with State and tribal departments of forestry In providing assistance under this section, the President shall coordinate with State and tribal departments of forestry.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5187_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Essential assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Essential assistance In providing assistance under this section, the President may use the authority provided under section 5170b of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5187_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazard mitigation assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hazard mitigation assistance Whether or not a major disaster is declared, the President may provide hazard mitigation assistance in accordance with section 5170c of this title in any area affected by a fire for which assistance was provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5187_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rules and regulations The President shall prescribe such rules and regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>