<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5189" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5189/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5189/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5189"><akn:num>5189</akn:num><akn:heading>Simplified procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5189. Simplified procedure(a) In generalIf the Federal estimate of the cost of—(1) repairing, restoring, reconstructing, or replacing under section 5172 of this title any damaged or destroyed public facility or private nonprofit facility,

(2) emergency assistance under section 5170b or 5192 of this title, or

(3) debris removed under section 5173 of this title,


is less than $1,000,000 (or, if the Administrator has established a threshold under subsection (b), the amount established under subsection (b)), the President (on application of the State or local government or the owner or operator of the private nonprofit facility) may make the contribution to such State or local government or owner or operator under section 5170b, 5172, 5173, or 5192 of this title, as the case may be, on the basis of such Federal estimate. Such $1,000,000 amount or, if applicable, the amount established under subsection (b), shall be adjusted annually to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor.

(b) Threshold(1) ReportNot later than 1 year after January 29, 2013, the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (in this section referred to as the “Administrator”), shall—(A) complete an analysis to determine whether an increase in the threshold for eligibility under subsection (a) is appropriate, which shall include consideration of cost-effectiveness, speed of recovery, capacity of grantees, past performance, and accountability measures; and

(B) submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report regarding the analysis conducted under subparagraph (A).


(2) AmountAfter the Administrator submits the report required under paragraph (1), the President shall direct the Administrator to—(A) immediately establish a threshold for eligibility under this secti</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5189_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general If the Federal estimate of the cost of— is less than $1,000,000 (or, if the Administrator has established a threshold under subsection (b), the amount established under subsection (b)), the President (on application of the State or local government or the owner or operator of the private nonprofit facility) may make the contribution to such State or local government or owner or operator under section 5170b, 5172, 5173, or 5192 of this title, as the case may be, on the basis of such Federal estimate. Such $1,000,000 amount or, if applicable, the amount established under subsection (b), shall be adjusted annually to reflect changes in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Department of Labor.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5189_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Threshold</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Threshold</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>