<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5197" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5197/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5197/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5197"><akn:num>5197</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5197. Administrative authority(a) In generalFor the purpose of carrying out the powers and duties assigned to the Administrator under this subchapter, the Administrator may exercise the administrative authorities provided under this section.


(b) Advisory personnel(1) The Administrator may employ not more than 100 part-time or temporary advisory personnel (including not to exceed 25 subjects of the United Kingdom or citizens of Canada) as the Administrator considers to be necessary in carrying out the provisions of this subchapter.

(2) Persons holding other offices or positions under the United States for which they receive compensation, while serving as advisory personnel, shall receive no additional compensation for such service. Other part-time or temporary advisory personnel so employed may serve without compensation or may receive compensation at a rate not to exceed $180 for each day of service, plus authorized subsistence and travel, as determined by the Administrator.


(c) Services of other agency personnel and volunteersThe Administrator may—(1) use the services of Federal agencies and, with the consent of any State or local government, accept and use the services of State and local agencies;

(2) establish and use such regional and other offices as may be necessary; and

(3) use such voluntary and uncompensated services by individuals or organizations as may from time to time be needed.


(d) GiftsNotwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may accept gifts of supplies, equipment, and facilities and may use or distribute such gifts for emergency preparedness purposes in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.


(e) ReimbursementThe Administrator may reimburse any Federal agency for any of its expenditures or for compensation of its personnel and use or consumption of its materials and facilities under this subchapter to the extent funds are available.


(f) PrintingThe Administrator may purchase such printing, binding, and</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general For the purpose of carrying out the powers and duties assigned to the Administrator under this subchapter, the Administrator may exercise the administrative authorities provided under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advisory personnel</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Advisory personnel</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Services of other agency personnel and volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Services of other agency personnel and volunteers The Administrator may—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Gifts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Gifts Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may accept gifts of supplies, equipment, and facilities and may use or distribute such gifts for emergency preparedness purposes in accordance with the provisions of this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reimbursement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reimbursement The Administrator may reimburse any Federal agency for any of its expenditures or for compensation of its personnel and use or consumption of its materials and facilities under this subchapter to the extent funds are available.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Printing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Printing The Administrator may purchase such printing, binding, and blank-book work from public, commercial, or private printing establishments or binderies as the Administrator considers necessary upon orders placed by the Director of the Government Publishing Office or upon waivers issued in accordance with section 504 of title 44.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Rules and regulations The Administrator may prescribe such rules and regulations as may be necessary and proper to carry out any of the provisions of this subchapter and perform any of the powers and duties provided by this subchapter. The Administrator may perform any of the powers and duties provided by this subchapter through or with the aid of such officials of the Federal Emergency Management Agency as the Administrator may designate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5197_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Failure to expend contributions correctly</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Failure to expend contributions correctly</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>