<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5206" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5206/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5206/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5206"><akn:num>5206</akn:num><akn:heading>Buy American</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5206. Buy American(a) Compliance with chapter 83 of title 41No funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act or any amendment made by this Act may be expended by an entity unless the entity, in expending the funds, complies with chapter 83 of title 41.


(b) Debarment of persons convicted of fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels(1) In generalIf the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency determines that a person has been convicted of intentionally affixing a label bearing a “Made in America” inscription to any product sold in or shipped to the United States that is not made in America, the Administrator shall determine, not later than 90 days after determining that the person has been so convicted, whether the person should be debarred from contracting under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.).


(2) Definition of debarIn this subsection, the term “debar” has the meaning given the term in section 4654(c) of title 10.



(Pub. L. 106–390, title III, § 306, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1574; Pub. L. 109–295, title VI, § 612(c), Oct. 4, 2006, 120 Stat. 1410; Pub. L. 117–81, div. A, title XVII, § 1702(j)(4), Dec. 27, 2021, 135 Stat. 2159.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis Act, referred to in subsec. (a), is Pub. L. 106–390, Oct. 30, 2000, 114 Stat. 1552, known as the Disaster Mitigation Act of 2000. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 2000 Amendment note set out under section 5121 of this title and Tables.
The Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, referred to in subsec. (b)(1), is Pub. L. 93–288, May 22, 1974, 88 Stat. 143, which is classified principally to this chapter. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title note set out under section 5121 of this title and Tables.

Codification
In subsec. (a), “chapter 83 of title 41” substituted for references to the Buy American Act on authority of Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance with chapter 83 of title 41</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance with chapter 83 of title 41 No funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act or any amendment made by this Act may be expended by an entity unless the entity, in expending the funds, complies with chapter 83 of title 41.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5206_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Debarment of persons convicted of fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Debarment of persons convicted of fraudulent use of “Made in America” labels</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>