<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5302" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5302/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5302/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5302"><akn:num>5302</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5302. General provisions(a) DefinitionsAs used in this chapter—(1) The term “unit of general local government” means any city, county, town, township, parish, village, or other general purpose political subdivision of a State; Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands, and American Samoa, or a general purpose political subdivision thereof; a combination of such political subdivisions that, except as provided in section 5306(d)(4) of this title, is recognized by the Secretary; and the District of Columbia. Such term also includes a State or a local public body or agency (as defined in section 4512 11 See References in Text note below. of this title), community association, or other entity, which is approved by the Secretary for the purpose of providing public facilities or services to a new community as part of a program meeting the eligibility standards of section 4513 1 of this title or title IV of the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 [42 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.].

(2) The term “State” means any State of the United States, or any instrumentality thereof approved by the Governor; and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.

(3) The term “metropolitan area” means a standard metropolitan statistical area as established by the Office of Management and Budget.

(4) The term “metropolitan city” means (A) a city within a metropolitan area which is the central city of such area, as defined and used by the Office of Management and Budget, or (B) any other city, within a metropolitan area, which has a population of fifty thousand or more. Any city that was classified as a metropolitan city for at least 2 years pursuant to the first sentence of this paragraph shall remain classified as a metropolitan city. Any unit of general local government that becomes eligible to be classified as a metropolitan city, and was not classified as a metropolitan city in the immediately preceding fiscal year, may, upon submission of written notification to the Secretary, defer its </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5302_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions As used in this chapter—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5302_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Basis and modification of definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Basis and modification of definitions Where appropriate, the definitions in subsection (a) shall be based, with respect to any fiscal year, on the most recent data compiled by the United States Bureau of the Census and the latest published reports of the Office of Management and Budget available ninety days prior to the beginning of such fiscal year. The Secretary may by regulation change or otherwise modify the meaning of the terms defined in subsection (a) in order to reflect any technical change or modification thereof made subsequent to such date by the United States Bureau of the Census or the Office of Management and Budget.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5302_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of public agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Designation of public agencies One or more public agencies, including existing local public agencies, may be designated by the chief executive officer of a State or a unit of general local government to undertake activities assisted under this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5302_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Local governments, inclusion in urban county population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Local governments, inclusion in urban county population With respect to program years beginning with the program year for which grants are made available from amounts appropriated for fiscal year 1982 under section 5303 of this title, the population of any unit of general local government which is included in that of an urban county as provided in subparagraph (A)(ii) or (D) of subsection (a)(6) shall be included in the population of such urban county for three program years beginning with the program year in which its population was first so included and shall not otherwise be eligible for a grant under section 5306 of this title as a separate entity, unless the urban county does not receive a grant for any year during such three-year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5302_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exclusion of local governments from urban county population; notification of election</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Exclusion of local governments from urban county population; notification of election Any county seeking qualification as an urban county, including any urban county seeking to continue such qualification, shall notify, as provided in this subsection, each unit of general local government, which is included therein and is eligible to elect to have its population excluded from that of an urban county under subsection (a)(6)(A)(ii)(I)(a), of its opportunity to make such an election. Such notification shall, at a time and in a manner prescribed by the Secretary, be provided so as to provide a reasonable period for response prior to the period for which such qualification is sought. The population of any unit of general local government which is provided such notification and which does not inform, at a time and in a manner prescribed by the Secretary, the county of its election to exclude its population from that of the county shall, if the county qualifies as an urban county, be incl</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>