<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5306" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5306/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5306/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5306"><akn:num>5306</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation and distribution of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5306. Allocation and distribution of funds(a) Amounts allocated to Indian tribes, discretionary fund, and metropolitan cities and urban counties; limitations on amount of annual grants(1) For each fiscal year, of the amount approved in appropriation Acts under section 5303 of this title for grants for such fiscal year (excluding the amounts provided for use in accordance with section 5307 of this title), the Secretary shall reserve for grants to Indian tribes 1 percent of the amount appropriated under such section. The Secretary shall provide for distribution of amounts under this paragraph to Indian tribes on the basis of a competition conducted pursuant to specific criteria for the selection of Indian tribes to receive such amounts. The criteria shall be contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment. Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, such grants to Indian tribes shall not be subject to the requirements of section 5304 of this title, except subsections (f), (g), and (k) of such section.

(2) For each fiscal year, of the amount approved in appropriation Acts under section 5303 of this title for grants for such fiscal year (excluding the amounts provided for use in accordance with section 5307 of this title), the Secretary shall reserve for grants to insular areas $7,000,000. The Secretary shall provide for distribution of amounts under this paragraph to insular areas on the basis of the ratio of the population of each insular area to the population of all insular areas. In determining the distribution of amounts to insular areas, the Secretary may also include other statistical criteria as data become available from the Bureau of the Census, but only if such criteria are contained in a regulation promulgated by the Secretary after notice and public comment.

(3) After reserving such amounts for Indian tribes under paragraph (1) and after reserving such amounts for insular areas under paragraph (2), the Secret</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amounts allocated to Indian tribes, discretionary fund, and metropolitan cities and urban counties; limitations on amount of annual grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Amounts allocated to Indian tribes, discretionary fund, and metropolitan cities and urban counties; limitations on amount of annual grants</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of amount allocated to metropolitan cities and urban counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of amount allocated to metropolitan cities and urban counties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallocation of undistributed funds within same metropolitan area as original allocation; amount and calculation of reallocation grant; disaster relief</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reallocation of undistributed funds within same metropolitan area as original allocation; amount and calculation of reallocation grant; disaster relief</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation among States for nonentitlement areas; amount and calculation of grants; distributions by State or Secretary; certain distributions made pursuant to prior provisions; certifications required by Governor enumerated; responsibility for administration and administrative expenses; reallocation; certifications required of units of general local government in nonentitlement areas; applicability of this chapter and other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Allocation among States for nonentitlement areas; amount and calculation of grants; distributions by State or Secretary; certain distributions made pursuant to prior provisions; certifications required by Governor enumerated; responsibility for administration and administrative expenses; reallocation; certifications required of units of general local government in nonentitlement areas; applicability of this chapter and other law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Qualification or submission dates, and finality and conclusiveness of computations and determinations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Qualification or submission dates, and finality and conclusiveness of computations and determinations The Secretary may fix such qualification or submission dates as he determines are necessary to permit the computations and determinations required by this section to be made in a timely manner, and all such computations and determinations shall be final and conclusive.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5306_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Pro rata adjustment of entitlement amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Pro rata adjustment of entitlement amounts If the total amount available for distribution in any fiscal year to metropolitan cities and urban counties under this section is insufficient to provide the amounts to which metropolitan cities and urban counties would be entitled under subsection (b), and funds are not otherwise appropriated to meet the deficiency, the Secretary shall meet the deficiency through a pro rata reduction of all amounts determined under subsection (b). If the total amount available for distribution in any fiscal year to metropolitan cities and urban counties under this section exceeds the amounts to which metropolitan cities and urban counties would be entitled under subsection (b), the Secretary shall distribute the excess through a pro rata increase of all amounts determined under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>