<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5307" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5307/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5307/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5307"><akn:num>5307</akn:num><akn:heading>Special purpose grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5307. Special purpose grants(a) Set-aside(1) In generalFor each fiscal year (except as otherwise provided in this paragraph), of the total amount provided in appropriation Acts under section 5303 of this title for the fiscal year, $60,000,000 shall be set aside for grants under subsection (b) for such year for the following purposes:(A) $6,500,000 shall be available for grants under subsection (b)(3) 11 See References in Text note below.;

(B) $6,000,000 shall be available for grants under subsection (b)(5) 1;

(C) $6,000,000 shall be available in fiscal year 1993 for grants under subsection (b)(7) 1;

(D) $3,000,000 shall be available for grants under subsection (c);

(E) such sums as may be necessary shall be available for grants under paragraphs (2), (4), and (6) 1 of subsection (b);

(F) $2,000,000 shall be available in fiscal year 1993 for a grant to the City of Bridgeport, Connecticut, subject to the approval of sufficient amounts in an appropriation Act and to binding commitments made by the City of Bridgeport and the State of Connecticut that the city and State, respectively, will supplement such amount with $2,000,000 of additional funds; and

(G) $7,500,000 shall be available to carry out the Community Outreach Partnership Act of 1992.


(2) Treatment of grantsAny grants made under this section shall be in addition to any other grants that may be made under this chapter to the same entities for the same purposes.



(b) Permissible uses of fundsFrom amounts set aside under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to make grants—(1) to States and units of general local government for the purpose of allocating amounts to any such State or unit of general local government that is determined by the Secretary to have received insufficient amounts under section 5306 of this title as a result of a miscalculation of its share of funds under such section;

(2) to historically Black colleges;

(3) to States, units of general local government, Indian tribes, or </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Set-aside</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Set-aside</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissible uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Permissible uses of funds From amounts set aside under subsection (a), the Secretary is authorized to make grants—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assistance to economically disadvantaged and minority students participating in community development work study programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assistance to economically disadvantaged and minority students participating in community development work study programs Of the amount set aside for use under subsection (b) in any fiscal year, the Secretary shall,22 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. make grants to institutions of higher education, either directly or through areawide planning organizations or States, for the purpose of providing assistance to economically disadvantaged and minority students who participate in community development work study programs and are enrolled in full-time graduate or undergraduate programs in community and economic development, community planning, or community management.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continued availability of unused funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Continued availability of unused funds Amounts set aside for use under subsection (b) in any fiscal year but not used in that year shall remain available for use in subsequent fiscal years in accordance with the provisions of that subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Satisfactory assurances required, special assurances required of Indian tribes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Satisfactory assurances required, special assurances required of Indian tribes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5307_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for selection of recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Criteria for selection of recipients Any grant made under this section shall be made pursuant to criteria for selection of recipients of such grants that the Secretary shall by regulation establish and which the Secretary shall publish together with any notification of availability of amounts under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>