<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5318a"><akn:num>5318a</akn:num><akn:heading>John Heinz Neighborhood Development Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5318a. John Heinz Neighborhood Development Program(a) DefinitionsFor the purposes of this section:(1) The term “eligible neighborhood development activity” means—(A) creating permanent jobs in the neighborhood;

(B) establishing or expanding businesses within the neighborhood;

(C) developing, rehabilitating, or managing neighborhood housing stock;

(D) developing delivery mechanisms for essential services that have lasting benefit to the neighborhood; or

(E) planning, promoting, or financing voluntary neighborhood improvement efforts.


(2) The term “eligible neighborhood development organization” means—(A)(i) an entity organized as a private, voluntary, nonprofit corporation under the laws of the State in which it operates;

(ii) an organization that is responsible to residents of its neighborhood through a governing body, not less than 51 per centum of the members of which are residents of the area served;

(iii) an organization that has conducted business for at least one year prior to the date of application for participation;

(iv) an organization that operates within an area that—(I) meets the requirements for Federal assistance under section 5318 of this title;

(II) is designated as an enterprise zone under Federal law;

(III) is designated as an enterprise zone under State law and recognized by the Secretary for purposes of this section as a State enterprise zone; or

(IV) is a qualified distressed community within the meaning of section 1834a(b)(1) of title 12; and


(v) an organization that conducts one or more eligible neighborhood development activities that have as their primary beneficiaries low- and moderate-income persons, as defined in section 5302(a)(20) of this title; or


(B) any facility that provides small entrepreneurial business with affordable shared support services and business development services and meets the requirements of subparagraph (A).


(3) The term “neighborhood development funding organization” means—(A) a depository inst</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions For the purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties of Secretary</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for awarding grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria for awarding grants The Secretary shall award grants under this section among the eligible neighborhood development organizations submitting applications for such grants on the basis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with informal working group</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Consultation with informal working group The Secretary shall consult with an informal working group representative of eligible neighborhood organizations with respect to the implementation and evaluation of the program established in this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matching funds for participating organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matching funds for participating organizations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization Of the amounts made available for assistance under section 5303 of this title, $1,000,000 for fiscal year 1993 (in addition to other amounts provided for such fiscal year) and $3,000,000 for fiscal year 1994 shall be available to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Short title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Short title This section may be cited as the “John Heinz Neighborhood Development Act”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>