<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5318/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5318"><akn:num>5318</akn:num><akn:heading>Urban development action grants</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5318. Urban development action grants(a) Authorization; purpose; amountThe Secretary is authorized to make urban development action grants to cities and urban counties which are experiencing severe economic distress to help stimulate economic development activity needed to aid in economic recovery. There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $225,000,000 for fiscal year 1988, and $225,000,000 for fiscal year 1989. Any amount appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.


(b) Eligibility of cities and urban counties; criteria and standards; regulations(1) Urban development action grants shall be made only to cities and urban counties which have, in the determination of the Secretary, demonstrated results in providing housing for low- and moderate-income persons and in providing equal opportunity in housing and employment for low- and moderate-income persons and members of minority groups. The Secretary shall issue regulations establishing criteria in accordance with the preceding sentence and setting forth minimum standards for determining the level of economic distress of cities and urban counties for eligibility for such grants. These standards shall take into account factors such as the age of housing; the extent of poverty; the extent of population lag; growth of per capita income; and the extent of unemployment, job lag, or surplus labor. Any city that has a population of less than 50,000 persons and is not the central city of a metropolitan area, and that was eligible for fiscal year 1983 under this paragraph for assistance under this section, shall continue to be eligible for such assistance until the Secretary revises the standards for eligibility for such cities under this paragraph and includes the extent of unemployment, job lag, or labor surplus as a standard of distress for such cities. The Secretary shall make such revision as soon as practicable following November 30, 1983.

(2) A city or urban count</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization; purpose; amount</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization; purpose; amount The Secretary is authorized to make urban development action grants to cities and urban counties which are experiencing severe economic distress to help stimulate economic development activity needed to aid in economic recovery. There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $225,000,000 for fiscal year 1988, and $225,000,000 for fiscal year 1989. Any amount appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility of cities and urban counties; criteria and standards; regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility of cities and urban counties; criteria and standards; regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applications; documentation of eligibility; proposed plan; assurance of notice and comment; assurance of consideration on historical landmarks</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Applications; documentation of eligibility; proposed plan; assurance of notice and comment; assurance of consideration on historical landmarks Applications for assistance under this section shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory selection criteria; award of points; distribution of funds; number of competitions per year; use of distress conditions data by urban counties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Mandatory selection criteria; award of points; distribution of funds; number of competitions per year; use of distress conditions data by urban counties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on power of Secretary to approve grants; waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Limitations on power of Secretary to approve grants; waiver The Secretary may not approve any grant to a city or urban county eligible under subsection (b)(2) unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permissibility of consistent but unenumerated activities; report on use of repaid grant funds for economic development activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Permissibility of consistent but unenumerated activities; report on use of repaid grant funds for economic development activities Activities assisted under this section may include such activities, in addition to those authorized under section 5305(a) of this title, as the Secretary determines to be consistent with the purposes of this section. In any case in which the project proposes the repayment to the applicant of the grant funds, such funds shall be made available by the applicant for economic development activities that are eligible activities under this section or section 5305 of this title. The applicant shall annually provide the Secretary with a statement of the projected receipt and use of repaid grant funds during the next year together with a report acceptable to the Secretary on the use of such funds during the most recent preceding full fiscal year of the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual review and audit; adjustments, withdrawals and reduction permitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Annual review and audit; adjustments, withdrawals and reduction permitted The Secretary shall, at least on an annual basis, make reviews and audits of recipients of grants under this section as necessary to determine the progress made in carrying out activities substantially in accordance with approved plans and timetables. The Secretary may adjust, reduce, or withdraw grant funds, or take other action as appropriate in accordance with the findings of these reviews and audits, except that funds already expended on eligible activities under this chapter shall not be recaptured or deducted from future grants made to the recipient.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on grants for industrial or commercial relocations or expansions; appeal of denial or cancellation of assistance; grants to adversely affected individuals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Limitations on grants for industrial or commercial relocations or expansions; appeal of denial or cancellation of assistance; grants to adversely affected individuals</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum percentage of funds to be allocated to certain noncentral cities; application by consortia of cities of less than 50,000 population</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Minimum percentage of funds to be allocated to certain noncentral cities; application by consortia of cities of less than 50,000 population Not less than 25 per centum of the funds made available for grants under this section shall be used for cities with populations of less than fifty thousand persons which are not central cities of a metropolitan statistical area. The Secretary shall encourage cooperation by geographically proximate cities of less than 50,000 population by permitting consortia of such cities, which may also include county governments that are not urban counties, to apply for grants on behalf of a city that is otherwise eligible for assistance under this section. Any grants awarded to such consortia shall be administered in compliance with eligibility requirements applicable to individual cities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5318_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Grant contingent on factors related to non-Federal funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Grant contingent on factors related to non-Federal funds A grant may be made under this section only where the Secretary determines that there is a strong probability that (1) the non-Federal investment in the project would not be made without the grant, and (2) the grant would not substitute for non-Federal funds which are otherwise available to the project.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>