<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5403" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5403/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5403/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5403"><akn:num>5403</akn:num><akn:heading>Construction and safety standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5403. Construction and safety standards(a) Establishment(1) AuthorityThe Secretary shall establish, by order, appropriate Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards, each of which—(A) shall—(i) be reasonable and practical;

(ii) meet high standards of protection consistent with the purposes of this chapter; and

(iii) be performance-based and objectively stated, unless clearly inappropriate; and


(B) except as provided in subsection (b), shall be established in accordance with the consensus standards development process.


(2) Consensus standards and regulatory development process(A) Initial agreementNot later than 180 days after December 27, 2000, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with an administering organization. The contractual agreement shall—(i) terminate on the date on which a contract is entered into under subparagraph (B); and

(ii) require the administering organization to—(I) recommend the initial members of the consensus committee under paragraph (3);

(II) administer the consensus standards development process until the termination of that agreement; and

(III) administer the consensus development and interpretation process for procedural and enforcement regulations and regulations specifying the permissible scope and conduct of monitoring until the termination of that agreement.



(B) Competitively procured contractUpon the expiration of the 4-year period beginning on the date on which all members of the consensus committee are appointed under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall, using competitive procedures (as such term is defined in section 132 of title 41), enter into a competitively awarded contract with an administering organization. The administering organization shall administer the consensus process for the development and interpretation of the Federal standards, the procedural and enforcement regulations, and regulations specifying the permissible scope and conduct of monitoring, in accordance with this chapter.

</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Other orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effective date of orders establishing standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Effective date of orders establishing standards Each order establishing a Federal manufactured home construction and safety standard shall specify the date such standard is to take effect, which shall not be sooner than one hundred and eighty days or later than one year after the date such order is issued, unless the Secretary finds, for good cause shown, that an earlier or later effective date is in the public interest, and publishes his reasons for such finding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supremacy of Federal standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supremacy of Federal standards Whenever a Federal manufactured home construction and safety standard established under this chapter is in effect, no State or political subdivision of a State shall have any authority either to establish, or to continue in effect, with respect to any manufactured home covered, any standard regarding the construction or safety applicable to the same aspect of performance of such manufactured home which is not identical to the Federal manufactured home construction and safety standard. Federal preemption under this subsection shall be broadly and liberally construed to ensure that disparate State or local requirements or standards do not affect the uniformity and comprehensiveness of the standards promulgated under this section nor the Federal superintendence of the manufactured housing industry as established by this chapter. Subject to section 5404 of this title, there is reserved to each State the right to establish standards for the stabilizing and</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations in establishing and interpreting standards and regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Considerations in establishing and interpreting standards and regulations The consensus committee, in recommending standards, regulations, and interpretations, and the Secretary, in establishing standards or regulations or issuing interpretations under this section, shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coverage; exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coverage; exclusion The Secretary shall exclude from the coverage of this chapter any structure which the manufacturer certifies, in a form prescribed by the Secretary, to be:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Manufactured housing construction and safety standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Manufactured housing construction and safety standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5403_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>New performance standards for hardboard siding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) New performance standards for hardboard siding The Secretary shall develop a new standard for hardboard panel siding on manufactured housing taking into account durability, longevity, consumer’s costs for maintenance and any other relevant information pursuant to subsection (e). The Secretary shall consult with the National Manufactured Home Advisory Council and the National Commission on Manufactured Housing in establishing the new standard. The new performance standard developed shall ensure the durability of hardboard sidings for at least a normal life of a mortgage with minimum maintenance required. Not later than 180 days from October 28, 1992, the Secretary shall update the standards for hardboard siding.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>