<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5413" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5413/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5413/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5413"><akn:num>5413</akn:num><akn:heading>Inspections and investigations for promulgation or enforcement of standards or execution of other du</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5413. Inspections and investigations for promulgation or enforcement of standards or execution of other duties(a) Authority of Secretary; results furnished to Attorney General and Secretary of the Treasury for appropriate actionThe Secretary is authorized to conduct such inspections and investigations as may be necessary to promulgate or enforce Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards established under this chapter or otherwise to carry out his duties under this chapter. He shall furnish the Attorney General and, when appropriate, the Secretary of the Treasury any information obtained indicating noncompliance with such standards for appropriate action.


(b) Designation by Secretary of persons to enter and inspect factories, etc.; presentation of credentials; reasonableness and scope of inspection(1) For purposes of enforcement of this chapter, persons duly designated by the Secretary, upon presenting appropriate credentials to the owner, operator, or agent in charge, are authorized—(A) to enter, at reasonable times and without advance notice, any factory, warehouse, or establishment in which manufactured homes are manufactured, stored, or held, for sale; and

(B) to inspect, at reasonable times and within reasonable limits and in a reasonable manner, any such factory, warehouse, or establishment, and to inspect such books, papers, records, and documents as are set forth in subsection (c). Each such inspection shall be commenced and completed with reasonable promptness.


(2) The Secretary is authorized to contract with State and local governments and private inspection organizations to carry out his functions under this subsection.


(c) Powers of SecretaryFor the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized—(1) to hold such hearings, take such testimony, sit and act at such times and places, administer such oaths, and require, by subpena or otherwise, the attendance and testimony of such witnesses and th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority of Secretary; results furnished to Attorney General and Secretary of the Treasury for appropriate action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority of Secretary; results furnished to Attorney General and Secretary of the Treasury for appropriate action The Secretary is authorized to conduct such inspections and investigations as may be necessary to promulgate or enforce Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards established under this chapter or otherwise to carry out his duties under this chapter. He shall furnish the Attorney General and, when appropriate, the Secretary of the Treasury any information obtained indicating noncompliance with such standards for appropriate action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation by Secretary of persons to enter and inspect factories, etc.; presentation of credentials; reasonableness and scope of inspection</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation by Secretary of persons to enter and inspect factories, etc.; presentation of credentials; reasonableness and scope of inspection</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Powers of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Powers of Secretary For the purpose of carrying out the provisions of this chapter, the Secretary is authorized—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Refusal to obey subpena or order of Secretary; order of compliance by district court; failure to obey order of compliance punishable as contempt</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Refusal to obey subpena or order of Secretary; order of compliance by district court; failure to obey order of compliance punishable as contempt Any of the district courts of the United States within the jurisdiction of which an inquiry is carried on may, in the case of contumacy or refusal to obey a subpena or order of the Secretary issued under paragraph (1) or paragraph (3) of subsection (c) of this section, issue an order requiring compliance therewith; and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Submission by manufacturer of building plans for manufactured homes; certification by manufacturer of conformity of building plans to standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Submission by manufacturer of building plans for manufactured homes; certification by manufacturer of conformity of building plans to standards Each manufacturer of manufactured homes shall submit the building plans for every model of such manufactured homes to the Secretary or his designee for the purpose of inspection under this section. The manufacturer must certify that each such building plan meets the Federal construction and safety standards in force at that time before the model involved is produced.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Records, reports and information from manufacturers, distributors and retailers of manufactured homes; inspection and examination of relevant books, papers, records and documents by designated person</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Records, reports and information from manufacturers, distributors and retailers of manufactured homes; inspection and examination of relevant books, papers, records and documents by designated person Each manufacturer, distributor, and retailer of manufactured homes shall establish and maintain such records, make such reports, and provide such information as the Secretary may reasonably require to enable him to determine whether such manufacturer, distributor, or retailer has acted or is acting in compliance with this chapter and Federal manufactured home construction and safety standards prescribed pursuant to this chapter and shall, upon request of a person duly designated by the Secretary, permit such person to inspect appropriate books, papers, records, and documents relevant to determining whether such manufacturer, distributor, or retailer has acted or is acting in compliance with this chapter and manufactured home construction and safety standards prescribed pursuant to this</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Performance and technical data from manufacturer; persons required to receive notification of data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Performance and technical data from manufacturer; persons required to receive notification of data Each manufacturer of manufactured homes shall provide to the Secretary such performance data and other technical data related to performance and safety as may be required to carry out the purposes of this chapter. These shall include records of tests and test results which the Secretary may require to be performed. The Secretary is authorized to require the manufacturer to give notification of such performance and technical data to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5413_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Disclosure of confidential information and trade secrets</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Disclosure of confidential information and trade secrets All information reported to or otherwise obtained by the Secretary or his representative pursuant to subsection (b), (c), (f), or (g) which contains or relates to a trade secret, or which, if disclosed, would put the person furnishing such information at a substantial competitive disadvantage, shall be considered confidential, except that such information may be disclosed to other officers or employees concerned with carrying out this chapter or when relevant in any proceeding under this chapter. Nothing in this section shall authorize the withholding of information by the Secretary or any officer or employee under his control from the duly authorized committees of the Congress.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>