<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5517" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5517/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5517/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5517"><akn:num>5517</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5517. Authorization of appropriations(a) Appropriations to National Aeronautics and Space AdministrationThere is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1975, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended, to carry out the functions vested in the Administrator by this subchapter.


(b) Appropriations to Department of Housing and Urban DevelopmentThere is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Housing and Urban Development for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1975, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended. Any sums so appropriated shall be available (1) to carry out the functions vested in the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by this subchapter, and (2) for transfer to the Department of Defense, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the General Services Administration to enable them to carry out their respective functions under this subchapter.


(c) Appropriations for programs under this subchapterThere is hereby authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal years ending June 30, 1976, 1977, 1978, and 1979, $50,000,000 in the aggregate to carry out the programs established by this subchapter.


(Pub. L. 93–409, § 19, Sept. 3, 1974, 88 Stat. 1078; Pub. L. 100–418, title V, § 5115(c), Aug. 23, 1988, 102 Stat. 1433.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 100–418 substituted “National Institute of Standards and Technology” for “National Bureau of Standards”.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5517_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations to National Aeronautics and Space Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Appropriations to National Aeronautics and Space Administration There is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1975, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended, to carry out the functions vested in the Administrator by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5517_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations to Department of Housing and Urban Development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Appropriations to Department of Housing and Urban Development There is hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Housing and Urban Development for the fiscal year ending June 30, 1975, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended. Any sums so appropriated shall be available (1) to carry out the functions vested in the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development by this subchapter, and (2) for transfer to the Department of Defense, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the General Services Administration to enable them to carry out their respective functions under this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5517_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriations for programs under this subchapter</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Appropriations for programs under this subchapter There is hereby authorized to be appropriated for the fiscal years ending June 30, 1976, 1977, 1978, and 1979, $50,000,000 in the aggregate to carry out the programs established by this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>