<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5814" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5814/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5814/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5814"><akn:num>5814</akn:num><akn:heading>Abolition and transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5814. Abolition and transfers(a) Abolition of Atomic Energy CommissionThe Atomic Energy Commission is hereby abolished. Sections 2031 and 2032 of this title are repealed.


(b) Transfer or lapse of functions of Atomic Energy CommissionAll other functions of the Commission, the Chairman and members of the Commission, and the officers and components of the Commission are hereby transferred or allowed to lapse pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.


(c) Functions of Atomic Energy Commission transferred to AdministratorThere are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator all functions of the Atomic Energy Commission, the Chairman and members of the Commission, and the officers and components of the Commission, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.


(d) Transfer of General Advisory Committee, Patent Compensation Board, and Divisions of Military Application and Naval Reactors to AdministrationThe General Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 2036 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the Patent Compensation Board established pursuant to section 2187 of this title, and the Divisions of Military Application and Naval Reactors established pursuant to section 2035 of this title, are transferred to the Energy Research and Development Administration and the functions of the Commission with respect thereto, and with respect to relations with the Military Liaison Committee established by section 2037 1 of this title, are transferred to the Administrator.


(e) Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of Secretary of the Interior and Department of the Interior; study of potential energy application of helium; report to President and CongressThere are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator such functions of the Secretary of the Interior, the Department of the Interior, and officers and components of such department—(1) as relate to or are utilized by the Office of Coal Research established pursuant to the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Abolition of Atomic Energy Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Abolition of Atomic Energy Commission The Atomic Energy Commission is hereby abolished. Sections 2031 and 2032 of this title are repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer or lapse of functions of Atomic Energy Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Transfer or lapse of functions of Atomic Energy Commission All other functions of the Commission, the Chairman and members of the Commission, and the officers and components of the Commission are hereby transferred or allowed to lapse pursuant to the provisions of this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Atomic Energy Commission transferred to Administrator</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Functions of Atomic Energy Commission transferred to Administrator There are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator all functions of the Atomic Energy Commission, the Chairman and members of the Commission, and the officers and components of the Commission, except as otherwise provided in this chapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of General Advisory Committee, Patent Compensation Board, and Divisions of Military Application and Naval Reactors to Administration</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Transfer of General Advisory Committee, Patent Compensation Board, and Divisions of Military Application and Naval Reactors to Administration The General Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 2036 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, the Patent Compensation Board established pursuant to section 2187 of this title, and the Divisions of Military Application and Naval Reactors established pursuant to section 2035 of this title, are transferred to the Energy Research and Development Administration and the functions of the Commission with respect thereto, and with respect to relations with the Military Liaison Committee established by section 2037 1 of this title, are transferred to the Administrator.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of Secretary of the Interior and Department of the Interior; study of potential energy application of helium; report to President and Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of Secretary of the Interior and Department of the Interior; study of potential energy application of helium; report to President and Congress There are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator such functions of the Secretary of the Interior, the Department of the Interior, and officers and components of such department— The Administrator shall conduct a study of the potential energy applications of helium and, within six months from October 11, 1974, report to the President and Congress his recommendations concerning the management of the Federal helium programs, as they relate to energy.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of National Science Foundation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of National Science Foundation There are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator such functions of the National Science Foundation as relate to or are utilized in connection with—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of Environmental Protection Agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Transfer to Administrator of certain functions of Environmental Protection Agency There are hereby transferred to and vested in the Administrator such functions of the Environmental Protection Agency and the officers and components thereof as relate to or are utilized in connection with research, development, and demonstration, but not assessment or monitoring for regulatory purposes, of alternative automotive power systems.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exercise of authority necessary or appropriate to perform transferred functions and carry out transferred programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Exercise of authority necessary or appropriate to perform transferred functions and carry out transferred programs To the extent necessary or appropriate to perform functions and carry out programs transferred by this chapter, the Administrator and Commission may exercise, in relation to the functions so transferred, any authority or part thereof available by law, including appropriation Acts, to the official or agency from which such functions were transferred.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5814_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Utilization of technical and management capabilities of other executive agencies; assignment of specific programs or projects in energy research and development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Utilization of technical and management capabilities of other executive agencies; assignment of specific programs or projects in energy research and development In the exercise of his responsibilities under section 5813 of this title, the Administrator shall utilize, with their consent, to the fullest extent he determines advisable the technical and management capabilities of other executive agencies having facilities, personnel, or other resources which can assist or advantageously be expanded to assist in carrying out such responsibilities. The Administrator shall consult with the head of each agency with respect to such facilities, personnel, or other resources, and may assign, with their consent, specific programs or projects in energy research and development as appropriate. In making such assignments under this subsection, the head of each such agency shall insure that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>