<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5847" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5847/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5847/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5847"><akn:num>5847</akn:num><akn:heading>Nuclear energy center site survey</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5847. Nuclear energy center site survey(a)(1) 11 So in original. No subsec. (b) has been enacted. The Commission is authorized and directed to make or cause to be made under its direction, a national survey, which shall include consideration of each of the existing or future electric reliability regions, or other appropriate regional areas, to locate and identify possible nuclear energy center sites. This survey shall be conducted in cooperation with other interested Federal, State, and local agencies, and the views of interested persons, including electric utilities, citizens’ groups, and others, shall be solicited and considered.

(2) For purposes of this section, the term “nuclear energy center site” means any site, including a site not restricted to land, large enough to support utility operations or other elements of the total nuclear fuel cycle, or both including, if appropriate, nuclear fuel reprocessing facilities, nuclear fuel fabrication plants, retrievable nuclear waste storage facilities, and unranium 22 So in original. Probably should be “uranium”. enrichment facilities.

(3) The survey shall include—(a) a regional evaluation of natural resources, including land, air, and water resources, available for use in connection with nuclear energy center sites; estimates of future electric power requirements that can be served by each nuclear energy center site; an assessment of the economic impact of each nuclear energy site; and consideration of any other relevant factors, including but not limited to population distribution, proximity to electric load centers and to other elements of the fuel cycle, transmission line rights-of-way, and the availability of other fuel resources;

(b) an evaluation of the environmental impact likely to result from construction and operation of such nuclear energy centers, including an evaluation whether such nuclear energy centers will result in greater or lesser environmental impact than separate siting of the reactors and/o</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5847_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>