<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5849" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5849/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5849/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5849"><akn:num>5849</akn:num><akn:heading>Other officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5849. Other officers(a) Executive DirectorThe Commission shall appoint an Executive Director for Operations, who shall serve at the pleasure of and be removable by the Commission.


(b) Functions of Executive DirectorThe Executive Director shall perform such functions as the Commission may direct, except that the Executive Director shall not limit the authority of the director of any component organization provided in this chapter to communicate with or report directly to the Commission when such director of a component organization deems it necessary to carry out his responsibilities. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, each such director shall keep the Executive Director fully and currently informed concerning the content of all such direct communications with the Commission.


(c) Equal employment opportunity reportThe Executive Director shall report to the Commission at semi-annual public meetings on the problems, progress, and status of the Commission’s equal employment opportunity efforts.


(d) Annual status reportThe Executive Director shall prepare and forward to the Commission an annual report (for the fiscal year 1978 and each succeeding fiscal year) on the status of the Commission’s programs concerning domestic safeguards matters including an assessment of the effectiveness and adequacy of safeguards at facilities and activities licensed by the Commission. The Commission shall forward to the Congress a report under this section prior to February 1, 1979, as a separate document, and prior to February 1 of each succeeding year as a separate chapter of the Commission’s annual report (required under section 5877(c) of this title) following the fiscal year to which such report applies.


(e) Additional officersThere shall be in the Commission not more than five additional officers appointed by the Commission. The positions of such officers shall be considered career positions and be subject to section 2201(d) of this title.


(Pub. L. 93–438, title II, </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5849_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Executive Director The Commission shall appoint an Executive Director for Operations, who shall serve at the pleasure of and be removable by the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5849_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Functions of Executive Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Functions of Executive Director The Executive Director shall perform such functions as the Commission may direct, except that the Executive Director shall not limit the authority of the director of any component organization provided in this chapter to communicate with or report directly to the Commission when such director of a component organization deems it necessary to carry out his responsibilities. Notwithstanding the preceding sentence, each such director shall keep the Executive Director fully and currently informed concerning the content of all such direct communications with the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5849_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Equal employment opportunity report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Equal employment opportunity report The Executive Director shall report to the Commission at semi-annual public meetings on the problems, progress, and status of the Commission’s equal employment opportunity efforts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5849_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual status report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Annual status report The Executive Director shall prepare and forward to the Commission an annual report (for the fiscal year 1978 and each succeeding fiscal year) on the status of the Commission’s programs concerning domestic safeguards matters including an assessment of the effectiveness and adequacy of safeguards at facilities and activities licensed by the Commission. The Commission shall forward to the Congress a report under this section prior to February 1, 1979, as a separate document, and prior to February 1 of each succeeding year as a separate chapter of the Commission’s annual report (required under section 5877(c) of this title) following the fiscal year to which such report applies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5849_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Additional officers There shall be in the Commission not more than five additional officers appointed by the Commission. The positions of such officers shall be considered career positions and be subject to section 2201(d) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>