<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5905" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5905/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5905/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5905"><akn:num>5905</akn:num><akn:heading>Comprehensive planning and programming</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5905. Comprehensive planning and programming(a) Pursuant to the authority and directions of this chapter and the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 (Public Law 93–438) [42 U.S.C. 5801 et seq.], the Department of Energy Organization Act (42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.), and titles XX through XXIII of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13401 et seq., 13451 et seq., 13501 et seq., 13521 et seq.], the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Board established under section 2302 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13522], shall transmit to the Congress, on or before June 30, 1975, a comprehensive plan for energy research, development, and demonstration. This plan shall be appropriately revised annually as provided in section 5914(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. Such plan shall be designed to achieve—(1) solutions to immediate and short-term (the period up to 5 years after submission of the plan or its annual revision) energy supply system and associated environmental problems;

(2) solutions to middle-term (the period from 5 years to 10 years after submission of the plan or its annual revision) energy supply system and associated environmental problems; and

(3) solutions to long-term (the period beyond 10 years after submission of the plan or its annual revision) energy supply system and associated environmental problems.


(b)(1) Based on the comprehensive energy research, development, and demonstration plan developed under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Board established under section 2302 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13522], shall develop and transmit to the Congress, on or before June 30, 1975, a comprehensive nonnuclear energy research, development, and demonstration program to implement the nonnuclear research, development, and demonstration aspects of the comprehensive plan. Such program shall be updated and transmitted to the Congress annually as part of the report required under</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5905_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Pursuant to the authority and directions of this chapter and the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 (Public Law 93–438) [42 U.S.C. 5801 et seq.], the Department of Energy Organization Act (42 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.), and titles XX through XXIII of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13401 et seq., 13451 et seq., 13501 et seq., 13521 et seq.], the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Board established under section 2302 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13522], shall transmit to the Congress, on or before June 30, 1975, a comprehensive plan for energy research, development, and demonstration. This plan shall be appropriately revised annually as provided in section 5914(a) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title. Such plan shall be designed to achieve—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5905_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5905_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Based upon the comprehensive plan developed under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the Advisory Board established under section 2302 of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 [42 U.S.C. 13522], shall develop and transmit to the Congress, on or before September 1, 1978, a comprehensive environment and safety program to insure the full consideration and evaluation of all environmental, health, and safety impacts of each element, program, or initiative contained in the nuclear and nonnuclear energy research, development, and demonstration plans. Such program shall be updated and transmitted to the Congress annually as part of the report required under section 5914 1 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>