<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5907a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5907a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5907a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5907a"><akn:num>5907a</akn:num><akn:heading>Small grant program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5907a. Small grant program(a) EstablishmentThere shall be established within the Department of Energy a program for appropriate technology under the direction of the Secretary. The Secretary shall develop and implement a program of small grants for the purpose of encouraging development and demonstration projects described in subsection (c) of this section.


(b) LimitationThe aggregate amount of financial support made available to any participant in such program, including affiliates, under this section shall not exceed $50,000 during any two-year period.


(c) Systems and technologies to be developed and demonstratedFunds made available under this section shall be used to provide for a coordinated and expanded effort for the development and demonstration of, and the dissemination of information with respect to, energy-related systems and supporting technologies appropriate to—(1) the needs of local communities and the enhancement of community self-reliance through the use of available resources;

(2) the use of renewable resources and the conservation of nonrenewable resources;

(3) the use of existing technologies applied to novel situations and uses;

(4) applications which are energy-conserving, environmentally sound, small scale, durable and low cost; and

(5) applications which demonstrate simplicity of installation, operation and maintenance.


(d) Eligible participants; simplified application procedures; report to Secretary; allocation criteria; guidelines(1) Grants, agreements or contracts under this section may be made to individuals, local nonprofit organizations and institutions, State and local agencies, Indian tribes and small businesses. The Secretary shall develop simplified procedures with respect to application for support under this section.

(2) Each grant, agreement or contract under this section shall be governed by the provisions of section 9 of the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 [42 U.S.C. 5908] and shall co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be established within the Department of Energy a program for appropriate technology under the direction of the Secretary. The Secretary shall develop and implement a program of small grants for the purpose of encouraging development and demonstration projects described in subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation The aggregate amount of financial support made available to any participant in such program, including affiliates, under this section shall not exceed $50,000 during any two-year period.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Systems and technologies to be developed and demonstrated</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Systems and technologies to be developed and demonstrated Funds made available under this section shall be used to provide for a coordinated and expanded effort for the development and demonstration of, and the dissemination of information with respect to, energy-related systems and supporting technologies appropriate to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible participants; simplified application procedures; report to Secretary; allocation criteria; guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible participants; simplified application procedures; report to Secretary; allocation criteria; guidelines</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5907a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reports to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Reports to Congress The Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>