<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5908" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5908/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5908/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5908"><akn:num>5908</akn:num><akn:heading>Patents and inventions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5908. Patents and inventions(a) Vesting of title to invention and issuance of patents to United States; prerequisitesWhenever any invention is made or conceived in the course of or under any contract of the Department, other than nuclear energy research, development, and demonstration pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.) and the Secretary determines that—(1) the person who made the invention was employed or assigned to perform research, development, or demonstration work and the invention is related to the work he was employed or assigned to perform, or that it was within the scope of his employment duties, whether or not it was made during working hours, or with a contribution by the Government of the use of Government facilities, equipment, materials, allocated funds, information proprietary to the Government, or services of Government employees during working hours; or

(2) the person who made the invention was not employed or assigned to perform research, development, or demonstration work, but the invention is nevertheless related to the contract or to the work or duties he was employed or assigned to perform, and was made during working hours, or with a contribution from the Government of the sort referred to in clause (1).11 So in original. Probably should be a comma.


title to such invention shall vest in the United States, and if patents on such invention are issued they shall be issued to the United States, unless in particular circumstances the Secretary waives all or any part of the rights of the United States to such invention in conformity with the provisions of this section.

(b) Contract as requiring report to Department of invention, etc., made in course of contractEach contract entered into by the Department with any person shall contain effective provisions under which such person shall furnish promptly to the Department a written report containing full and complete technical information concerning any invention, d</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Vesting of title to invention and issuance of patents to United States; prerequisites</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Vesting of title to invention and issuance of patents to United States; prerequisites Whenever any invention is made or conceived in the course of or under any contract of the Department, other than nuclear energy research, development, and demonstration pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (42 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.) and the Secretary determines that— title to such invention shall vest in the United States, and if patents on such invention are issued they shall be issued to the United States, unless in particular circumstances the Secretary waives all or any part of the rights of the United States to such invention in conformity with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contract as requiring report to Department of invention, etc., made in course of contract</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contract as requiring report to Department of invention, etc., made in course of contract Each contract entered into by the Department with any person shall contain effective provisions under which such person shall furnish promptly to the Department a written report containing full and complete technical information concerning any invention, discovery, improvement, or innovation which may be made in the course of or under such contract.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver by Secretary of rights of United States; regulations prescribing procedures; record of waiver determinations; objectives</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver by Secretary of rights of United States; regulations prescribing procedures; record of waiver determinations; objectives Under such regulations in conformity with the provisions of this section as the Secretary shall prescribe, the Secretary may waive all or any part of the rights of the United States under this section with respect to any invention or class of inventions made or which may be made by any person or class of persons in the course of or under any contract of the Department if he determines that the interests of the United States and the general public will be best served by such waiver. The Department shall maintain a publicly available, periodically updated record of waiver determinations. In making such determinations, the Secretary shall have the following objectives:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations applicable at time of contracting for waiver determination by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Considerations applicable at time of contracting for waiver determination by Secretary In determining whether a waiver to the contractor at the time of contracting will best serve the interests of the United States and the general public, the Secretary shall specifically include as considerations—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Considerations applicable to identified invention for waiver determination by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Considerations applicable to identified invention for waiver determination by Secretary In determining whether a waiver to the contractor or inventor or rights to an identified invention will best serve the interests of the United States and the general public, the Secretary shall specifically include as considerations paragraphs (4) through (11) of subsection (d) as applied to the invention and—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights subject to reservation where title to invention vested in United States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Rights subject to reservation where title to invention vested in United States Whenever title to an invention is vested in the United States, there may be reserved to the contractor or inventor—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>to (i) Repealed. Pub. L. 96–517, § 7(c), Dec. 12, 1980, 94 Stat. 3027</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) to (i) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small business status of applicant for waiver or licenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Small business status of applicant for waiver or licenses The Secretary shall, in granting waivers or licenses, consider the small business status of the applicant.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_k"><akn:num>(k)</akn:num><akn:heading>Protection of invention, etc., rights by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(k) Protection of invention, etc., rights by Secretary The Secretary is authorized to take all suitable and necessary steps to protect any invention or discovery to which the United States holds title, and to require that contractors or persons who acquire rights to inventions under this section protect such inventions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5908_l"><akn:num>(l)</akn:num><akn:heading>Department as defense agency of United States for purpose of maintaining secrecy of inventions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(l) Department as defense agency of United States for purpose of maintaining secrecy of inventions The Department shall be considered a defense agency of the United States for the purpose of chapter 17 of title 35.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>