<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5912" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5912/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/5912/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_5912"><akn:num>5912</akn:num><akn:heading>Water resource assessments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 5912. Water resource assessments(a) Assessments by Water Resources Council of water resource requirements and water supply availability for nonnuclear energy technologies; preparation requirementsThe Water Resources Council shall undertake assessments of water resource requirements and water supply availability for any nonnuclear energy technology and any probable combinations of technologies which are the subject of Federal research and development efforts authorized by this chapter, and the commercial development of which could have significant impacts on water resources. In the preparation of its assessment, the Council shall—(1) utilize to the maximum extent practicable data on water supply and demand available in the files of member agencies of the Council;

(2) collect and compile any additional data it deems necessary for complete and accurate assessments;

(3) give full consideration to the constraints upon availability imposed by treaty, compact, court decree, State water laws, and water rights granted pursuant to State and Federal law;

(4) assess the effects of development of such technology on water quality;

(5) include estimates of cost associated with production and management of the required water supply, and the cost of disposal of waste water generated by the proposed facility or process;

(6) assess the environmental, social, and economic impact of any change in use of currently utilized water resource that may be required by the proposed facility or process; and

(7) consult with the Council on Environmental Quality.


(b) Request by Secretary that Water Resources Council prepare assessment of availability of adequate water resources for proposed demonstration projects; report; publicationFor any proposed demonstration project which may involve a significant impact on water resources, the Secretary shall, as a precondition of Federal assistance to that proj­ect, request the Water Resources Council to prepare an assessment of water requirements </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessments by Water Resources Council of water resource requirements and water supply availability for nonnuclear energy technologies; preparation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Assessments by Water Resources Council of water resource requirements and water supply availability for nonnuclear energy technologies; preparation requirements The Water Resources Council shall undertake assessments of water resource requirements and water supply availability for any nonnuclear energy technology and any probable combinations of technologies which are the subject of Federal research and development efforts authorized by this chapter, and the commercial development of which could have significant impacts on water resources. In the preparation of its assessment, the Council shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Request by Secretary that Water Resources Council prepare assessment of availability of adequate water resources for proposed demonstration projects; report; publication</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Request by Secretary that Water Resources Council prepare assessment of availability of adequate water resources for proposed demonstration projects; report; publication For any proposed demonstration project which may involve a significant impact on water resources, the Secretary shall, as a precondition of Federal assistance to that proj­ect, request the Water Resources Council to prepare an assessment of water requirements and availability for such project. A report on the assessment shall be published in the Federal Register for public review thirty days prior to the expenditure of Federal funds on the demonstration.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Assessment by Water Resources Council of availability of adequate water resources as precondition for Federal assistance for commercial application of nonnuclear energy technologies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Assessment by Water Resources Council of availability of adequate water resources as precondition for Federal assistance for commercial application of nonnuclear energy technologies For any proposed Federal assistance for commercial application of energy technologies pursuant to this chapter, the Water Resource 11 So in original. Probably should be “Resources”. Council shall, as a precondition of such Federal assistance, provide to the Secretary an assessment of the availability of adequate water resources for such commercial application and an evaluation of the environmental, social, and economic impacts of the dedication of water to such uses.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Publication of reports of assessments and evaluations by Water Resources Council in Federal Register; public review and comments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Publication of reports of assessments and evaluations by Water Resources Council in Federal Register; public review and comments Reports of assessments and evaluations prepared by the Council pursuant to subsections (a) and (c) shall be published in the Federal Register and at least ninety days shall be provided for public review and comment. Comments received shall accompany the reports when they are submitted to the Secretary and shall be available to the public.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Inclusion of survey and analysis of regional and national water resource availability in biennial assessment by Water Resources Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Inclusion of survey and analysis of regional and national water resource availability in biennial assessment by Water Resources Council The Council shall include a broad survey and analysis of regional and national water resource availability for energy development in the biennial assessment required by section 1962a–1(a) of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_5912_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretary as member of Water Resources Council</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Secretary as member of Water Resources Council The Secretary shall, upon enactment of this subsection, be a member of the Council.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>