<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/604a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/604a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/604a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_604a"><akn:num>604a</akn:num><akn:heading>Services provided by charitable, religious, or private organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 604a. Services provided by charitable, religious, or private organizations(a) In general(1) State optionsA State may—(A) administer and provide services under the programs described in subparagraphs (A) and (B)(i) of paragraph (2) through contracts with charitable, religious, or private organizations; and

(B) provide beneficiaries of assistance under the programs described in subparagraphs (A) and (B)(ii) of paragraph (2) with certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement which are redeemable with such organizations.


(2) Programs describedThe programs described in this paragraph are the following programs:(A) A State program funded under this part (as amended by section 103(a) of this Act).

(B) Any other program established or modified under title I or II of this Act, that—(i) permits contracts with organizations; or

(ii) permits certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement to be provided to beneficiaries, as a means of providing assistance.




(b) Religious organizationsThe purpose of this section is to allow States to contract with religious organizations, or to allow religious organizations to accept certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement under any program described in subsection (a)(2), on the same basis as any other nongovernmental provider without impairing the religious character of such organizations, and without diminishing the religious freedom of beneficiaries of assistance funded under such program.


(c) Nondiscrimination against religious organizationsIn the event a State exercises its authority under subsection (a), religious organizations are eligible, on the same basis as any other private organization, as contractors to provide assistance, or to accept certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement, under any program described in subsection (a)(2) so long as the programs are implemented consistent with the Establishment Clause of the United States Constitution. Except as provided in subsection (k),</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Religious organizations The purpose of this section is to allow States to contract with religious organizations, or to allow religious organizations to accept certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement under any program described in subsection (a)(2), on the same basis as any other nongovernmental provider without impairing the religious character of such organizations, and without diminishing the religious freedom of beneficiaries of assistance funded under such program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination against religious organizations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Nondiscrimination against religious organizations In the event a State exercises its authority under subsection (a), religious organizations are eligible, on the same basis as any other private organization, as contractors to provide assistance, or to accept certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement, under any program described in subsection (a)(2) so long as the programs are implemented consistent with the Establishment Clause of the United States Constitution. Except as provided in subsection (k), neither the Federal Government nor a State receiving funds under such programs shall discriminate against an organization which is or applies to be a contractor to provide assistance, or which accepts certificates, vouchers, or other forms of disbursement, on the basis that the organization has a religious character.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Religious character and freedom</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Religious character and freedom</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rights of beneficiaries of assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Rights of beneficiaries of assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Employment practices</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Employment practices A religious organization’s exemption provided under section 2000e–1 of this title regarding employment practices shall not be affected by its participation in, or receipt of funds from, programs described in subsection (a)(2).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Nondiscrimination against beneficiaries</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Nondiscrimination against beneficiaries Except as otherwise provided in law, a religious organization shall not discriminate against an individual in regard to rendering assistance funded under any program described in subsection (a)(2) on the basis of religion, a religious belief, or refusal to actively participate in a religious practice.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fiscal accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Fiscal accountability</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Compliance Any party which seeks to enforce its rights under this section may assert a civil action for injunctive relief exclusively in an appropriate State court against the entity or agency that allegedly commits such violation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_604a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on use of funds for certain purposes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Limitations on use of funds for certain purposes No funds provided directly to institutions or organizations to provide services and administer programs under subsection (a)(1)(A) shall be expended for sectarian worship, instruction, or proselytization.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>