<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6104" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6104/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6104/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6104"><akn:num>6104</akn:num><akn:heading>Enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6104. Enforcement(a) Methods of achieving compliance with regulationsThe head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under section 6103 of this title may seek to achieve compliance with any such regulation—(1) by terminating, or refusing to grant or to continue, assistance under the program or activity involved to any recipient with respect to whom there has been an express finding on the record, after reasonable notice and opportunity for hearing, of a failure to comply with any such regulation; or

(2) by any other means authorized by law.


(b) Limitations on termination of, or on refusal to grant or to continue, assistance; disbursement of withheld funds to achiever agenciesAny termination of, or refusal to grant or to continue, assistance under subsection (a)(1) shall be limited to the particular political entity or other recipient with respect to which a finding has been made under subsection (a)(1). Any such termination or refusal shall be limited in its effect to the particular program or activity, or part of such program or activity, with respect to which such finding has been made. No such termination or refusal shall be based in whole or in part on any finding with respect to any program or activity which does not receive Federal financial assistance. Whenever the head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under section 6103 of this title withholds funds pursuant to subsection (a), he may, in accordance with regulations he shall prescribe, disburse the funds so withheld directly to any public or nonprofit private organization or agency, or State or political subdivision thereof, which demonstrates the ability to achieve the goals of the Federal statute author­izing the program or activity while complying with regulations issued under section 6103 of this title.


(c) Advice as to failure to comply with regulation; determination that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary meansNo action may be taken und</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methods of achieving compliance with regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Methods of achieving compliance with regulations The head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under section 6103 of this title may seek to achieve compliance with any such regulation—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on termination of, or on refusal to grant or to continue, assistance; disbursement of withheld funds to achiever agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitations on termination of, or on refusal to grant or to continue, assistance; disbursement of withheld funds to achiever agencies Any termination of, or refusal to grant or to continue, assistance under subsection (a)(1) shall be limited to the particular political entity or other recipient with respect to which a finding has been made under subsection (a)(1). Any such termination or refusal shall be limited in its effect to the particular program or activity, or part of such program or activity, with respect to which such finding has been made. No such termination or refusal shall be based in whole or in part on any finding with respect to any program or activity which does not receive Federal financial assistance. Whenever the head of any Federal department or agency who prescribes regulations under section 6103 of this title withholds funds pursuant to subsection (a), he may, in accordance with regulations he shall prescribe, disburse the funds so withheld directly to any pu</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Advice as to failure to comply with regulation; determination that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Advice as to failure to comply with regulation; determination that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means No action may be taken under subsection (a) until the head of the Federal department or agency involved has advised the appropriate person of the failure to comply with the regulation involved and has determined that compliance cannot be secured by voluntary means.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report to Congressional committees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report to Congressional committees In the case of any action taken under subsection (a), the head of the Federal department or agency involved shall transmit a written report of the circumstances and grounds of such action to the committees of the House of Representatives and the Senate having legislative jurisdiction over the program or activity involved. No such action shall take effect until thirty days after the transmission of any such report.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Injunctions; notice of violations; costs; conditions for actions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Injunctions; notice of violations; costs; conditions for actions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6104_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exhaustion of administrative remedies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Exhaustion of administrative remedies With respect to actions brought for relief based on an alleged violation of the provisions of this chapter, administrative remedies shall be deemed exhausted upon the expiration of 180 days from the filing of an administrative complaint during which time the Federal department or agency makes no finding with regard to the complaint, or upon the day that the Federal department or agency issues a finding in favor of the recipient of financial assistance, whichever occurs first.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>