<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/613" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/613/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/613/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_613"><akn:num>613</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of temporary assistance for needy families and related programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 613. Evaluation of temporary assistance for needy families and related programs(a) Evaluation of the impacts of TANFThe Secretary shall conduct research on the effect of State programs funded under this part and any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 609(a)(7)(B)(i) of this title) on employment, self-sufficiency, child well-being, unmarried births, marriage, poverty, economic mobility, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.


(b) Evaluation of grants to improve child well-being by promoting healthy marriage and responsible fatherhoodThe Secretary shall conduct research to determine the effects of the grants made under section 603(a)(2) of this title on child well-being, marriage, family stability, economic mobility, poverty, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.


(c) Dissemination of informationThe Secretary shall, in consultation with States receiving funds provided under this part, develop methods of disseminating information on any research, evaluation, or study conducted under this section, including facilitating the sharing of information and best practices among States and localities.


(d) State-initiated evaluationsA State shall be eligible to receive funding to evaluate the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 609(a)(7)(B)(i) of this title) if—(1) the State submits to the Secretary a description of the proposed evaluation;

(2) the Secretary determines that the design and approach of the proposed evaluation is rigorous and is likely to yield information that is credible and will be useful to other States; and

(3) unless waived by the Secretary, the State contributes to the cost of the evaluation, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to at least 25 percent of the cost of the proposed evaluation.


(e) Census Bureau research(1) The Bureau of the Census shall implement or enhance household s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of the impacts of TANF</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Evaluation of the impacts of TANF The Secretary shall conduct research on the effect of State programs funded under this part and any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 609(a)(7)(B)(i) of this title) on employment, self-sufficiency, child well-being, unmarried births, marriage, poverty, economic mobility, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Evaluation of grants to improve child well-being by promoting healthy marriage and responsible fatherhood</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Evaluation of grants to improve child well-being by promoting healthy marriage and responsible fatherhood The Secretary shall conduct research to determine the effects of the grants made under section 603(a)(2) of this title on child well-being, marriage, family stability, economic mobility, poverty, and other factors as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Dissemination of information</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Dissemination of information The Secretary shall, in consultation with States receiving funds provided under this part, develop methods of disseminating information on any research, evaluation, or study conducted under this section, including facilitating the sharing of information and best practices among States and localities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>State-initiated evaluations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) State-initiated evaluations A State shall be eligible to receive funding to evaluate the State program funded under this part or any other State program funded with qualified State expenditures (as defined in section 609(a)(7)(B)(i) of this title) if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Census Bureau research</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Census Bureau research</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research and evaluation conducted under this section</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Research and evaluation conducted under this section Research and evaluation conducted under this section designed to determine the effects of a program or policy (other than research conducted under subsection (e)) shall use experimental designs using random assignment or other reliable, evidence-based research methodologies that allow for the strongest possible causal inferences when random assignment is not feasible.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Development of What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Approaches 11 So in original. The word “Projects” is used in text. to Move Welfare Recipients into Work</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Development of What Works Clearinghouse of Proven and Promising Approaches</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_613_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Appropriation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>