<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/615" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/615/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/615/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_615"><akn:num>615</akn:num><akn:heading>Waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 615. Waivers(a) Continuation of waivers(1) Waivers in effect on August 22, 1996(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), if any waiver granted to a State under section 1315 of this title or otherwise which relates to the provision of assistance under a State plan under this part (as in effect on September 30, 1996) is in effect as of August 22, 1996, the amendments made by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (other than by section 103(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996) shall not apply with respect to the State before the expiration (determined without regard to any extensions) of the waiver to the extent such amendments are inconsistent with the waiver.


(B) Financing limitationNotwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning with fiscal year 1996, a State operating under a waiver described in subparagraph (A) shall be entitled to payment under section 603 of this title for the fiscal year, in lieu of any other payment provided for in the waiver.



(2) Waivers granted subsequently(A) In generalExcept as provided in subparagraph (B), if any waiver granted to a State under section 1315 of this title or otherwise which relates to the provision of assistance under a State plan under this part (as in effect on September 30, 1996) is submitted to the Secretary before August 22, 1996, and approved by the Secretary on or before July 1, 1997, and the State demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary that the waiver will not result in Federal expenditures under subchapter IV of this chapter (as in effect without regard to the amendments made by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996) that are greater than would occur in the absence of the waiver, the amendments made by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 (other than by section 103(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Re</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Continuation of waivers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>State option to terminate waiver</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) State option to terminate waiver</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Secretarial encouragement of current waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Secretarial encouragement of current waivers The Secretary shall encourage any State operating a waiver described in subsection (a) to continue the waiver and to evaluate, using random sampling and other characteristics of accepted scientific evaluations, the result or effect of the waiver.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_615_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Continuation of individual waivers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Continuation of individual waivers A State may elect to continue 1 or more individual waivers described in subsection (a).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>