<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/622" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/622/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/622/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_622"><akn:num>622</akn:num><akn:heading>State plans for child welfare services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 622. State plans for child welfare services(a) Joint developmentIn order to be eligible for payment under this subpart, a State must have a plan for child welfare services which has been developed jointly by the Secretary and the State agency designated pursuant to subsection (b)(1), and which meets the requirements of subsection (b).


(b) Requisite features of State plansEach plan for child welfare services under this subpart shall—(1) provide that a State agency will administer or supervise the administration of the plan under this subpart;

(2) provide for coordination between the services provided for children under the plan and the services and assistance provided under division A 11 See References in Text note below. of subchapter XX, under the State program funded under part A, under the State plan approved under subpart 2 of this part, under the State plan approved under the State plan approved 22 So in original. under part E, and under other State programs having a relationship to the program under this subpart, with a view to provision of welfare and related services which will best promote the welfare of such children and their families;

(3) include a description of the services and activities which the State will fund under the State program carried out pursuant to this subpart, and how the services and activities will achieve the purpose of this subpart;

(4) contain a description of—(A) the steps the State will take to provide child welfare services statewide and to expand and strengthen the range of existing services and develop and implement services to improve child outcomes;

(B) the child welfare services staff development and training plans of the State; and

(C) the steps that the State will take to ensure that, with respect to any judicial proceeding involving a child and in which there is an allegation of child abuse or neglect, including a proceeding on dependency, adoption, guardianship, or termination of parental rights, information abo</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_622_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Joint development</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Joint development In order to be eligible for payment under this subpart, a State must have a plan for child welfare services which has been developed jointly by the Secretary and the State agency designated pursuant to subsection (b)(1), and which meets the requirements of subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_622_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requisite features of State plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requisite features of State plans Each plan for child welfare services under this subpart shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_622_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this subpart:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>