<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6241" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6241/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6241/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6241"><akn:num>6241</akn:num><akn:heading>Drawdown and sale of petroleum products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6241. Drawdown and sale of petroleum products(a) Power of SecretaryThe Secretary may drawdown and sell petroleum products in the Reserve only in accordance with the provisions of this section.


(b), (c) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(15)(C), Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2031

(d) Presidential finding prerequisite to drawdown and sale(1) Drawdown and sale of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve may not be made unless the President has found drawdown and sale are required by a severe energy supply interruption or by obligations of the United States under the international energy program.

(2) For purposes of this section, in addition to the circumstances set forth in section 6202(8) of this title, a severe energy supply interruption shall be deemed to exist if the President determines that—(A) an emergency situation exists and there is a significant reduction in supply which is of significant scope and duration;

(B) a severe increase in the price of petroleum products has resulted from such emergency situation; and

(C) such price increase is likely to cause a major adverse impact on the national economy.



(e) Sales procedures(1) The Secretary shall sell petroleum products withdrawn from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve at public sale to the highest qualified bidder in the amounts, for the period, and after a notice of sale considered appropriate by the Secretary, and without regard to Federal, State, or local regulations controlling sales of petroleum products.

(2) The Secretary may cancel in whole or in part any offer to sell petroleum products as part of any drawdown and sale under this section.


(f) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(15)(C), Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2031

(g) Directive to carry out test drawdown and sale(1) The Secretary shall conduct a continuing evaluation of the drawdown and sales procedures. In the conduct of an evaluation, the Secretary is authorized to carry out a test drawdown and sale or exchange of pe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Power of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Power of Secretary The Secretary may drawdown and sell petroleum products in the Reserve only in accordance with the provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>, (c) Repealed. Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(15)(C), Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2031</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) , (c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Presidential finding prerequisite to drawdown and sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Presidential finding prerequisite to drawdown and sale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sales procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Sales procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 106–469, title I, § 103(15)(C), Nov. 9, 2000, 114 Stat. 2031</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Directive to carry out test drawdown and sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Directive to carry out test drawdown and sale</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prevention or reduction of adverse impact of severe domestic energy supply interruptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Prevention or reduction of adverse impact of severe domestic energy supply interruptions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exchange of withdrawn products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Exchange of withdrawn products Notwithstanding any other law, the President may permit any petroleum products withdrawn from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve in accordance with this section to be sold and delivered for refining or exchange outside of the United States, in connection with an arrangement for the delivery of refined petroleum products to the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6241_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchases from Strategic Petroleum Reserve by entities in insular areas of United States and Freely Associated States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Purchases from Strategic Petroleum Reserve by entities in insular areas of United States and Freely Associated States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>