<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6243" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6243/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6243/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6243"><akn:num>6243</akn:num><akn:heading>Records and accounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6243. Records and accounts(a) Preparation and maintenanceThe Secretary may require any person to prepare and maintain such records or accounts as the Secretary, by rule, determines necessary to carry out the purposes of this part.


(b) Audit of operations of storage facilityThe Secretary may audit the operations of any storage facility in which any petroleum product is stored or required to be stored pursuant to the provisions of this part.


(c) Access to and inspection of records or accounts and storage facilitiesThe Secretary may require access to, and the right to inspect and examine, at reasonable times, (1) any records or accounts required to be prepared or maintained pursuant to subsection (a) and (2) any storage facilities subject to audit by the United States under the authority of this part.


(Pub. L. 94–163, title I, § 163, Dec. 22, 1975, 89 Stat. 889; Pub. L. 95–619, title VI, § 691(b)(2), Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3288.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1978—Pub. L. 95–619 substituted “Secretary” for “Administrator”, meaning Administrator of the Federal Energy Administration, wherever appearing.</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6243_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation and maintenance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Preparation and maintenance The Secretary may require any person to prepare and maintain such records or accounts as the Secretary, by rule, determines necessary to carry out the purposes of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6243_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audit of operations of storage facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audit of operations of storage facility The Secretary may audit the operations of any storage facility in which any petroleum product is stored or required to be stored pursuant to the provisions of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6243_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to and inspection of records or accounts and storage facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Access to and inspection of records or accounts and storage facilities The Secretary may require access to, and the right to inspect and examine, at reasonable times, (1) any records or accounts required to be prepared or maintained pursuant to subsection (a) and (2) any storage facilities subject to audit by the United States under the authority of this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>