<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6293" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6293/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6293/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6293"><akn:num>6293</akn:num><akn:heading>Test procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6293. Test procedures(a) General ruleAll test procedures and related determinations prescribed or made by the Secretary with respect to any covered product (or class thereof) which are in effect on March 17, 1987, shall remain in effect until the Secretary amends such test procedures and related determinations under subsection (b).


(b) Amended and new procedures(1) Test procedures.—(A) Amendment.—At least once every 7 years, the Secretary shall review test procedures for all covered products and—(i) amend test procedures with respect to any covered product, if the Secretary determines that amended test procedures would more accurately or fully comply with the requirements of paragraph (3); or

(ii) publish notice in the Federal Register of any determination not to amend a test procedure.


(B) The Secretary may, in accordance with the requirements of this subsection, prescribe test procedures for any consumer product classified as a covered product under section 6292(b) of this title.

(C) The Secretary shall direct the National Institute of Standards and Technology to assist in developing new or amended test procedures.


(2) If the Secretary determines, on his own behalf or in response to a petition by any interested person, that a test procedure should be prescribed or amended, the Secretary shall promptly publish in the Federal Register proposed test procedures and afford interested persons an opportunity to present oral and written data, views, and arguments with respect to such procedures. The comment period shall not be less than 60 days and may be extended for good cause shown to not more than 270 days. In prescribing or amending a test procedure, the Secretary shall take into account such information as the Secretary determines relevant to such procedure, including technological developments relating to energy use or energy efficiency of the type (or class) of covered products involved.

(3) Any test procedures prescribed or amended under this section s</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General rule</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General rule All test procedures and related determinations prescribed or made by the Secretary with respect to any covered product (or class thereof) which are in effect on March 17, 1987, shall remain in effect until the Secretary amends such test procedures and related determinations under subsection (b).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amended and new procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Amended and new procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on certain representations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Restriction on certain representations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Case in which test procedure is not required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Case in which test procedure is not required</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Amendment of standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Amendment of standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6293_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional consumer and commercial products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Additional consumer and commercial products</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>