<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_629c"><akn:num>629c</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotments to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 629c. Allotments to States(a) Indian tribes or tribal consortiaFrom the amount reserved pursuant to section 629f(b)(2) of this title for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each Indian tribe with a plan approved under this subpart an amount that bears the same ratio to such reserved amount as the number of children in the Indian tribe bears to the total number of children in all Indian tribes with State plans so approved, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most current and reliable information available to the Secretary. If a consortium of Indian tribes submits a plan approved under this subpart, the Secretary shall allot to the consortium an amount equal to the sum of the allotments determined for each Indian tribe that is part of the consortium.


(b) TerritoriesFrom the amount described in section 629f(a) of this title for any fiscal year that remains after applying section 629f(b) of this title for the fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each of the jurisdictions of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa an amount determined in the same manner as the allotment to each of such jurisdictions is determined under section 623 of this title.


(c) Other States(1) In generalFrom the amount described in section 629f(a) of this title for any fiscal year that remains after applying section 629f(b) of this title and subsection (b) of this section for the fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each State (other than an Indian tribe) which is not specified in subsection (b) of this section an amount equal to such remaining amount multiplied by the supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits percentage of the State for the fiscal year.


(2) Supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits percentage defined(A) In generalAs used in paragraph (1) of this subsection, the term “supplemental nutrition assistance program benefits percentage” means, with respect to a State and a fiscal ye</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribes or tribal consortia</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Indian tribes or tribal consortia From the amount reserved pursuant to section 629f(b)(2) of this title for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each Indian tribe with a plan approved under this subpart an amount that bears the same ratio to such reserved amount as the number of children in the Indian tribe bears to the total number of children in all Indian tribes with State plans so approved, as determined by the Secretary on the basis of the most current and reliable information available to the Secretary. If a consortium of Indian tribes submits a plan approved under this subpart, the Secretary shall allot to the consortium an amount equal to the sum of the allotments determined for each Indian tribe that is part of the consortium.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Territories</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Territories From the amount described in section 629f(a) of this title for any fiscal year that remains after applying section 629f(b) of this title for the fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot to each of the jurisdictions of Puerto Rico, Guam, the Virgin Islands, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa an amount determined in the same manner as the allotment to each of such jurisdictions is determined under section 623 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Other States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Other States</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reallotments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Reallotments The amount of any allotment to a State under subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section for any fiscal year that the State certifies to the Secretary will not be required for carrying out the State plan under section 629b of this title shall be available for reallotment using the allotment methodology specified in subsection (a), (b), or (c) of this section. Any amount so reallotted to a State is deemed part of the allotment of the State under the preceding provisions of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allotment of funds reserved to support monthly caseworker visits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Allotment of funds reserved to support monthly caseworker visits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>