<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_629f"><akn:num>629f</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations; reservation of certain amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 629f. Authorization of appropriations; reservation of certain amounts(a) AuthorizationIn addition to any amount otherwise made available to carry out this subpart, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subpart $345,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and $420,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.


(b) Reservation of certain amountsFrom the amount specified in subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve amounts as follows:(1) State court improvementsThe Secretary shall reserve $30,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each succeeding fiscal year for grants under section 629h of this title.


(2) Indian tribes or tribal consortiaThe Secretary shall reserve 3 percent for allotment to Indian tribes or tribal consortia in accordance with section 629c(a) of this title.


(3) Support for monthly caseworker visits(A) ReservationThe Secretary shall reserve for allotment in accordance with section 629c(e) of this title $20,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and $26,000,000 for fiscal year 2026 and each succeeding fiscal year.


(B) Use of funds(i) In generalA State to which an amount is paid from amounts reserved under subparagraph (A) shall use the amount to improve the quality of monthly caseworker visits with children who are in foster care under the responsibility of the State, with an emphasis on—(I) reducing caseload ratios and the administrative burden on caseworkers, to improve caseworker decision making on the safety, permanency, and well-being of foster children and on activities designed to increase retention, recruitment, and training of caseworkers;

(II) implementing technology solutions to streamline caseworker duties and modernize systems, ensuring improved efficiency and effectiveness in child welfare services;

(III) improving caseworker safety;

(IV) mental health resources to support caseworker well-being, including peer-to-peer support programs; and

(V) recruitment campaigns aimed </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization In addition to any amount otherwise made available to carry out this subpart, there are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subpart $345,000,000 for fiscal year 2025 and $420,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2029.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reservation of certain amounts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Reservation of certain amounts From the amount specified in subsection (a) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve amounts as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Support for foster family homes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Support for foster family homes Out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary for fiscal year 2018, $8,000,000 for the Secretary to make competitive grants to States, Indian tribes, or tribal consortia to support the recruitment and retention of high-quality foster families to increase their capacity to place more children in family settings, focused on States, Indian tribes, or tribal consortia with the highest percentage of children in non-family settings. The amount appropriated under this subparagraph shall remain available through fiscal year 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>