<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/629k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_629k"><akn:num>629k</akn:num><akn:heading>Reduction of administrative burden</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 629k. Reduction of administrative burden(a) In generalThe Secretary shall reduce the burden of administering this part imposed on the recipients of funds under this part, by—(1) reviewing and revising administrative data collection instruments and forms to eliminate duplication and streamline reporting requirements for the recipients while collecting all data required under this part;

(2) in coordination with activities required under the Paperwork Reduction Act, conducting an analysis of the total number of hours reported by the recipients to comply with paperwork requirements and exploring, in consultation with the recipients, how to reduce the number of hours required for the compliance by at least 15 percent;

(3) collecting input from the recipients with respect to fiscal and oversight requirements and making changes to ensure consistency with standards and guidelines for other Federal formula grant programs based on the input; and

(4) respecting the sovereignty of Indian tribes when complying with this subsection.


(b) Limitation on applicabilitySubsection (a) of this section shall not apply to any reporting or data collection otherwise required by law that would affect the ability of the Secretary to monitor and ensure compliance with State plans approved under this part or ensure that funds are expended consistent with this part.


(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title IV, § 441, as added Pub. L. 118–258, title I, § 106(f)(1), Jan. 4, 2025, 138 Stat. 2952.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThe Paperwork Reduction Act, referred to in subsec. (a)(2), probably means chapter 35 (§ 3501 et seq.) of Title 44, Public Printing and Documents. See Short Title note set out under section 3501 of Title 44.

Statutory Notes and Related Subsidiaries
Effective DateSection effective Oct. 1, 2025, and applicable to payments under this part for calendar quarters beginning on or after such date, with delay permitted if either State legislation or tribal action is required to m</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall reduce the burden of administering this part imposed on the recipients of funds under this part, by—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_629k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on applicability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on applicability Subsection (a) of this section shall not apply to any reporting or data collection otherwise required by law that would affect the ability of the Secretary to monitor and ensure compliance with State plans approved under this part or ensure that funds are expended consistent with this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>