<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6321" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6321/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6321/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6321"><akn:num>6321</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings; purpose; definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6321. Findings; purpose; definitions(a) FindingsCongress finds that—(1) the development and implementation by States of laws, policies, programs, and procedures to conserve and to improve efficiency in the use of energy will have an immediate and substantial effect in reducing the rate of growth of energy demand and in minimizing the adverse social, economic, political, and environmental impacts of increasing energy consumption;

(2) the development and implementation of energy conservation programs by States will most efficiently and effectively minimize any adverse economic or employment impacts of changing patterns of energy use and meet local economic, climatic, geographic, and other unique conditions and requirements of each State; and

(3) the Federal Government has a responsibility to foster and promote comprehensive energy conservation programs and practices by establishing guidelines for such programs and providing overall coordination, technical assistance, and financial support for specific State initiatives in energy conservation.


(b) PurposeIt is the purpose of this part to promote the conservation of energy and reduce the rate of growth of energy demand by authorizing the Secretary to establish procedures and guidelines for the development and implementation of specific State energy conservation programs and to provide Federal financial and technical assistance to States in support of such programs.


(c) DefinitionsIn this part:(1) ApplianceThe term “appliance” means any article, such as a room air-conditioner, refrigerator-freezer, or dishwasher, which the Secretary classifies as an appliance for purposes of this part.


(2) BuildingThe term “building” means any structure which includes provision for a heating or cooling system, or both, or for a hot water system.


(3) Energy auditThe term “energy audit” means any process which identifies and specifies the energy and cost savings which are likely to be realized through the purchase and installat</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Findings</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Findings Congress finds that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Purpose It is the purpose of this part to promote the conservation of energy and reduce the rate of growth of energy demand by authorizing the Secretary to establish procedures and guidelines for the development and implementation of specific State energy conservation programs and to provide Federal financial and technical assistance to States in support of such programs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6321_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions In this part:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>