<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6322" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6322/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6322/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6322"><akn:num>6322</akn:num><akn:heading>State energy conservation plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6322. State energy conservation plans(a) Feasibility reportsThe Secretary shall, by rule, within 60 days after December 22, 1975, prescribe guidelines for the preparation of a State energy conservation feasibility report. The Secretary shall invite the Governor of each State to submit, within 3 months after the effective date of such guidelines, such a report. Such report shall include—(1) an assessment of the feasibility of establishing a State energy conservation goal, which goal shall consist of a reduction, as a result of the implementation of the State energy conservation plan described in this section, of 5 percent or more in the total amount of energy consumed in such State in the year 1980 from the projected energy consumption for such State in the year 1980, and

(2) a proposal by such State for the development of a State energy conservation plan to achieve such goal.


(b) GuidelinesThe Secretary shall, by rule, within 6 months after December 22, 1975, prescribe guidelines with respect to measures required to be included in, and guidelines for the development, modification, and funding of, State energy conservation plans. The Secretary shall invite the Governor of each State to submit, within 5 months after the effective date of such guidelines, a report. Such report shall include—(1) a proposed State energy conservation plan designed to result in scheduled progress toward, and achievement of, the State energy conservation goal of such State; and

(2) a detailed description of the requirements, including the estimated cost of implementation and the estimated energy savings, associated with each functional category of energy conservation included in the State energy conservation plan.


(c) Mandatory features of plansEach proposed State energy conservation plan to be eligible for Federal assistance under this part shall include—(1) mandatory lighting efficiency standards for public buildings (except public buildings owned or leased by the United States);
</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Feasibility reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Feasibility reports The Secretary shall, by rule, within 60 days after December 22, 1975, prescribe guidelines for the preparation of a State energy conservation feasibility report. The Secretary shall invite the Governor of each State to submit, within 3 months after the effective date of such guidelines, such a report. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Guidelines</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Guidelines The Secretary shall, by rule, within 6 months after December 22, 1975, prescribe guidelines with respect to measures required to be included in, and guidelines for the development, modification, and funding of, State energy conservation plans. The Secretary shall invite the Governor of each State to submit, within 5 months after the effective date of such guidelines, a report. Such report shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mandatory features of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mandatory features of plans Each proposed State energy conservation plan to be eligible for Federal assistance under this part shall include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optional features of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Optional features of plans Each proposed State energy conservation plan may include—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standby plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Standby plans The Governor of any State may submit to the Secretary a State energy conservation plan which is a standby energy conservation plan to significantly reduce energy demand by regulating the public and private consumption of energy during a severe energy supply interruption, which plan may be separately eligible for Federal assistance under this part without regard to subsections (c) and (d) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy Technology Commercialization Services Program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Energy Technology Commercialization Services Program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6322_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Review of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Review of plans The Secretary shall, at least once every 3 years, invite the Governor of each State to review and, if necessary, revise the energy conservation plan of such State submitted under subsection (b) or (e). Such reviews should consider the energy conservation plans of other States within the region, and identify opportunities and actions carried out in pursuit of common energy conservation goals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>