<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6325" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6325/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6325/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6325"><akn:num>6325</akn:num><akn:heading>General provisions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6325. General provisions(a) RulesThe Secretary may prescribe such rules as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out his authority under this part.


(b) Departmental consultationIn carrying out the provisions of sections 6322 and 6324 of this title and subsection (a) of section 6323 of this title, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate departments and Federal agencies.


(c) Annual reportThe Secretary shall, as part of the report required under section 7267 of this title, report to the President and the Congress, and shall furnish copies of such report to the Governor of each State, on the operation of the program under this part. Such report shall include an estimate of the energy conservation achieved, the degree of State participation and achievement, a description of innovative conservation programs undertaken by individual States, and the recommendations of the Secretary, if any, for additional legislation.


(d) Duty of Federal Trade Commission to prevent unfair or deceptive practices or acts relating to implementation of energy measuresThe Federal Trade Commission shall (1) cooperate with and assist State agencies which have primary responsibilities for the protection of consumers in activities aimed at preventing unfair and deceptive acts or practices affecting commerce which relate to the implementation of measures likely to conserve, or improve efficiency in the use of, energy, including energy conservation measures and renewable-resource energy measures, and (2) undertake its own program, pursuant to the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.], to prevent unfair or deceptive acts or practices affecting commerce which relate to the implementation of any such measures.


(e) List of energy measures eligible for financial assistance; designation of types and requirements of energy auditsWithin 90 days after August 14, 1976, the Secretary shall—(1) develop, by rule after consultation with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Rules The Secretary may prescribe such rules as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out his authority under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Departmental consultation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Departmental consultation In carrying out the provisions of sections 6322 and 6324 of this title and subsection (a) of section 6323 of this title, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate departments and Federal agencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Annual report The Secretary shall, as part of the report required under section 7267 of this title, report to the President and the Congress, and shall furnish copies of such report to the Governor of each State, on the operation of the program under this part. Such report shall include an estimate of the energy conservation achieved, the degree of State participation and achievement, a description of innovative conservation programs undertaken by individual States, and the recommendations of the Secretary, if any, for additional legislation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duty of Federal Trade Commission to prevent unfair or deceptive practices or acts relating to implementation of energy measures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duty of Federal Trade Commission to prevent unfair or deceptive practices or acts relating to implementation of energy measures The Federal Trade Commission shall (1) cooperate with and assist State agencies which have primary responsibilities for the protection of consumers in activities aimed at preventing unfair and deceptive acts or practices affecting commerce which relate to the implementation of measures likely to conserve, or improve efficiency in the use of, energy, including energy conservation measures and renewable-resource energy measures, and (2) undertake its own program, pursuant to the Federal Trade Commission Act [15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.], to prevent unfair or deceptive acts or practices affecting commerce which relate to the implementation of any such measures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>List of energy measures eligible for financial assistance; designation of types and requirements of energy audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) List of energy measures eligible for financial assistance; designation of types and requirements of energy audits Within 90 days after August 14, 1976, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Authorization of appropriations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6325_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>State Energy Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) State Energy Advisory Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>