<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6342" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6342/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6342/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6342"><akn:num>6342</akn:num><akn:heading>Survey and Registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6342. Survey and Registry(a) Recoverable waste energy inventory program(1) In generalThe Administrator, in cooperation with the Secretary and State energy offices, shall establish a recoverable waste energy inventory program.


(2) SurveyThe program shall include—(A) an ongoing survey of all major industrial and large commercial combustion sources in the United States (as defined by the Administrator) and the sites at which the sources are located; and

(B) a review of each source for the quantity and quality of waste energy produced at the source.



(b) Criteria(1) In generalNot later than 270 days after December 19, 2007, the Administrator shall publish a rule for establishing criteria for including sites in the Registry.


(2) InclusionsThe criteria shall include—(A) a requirement that, to be included in the Registry, a project at the site shall be determined to be economically feasible by virtue of offering a payback of invested costs not later than 5 years after the date of first full project operation (including incentives offered under this part);

(B) standards to ensure that projects proposed for inclusion in the Registry are not developed or used for the primary purpose of making sales of excess electric power under the regulatory provisions of this part; and

(C) procedures for contesting the listing of any source or site on the Registry by any State, utility, or other interested person.



(c) Technical supportOn the request of the owner or operator of a source or site included in the Registry, the Secretary shall—(1) provide to owners or operators of combustion sources technical support; and

(2) offer partial funding (in an amount equal to not more than one-half of total costs) for feasibility studies to confirm whether or not investment in recovery of waste energy or combined heat and power at a source would offer a payback period of 5 years or less.


(d) Registry(1) Establishment(A) In generalNot later than 1 year after December 19, 2007, the Adm</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recoverable waste energy inventory program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recoverable waste energy inventory program</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical support On the request of the owner or operator of a source or site included in the Registry, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Registry</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Registry</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Self-certification</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Self-certification</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>New facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) New facilities As a new energy-consuming industrial facility is developed after December 19, 2007, to the extent the facility may constitute a site with recoverable waste energy that may qualify for inclusion on the Registry, the Administrator may elect to include the facility on the Registry, at the request of the owner, operator, or developer of the facility, on a conditional basis with the site to be removed from the Registry if the development ceases or the site fails to qualify for listing under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Optimum means of recovery</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Optimum means of recovery For each site listed in the Registry, at the request of the owner or operator of the site, the Administrator shall offer, in cooperation with Clean Energy Application Centers operated by the Secretary of Energy, suggestions for optimum means of recovery of value from waste energy stream in the form of electricity, useful thermal energy, or other energy-related products.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Revision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Revision Each annual report of a State under section 8258(a) of title 42 shall include the results of the survey for the State under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6342_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization of appropriations There are authorized to be appropriated to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>