<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6344" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6344/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6344/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6344"><akn:num>6344</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional incentives for recovery, use, and prevention of industrial waste energy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6344. Additional incentives for recovery, use, and prevention of industrial waste energy(a) Consideration of standard(1) In generalNot later than 180 days after the receipt by a State regulatory authority (with respect to each electric utility for which the authority has ratemaking authority), or nonregulated electric utility, of a request from a project sponsor or owner or operator, the State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility shall—(A) provide public notice and conduct a hearing respecting the standard established by subsection (b); and

(B) on the basis of the hearing, consider and make a determination whether or not it is appropriate to implement the standard to carry out the purposes of this part.


(2) Relationship to State lawFor purposes of any determination under paragraph (1) and any review of the determination in any court, the purposes of this section supplement otherwise applicable State law.


(3) Nonadoption of standardNothing in this part prohibits any State regulatory authority or nonregulated electric utility from making any determination that it is not appropriate to adopt any standard described in paragraph (1), pursuant to authority under otherwise applicable State law.



(b) Standard for sales of excess powerFor purposes of this section, the standard referred to in subsection (a) shall provide that an owner or operator of a waste energy recovery project identified on the Registry that generates net excess power shall be eligible to benefit from at least 1 of the options described in subsection (c) for disposal of the net excess power in accordance with the rate conditions and limitations described in subsection (d).


(c) OptionsThe options referred to in subsection (b) are as follows:(1) Sale of net excess power to utilityThe electric utility shall purchase the net excess power from the owner or operator of the eligible waste energy recovery project during the operation of the project under a contract entered into for tha</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of standard</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consideration of standard</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Standard for sales of excess power</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Standard for sales of excess power For purposes of this section, the standard referred to in subsection (a) shall provide that an owner or operator of a waste energy recovery project identified on the Registry that generates net excess power shall be eligible to benefit from at least 1 of the options described in subsection (c) for disposal of the net excess power in accordance with the rate conditions and limitations described in subsection (d).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Options</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Options The options referred to in subsection (b) are as follows:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rate conditions and criteria</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rate conditions and criteria</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedural requirements for consideration and determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Procedural requirements for consideration and determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6344_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Implementation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Implementation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>