<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6363" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6363/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6363/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6363"><akn:num>6363</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal actions with respect to recycled oil</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6363. Federal actions with respect to recycled oil(a) PurposeThe purposes of this section are—(1) to encourage the recycling of used oil;

(2) to promote the use of recycled oil;

(3) to reduce consumption of new oil by promoting increased utilization of recycled oil; and

(4) to reduce environmental hazards and wasteful practices associated with the disposal of used oil.


(b) DefinitionsAs used in this section:(1) the term “used oil” means any oil which has been refined from crude oil, has been used, and as a result of such use has been contaminated by physical or chemical impurities.

(2) The term “recycled oil” means—(A) used oil from which physical and chemical contaminants acquired through use have been removed by re-refining or other processing, or

(B) any blend of oil, consisting of such re-refined or otherwise processed used oil and new oil or additives,


with respect to which the manufacturer has determined, pursuant to the rule prescribed under subsection (d)(1)(A)(i), is substantially equivalent to new oil for a particular end use.

(3) The term “new oil” means any oil which has been refined from crude oil and has not been used, and which may or may not contain additives. Such term does not include used oil or recycled oil.

(4) The term “manufacturer” means any person who re-refines or otherwise processes used oil to remove physical or chemical impurities acquired through use or who blends such re-refined or otherwise processed used oil with new oil or additives.

(5) The term “Commission” means the Federal Trade Commission.


(c) Test procedures for determining substantial equivalency of recycled oil and new oilAs soon as practicable after December 22, 1975, the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop test procedures for the determination of substantial equivalency of re-refined or otherwise processed used oil or blend of oil, consisting of such re-refined or otherwise processed used oil and new oil or additives, with new oil f</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purpose The purposes of this section are—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Definitions As used in this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Test procedures for determining substantial equivalency of recycled oil and new oil</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Test procedures for determining substantial equivalency of recycled oil and new oil As soon as practicable after December 22, 1975, the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop test procedures for the determination of substantial equivalency of re-refined or otherwise processed used oil or blend of oil, consisting of such re-refined or otherwise processed used oil and new oil or additives, with new oil for a particular end use. As soon as practicable after development of such test procedures, the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall report such procedures to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Promulgation of rules prescribing test procedures and labeling standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Promulgation of rules prescribing test procedures and labeling standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Labeling standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Labeling standards Beginning on the effective date of the standards prescribed pursuant to subsection (d)(1)(A)—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6363_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Conformity of acts of Federal officials to Commission rules</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Conformity of acts of Federal officials to Commission rules After the effective date of the rules required to be prescribed under subsection (d)(1)(A), all Federal officials shall act within their authority to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>