<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6371k" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6371k/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6371k/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6371k"><akn:num>6371k</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination of energy retrofitting assistance for schools</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6371k. Coordination of energy retrofitting assistance for schools(a) Definition of schoolIn this section, the term “school” means—(1) an elementary school or secondary school (as defined in section 7801 of title 20);

(2) an institution of higher education (as defined in section 1001(a) of title 20);

(3) a postsecondary vocational institution (as defined in section 1002(c) of title 20);

(4) a school of the defense dependents’ education system under the Defense Dependents’ Education Act of 1978 (20 U.S.C. 921 et seq.) or established under section 2164 of title 10;

(5) a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Education;

(6) a tribally controlled school (as defined in section 2511 of title 25); and

(7) a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 1059c(b) of title 20).


(b) Designation of lead agencyThe Secretary of Energy (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), acting through the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, shall act as the lead Federal agency for coordinating and disseminating information on existing Federal programs and assistance that may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects for schools.


(c) RequirementsIn carrying out coordination and outreach under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—(1) in consultation and coordination with the appropriate Federal agencies, carry out a review of existing programs and financing mechanisms (including revolving loan funds and loan guarantees) available in or from the Department of Agriculture, the Department of Energy, the Department of Education, the Department of the Treasury, the Internal Revenue Service, the Environmental Protection Agency, and other appropriate Federal agencies with jurisdiction over energy financing and facilitation that are currently used or may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects for schools;

(2) </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6371k_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definition of school</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definition of school In this section, the term “school” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6371k_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of lead agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Designation of lead agency The Secretary of Energy (in this section referred to as the “Secretary”), acting through the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, shall act as the lead Federal agency for coordinating and disseminating information on existing Federal programs and assistance that may be used to help initiate, develop, and finance energy efficiency, renewable energy, and energy retrofitting projects for schools.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6371k_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Requirements In carrying out coordination and outreach under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6371k_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Report Not later than 180 days after December 27, 2020, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report describing the implementation of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>