<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6372e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6372e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6372e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6372e"><akn:num>6372e</akn:num><akn:heading>Grants for technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6372e. Grants for technical assistance(a) Authorization of SecretaryThe Secretary may make grants to States and to units of local government and public care institutions in payment of technical assistance program costs for buildings owned by units of local government and public care institutions the applications for which have been approved under section 6372d of this title.


(b) Restriction on use of fundsAmounts made available for purposes of this section (together with any amounts available for such purposes from other Federal sources) may not be used to pay more than 50 percent of technical assistance program costs.


(c) Allocation requirementsGrants made under this section in any State in any year shall be made in accordance with the requirements contained in section 6372g of this title.


(d) Prescription of rules limiting allocations to States for administrative expensesThe Secretary shall prescribe rules limiting the amount of funds allocated to a State which may be expended for administrative expenses by such State.


(Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 400F, as added Pub. L. 95–619, title III, § 311(a), Nov. 9, 1978, 92 Stat. 3252.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6372e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authorization of Secretary The Secretary may make grants to States and to units of local government and public care institutions in payment of technical assistance program costs for buildings owned by units of local government and public care institutions the applications for which have been approved under section 6372d of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6372e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Restriction on use of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Restriction on use of funds Amounts made available for purposes of this section (together with any amounts available for such purposes from other Federal sources) may not be used to pay more than 50 percent of technical assistance program costs.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6372e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Allocation requirements Grants made under this section in any State in any year shall be made in accordance with the requirements contained in section 6372g of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6372e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescription of rules limiting allocations to States for administrative expenses</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Prescription of rules limiting allocations to States for administrative expenses The Secretary shall prescribe rules limiting the amount of funds allocated to a State which may be expended for administrative expenses by such State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>