<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6374d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6374d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6374d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6374d"><akn:num>6374d</akn:num><akn:heading>Studies and reports</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6374d. Studies and reports(a) Methanol study(1) The Secretary shall study methanol plants, including the costs and practicability of such plants, that are—(A) capable of utilizing current domestic supplies of unutilized natural gas;

(B) relocatable; or

(C) suitable for natural gas to methanol conversion by natural gas distribution companies.


(2) For purposes of this subsection, the term “unutilized natural gas” means gas that is available in small remote fields and cannot be economically transported to natural gas pipelines, or gas the quality of which is so poor that extensive and uneconomic pretreatment is required prior to its introduction into the natural gas distribution system.

(3) The Secretary shall submit a report under this subsection to the Committees on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, no later than September 30, 1990.


(b) Omitted

(c) Public participationAdequate opportunity shall be provided for public comment on the reports required by this section before they are submitted to the Congress, and a summary of such comments shall be attached to such reports.


(Pub. L. 94–163, title III, § 400EE, as added Pub. L. 100–494, § 4(a), Oct. 14, 1988, 102 Stat. 2447.)

Editorial Notes

References in TextThis part, referred to in subsec. (b)(1)(A), was in the original “the Alternative Motor Fuels Act of 1988”, Pub. L. 100–494, Oct. 14, 1988, 102 Stat. 2441, which is classified principally to this part. For complete classification of this Act to the Code, see Short Title of 1988 Amendment note set out under section 6201 of this title and Tables.

Codification
Subsec. (b) of this section, which required the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to submit biennially to Congress a report which includes a comprehensive analysis of the environmental impacts associated with the production and use of alternative motor vehicle fue</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6374d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methanol study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Methanol study</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6374d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Omitted</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Omitted</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6374d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public participation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public participation Adequate opportunity shall be provided for public comment on the reports required by this section before they are submitted to the Congress, and a summary of such comments shall be attached to such reports.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>