<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6393" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6393/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6393/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6393"><akn:num>6393</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative procedure and judicial review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6393. Administrative procedure and judicial review(a)(1) Subject to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of this subsection, the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 shall apply to any rule, regulation, or order having the applicability and effect of a rule as defined in section 551(4) of title 5 issued under title I (other than section 103 11 See References in Text note below. thereof) and title II of this Act, or this title 1 (other than any provision of such titles which amends another law).

(2)(A) Notice of any proposed rule, regulation, or order described in paragraph (1) which is substantive and of general applicability shall be given by publication of such proposed rule, regulation, or order in the Federal Register. In each case, a minimum of 30 days following the date of such publication and prior to the effective date of the rule shall be provided for opportunity to comment; except that the 30-day period for opportunity to comment prior to the effective date of the rule may be—(i) reduced to no less than 10 days if the President finds that strict compliance would seriously impair the operation of the program to which such rule, regulation, or order relates and such findings are set out in such rule, regulation, or order, or

(ii) waived entirely, if the President finds that such waiver is necessary to act expeditiously during an emergency affecting the national security of the United States.


(B) Public notice of any rule, regulation, or order which is substantive and of general applicability which is promulgated by officers of a State or political subdivision thereof or to State or local boards which have been delegated authority pursuant to title I or II of this Act or this title (other than any provision of such title) 22 So in original. The closing parenthesis probably should follow “another law”. which amend 33 So in original. Probably should be “amends”. another law shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be achieved by publication of suc</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(a)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(b) The procedures for judicial review established by section 211 of the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970 shall apply to proceedings to which subsection (a) applies, as if such proceedings took place under such Act. Such procedures for judicial review shall apply notwithstanding the expiration of the Economic Stabilization Act of 1970.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6393_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Any agency authorized to issue any rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a)(1) shall, upon written request of any person, which request is filed after any grant or denial of a request for exception or exemption from any such rule, regulation, or order, furnish such person, within 30 days after the date on which such request is filed, with a written opinion setting forth applicable facts and the legal basis in support of such grant or denial.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>