<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6422" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6422/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6422/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6422"><akn:num>6422</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedure for Congressional consideration of certain authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6422. Expedited procedure for Congressional consideration of certain authorities(a) Contingency plan identification number; transmittal of plan to CongressAny contingency plan transmitted to the Congress pursuant to section 6261(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall bear an identification number and shall be transmitted to both Houses of Congress on the same day and to each House while it is in session.


(b) Necessity of Congressional resolution within certain period for plan to be considered approved(1) No such energy conservation contingency plan may be considered approved for purposes of section 6261(b) 1 of this title unless between the date of transmittal and the end of the first period of 60 calendar days of continuous session of Congress after the date on which such action is transmitted to such House, each House of Congress passes a resolution described in subsection (d)(2)(A).

(2)(A) Subject to subparagraph (B), any such rationing contingency plan shall be considered approved for purposes of section 6261(d) 1 of this title only if such plan is not disapproved by a resolution described in subsection (d)(2)(B)(i) which passes each House of the Congress during the 30-calendar-day period of continuous session after the plan is transmitted to such Houses and which thereafter becomes law.

(B) A rationing contingency plan may be considered approved prior to the expiration of the 30-calendar-day period after such plan is transmitted if a resolution described in subsection (d)(2)(B)(ii) is passed by each House of the Congress and thereafter becomes law.



(c) Computation of periodFor the purpose of subsection (b) of this section—(1) continuity of session is broken only by an adjournment of Congress sine die; and

(2) the days on which either House is not in session because of an adjournment of more than 3 days to a day certain are excluded in the computation of the calendar-day period involved.


(d) Resolution with respect to conting</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6422_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contingency plan identification number; transmittal of plan to Congress</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Contingency plan identification number; transmittal of plan to Congress Any contingency plan transmitted to the Congress pursuant to section 6261(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title shall bear an identification number and shall be transmitted to both Houses of Congress on the same day and to each House while it is in session.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6422_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Necessity of Congressional resolution within certain period for plan to be considered approved</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Necessity of Congressional resolution within certain period for plan to be considered approved</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6422_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Computation of period For the purpose of subsection (b) of this section—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6422_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resolution with respect to contingency plan</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Resolution with respect to contingency plan</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>