<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6506a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6506a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6506a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6506a"><akn:num>6506a</akn:num><akn:heading>Competitive leasing of oil and gas</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6506a. Competitive leasing of oil and gas(a) In generalThe Secretary shall conduct an expeditious program of competitive leasing of oil and gas in the Reserve in accordance with this Act.


(b) Mitigation of adverse effectsActivities undertaken pursuant to this Act shall include or provide for such conditions, restrictions, and prohibitions as the Secretary deems necessary or appropriate to mitigate reasonably foreseeable and significantly adverse effects on the surface resources of the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska.


(c) Land use planning; BLM wilderness studyThe provisions of section 1712 and section 1782 of title 43 shall not be applicable to the Reserve.


(d) First lease saleThe; 11 So in original. first lease sale shall be conducted within twenty months of December 12, 1980: Provided, That the first lease sale shall be conducted only after publication of a final environmental impact statement if such is deemed necessary under the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).


(e) WithdrawalsThe withdrawals established by section 6502 of this title are rescinded for the purposes of the oil and gas leasing program authorized under this section.


(f) Bidding systemsBidding systems used in lease sales shall be based on bidding systems included in section 205(a)(1)(A) through (H) 22 See References in Text note below. of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act Amendments of 1978 (92 Stat. 629).


(g) Geological structuresLease tracts may encompass identified geological structures.


(h) Size of lease tractsThe size of lease tracts may be up to sixty thousand acres, as determined by the Secretary.


(i) Terms(1) In generalEach lease shall be issued for an initial period of not more than 10 years, and shall be extended for so long thereafter as oil or gas is produced from the lease in paying quantities, oil or gas is capable of being produced in paying quantities, or drilling or reworking operations, as approved by the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general The Secretary shall conduct an expeditious program of competitive leasing of oil and gas in the Reserve in accordance with this Act.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mitigation of adverse effects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Mitigation of adverse effects Activities undertaken pursuant to this Act shall include or provide for such conditions, restrictions, and prohibitions as the Secretary deems necessary or appropriate to mitigate reasonably foreseeable and significantly adverse effects on the surface resources of the National Petroleum Reserve in Alaska.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Land use planning; BLM wilderness study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Land use planning; BLM wilderness study The provisions of section 1712 and section 1782 of title 43 shall not be applicable to the Reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>First lease sale</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) First lease sale The; 11 So in original. first lease sale shall be conducted within twenty months of December 12, 1980: Provided, That the first lease sale shall be conducted only after publication of a final environmental impact statement if such is deemed necessary under the provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawals</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawals The withdrawals established by section 6502 of this title are rescinded for the purposes of the oil and gas leasing program authorized under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Bidding systems</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Bidding systems Bidding systems used in lease sales shall be based on bidding systems included in section 205(a)(1)(A) through (H) 22 See References in Text note below. of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act Amendments of 1978 (92 Stat. 629).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Geological structures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Geological structures Lease tracts may encompass identified geological structures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Size of lease tracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Size of lease tracts The size of lease tracts may be up to sixty thousand acres, as determined by the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Terms</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6506a_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Unit agreements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Unit agreements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>