<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6615b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6615b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6615b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6615b"><akn:num>6615b</akn:num><akn:heading>Quadrennial science and technology review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6615b. Quadrennial science and technology review(a) Requirements(1) Quadrennial reviews requiredNot later than December 31, 2023, and every four years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall complete a review of the science and technology enterprise of the United States (in this section referred to as the “quadrennial science and technology review”).


(2) ScopeThe quadrennial science and technology review shall be a comprehensive examination of the science and technology strategy of the United States, including recommendations for maintaining global leadership in science and technology and advancing science and technology to address the societal and national challenges and guidance regarding the coordination of programs, assets, capabilities, budget, policies, and authorities across all Federal research and development programs.


(3) ConsultationThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall conduct each quadrennial science and technology review in consultation with the following:(A) The National Science and Technology Council.

(B) The President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology.

(C) The National Science Board.

(D) The National Security Council.

(E) The heads of other relevant Federal agencies.

(F) Other relevant governmental and nongovernmental entities, including representatives from industry, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, Members of Congress, and other policy experts.


(4) CoordinationThe Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall ensure that each quadrennial science and technology review is coordinated with other relevant statutorily required reviews, and to the maximum extent practicable incorporates information and recommendations from existing reviews to avoid duplication.



(b) ContentsIn each quadrennial science and technology review, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall—(1) provide an integrated view</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6615b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6615b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Contents In each quadrennial science and technology review, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6615b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Reporting</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Reporting</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6615b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Termination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Termination This section shall terminate on the date that is ten years after August 9, 2022.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>