<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/664" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/664/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/664/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_664"><akn:num>664</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection of past-due support from Federal tax refunds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 664. Collection of past-due support from Federal tax refunds(a) Procedures applicable; distribution(1) Upon receiving notice from a State agency administering a plan approved under this part that a named individual owes past-due support which has been assigned to such State pursuant to section 608(a)(3) or section 671(a)(17) of this title, the Secretary of the Treasury shall determine whether any amounts, as refunds of Federal taxes paid, are payable to such individual (regardless of whether such individual filed a tax return as a married or unmarried individual). If the Secretary of the Treasury finds that any such amount is payable, he shall withhold from such refunds an amount equal to the past-due support, shall concurrently send notice to such individual that the withholding has been made (including in or with such notice a notification to any other person who may have filed a joint return with such individual of the steps which such other person may take in order to secure his or her proper share of the refund), and shall pay such amount to the State agency (together with notice of the individual’s home address) for distribution in accordance with section 657 of this title. This subsection may be executed by the disbursing official of the Department of the Treasury.

(2)(A) Upon receiving notice from a State agency administering a plan approved under this part that a named individual owes past-due support which such State has agreed to collect under paragraph (4)(A)(ii) or (32) of section 654 of this title, and that the State agency has sent notice to such individual in accordance with paragraph (3)(A), the Secretary of the Treasury shall determine whether any amounts, as refunds of Federal taxes paid, are payable to such individual (regardless of whether such individual filed a tax return as a married or unmarried individual). If the Secretary of the Treasury finds that any such amount is payable, he shall withhold from such refunds an amount equal to such </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures applicable; distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Procedures applicable; distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations; contents, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Regulations; contents, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Past-due support” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) “Past-due support” defined In this part the term “past-due support” means the amount of a delinquency, determined under a court order, or an order of an administrative process established under State law, for support and maintenance of a child (whether or not a minor), or of a child (whether or not a minor) and the parent with whom the child is living.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_664_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability to Indian tribes and tribal organizations receiving a grant under this part</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Applicability to Indian tribes and tribal organizations receiving a grant under this part This section, except for the requirement to distribute amounts in accordance with section 657 of this title, shall apply to an Indian tribe or tribal organization receiving a grant under section 655(f) of this title in the same manner in which this section applies to a State with a plan approved under this part.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>