<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/666" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/666/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/666/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_666"><akn:num>666</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of statutorily prescribed procedures to improve effectiveness of child support enforceme</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 666. Requirement of statutorily prescribed procedures to improve effectiveness of child support enforcement(a) Types of procedures requiredIn order to satisfy section 654(20)(A) of this title, each State must have in effect laws requiring the use of the following procedures, consistent with this section and with regulations of the Secretary, to increase the effectiveness of the program which the State administers under this part:(1)(A) Procedures described in subsection (b) for the withholding from income of amounts payable as support in cases subject to enforcement under the State plan.

(B) Procedures under which the income of a person with a support obligation imposed by a support order issued (or modified) in the State before January 1, 1994, if not otherwise subject to withholding under subsection (b), shall become subject to withholding as provided in subsection (b) if arrearages occur, without the need for a judicial or administrative hearing.


(2) Expedited administrative and judicial procedures (including the procedures specified in subsection (c)) for establishing paternity and for establishing, modifying, and enforcing support obligations. The Secretary may waive the provisions of this paragraph with respect to one or more political subdivisions within the State on the basis of the effectiveness and timeliness of support order issuance and enforcement or paternity establishment within the political subdivision (in accordance with the general rule for exemptions under subsection (d)).

(3) Procedures under which the State child support enforcement agency shall request, and the State shall provide, that for the purpose of enforcing a support order under any State plan approved under this part—(A) any refund of State income tax which would otherwise be payable to a noncustodial parent will be reduced, after notice has been sent to that noncustodial parent of the proposed reduction and the procedures to be followed to contest it (and after full compliance </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of procedures required</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Types of procedures required In order to satisfy section 654(20)(A) of this title, each State must have in effect laws requiring the use of the following procedures, consistent with this section and with regulations of the Secretary, to increase the effectiveness of the program which the State administers under this part: Notwithstanding section 654(20)(B) of this title, the procedures which are required under paragraphs (3), (4), (6), (7), and (15) need not be used or applied in cases where the State determines (using guidelines which are generally available within the State and which take into account the payment record of the noncustodial parent, the availability of other remedies, and other relevant considerations) that such use or application would not carry out the purposes of this part or would be otherwise inappropriate in the circumstances.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withholding from income of amounts payable as support</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Withholding from income of amounts payable as support The procedures referred to in subsection (a)(1)(A) (relating to the withholding from income of amounts payable as support) must provide for the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Expedited procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Expedited procedures The procedures specified in this subsection are the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Exemption of States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Exemption of States If a State demonstrates to the satisfaction of the Secretary, through the presentation to the Secretary of such data pertaining to caseloads, processing times, administrative costs, and average support collections, and such other data or estimates as the Secretary may specify, that the enactment of any law or the use of any procedure or procedures required by or pursuant to this section will not increase the effectiveness and efficiency of the State child support enforcement program, the Secretary may exempt the State, subject to the Secretary’s continuing review and to termination of the exemption should circumstances change, from the requirement to enact the law or use the procedure or procedures involved.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Overdue support” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) “Overdue support” defined For purposes of this section, the term “overdue support” means the amount of a delinquency pursuant to an obligation determined under a court order, or an order of an administrative process established under State law, for support and maintenance of a minor child which is owed to or on behalf of such child, or for support and maintenance of the noncustodial parent’s spouse (or former spouse) with whom the child is living if and to the extent that spousal support (with respect to such spouse or former spouse) would be included for purposes of section 654(4) of this title. At the option of the State, overdue support may include amounts which otherwise meet the definition in the first sentence of this subsection but which are owed to or on behalf of a child who is not a minor child. The option to include support owed to children who are not minors shall apply independently to each procedure specified under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uniform Interstate Family Support Act</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Uniform Interstate Family Support Act In order to satisfy section 654(20)(A) of this title, each State must have in effect the Uniform Interstate Family Support Act, as approved by the American Bar Association on February 9, 1993, including any amendments officially adopted as of September 30, 2008 by the National Conference of Commissioners on Uniform State Laws.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_666_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Laws voiding fraudulent transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Laws voiding fraudulent transfers In order to satisfy section 654(20)(A) of this title, each State must have in effect—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>