<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/667" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/667/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/667/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_667"><akn:num>667</akn:num><akn:heading>State guidelines for child support awards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 667. State guidelines for child support awards(a) Establishment of guidelines; methodEach State, as a condition for having its State plan approved under this part, must establish guidelines for child support award amounts within the State. The guidelines may be established by law or by judicial or administrative action, and shall be reviewed at least once every 4 years to ensure that their application results in the determination of appropriate child support award amounts.


(b) Availability of guidelines; rebuttable presumption(1) The guidelines established pursuant to subsection (a) shall be made available to all judges and other officials who have the power to determine child support awards within such State.

(2) There shall be a rebuttable presumption, in any judicial or administrative proceeding for the award of child support, that the amount of the award which would result from the application of such guidelines is the correct amount of child support to be awarded. A written finding or specific finding on the record that the application of the guidelines would be unjust or inappropriate in a particular case, as determined under criteria established by the State, shall be sufficient to rebut the presumption in that case.


(c) Technical assistance to States; State to furnish Secretary with copiesThe Secretary shall furnish technical assistance to the States for establishing the guidelines, and each State shall furnish the Secretary with copies of its guidelines.


(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title IV, § 467, as added Pub. L. 98–378, § 18(a), Aug. 16, 1984, 98 Stat. 1321; amended Pub. L. 100–485, title I, § 103(a), (b), Oct. 13, 1988, 102 Stat. 2346.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1988—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 100–485, § 103(b), inserted “, and shall be reviewed at least once every 4 years to ensure that their application results in the determination of appropriate child support award amounts” before period at end.
Subsec. (b). Pub. L. 100–485, § 103(a), designated exi</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment of guidelines; method</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment of guidelines; method Each State, as a condition for having its State plan approved under this part, must establish guidelines for child support award amounts within the State. The guidelines may be established by law or by judicial or administrative action, and shall be reviewed at least once every 4 years to ensure that their application results in the determination of appropriate child support award amounts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of guidelines; rebuttable presumption</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Availability of guidelines; rebuttable presumption</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_667_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance to States; State to furnish Secretary with copies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Technical assistance to States; State to furnish Secretary with copies The Secretary shall furnish technical assistance to the States for establishing the guidelines, and each State shall furnish the Secretary with copies of its guidelines.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>