<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/669" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/669/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/669/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_669"><akn:num>669</akn:num><akn:heading>Collection and reporting of child support enforcement data</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 669. Collection and reporting of child support enforcement data(a) In generalWith respect to each type of service described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall collect and maintain up-to-date statistics, by State, and on a fiscal year basis, on—(1) the number of cases in the caseload of the State agency administering the plan approved under this part in which the service is needed; and

(2) the number of such cases in which the service has actually been provided.


(b) Types of servicesThe statistics required by subsection (a) shall be separately stated with respect to paternity establishment services and child support obligation establishment services.


(c) Types of service recipientsThe statistics required by subsection (a) shall be separately stated with respect to—(1) recipients of assistance under a State program funded under part A or of payments or services under a State plan approved under part E; and

(2) individuals who are not such recipients.


(d) Rule of interpretationFor purposes of subsection (a)(2), a service has actually been provided when the task described by the service has been accomplished.


(Aug. 14, 1935, ch. 531, title IV, § 469, as added Pub. L. 100–485, title I, § 129, Oct. 13, 1988, 102 Stat. 2356; amended Pub. L. 100–647, title VIII, § 8105(6), Nov. 10, 1988, 102 Stat. 3797; Pub. L. 104–193, title I, § 108(c)(16), title III, § 395(d)(2)(E), Aug. 22, 1996, 110 Stat. 2166, 2260; Pub. L. 105–200, title IV, § 407(a), July 16, 1998, 112 Stat. 672.)

Editorial Notes
Amendments1998—Pub. L. 105–200 reenacted section catchline without change, added subsecs. (a) to (c), redesignated former subsec. (c) as (d) and inserted heading, and struck out former subsec. (a) relating to statistics on need for and actual provision of services and subsec. (b) relating to types of services.
1996—Subsec. (a). Pub. L. 104–193, § 108(c)(16), substituted “assistance under State programs funded under part A of this subchapter and for families not receiving su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) In general With respect to each type of service described in subsection (b), the Secretary shall collect and maintain up-to-date statistics, by State, and on a fiscal year basis, on—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Types of services The statistics required by subsection (a) shall be separately stated with respect to paternity establishment services and child support obligation establishment services.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Types of service recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Types of service recipients The statistics required by subsection (a) shall be separately stated with respect to—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_669_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rule of interpretation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Rule of interpretation For purposes of subsection (a)(2), a service has actually been provided when the task described by the service has been accomplished.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>