<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/675" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/675/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/675/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_675"><akn:num>675</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 675. Definitions
As used in this part or part B of this subchapter:(1) The term “case plan” means a written document which meets the requirements of section 675a of this title and includes at least the following:(A) A description of the type of home or institution in which a child is to be placed, including a discussion of the safety and appropriateness of the placement and how the agency which is responsible for the child plans to carry out the voluntary placement agreement entered into or judicial determination made with respect to the child in accordance with section 672(a)(1) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title.

(B) A plan for assuring that the child receives safe and proper care and that services are provided to the parents, child, and foster parents in order to improve the conditions in the parents’ home, facilitate return of the child to his own safe home or the permanent placement of the child, and address the needs of the child while in foster care, including a discussion of the appropriateness of the services that have been provided to the child under the plan. With respect to a child who has attained 14 years of age, the plan developed for the child in accordance with this paragraph, and any revision or addition to the plan, shall be developed in consultation with the child and, at the option of the child, with up to 2 members of the case planning team who are chosen by the child and who are not a foster parent of, or caseworker for, the child. A State may reject an individual selected by a child to be a member of the case planning team at any time if the State has good cause to believe that the individual would not act in the best interests of the child. One individual selected by a child to be a member of the child’s case planning team may be designated to be the child’s advisor and, as necessary, advocate, with respect to the application of the reasonable and prudent parent standard to the child.

(C) The health and education records</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) The term “case plan” means a written document which meets the requirements of section 675a of this title and includes at least the following:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “parents” means biological or adoptive parents or legal guardians, as determined by applicable State law.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “adoption assistance agreement” means a written agreement, binding on the parties to the agreement, between the State agency, other relevant agencies, and the prospective adoptive parents of a minor child which at a minimum (A) specifies the nature and amount of any payments, services, and assistance to be provided under such agreement, and (B) stipulates that the agreement shall remain in effect regardless of the State of which the adoptive parents are residents at any given time. The agreement shall contain provisions for the protection (under an interstate compact approved by the Secretary or otherwise) of the interests of the child in cases where the adoptive parents and child move to another State while the agreement is effective.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “case review system” means a procedure for assuring that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “administrative review” means a review open to the participation of the parents of the child, conducted by a panel of appropriate persons at least one of whom is not responsible for the case management of, or the delivery of services to, either the child or the parents who are the subject of the review.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “legal guardianship” means a judicially created relationship between child and caretaker which is intended to be permanent and self-sustaining as evidenced by the transfer to the caretaker of the following parental rights with respect to the child: protection, education, care and control of the person, custody of the person, and decisionmaking. The term “legal guardian” means the caretaker in such a relationship.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “sex trafficking victim” means a victim of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_675_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>