<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6833" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6833/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6833/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6833"><akn:num>6833</akn:num><akn:heading>Updating State building energy efficiency codes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6833. Updating State building energy efficiency codes(a) Consideration and determination respecting residential building energy codes(1) Not later than 2 years after October 24, 1992, each State shall certify to the Secretary that it has reviewed the provisions of its residential building code regarding energy efficiency and made a determination as to whether it is appropriate for such State to revise such residential building code provisions to meet or exceed CABO Model Energy Code, 1992.

(2) The determination referred to in paragraph (1) shall be—(A) made after public notice and hearing;

(B) in writing;

(C) based upon findings included in such determination and upon the evidence presented at the hearing; and

(D) available to the public.


(3) Each State may, to the extent consistent with otherwise applicable State law, revise the provisions of its residential building code regarding energy efficiency to meet or exceed CABO Model Energy Code, 1992, or may decline to make such revisions.

(4) If a State makes a determination under paragraph (1) that it is not appropriate for such State to revise its residential building code, such State shall submit to the Secretary, in writing, the reasons for such determination, and such statement shall be available to the public.

(5)(A) Whenever CABO Model Energy Code, 1992,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. (or any successor of such code) is revised, the Secretary shall, not later than 12 months after such revision, determine whether such revision would improve energy efficiency in residential buildings. The Secretary shall publish notice of such determination in the Federal Register.

(B) If the Secretary makes an affirmative determination under subparagraph (A), each State shall, not later than 2 years after the date of the publication of such determination, certify that it has reviewed the provisions of its residential building code regarding energy efficiency and made a determination as to whethe</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6833_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration and determination respecting residential building energy codes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Consideration and determination respecting residential building energy codes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6833_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Certification of commercial building energy code updates</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Certification of commercial building energy code updates</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6833_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Extensions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Extensions The Secretary shall permit extensions of the deadlines for the certification requirements under subsections (a) and (b) if a State can demonstrate that it has made a good faith effort to comply with such requirements and that it has made significant progress in doing so.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6833_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Technical assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Technical assistance The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to States to implement the requirements of this section, and to improve and implement State residential and commercial building energy efficiency codes or to otherwise promote the design and construction of energy efficient buildings.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6833_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Availability of incentive funding</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Availability of incentive funding</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>