<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6838" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6838/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6838/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6838"><akn:num>6838</akn:num><akn:heading>Cost-effective codes implementation for efficiency and resilience</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6838. Cost-effective codes implementation for efficiency and resilience(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) Eligible entityThe term “eligible entity” means—(A) a relevant State agency, as determined by the Secretary, such as a State building code agency, State energy office, or Tribal energy office; and

(B) a partnership.


(2) PartnershipThe term “partnership” means a partnership between an eligible entity described in paragraph (1)(A) and 1 or more of the following entities:(A) Local building code agencies.

(B) Codes and standards developers.

(C) Associations of builders and design and construction professionals.

(D) Local and utility energy efficiency programs.

(E) Consumer, energy efficiency, and environmental advocates.

(F) Other entities, as determined by the Secretary.


(3) SecretaryThe term “Secretary” means the Secretary of Energy.



(b) Establishment(1) In generalThe Secretary shall establish within the Building Technologies Office of the Department of Energy a program under which the Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to eligible entities to enable sustained cost-effective implementation of updated building energy codes.


(2) Updated building energy codeAn update to a building energy code under this section, including an amendment that results in increased efficiency compared to the previously adopted building energy code, shall include any update made available after the existing building energy code, even if it is not the most recent updated code available.



(c) Criteria; priorityIn awarding grants under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—(1) consider—(A) prospective energy savings and plans to measure the savings, including utilizing the Environmental Protection Agency Portfolio Manager, the Home Energy Score rating of the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy of the Department of Energy, the Energy Star Building rating methodologies of the Environmental Protection Agency, and other methodologies determined appro</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6838_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6838_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6838_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria; priority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Criteria; priority In awarding grants under subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6838_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligible activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Eligible activities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6838_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization of appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Authorization of appropriations There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $225,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>