<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6865" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6865/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6865/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6865"><akn:num>6865</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on financial assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6865. Limitations on financial assistance(a) Purchase of materials and administration of projects(1) Not more than an amount equal to 15 percent of any grant made by the Secretary under this part may be used for administrative purposes in carrying out duties under this part, except that not more than one-half of such amount may be used by any State for such purposes, and a State may provide in the plan adopted pursuant to subsection (b) for recipients of grants of less than $350,000 to use up to an additional 5 percent of such grant for administration if the State has determined that such recipient requires such additional amount to implement effectively the administrative requirements established by the Secretary pursuant to this part.

(2) The Secretary shall establish energy audit procedures and techniques which (i) meet standards established by the Secretary after consultation with the State Energy Advisory Board established under section 6325(g) of this title, (ii) establish priorities for selection of weatherization measures based on their cost and contribution to energy efficiency, (iii) measure the energy requirement of individual dwellings and the rate of return of the total conservation investment in a dwelling, and (iv) account for interaction among energy efficiency measures.


(b) Allocation, termination or discontinuance by SecretaryThe Secretary shall insure that financial assistance provided under this part will—(1) be allocated within the State or area in accordance with a published State or area plan, which is adopted by such State after notice and a public hearing, describing the proposed funding distributions and recipients;

(2) be allocated, pursuant to such State or area plan, to community action agencies carrying out programs under title II of the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 [42 U.S.C. 2781 et seq.] or to other appropriate and qualified public or nonprofit entities in such State or area so that—(A) funds will be allocated on the basis </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6865_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Purchase of materials and administration of projects</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Purchase of materials and administration of projects</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6865_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Allocation, termination or discontinuance by Secretary</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Allocation, termination or discontinuance by Secretary The Secretary shall insure that financial assistance provided under this part will—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6865_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitations on expenditures; exceptions; annual adjustments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Limitations on expenditures; exceptions; annual adjustments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6865_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary financial assistance to States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Supplementary financial assistance to States Beginning with fiscal year 1992, the Secretary may allocate funds appropriated pursuant to section 6872(b) 33 See References in Text note below. of this title to provide supplementary financial assistance to those States which the Secretary determines have achieved the best performance during the previous fiscal year in achieving the purposes of this part. In making this determination, the Secretary shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6865_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplementary financial assistance to grant recipients</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Supplementary financial assistance to grant recipients</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>