<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6908" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6908/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6908/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6908"><akn:num>6908</akn:num><akn:heading>Small town environmental planning</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6908. Small town environmental planning(a) EstablishmentThe Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (hereafter referred to as the “Administrator”) shall establish a program to assist small communities in planning and financing environmental facilities. The program shall be known as the “Small Town Environmental Planning Program”.


(b) Small Town Environmental Planning Task Force(1) The Administrator shall establish a Small Town Environmental Planning Task Force which shall be composed of representatives of small towns from different areas of the United States, Federal and State governmental agencies, and public interest groups. The Administrator shall terminate the Task Force not later than 2 years after the establishment of the Task Force.

(2) The Task Force shall—(A) identify regulations developed pursuant to Federal environmental laws which pose significant compliance problems for small towns;

(B) identify means to improve the working relationship between the Environmental Protection Agency (hereafter referred to as the Agency) and small towns;

(C) review proposed regulations for the protection of the environmental and public health and suggest revisions that could improve the ability of small towns to comply with such regulations;

(D) identify means to promote regionalization of environmental treatment systems and infrastructure serving small towns to improve the economic condition of such systems and infrastructure; and

(E) provide such other assistance to the Administrator as the Administrator deems appropriate.



(c) Identification of environmental requirements(1) Not later than 6 months after October 6, 1992, the Administrator shall publish a list of requirements under Federal environmental and public health statutes (and the regulations developed pursuant to such statutes) applicable to small towns. Not less than annually, the Administrator shall make such additions and deletions to and from the list as the Administrator deems appropri</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (hereafter referred to as the “Administrator”) shall establish a program to assist small communities in planning and financing environmental facilities. The program shall be known as the “Small Town Environmental Planning Program”.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Town Environmental Planning Task Force</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Small Town Environmental Planning Task Force</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification of environmental requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Identification of environmental requirements</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small Town Ombudsman</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small Town Ombudsman The Administrator shall establish and staff an Office of the Small Town Ombudsman. The Office shall provide assistance to small towns in connection with the Small Town Environmental Planning Program and other business with the Agency. Each regional office shall identify a small town contact. The Small Town Ombudsman and the regional contacts also may assist larger communities, but only if first priority is given to providing assistance to small towns.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Multi-media permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Multi-media permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>“Small town” defined</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) “Small town” defined For purposes of this section, the term “small town” means an incorporated or unincorporated community (as defined by the Administrator) with a population of less than 2,500 individuals.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6908_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Authorization There is authorized to be appropriated the sum of $500,000 to implement this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>