<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6921" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6921/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6921/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6921"><akn:num>6921</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and listing of hazardous waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6921. Identification and listing of hazardous waste(a) Criteria for identification or listingNot later than eighteen months after October 21, 1976, the Administrator shall, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, and after consultation with appropriate Federal and State agencies, develop and promulgate criteria for identifying the characteristics of hazardous waste, and for listing hazardous waste, which should be subject to the provisions of this subchapter, taking into account toxicity, persistence, and degradability in nature, potential for accumulation in tissue, and other related factors such as flammability, corrosiveness, and other hazardous characteristics. Such criteria shall be revised from time to time as may be appropriate.


(b) Identification and listing(1) Not later than eighteen months after October 21, 1976, and after notice and opportunity for public hearing, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations identifying the characteristics of hazardous waste, and listing particular hazardous wastes (within the meaning of section 6903(5) of this title), which shall be subject to the provisions of this subchapter. Such regulations shall be based on the criteria promulgated under subsection (a) and shall be revised from time to time thereafter as may be appropriate. The Administrator, in cooperation with the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry and the National Toxicology Program, shall also identify or list those hazardous wastes which shall be subject to the provisions of this subchapter solely because of the presence in such wastes of certain constituents (such as identified carcinogens, mutagens, or teratagens) 11 So in original. Probably should be “teratogens)”. at levels in excess of levels which endanger human health.

(2)(A) Notwithstanding the provisions of paragraph (1) of this subsection, drilling fluids, produced waters, and other wastes associated with the exploration, development, or production of crude oil or natural</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Criteria for identification or listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Criteria for identification or listing Not later than eighteen months after October 21, 1976, the Administrator shall, after notice and opportunity for public hearing, and after consultation with appropriate Federal and State agencies, develop and promulgate criteria for identifying the characteristics of hazardous waste, and for listing hazardous waste, which should be subject to the provisions of this subchapter, taking into account toxicity, persistence, and degradability in nature, potential for accumulation in tissue, and other related factors such as flammability, corrosiveness, and other hazardous characteristics. Such criteria shall be revised from time to time as may be appropriate.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Identification and listing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Identification and listing</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Petition by State Governor</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Petition by State Governor At any time after the date eighteen months after October 21, 1976, the Governor of any State may petition the Administrator to identify or list a material as a hazardous waste. The Administrator shall act upon such petition within ninety days following his receipt thereof and shall notify the Governor of such action. If the Administrator denies such petition because of financial considerations, in providing such notice to the Governor he shall include a statement concerning such considerations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small quantity generator waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small quantity generator waste</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Specified wastes</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Specified wastes</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Delisting procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Delisting procedures</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>EP toxicity</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) EP toxicity Not later than twenty-eight months after November 8, 1984, the Administrator shall examine the deficiencies of the extraction procedure toxicity characteristic as a predictor of the leaching potential of wastes and make changes in the extraction procedure toxicity characteristic, including changes in the leaching media, as are necessary to insure that it accurately predicts the leaching potential of wastes which pose a threat to human health and the environment when mismanaged.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional characteristics</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Additional characteristics Not later than two years after November 8, 1984, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations under this section identifying additional characteristics of hazardous waste, including measures or indicators of toxicity.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Clarification of household waste exclusion</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Clarification of household waste exclusion A resource recovery facility recovering energy from the mass burning of municipal solid waste shall not be deemed to be treating, storing, disposing of, or otherwise managing hazardous wastes for the purposes of regulation under this subchapter, if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6921_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Methamphetamine production</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Methamphetamine production Not later than every 24 months, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report setting forth information collected by the Administrator from law enforcement agencies, States, and other relevant stakeholders that identifies the byproducts of the methamphetamine production process and whether the Administrator considers each of the byproducts to be a hazardous waste pursuant to this section and relevant regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>