<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6925" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6925/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6925/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6925"><akn:num>6925</akn:num><akn:heading>Permits for treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6925. Permits for treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste(a) Permit requirementsNot later than eighteen months after October 21, 1976, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations requiring each person owning or operating an existing facility or planning to construct a new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter to have a permit issued pursuant to this section. Such regulations shall take effect on the date provided in section 6930 of this title and upon and after such date the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste and the construction of any new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste is prohibited except in accordance with such a permit. No permit shall be required under this section in order to construct a facility if such facility is constructed pursuant to an approval issued by the Administrator under section 2605(e) of title 15 for the incineration of polychlorinated biphenyls and any person owning or operating such a facility may, at any time after operation or construction of such facility has begun, file an application for a permit pursuant to this section authorizing such facility to incinerate hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter.


(b) Requirements of permit applicationEach application for a permit under this section shall contain such information as may be required under regulations promulgated by the Administrator, including information respecting—(1) estimates with respect to the composition, quantities, and concentrations of any hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter, or combinations of any such hazardous waste and any other solid waste, proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored, and the time, frequency, or rate of which such waste is proposed to be disposed of, treated, transported, or stored; and

(2) the site at which such hazardous waste or the </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Permit requirements Not later than eighteen months after October 21, 1976, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations requiring each person owning or operating an existing facility or planning to construct a new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste identified or listed under this subchapter to have a permit issued pursuant to this section. Such regulations shall take effect on the date provided in section 6930 of this title and upon and after such date the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste and the construction of any new facility for the treatment, storage, or disposal of any such hazardous waste is prohibited except in accordance with such a permit. No permit shall be required under this section in order to construct a facility if such facility is constructed pursuant to an approval issued by the Administrator under section 2605(e) of title 15 for the incineration of polychlorinated biphenyls and any person owning or ope</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements of permit application</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Requirements of permit application Each application for a permit under this section shall contain such information as may be required under regulations promulgated by the Administrator, including information respecting—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit issuance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Permit issuance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Permit revocation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Permit revocation Upon a determination by the Administrator (or by a State, in the case of a State having an authorized hazardous waste program under section 6926 of this title) of noncompliance by a facility having a permit under this chapter with the requirements of this section or section 6924 of this title, the Administrator (or State, in the case of a State having an authorized hazardous waste program under section 6926 of this title) shall revoke such permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Interim status</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coal mining wastes and reclamation permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Coal mining wastes and reclamation permits Notwithstanding subsection (a) through (e) of this section, any surface coal mining and reclamation permit covering any coal mining wastes or overburden which has been issued or approved under the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 [30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.] shall be deemed to be a permit issued pursuant to this section with respect to the treatment, storage, or disposal of such wastes or overburden. Regulations promulgated by the Administrator under this subchapter shall not be applicable to treatment, storage, or disposal of coal mining wastes and overburden which are covered by such a permit.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Research, development, and demonstration permits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Research, development, and demonstration permits</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste minimization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Waste minimization Effective September 1, 1985, it shall be a condition of any permit issued under this section for the treatment, storage, or disposal of hazardous waste on the premises where such waste was generated that the permittee certify, no less often than annually, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim status facilities receiving wastes after July 26, 1982</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Interim status facilities receiving wastes after The standards concerning ground water monitoring, unsaturated zone monitoring, and corrective action, which are applicable under section 6924 of this title to new landfills, surface impoundments, land treatment units, and waste-pile units required to be permitted under subsection (c) shall also apply to any landfill, surface impoundment, land treatment unit, or waste-pile unit qualifying for the authorization to operate under subsection (e) which receives hazardous waste after July 26, 1982.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6925_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Interim status surface impoundments</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Interim status surface impoundments</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>