<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939d" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939d/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939d/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6939d"><akn:num>6939d</akn:num><akn:heading>Public vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6939d. Public vessels(a) Waste generated on public vesselsAny hazardous waste generated on a public vessel shall not be subject to the storage, manifest, inspection, or recordkeeping requirements of this chapter until such waste is transferred to a shore facility, unless—(1) the waste is stored on the public vessel for more than 90 days after the public vessel is placed in reserve or is otherwise no longer in service; or

(2) the waste is transferred to another public vessel within the territorial waters of the United States and is stored on such vessel or another public vessel for more than 90 days after the date of transfer.


(b) Computation of storage periodFor purposes of subsection (a), the 90-day period begins on the earlier of—(1) the date on which the public vessel on which the waste was generated is placed in reserve or is otherwise no longer in service; or

(2) the date on which the waste is transferred from the public vessel on which the waste was generated to another public vessel within the territorial waters of the United States;


and continues, without interruption, as long as the waste is stored on the original public vessel (if in reserve or not in service) or another public vessel.

(c) DefinitionsFor purposes of this section:(1) The term “public vessel” means a vessel owned or bareboat chartered and operated by the United States, or by a foreign nation, except when the vessel is engaged in commerce.

(2) The terms “in reserve” and “in service” have the meanings applicable to those terms under section 8663 and sections 8674 through 8678 of title 10 and regulations prescribed under those sections.


(d) Relationship to other lawNothing in this section shall be construed as altering or otherwise affecting the provisions of section 8681 of title 10.


(Pub. L. 89–272, title II, § 3022, as added Pub. L. 102–386, title I, § 106(a), Oct. 6, 1992, 106 Stat. 1513; amended Pub. L. 115–232, div. A, title VIII, § 809(n)(2), Aug. 13, 2018, 132 Stat. 1844.)</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939d_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waste generated on public vessels</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Waste generated on public vessels Any hazardous waste generated on a public vessel shall not be subject to the storage, manifest, inspection, or recordkeeping requirements of this chapter until such waste is transferred to a shore facility, unless—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939d_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Computation of storage period</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Computation of storage period For purposes of subsection (a), the 90-day period begins on the earlier of— and continues, without interruption, as long as the waste is stored on the original public vessel (if in reserve or not in service) or another public vessel.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939d_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Definitions For purposes of this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939d_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Relationship to other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Relationship to other law Nothing in this section shall be construed as altering or otherwise affecting the provisions of section 8681 of title 10.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>