<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939f" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939f/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939f/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6939f"><akn:num>6939f</akn:num><akn:heading>Long-term storage</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6939f. Long-term storage(a) Designation of facility(1) In generalNot later than January 1, 2010, the Secretary of Energy (referred to in this section as the “Secretary”) shall designate a facility or facilities of the Department of Energy, which shall not include the Y–12 National Security Complex or any other portion or facility of the Oak Ridge Reservation of the Department of Energy, for the purpose of long-term management and storage of elemental mercury generated within the United States.


(2) Operation of facilityNot later than January 1, 2019, the facility designated in paragraph (1) shall be operational and shall accept custody, for the purpose of long-term management and storage, of elemental mercury generated within the United States and delivered to such facility.



(b) Fees(1) In general(A) Assessment and collectionAfter consultation with persons who are likely to deliver elemental mercury to a designated facility for long-term management and storage under the program prescribed in subsection (a), and with other interested persons, the Secretary shall assess and collect a fee at the time of delivery for providing such management and storage, based on the pro rata cost of long-term management and storage of elemental mercury delivered to the facility.


(B) AmountThe amount of the fees described in subparagraph (A)—(i) shall be made publicly available not later than October 1, 2018;

(ii) may be adjusted annually;

(iii) shall be set in an amount sufficient to cover the costs described in paragraph (2), subject to clause (iv); and

(iv) for generators temporarily accumulating elemental mercury in a facility subject to subparagraphs (B) and (D)(iv) of subsection (g)(2) if the facility designated in subsection (a) is not operational by January 1, 2019, shall be adjusted to subtract the cost of the temporary accumulation during the period in which the facility designated under subsection (a) is not operational.


(C) Conveyance of title and permittingIf </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Designation of facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Report Not later than 60 days after the end of each Federal fiscal year, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report on all of the costs incurred in the previous fiscal year associated with the long-term management and storage of elemental mercury. Such report shall set forth separately the costs associated with activities taken under this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Management standards for a facility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Management standards for a facility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indemnification of persons delivering elemental mercury</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Indemnification of persons delivering elemental mercury</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms, conditions, and procedures</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Terms, conditions, and procedures The Secretary is authorized to establish such terms, conditions, and procedures as are necessary to carry out this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on other law</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Effect on other law</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939f_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Study Not later than July 1, 2014, the Secretary shall transmit to the Congress the results of a study, conducted in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>