<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939g" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939g/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6939g/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6939g"><akn:num>6939g</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous waste electronic manifest system</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6939g. Hazardous waste electronic manifest system(a) DefinitionsIn this section:(1) BoardThe term “Board” means the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Advisory Board established under subsection (f).


(2) FundThe term “Fund” means the Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Fund established by subsection (d).


(3) PersonThe term “person” includes an individual, corporation (including a Government corporation), company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, trust, municipality, commission, Federal agency, State, political subdivision of a State, or interstate body.


(4) SystemThe term “system” means the hazardous waste electronic manifest system established under subsection (b).


(5) UserThe term “user” means a hazardous waste generator, a hazardous waste transporter, an owner or operator of a hazardous waste treatment, storage, recycling, or disposal facility, or any other person that—(A) is required to use a manifest to comply with any Federal or State requirement to track the shipment, transportation, and receipt of hazardous waste or other material that is shipped from the site of generation to an off-site facility for treatment, storage, disposal, or recycling; and

(B)(i) elects to use the system to complete and transmit an electronic manifest format; or

(ii) submits to the system for data processing purposes a paper copy of the manifest (or data from such a paper copy), in accordance with such regulations as the Administrator may promulgate to require such a submission.




(b) EstablishmentNot later than 3 years after October 5, 2012, the Administrator shall establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system that may be used by any user.


(c) User fees(1) In generalIn accordance with paragraph (4), the Administrator may impose on users such reasonable service fees as the Administrator determines to be necessary to pay costs incurred in developing, operating, maintaining, and upgrading the system, including any co</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section:</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Establishment Not later than 3 years after October 5, 2012, the Administrator shall establish a hazardous waste electronic manifest system that may be used by any user.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>User fees</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) User fees</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Fund</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Fund</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Contracts</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Advisory Board</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Hazardous Waste Electronic Manifest System Advisory Board</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Regulations</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirement of compliance with respect to certain States</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Requirement of compliance with respect to certain States In any case in which the State in which waste is generated, or the State in which waste will be transported to a designated facility, requires that the waste be tracked through a hazardous waste manifest, the designated facility that receives the waste shall, regardless of the State in which the facility is located—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6939g_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authorization for start-up activities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Authorization for start-up activities There are authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2013 through 2015 for start-up activities to carry out this section, to be offset by collection of user fees under subsection (c) such that all such appropriated funds are offset by fees as provided in subsection (c).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>