<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6943" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6943/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6943/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6943"><akn:num>6943</akn:num><akn:heading>Requirements for approval of plans</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6943. Requirements for approval of plans(a) Minimum requirementsIn order to be approved under section 6947 of this title, each State plan must comply with the following minimum requirements—(1) The plan shall identify (in accordance with section 6946(b) of this title) (A) the responsibilities of State, local, and regional authorities in the implementation of the State plan, (B) the distribution of Federal funds to the authorities responsible for development and implementation of the State plan, and (C) the means for coordinating regional planning and implementation under the State plan.

(2) The plan shall, in accordance with sections 6944(b) and 6945(a) of this title, prohibit the establishment of new open dumps within the State, and contain requirements that all solid waste (including solid waste originating in other States, but not including hazardous waste) shall be (A) utilized for resource recovery or (B) disposed of in sanitary landfills (within the meaning of section 6944(a) of this title) or otherwise disposed of in an environmentally sound manner.

(3) The plan shall provide for the closing or upgrading of all existing open dumps within the State pursuant to the requirements of section 6945 of this title.

(4) The plan shall provide for the establishment of such State regulatory powers as may be necessary to implement the plan.

(5) The plan shall provide that no State or local government within the State shall be prohibited under State or local law from negotiating and entering into long-term contracts for the supply of solid waste to resource recovery facilities, from entering into long-term contracts for the operation of such facilities, or from securing long-term markets for material and energy recovered from such facilities or for conserving materials or energy by reducing the volume of waste.

(6) The plan shall provide for such resource conservation or recovery and for the disposal of solid waste in sanitary landfills or any combination of practic</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6943_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Minimum requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Minimum requirements In order to be approved under section 6947 of this title, each State plan must comply with the following minimum requirements—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6943_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Discretionary plan provisions relating to re­cycled oil</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Discretionary plan provisions relating to re­cycled oil Any State plan submitted under this subchapter may include, at the option of the State, provisions to carry out each of the following: Any plan submitted under this chapter before October 15, 1980, may be amended, at the option of the State, at any time after such date to include any provision referred to in this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6943_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Energy and materials conservation and recovery feasibility planning and assistance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Energy and materials conservation and recovery feasibility planning and assistance</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6943_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Size of waste-to-energy facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Size of waste-to-energy facilities Notwithstanding any of the above requirements, it is the intention of this chapter and the planning process developed pursuant to this chapter that in determining the size of the waste-to-energy facility, adequate provision shall be given to the present and reasonably anticipated future needs of the recycling and resource recovery interest within the area encompassed by the planning process.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>