<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6982" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6982/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6982/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6982"><akn:num>6982</akn:num><akn:heading>Special studies; plans for research, development, and demonstrations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6982. Special studies; plans for research, development, and demonstrations(a) Glass and plasticThe Administrator shall undertake a study and publish a report on resource recovery from glass and plastic waste, including a scientific, technological, and economic investigation of potential solutions to implement such recovery.


(b) Composition of waste streamThe Administrator shall undertake a systematic study of the composition of the solid waste stream and of anticipated future changes in the composition of such stream and shall publish a report containing the results of such study and quantitatively evaluating the potential utility of such components.


(c) Priorities studyFor purposes of determining priorities for research on recovery of materials and energy from solid waste and developing materials and energy recovery research, development, and demonstration strategies, the Administrator shall review, and make a study of, the various existing and promising techniques of energy recovery from solid waste (including, but not limited to, waterwall furnace incinerators, dry shredded fuel systems, pyrolysis, densified refuse-derived fuel systems, anerobic digestion, and fuel and feedstock preparation systems). In carrying out such study the Administrator shall investigate with respect to each such technique—(1) the degree of public need for the potential results of such research, development, or demonstration,

(2) the potential for research, development, and demonstration without Federal action, including the degree of restraint on such potential posed by the risks involved, and

(3) the magnitude of effort and period of time necessary to develop the technology to the point where Federal assistance can be ended.


(d) Small-scale and low technology studyThe Administrator shall undertake a comprehensive study and analysis of, and publish a report on, systems of small-scale and low technology solid waste management, including household resource recovery and resource r</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Glass and plastic</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Glass and plastic The Administrator shall undertake a study and publish a report on resource recovery from glass and plastic waste, including a scientific, technological, and economic investigation of potential solutions to implement such recovery.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Composition of waste stream</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Composition of waste stream The Administrator shall undertake a systematic study of the composition of the solid waste stream and of anticipated future changes in the composition of such stream and shall publish a report containing the results of such study and quantitatively evaluating the potential utility of such components.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priorities study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Priorities study For purposes of determining priorities for research on recovery of materials and energy from solid waste and developing materials and energy recovery research, development, and demonstration strategies, the Administrator shall review, and make a study of, the various existing and promising techniques of energy recovery from solid waste (including, but not limited to, waterwall furnace incinerators, dry shredded fuel systems, pyrolysis, densified refuse-derived fuel systems, anerobic digestion, and fuel and feedstock preparation systems). In carrying out such study the Administrator shall investigate with respect to each such technique—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Small-scale and low technology study</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Small-scale and low technology study The Administrator shall undertake a comprehensive study and analysis of, and publish a report on, systems of small-scale and low technology solid waste management, including household resource recovery and resource recovery systems which have special application to multiple dwelling units and high density housing and office complexes. Such study and analysis shall include an investigation of the degree to which such systems could contribute to energy conservation.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Front-end source separation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Front-end source separation The Administrator shall undertake research and studies concerning the compatibility of front-end source separation systems with high technology resource recovery systems and shall publish a report containing the results of such research and studies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mining waste</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Mining waste The Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior, shall conduct a detailed and comprehensive study on the adverse effects of solid wastes from active and abandoned surface and underground mines on the environment, including, but not limited to, the effects of such wastes on humans, water, air, health, welfare, and natural resources, and on the adequacy of means and measures currently employed by the mining industry, Government agencies, and others to dispose of and utilize such solid wastes and to prevent or substantially mitigate such adverse effects. Such study shall include an analysis of— In furtherance of this study, the Administrator shall, as he deems appropriate, review studies and other actions of other Federal agencies concerning such wastes with a view toward avoiding duplication of effort and the need to expedite such study. Not later than thirty-six months after October 21, 1980, the Administrator shall publish a report of such study a</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Sludge</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Sludge The Administrator shall undertake a comprehensive study and publish a report on sludge. Such study shall include an analysis of—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Tires</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Tires The Administrator shall undertake a study and publish a report respecting discarded motor vehicle tires which shall include an analysis of the problems involved in the collection, recovery of resources including energy, and use of such tires.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_i"><akn:num>(i)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource recovery facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(i) Resource recovery facilities The Administrator shall conduct research and report on the economics of, and impediments, to the effective functioning of resource recovery facilities.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6982_j"><akn:num>(j)</akn:num><akn:heading>Resource Conservation Committee</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(j) Resource Conservation Committee</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>