<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991e" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991e/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991e/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6991e"><akn:num>6991e</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal enforcement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6991e. Federal enforcement(a) Compliance orders(1) Except as provided in paragraph (2), whenever on the basis of any information, the Administrator determines that any person is in violation of any requirement of this subchapter, the Administrator may issue an order requiring compliance within a reasonable specified time period or the Administrator may commence a civil action in the United States district court in which the violation occurred for appropriate relief, including a temporary or permanent injunction.

(2) In the case of a violation of any requirement of this subchapter where such violation occurs in a State with a program approved under section 6991c of this title, the Administrator shall give notice to the State in which such violation has occurred prior to issuing an order or commencing a civil action under this section.

(3) If a violator fails to comply with an order under this subsection within the time specified in the order, he shall be liable for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000 for each day of continued noncompliance.


(b) ProcedureAny order issued under this section shall become final unless, no later than thirty days after the order is served, the person or persons named therein request a public hearing. Upon such request the Administrator shall promptly conduct a public hearing. In connection with any proceeding under this section the Administrator may issue subpoenas for the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of relevant papers, books, and documents, and may promulgate rules for discovery procedures.


(c) Contents of orderAny order issued under this section shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation, specify a reasonable time for compliance, and assess a penalty, if any, which the Administrator determines is reasonable taking into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with the applicable requirements.


(d) Civil penalties(1) Any owner who know</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991e_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Compliance orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Compliance orders</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991e_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedure</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Procedure Any order issued under this section shall become final unless, no later than thirty days after the order is served, the person or persons named therein request a public hearing. Upon such request the Administrator shall promptly conduct a public hearing. In connection with any proceeding under this section the Administrator may issue subpoenas for the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of relevant papers, books, and documents, and may promulgate rules for discovery procedures.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991e_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Contents of order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Contents of order Any order issued under this section shall state with reasonable specificity the nature of the violation, specify a reasonable time for compliance, and assess a penalty, if any, which the Administrator determines is reasonable taking into account the seriousness of the violation and any good faith efforts to comply with the applicable requirements.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991e_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Civil penalties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Civil penalties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991e_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Incentive for performance</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Incentive for performance Both of the following may be taken into account in determining the terms of a civil penalty under subsection (d):</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>