<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6991"><akn:num>6991</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions and exemptions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6991. Definitions and exemptions
In this subchapter:(1) Indian tribe.—(A) In general.—The term “Indian tribe” means any Indian tribe, band, nation, or other organized group or community that is recognized as being eligible for special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.

(B) Inclusions.—The term “Indian tribe” includes an Alaska Native village, as defined in or established under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.); and 11 So in original. The semicolon probably should be a period and the word “and” probably should not appear.


(2) The term “nonoperational storage tank” means any underground storage tank in which regulated substances will not be deposited or from which regulated substances will not be dispensed after November 8, 1984.

(3) The term “operator” means any person in control of, or having responsibility for, the daily operation of the underground storage tank.

(4) The term “owner” means—(A) in the case of an underground storage tank in use on November 8, 1984, or brought into use after that date, any person who owns an underground storage tank used for the storage, use, or dispensing of regulated substances and

(B) in the case of any underground storage tank in use before November 8, 1984, but no longer in use on November 8, 1984, any person who owned such tank immediately before the discontinuation of its use.


(5) The term “person” has the same meaning as provided in section 6903(15) of this title, except that such term includes a consortium, a joint venture, and a commercial entity, and the United States Government.

(6) The term “petroleum” means petroleum, including crude oil or any fraction thereof which is liquid at standard conditions of temperature and pressure (60 degrees Fahrenheit and 14.7 pounds per square inch absolute).

(7) The term “regulated substance” means—(A) any substance defined in section 9601(14) of this title (but not including any su</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:heading>Indian tribe.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(1)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) The term “nonoperational storage tank” means any underground storage tank in which regulated substances will not be deposited or from which regulated substances will not be dispensed after November 8, 1984.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) The term “operator” means any person in control of, or having responsibility for, the daily operation of the underground storage tank.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) The term “owner” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) The term “person” has the same meaning as provided in section 6903(15) of this title, except that such term includes a consortium, a joint venture, and a commercial entity, and the United States Government.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) The term “petroleum” means petroleum, including crude oil or any fraction thereof which is liquid at standard conditions of temperature and pressure (60 degrees Fahrenheit and 14.7 pounds per square inch absolute).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) The term “regulated substance” means—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) The term “release” means any spilling, leaking, emitting, discharging, escaping, leaching, or disposing from an underground storage tank into ground water, surface water or subsurface soils.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust fund.—</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(9) The term “Trust Fund” means the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund established by section 9508 of title 26.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) The term “underground storage tank” means any one or combination of tanks (including underground pipes connected thereto) which is used to contain an accumulation of regulated substances, and the volume of which (including the volume of the underground pipes connected thereto) is 10 per centum or more beneath the surface of the ground. Such term does not include any— The term “underground storage tank” shall not include any pipes connected to any tank which is described in subparagraphs (A) through (I).</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>