<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991c" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991c/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/6991c/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_6991c"><akn:num>6991c</akn:num><akn:heading>Approval of State programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 6991c. Approval of State programs(a) Elements of State programBeginning 30 months after November 8, 1984, any State may,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. submit an underground storage tank release detection, prevention, and correction program for review and approval by the Administrator. The program may cover tanks used to store regulated substances referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6991(7) of this title. A State program may be approved by the Administrator under this section only if the State demonstrates that the State program includes the following requirements and standards and provides for adequate enforcement of compliance with such requirements and standards—(1) requirements for maintaining a leak detection system, an inventory control system together with tank testing, or a comparable system or method designed to identify releases in a manner consistent with the protection of human health and the environment;

(2) requirements for maintaining records of any monitoring or leak detection system or inventory control system or tank testing system;

(3) requirements for reporting of any releases and corrective action taken in response to a release from an underground storage tank;

(4) requirements for taking corrective action in response to a release from an underground storage tank;

(5) requirements for the closure of tanks to prevent future releases of regulated substances into the environment;

(6) requirements for maintaining evidence of financial responsibility for taking corrective action and compensating third parties for bodily injury and property damage caused by sudden and nonsudden accidental releases arising from operating an underground storage tank;

(7) standards of performance for new underground storage tanks;

(8) requirements—(A) for notifying the appropriate State agency or department (or local agency or department) designated according to section 6991a(b)(1) of this title of the existence of any oper</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Elements of State program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Elements of State program Beginning 30 months after November 8, 1984, any State may,11 So in original. The comma probably should not appear. submit an underground storage tank release detection, prevention, and correction program for review and approval by the Administrator. The program may cover tanks used to store regulated substances referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 6991(7) of this title. A State program may be approved by the Administrator under this section only if the State demonstrates that the State program includes the following requirements and standards and provides for adequate enforcement of compliance with such requirements and standards—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Federal standards</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Federal standards</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Financial responsibility</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Financial responsibility</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>EPA determination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) EPA determination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Withdrawal of authorization</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Withdrawal of authorization Whenever the Administrator determines after public hearing that a State is not administering and enforcing a program authorized under this subchapter in accordance with the provisions of this section, he shall so notify the State. If appropriate action is not taken within a reasonable time, not to exceed one hundred and twenty days after such notification, the Administrator shall withdraw approval of such program and reestablish the Federal program pursuant to this subchapter.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_6991c_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Trust Fund distribution</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Trust Fund distribution</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>