<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/706" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/706/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/706/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_706"><akn:num>706</akn:num><akn:heading>Administrative and fiscal accountability</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 706. Administrative and fiscal accountability(a) Annual reporting requirements; form, etc.(1) Each State shall prepare and submit to the Secretary annual reports on its activities under this subchapter. Each such report shall be prepared by, or in consultation with, the State maternal and child health agency. In order properly to evaluate and to compare the performance of different States assisted under this subchapter and to assure the proper expenditure of funds under this subchapter, such reports shall be in such standardized form and contain such information (including information described in paragraph (2)) as the Secretary determines (after consultation with the States) to be necessary (A) to secure an accurate description of those activities, (B) to secure a complete record of the purposes for which funds were spent, of the recipients of such funds,,11 So in original. (C) to describe the extent to which the State has met the goals and objectives it set forth under section 705(a)(2)(B)(i) of this title and the national health objectives referred to in section 701(a) of this title, and (D) to determine the extent to which funds were expended consistent with the State’s application transmitted under section 705(a) of this title. Copies of the report shall be provided, upon request, to any interested public agency, and each such agency may provide its views on these reports to the Congress.

(2) Each annual report under paragraph (1) shall include the following information:(A)(i) The number of individuals served by the State under this subchapter (by class of individuals).

(ii) The proportion of each class of such individuals which has health coverage.

(iii) The types (as defined by the Secretary) of services provided under this subchapter to individuals within each such class.

(iv) The amounts spent under this subchapter on each type of services, by class of individuals served.


(B) Information on the status of maternal and child health in the State, inclu</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_706_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Annual reporting requirements; form, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Annual reporting requirements; form, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_706_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Audits; implementation, standards, etc.</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Audits; implementation, standards, etc.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_706_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Public inspection of reports and audits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Public inspection of reports and audits The State shall make copies of the reports and audits required by this section available for public inspection within the State.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_706_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Access to books, records, etc.; creation of new records</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Access to books, records, etc.; creation of new records</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>