<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7112" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7112/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7112/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7112"><akn:num>7112</akn:num><akn:heading>Congressional declaration of purpose</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7112. Congressional declaration of purpose
The Congress therefore declares that the establishment of a Department of Energy is in the public interest and will promote the general welfare by assuring coordinated and effective administration of Federal energy policy and programs. It is the purpose of this chapter:(1) To establish a Department of Energy in the executive branch.

(2) To achieve, through the Department, effective management of energy functions of the Federal Government, including consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies in order to encourage them to establish and observe policies consistent with a coordinated energy policy, and to promote maximum possible energy conservation measures in connection with the activities within their respective jurisdictions.

(3) To provide for a mechanism through which a coordinated national energy policy can be formulated and implemented to deal with the short-, mid- and long-term energy problems of the Nation; and to develop plans and programs for dealing with domestic energy production and import shortages.

(4) To create and implement a comprehensive energy conservation strategy that will receive the highest priority in the national energy program.

(5) To carry out the planning, coordination, support, and management of a balanced and comprehensive energy research and development program, including—(A) assessing the requirements for energy research and development;

(B) developing priorities necessary to meet those requirements;

(C) undertaking programs for the optimal development of the various forms of energy production and conservation; and

(D) disseminating information resulting from such programs, including disseminating information on the commercial feasibility and use of energy from fossil, nuclear, solar, geothermal, and other energy technologies.


(6) To place major emphasis on the development and commercial use of solar, geothermal, recycling and other technologies utilizing </akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_1"><akn:num>(1)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(1) To establish a Department of Energy in the executive branch.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_2"><akn:num>(2)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(2) To achieve, through the Department, effective management of energy functions of the Federal Government, including consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies in order to encourage them to establish and observe policies consistent with a coordinated energy policy, and to promote maximum possible energy conservation measures in connection with the activities within their respective jurisdictions.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_3"><akn:num>(3)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(3) To provide for a mechanism through which a coordinated national energy policy can be formulated and implemented to deal with the short-, mid- and long-term energy problems of the Nation; and to develop plans and programs for dealing with domestic energy production and import shortages.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_4"><akn:num>(4)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(4) To create and implement a comprehensive energy conservation strategy that will receive the highest priority in the national energy program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_5"><akn:num>(5)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(5) To carry out the planning, coordination, support, and management of a balanced and comprehensive energy research and development program, including—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_6"><akn:num>(6)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(6) To place major emphasis on the development and commercial use of solar, geothermal, recycling and other technologies utilizing renewable energy resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_7"><akn:num>(7)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(7) To continue and improve the effectiveness and objectivity of a central energy data collection and analysis program within the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_8"><akn:num>(8)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(8) To facilitate establishment of an effective strategy for distributing and allocating fuels in periods of short supply and to provide for the administration of a national energy supply reserve.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_9"><akn:num>(9)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(9) To promote the interests of consumers through the provision of an adequate and reliable supply of energy at the lowest reasonable cost.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7112_10"><akn:num>(10)</akn:num><akn:content><akn:p>(10) To establish and implement through the Department, in coordination with the Secretaries of State, Treasury, and Defense, policies regarding international energy issues that have a direct impact on research, development, utilization, supply, and conservation of energy in the United States and to undertake activities involving the integration of domestic and foreign policy relating to energy, including provision of independent technical advice to the President on international negotiations involving energy resources, energy technologies, or nuclear weapons issues, except that the Secretary of State shall continue to exercise primary authority for the conduct of foreign policy relating to energy and nuclear nonproliferation, pursuant to policy guidelines established by the President.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>