<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/711a" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/711a/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/711a/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_711a"><akn:num>711a</akn:num><akn:heading>Emergency assistance to families through home visiting programs</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 711a. Emergency assistance to families through home visiting programs(a) Supplemental appropriationIn addition to amounts otherwise appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $150,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2022, to enable eligible entities to conduct programs in accordance with section 711 of this title and subsection (c) of this section.


(b) Eligibility for fundsTo be eligible to receive funds made available by subsection (a) of this section, an entity shall—(1) as of March 11, 2021, be conducting a program under section 711 of this title;

(2) ensure the modification of grants, contracts, and other agreements, as applicable, executed under section 711 of this title under which the program is conducted as are necessary to provide that, during the period that begins with March 11, 2021, and ends with the end of the 2nd succeeding fiscal year after the funds are awarded, the entity shall—(A) not reduce funding for, or staffing levels of, the program on account of reduced enrollment in the program; and

(B) when using funds to provide emergency supplies to eligible families receiving grant services under section 711 of this title, ensure coordination with local diaper banks to the extent practicable; and


(3) reaffirm that, in conducting the program, the entity will focus on priority populations (as defined in section 711(d)(4) of this title).


(c) Uses of fundsAn entity to which funds are provided under this section shall use the funds—(1) to serve families with home visits or with virtual visits, that may be conducted by the use of electronic information and telecommunications technologies, in a service delivery model described in section 711(d)(3)(A) of this title;

(2) to pay hazard pay or other additional staff costs associated with providing home visits or administration for programs funded under section 711 of this title;

(3) to train hom</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711a_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Supplemental appropriation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Supplemental appropriation In addition to amounts otherwise appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury of the United States not otherwise appropriated, there are appropriated to the Secretary $150,000,000, to remain available through September 30, 2022, to enable eligible entities to conduct programs in accordance with section 711 of this title and subsection (c) of this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711a_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Eligibility for funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Eligibility for funds To be eligible to receive funds made available by subsection (a) of this section, an entity shall—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_711a_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Uses of funds</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Uses of funds An entity to which funds are provided under this section shall use the funds—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>