<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7139" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7139/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7139/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7139"><akn:num>7139</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Science; establishment; appointment of Director; compensation; duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7139. Office of Science; establishment; appointment of Director; compensation; duties(a) EstablishmentThere shall be within the Department an Office of Science to be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall be compensated at the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5.


(b) Duties and responsibilities of DirectorIt shall be the duty and responsibility of the Director—(1) to advise the Secretary with respect to the physical research program transferred to the Department from the Energy Research and Development Administration;

(2) to monitor the Department’s energy research and development programs in order to advise the Secretary with respect to any undesirable duplication or gaps in such programs;

(3) to advise the Secretary with respect to the well-being and management of the multipurpose laboratories under the jurisdiction of the Department, excluding laboratories that constitute part of the nuclear weapons complex;

(4) to advise the Secretary with respect to education and training activities required for effective short- and long-term basic and applied research activities of the Department;

(5) to advise the Secretary with respect to grants and other forms of financial assistance required for effective short- and long-term basic and applied research activities of the Department; and

(6) to carry out such additional duties assigned to the Office by the Secretary.


(c) MissionThe mission of the Office of Science shall be the delivery of scientific discoveries, capabilities, and major scientific tools to transform the understanding of nature and to advance the energy, economic, and national security of the United States.


(d) User facilitiesThe Director shall carry out the construction, operation, and maintenance of user facilities to support the mission described in subsection (c). As practicable, these facilities shall serve th</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7139_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Establishment</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Establishment There shall be within the Department an Office of Science to be headed by a Director, who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, and who shall be compensated at the rate provided for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7139_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties and responsibilities of Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Duties and responsibilities of Director It shall be the duty and responsibility of the Director—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7139_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Mission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Mission The mission of the Office of Science shall be the delivery of scientific discoveries, capabilities, and major scientific tools to transform the understanding of nature and to advance the energy, economic, and national security of the United States.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7139_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>User facilities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) User facilities The Director shall carry out the construction, operation, and maintenance of user facilities to support the mission described in subsection (c). As practicable, these facilities shall serve the needs of the Department, industry, the academic community, and other relevant entities for the purposes of advancing the missions of the Department, improving the competitiveness of the United States, protecting public health and safety, and addressing other national priorities including emergencies.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7139_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Coordination</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Coordination</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>