<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7142" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7142/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7142/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7142"><akn:num>7142</akn:num><akn:heading>National Atomic Museum and National Atomic Testing Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7142. National Atomic Museum and National Atomic Testing Museum(a) Recognition and statusThe museum operated by the Department of Energy and currently located at Building 20358 on Wyoming Avenue South near the corner of M street within the confines of the Kirtland Air Force Base (East), Albuquerque, New Mexico—(1) is recognized as the official atomic museum of the United States;

(2) shall be known as the “National Atomic Museum”; and

(3) shall have the sole right throughout the United States and its possessions to have and use the name “National Atomic Museum”.


(b) Volunteers(1) In operating the National Atomic Museum, the Secretary of Energy may—(A) recruit, train, and accept the services of individuals without compensation as volunteers for, or in aid of, interpretive functions or other services or activities of and related to the museum; and

(B) provide to volunteers incidental expenses, such as nominal awards, uniforms, and transportation.


(2) Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), a volunteer who is not otherwise employed by the Federal Government is not subject to laws relating to Federal employment, including those relating to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave, unemployment compensation, and Federal employee benefits, because of service as a volunteer under this subsection.

(3) For purposes of chapter 171 of title 28 (relating to tort claims), a volunteer under this subsection is considered a Federal employee.

(4) For the purposes of subchapter I of chapter 81 of title 5 (relating to compensation for work-related injuries), a volunteer under this subsection is considered an employee of the United States.


(c) Authority(1) In operating the National Atomic Museum, the Secretary of Energy may—(A) accept and use donations of money or gifts pursuant to section 7262 11 See References in Text note below. of this title, if such gifts or money are designated in a written document signed by the donor as intended for the museum, and such don</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7142_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition and status</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Recognition and status The museum operated by the Department of Energy and currently located at Building 20358 on Wyoming Avenue South near the corner of M street within the confines of the Kirtland Air Force Base (East), Albuquerque, New Mexico—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7142_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Volunteers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Volunteers</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7142_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Authority</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7142_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Recognition and status of National Atomic Testing Museum</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Recognition and status of National Atomic Testing Museum The museum operated by the Nevada Test Site Historical Foundation and located in Las Vegas, Nevada—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>