<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7144b" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7144b/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7144b/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7144b"><akn:num>7144b</akn:num><akn:heading>Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7144b. Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence(a) DefinitionsIn this section, the terms “intelligence community” and “National Intelligence Program” have the meanings given such terms in section 3003 of title 50.


(b) In generalThere is in the Department an Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence. Such office shall be under the National Intelligence Program.


(c) Director(1) The head of the Office shall be the Director of the Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence, who shall be an employee in the Senior Executive Service, the Senior Intelligence Service, the Senior National Intelligence Service, or any other Service that the Secretary, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, considers appropriate. The Director of the Office shall report directly to the Secretary.

(2) The Secretary shall select an individual to serve as the Director from among individuals who have substantial expertise in matters relating to the intelligence community, including foreign intelligence and counterintelligence.


(d) Duties(1) Subject to the authority, direction, and control of the Secretary, the Director shall perform such duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary may prescribe.

(2) The Director shall be responsible for establishing policy for intelligence and counterintelligence programs and activities at the Department.

(3) The Director shall develop and implement—(A) a plan and cost assessment for delineated and standardized counterintelligence training for all personnel who interact with classified and sensitive military technology and dual-use commercial technology in the Department; and

(B) a delineated and standardized training plan to train officers in the Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence who have counterintelligence responsibilities on counterintelligence skills and practices.



(Pub. L. 95–91, title II, § 215, as added Pub. L. 106–65, div. C, title XXXII, § 3204(a), Oct. 5, 1999, 113 Stat. 955; amended Pub</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7144b_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions In this section, the terms “intelligence community” and “National Intelligence Program” have the meanings given such terms in section 3003 of title 50.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7144b_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>In general</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) In general There is in the Department an Office of Intelligence and Counterintelligence. Such office shall be under the National Intelligence Program.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7144b_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Director</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Director</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7144b_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Duties</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Duties</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>