<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7153" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7153/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7153/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7153"><akn:num>7153</akn:num><akn:heading>Administration of leasing transfers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7153. Administration of leasing transfers(a) Authority retained by Secretary of the InteriorThe Secretary of the Interior shall retain any authorities not transferred under section 7152(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and shall be solely responsible for the issuance and supervision of Federal leases and the enforcement of all regulations applicable to the leasing of mineral resources, including but not limited to lease terms and conditions and production rates. No regulation promulgated by the Secretary shall restrict or limit any authority retained by the Secretary of the Interior under section 7152(b) 1 of this title with respect to the issuance or supervision of Federal leases. Nothing in section 7152(b) 1 of this title shall be construed to affect Indian lands and resources or to transfer any functions of the Secretary of the Interior concerning such lands and resources.


(b) Consultation with Secretary of the Interior with respect to promulgation of regulationsIn exercising the authority under section 7152(b) 1 of this title to promulgate regulations, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior during the preparation of such regulations and shall afford the Secretary of the Interior not less than thirty days, prior to the date on which the Department first publishes or otherwise prescribes regulations, to comment on the content and effect of such regulations.


(c) Repealed. Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201, Dec. 23, 1981, 95 Stat. 1407

(d) Preparation of environmental impact statementThe Department of the Interior shall be the lead agency for the purpose of preparation of an environmental impact statement required by section 4332(2)(C) of this title for any action with respect to the Federal leases taken under the authority of this section, unless the action involves only matters within the exclusive authority of the Secretary.


(Pub. L. 95–91, title III, § 303, Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 579; Pub. L. 97–100, title II,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7153_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Authority retained by Secretary of the Interior</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Authority retained by Secretary of the Interior The Secretary of the Interior shall retain any authorities not transferred under section 7152(b) 11 See References in Text note below. of this title and shall be solely responsible for the issuance and supervision of Federal leases and the enforcement of all regulations applicable to the leasing of mineral resources, including but not limited to lease terms and conditions and production rates. No regulation promulgated by the Secretary shall restrict or limit any authority retained by the Secretary of the Interior under section 7152(b) 1 of this title with respect to the issuance or supervision of Federal leases. Nothing in section 7152(b) 1 of this title shall be construed to affect Indian lands and resources or to transfer any functions of the Secretary of the Interior concerning such lands and resources.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7153_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consultation with Secretary of the Interior with respect to promulgation of regulations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Consultation with Secretary of the Interior with respect to promulgation of regulations In exercising the authority under section 7152(b) 1 of this title to promulgate regulations, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of the Interior during the preparation of such regulations and shall afford the Secretary of the Interior not less than thirty days, prior to the date on which the Department first publishes or otherwise prescribes regulations, to comment on the content and effect of such regulations.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7153_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 97–100, title II, § 201, Dec. 23, 1981, 95 Stat. 1407</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7153_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Preparation of environmental impact statement</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Preparation of environmental impact statement The Department of the Interior shall be the lead agency for the purpose of preparation of an environmental impact statement required by section 4332(2)(C) of this title for any action with respect to the Federal leases taken under the authority of this section, unless the action involves only matters within the exclusive authority of the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>