<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7172" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7172/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7172/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7172"><akn:num>7172</akn:num><akn:heading>Jurisdiction of Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7172. Jurisdiction of Commission(a) Transfer of functions from Federal Power Commission(1) There are transferred to, and vested in, the Commission the following functions of the Federal Power Commission or of any member of the Commission or any officer or component of the Commission:(A) the investigation, issuance, transfer, renewal, revocation, and enforcement of licenses and permits for the construction, operation, and maintenance of dams, water conduits, reservoirs, powerhouses, transmission lines, or other works for the development and improvement of navigation and for the development and utilization of power across, along, from, or in navigable waters under part I of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.];

(B) the establishment, review, and enforcement of rates and charges for the transmission or sale of electric energy, including determinations on construction work in progress, under part II of the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 824 et seq.], and the interconnection, under section 202(b), of such Act [16 U.S.C. 824a(b)], of facilities for the generation, transmission, and sale of electric energy (other than emergency interconnection);

(C) the establishment, review, and enforcement of rates and charges for the transportation and sale of natural gas by a producer or gatherer or by a natural gas pipeline or natural gas company under sections 1, 4, 5, and 6 of the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717, 717c to 717e];

(D) the issuance of a certificate of public convenience and necessity, including abandonment of facilities or services, and the establishment of physical connections under section 7 of the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717f];

(E) the establishment, review, and enforcement of curtailments, other than the establishment and review of priorities for such curtailments, under the Natural Gas Act [15 U.S.C. 717 et seq.]; and

(F) the regulation of mergers and securities acquisition under the Federal Power Act [16 U.S.C. 791a et seq.] and Natural Gas Act [1</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Transfer of functions from Federal Power Commission</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Transfer of functions from Federal Power Commission</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Repealed. Pub. L. 103–272, § 7(b), July 5, 1994, 108 Stat. 1379</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Repealed.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Consideration of proposals made by Secretary to amend regulations issued under section 753 of title 15; exception</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Consideration of proposals made by Secretary to amend regulations issued under</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters involving agency determinations to be made on record after agency hearing</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Matters involving agency determinations to be made on record after agency hearing The Commission shall have jurisdiction to hear and determine any other matter arising under any other function of the Secretary— except that nothing in this subsection shall require that functions under sections 6213 and 6214 1 of this title shall be within the jurisdiction of the Commission unless the Secretary assigns such a function to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Matters assigned by Secretary after public notice and matters referred under section 7174 of this title</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Matters assigned by Secretary after public notice and matters referred under In addition to the other provisions of this section, the Commission shall have jurisdiction over any other matter which the Secretary may assign to the Commission after public notice, or which are required to be referred to the Commission pursuant to section 7174 of this title.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Limitation No function described in this section which regulates the exports or imports of natural gas or electricity shall be within the jurisdiction of the Commission unless the Secretary assigns such a function to the Commission.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Final agency action</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Final agency action The decision of the Commission involving any function within its jurisdiction, other than action by it on a matter referred to it pursuant to section 7174 of this title, shall be final agency action within the meaning of section 704 of title 5 and shall not be subject to further review by the Secretary or any officer or employee of the Department.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7172_h"><akn:num>(h)</akn:num><akn:heading>Rules, regulations, and statements of policy</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(h) Rules, regulations, and statements of policy The Commission is authorized to prescribe rules, regulations, and statements of policy of general applicability with respect to any function under the jurisdiction of the Commission pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>