<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7191" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7191/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7191/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7191"><akn:num>7191</akn:num><akn:heading>Procedures for issuance of rules, regulations, or orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7191. Procedures for issuance of rules, regulations, or orders(a) Applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5(1) Subject to the other requirements of this subchapter, the provisions of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5 shall apply in accordance with its terms to any rule or regulation, or any order having the applicability and effect of a rule (as defined in section 551(4) of title 5), issued pursuant to authority vested by law in, or transferred or delegated to, the Secretary, or required by this chapter or any other Act to be carried out by any other officer, employee, or component of the Department, other than the Commission, including any such rule, regulation, or order of a State, or local government agency or officer thereof, issued pursuant to authority delegated by the Secretary in accordance with this subchapter. If any provision of any Act, the functions of which are transferred, vested, or delegated pursuant to this chapter, provides administrative procedure requirements in addition to the requirements provided in this subchapter, such additional requirements shall also apply to actions under that provision.

(2) Notwithstanding paragraph (1), this subchapter shall apply to the Commission to the same extent this subchapter applies to the Secretary in the exercise of any of the Commission’s functions under section 7172(c)(1) of this title or which the Secretary has assigned under section 7172(e) of this title.


(b) Substantial issue of fact or law or likelihood of substantial impact on Nation’s economy, etc.; oral presentation(1) If the Secretary determines, on his own initiative or in response to any showing made pursuant to paragraph (2) (with respect to a proposed rule, regulation, or order described in subsection (a)) that no substantial issue of fact or law exists and that such rule, regulation, or order is unlikely to have a substantial impact on the Nation’s economy or large numbers of individuals or businesses, such proposed rule,</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7191_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Applicability of subchapter II of chapter 5 of title 5</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7191_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Substantial issue of fact or law or likelihood of substantial impact on Nation’s economy, etc.; oral presentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Substantial issue of fact or law or likelihood of substantial impact on Nation’s economy, etc.; oral presentation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7191_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Waiver of requirements</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Waiver of requirements The requirements of subsection (b) of this section may be waived where strict compliance is found by the Secretary to be likely to cause serious harm or injury to the public health, safety, or welfare, and such finding is set out in detail in such rule, regulation, or order. In the event the requirements of this section are waived, the requirements shall be satisfied within a reasonable period of time subsequent to the promulgation of such rule, regulation, or order.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7191_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effects confined to single unit of local government, geographic area within State, or State; hearing or oral presentation</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Effects confined to single unit of local government, geographic area within State, or State; hearing or oral presentation</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7191_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Prescription of procedures for State and local government agencies</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Prescription of procedures for State and local government agencies Where authorized by any law vested, transferred, or delegated pursuant to this chapter, the Secretary may, by rule, prescribe procedures for State or local government agencies authorized by the Secretary to carry out such functions as may be permitted under applicable law. Such procedures shall apply to such agencies in lieu of this section, and shall require that prior to taking any action, such agencies shall take steps reasonably calculated to provide notice to persons who may be affected by the action, and shall afford an opportunity for presentation of views (including oral presentation of views where practicable) within a reasonable time before taking the action.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>