<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7193" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7193/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7193/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7193"><akn:num>7193</akn:num><akn:heading>Remedial orders</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7193. Remedial orders(a) Violations of rules, regulations, or orders promulgated pursuant to Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973If upon investigation the Secretary or his authorized representative believes that a person has violated any regulation, rule, or order described in section 7191(a) of this title promulgated pursuant to the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 11 See References in Text note below. [15 U.S.C. 751 et seq.], he may issue a remedial order to the person. Each remedial order shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of such rule, regulation, or order alleged to have been violated. For purposes of this section “person” includes any individual, association, company, corporation, partnership, or other entity however organized.


(b) Notice of intent to contest; final order not subject to reviewIf within thirty days after the receipt of the remedial order issued by the Secretary, the person fails to notify the Secretary that he intends to contest the remedial order, the remedial order shall become effective and shall be deemed a final order of the Secretary and not subject to review by any court or agency.


(c) Notice of contestation to Commission; stay; hearing; cross examination; final order; enforcement and reviewIf within thirty days after the receipt of the remedial order issued by the Secretary, the person notifies the Secretary that he intends to contest a remedial order issued under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall immediately advise the Commission of such notification. Upon such notice, the Commission shall stay the effect of the remedial order, unless the Commission finds the public interest requires immediate compliance with such remedial order. The Commission shall, upon request, afford an opportunity for a hearing, including, at a minimum, the submission of briefs, oral or documentary evidence, and oral arguments. To the</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Violations of rules, regulations, or orders promulgated pursuant to Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Violations of rules, regulations, or orders promulgated pursuant to Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 If upon investigation the Secretary or his authorized representative believes that a person has violated any regulation, rule, or order described in section 7191(a) of this title promulgated pursuant to the Emergency Petroleum Allocation Act of 1973 11 See References in Text note below. [15 U.S.C. 751 et seq.], he may issue a remedial order to the person. Each remedial order shall be in writing and shall describe with particularity the nature of the violation, including a reference to the provision of such rule, regulation, or order alleged to have been violated. For purposes of this section “person” includes any individual, association, company, corporation, partnership, or other entity however organized.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of intent to contest; final order not subject to review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Notice of intent to contest; final order not subject to review If within thirty days after the receipt of the remedial order issued by the Secretary, the person fails to notify the Secretary that he intends to contest the remedial order, the remedial order shall become effective and shall be deemed a final order of the Secretary and not subject to review by any court or agency.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Notice of contestation to Commission; stay; hearing; cross examination; final order; enforcement and review</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Notice of contestation to Commission; stay; hearing; cross examination; final order; enforcement and review If within thirty days after the receipt of the remedial order issued by the Secretary, the person notifies the Secretary that he intends to contest a remedial order issued under subsection (a) of this section, the Secretary shall immediately advise the Commission of such notification. Upon such notice, the Commission shall stay the effect of the remedial order, unless the Commission finds the public interest requires immediate compliance with such remedial order. The Commission shall, upon request, afford an opportunity for a hearing, including, at a minimum, the submission of briefs, oral or documentary evidence, and oral arguments. To the extent that the Commission in its discretion determines that such is required for a full and true disclosure of the facts, the Commission shall afford the right of cross examination. The Commission shall thereafter issue an order, based on</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Time limits</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Time limits The Secretary may set reasonable time limits for the Commission to complete action on a proceeding referred to it pursuant to this section.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Effect on procedural action taken by Secretary prior to issuance of initial remedial order</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Effect on procedural action taken by Secretary prior to issuance of initial remedial order Nothing in preceding provisions of this section shall be construed to affect any procedural action taken by the Secretary prior to or incident to initial issuance of a remedial order which is the subject of the hearing provided in preceding provisions of this section, but such procedures shall be reviewable in the hearing.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Savings provision</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Savings provision The provisions of preceding provisions of this section shall be applicable only with respect to proceedings initiated by a notice of probable violation issued after October 1, 1977.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7193_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retroactive application; marketing of petroleum products</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Retroactive application; marketing of petroleum products With respect to any person whose sole petroleum industry operation relates to the marketing of petroleum products, the Secretary or any person acting on his behalf may not exercise discretion to maintain a civil action (other than an action for injunctive relief) or issue a remedial order against such person for any violation of any rule or regulation if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>