<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7237" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7237/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7237/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7237"><akn:num>7237</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority placement, job placement, retraining, and counseling programs for United States Department </akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7237. Priority placement, job placement, retraining, and counseling programs for United States Department of Energy employees affected by reduction in force(a) Definitions(1) For the purposes of this section, the term “agency” means the United States Department of Energy.

(2) For the purposes of this section, the term “eligible employee” means any employee of the agency who—(A) is scheduled to be separated from service due to a reduction in force under—(i) regulations prescribed under section 3502 of title 5; or

(ii) procedures established under section 3595 of title 5; or


(B) is separated from service due to such a reduction in force, but does not include—(i) an employee separated from service for cause on charges of misconduct or delinquency; or

(ii) an employee who, at the time of separation, meets the age and service requirements for an immediate annuity under subchapter III of chapter 83 or chapter 84 of title 5.




(b) Priority placement and retraining programNot later than 30 days after September 30, 1996, the United States Department of Energy shall establish an agency-wide priority placement and retraining program for eligible employees.


(c) Filling vacancy from outside agencyThe priority placement program established under subsection (b) shall include provisions under which a vacant position shall not be filled by the appointment or transfer of any individual from outside of the agency if—(1) there is then available any eligible employee who applies for the position within 30 days of the agency issuing a job announcement and is qualified (or can be trained or retrained to become qualified within 90 days of assuming the position) for the position; and

(2) the position is within the same commuting area as the eligible employee’s last-held position or residence.


(d) Job placement and counseling servicesThe head of the agency may establish a program to provide job placement and counseling services to eligible employees. A program established under</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7237_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>Definitions</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) Definitions</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7237_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Priority placement and retraining program</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Priority placement and retraining program Not later than 30 days after September 30, 1996, the United States Department of Energy shall establish an agency-wide priority placement and retraining program for eligible employees.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7237_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Filling vacancy from outside agency</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Filling vacancy from outside agency The priority placement program established under subsection (b) shall include provisions under which a vacant position shall not be filled by the appointment or transfer of any individual from outside of the agency if—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7237_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Job placement and counseling services</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Job placement and counseling services The head of the agency may establish a program to provide job placement and counseling services to eligible employees. A program established under subsection (d) may include, but is not limited to, such services as—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>