<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7256" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7256/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7256/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7256"><akn:num>7256</akn:num><akn:heading>Contracts, leases, etc., with public agencies and private organizations and persons</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7256. Contracts, leases, etc., with public agencies and private organizations and persons(a) General authorityThe Secretary is authorized to enter into and perform such contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other similar transactions with public agencies and private organizations and persons, and to make such payments (in lump sum or installments, and by way of advance or reimbursement) as he may deem to be necessary or appropriate to carry out functions now or hereafter vested in the Secretary.


(b) Limitation on authority; appropriationsNotwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, no authority to enter into contracts or to make payments under this subchapter shall be effective except to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.


(c) Leasing of excess Department of Energy propertyThe Secretary may lease, upon terms and conditions the Secretary considers appropriate to promote national security or the public interest, acquired real property and related personal property that—(1) is located at a facility of the Department of Energy to be closed or reconfigured;

(2) at the time the lease is entered into, is not needed by the Department of Energy; and

(3) is under the control of the Department of Energy.


(d) Terms of lease(1) A lease entered into under subsection (c) may not be for a term of more than 10 years, except that the Secretary may enter into a lease that includes an option to renew for a term of more than 10 years if the Secretary determines that entering into such a lease will promote the national security or be in the public interest.

(2) A lease entered into under subsection (c) may provide for the payment (in cash or in kind) by the lessee of consideration in an amount that is less than the fair market rental value of the leasehold interest. Services relating to the protection and maintenance of the leased property may constitute all or part of such consideration.


(e) Environmental conce</akn:p></akn:content><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_a"><akn:num>(a)</akn:num><akn:heading>General authority</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(a) General authority The Secretary is authorized to enter into and perform such contracts, leases, cooperative agreements, or other similar transactions with public agencies and private organizations and persons, and to make such payments (in lump sum or installments, and by way of advance or reimbursement) as he may deem to be necessary or appropriate to carry out functions now or hereafter vested in the Secretary.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_b"><akn:num>(b)</akn:num><akn:heading>Limitation on authority; appropriations</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(b) Limitation on authority; appropriations Notwithstanding any other provision of this subchapter, no authority to enter into contracts or to make payments under this subchapter shall be effective except to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_c"><akn:num>(c)</akn:num><akn:heading>Leasing of excess Department of Energy property</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(c) Leasing of excess Department of Energy property The Secretary may lease, upon terms and conditions the Secretary considers appropriate to promote national security or the public interest, acquired real property and related personal property that—</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_d"><akn:num>(d)</akn:num><akn:heading>Terms of lease</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(d) Terms of lease</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_e"><akn:num>(e)</akn:num><akn:heading>Environmental concerns</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(e) Environmental concerns</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_f"><akn:num>(f)</akn:num><akn:heading>Retention and use of rentals; report</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(f) Retention and use of rentals; report To the extent provided in advance in appropriations Acts, the Secretary may retain and use money rentals received by the Secretary directly from a lease entered into under subsection (c) in any amount the Secretary considers necessary to cover the administrative expenses of the lease, the maintenance and repair of the leased property, or environmental restoration activities at the facility where the leased property is located. Amounts retained under this subsection shall be retained in a separate fund established in the Treasury for such purpose. The Secretary shall annually submit to the Congress a report on amounts retained and amounts used under this subsection.</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection><akn:subsection eId="subsec_7256_g"><akn:num>(g)</akn:num><akn:heading>Additional authorities</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>(g) Additional authorities</akn:p></akn:content></akn:subsection></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>