<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0"><akn:act><akn:meta><akn:identification source="#cosilico"><akn:FRBRWork prescriptive="true" authoritative="true"><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7266" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="retrieval" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#us-congress" /><akn:FRBRcountry value="us" /></akn:FRBRWork><akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7266/eng@2025" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /><akn:FRBRlanguage language="en" /></akn:FRBRExpression><akn:FRBRManifestation><akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us/usc/42/7266/eng@2025/main.xml" /><akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" /><akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" /></akn:FRBRManifestation></akn:identification></akn:meta><akn:body><akn:section eId="sec_7266"><akn:num>7266</akn:num><akn:heading>Designation of conservation officers</akn:heading><akn:content><akn:p>§ 7266. Designation of conservation officers
The Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Secretary of Transportation, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, the United States Postal Service, and the Administrator of General Services shall each designate one Assistant Secretary or Assistant Administrator, as the case may be, as the principal conservation officer of such Department or of the Administration. Such designated principal conservation officer shall be principally responsible for planning and implementation of energy conservation programs by such Department or Administration and principally responsible for coordination with the Department of Energy with respect to energy matters. Each agency, Department or Administration required to designate a principal conservation officer pursuant to this section shall periodically inform the Secretary of the identity of such conservation officer, and the Secretary shall periodically publish a list identifying such officers.
(Pub. L. 95–91, title VI, § 656, Aug. 4, 1977, 91 Stat. 602.)</akn:p></akn:content></akn:section></akn:body></akn:act></akn:akomaNtoso>